<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40993794</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2057-3804</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardio-oncology (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiooncology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular toxicity of Fruquintinib in patients with colorectal and other cancers: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>82</StartPage><MedlinePgn>82</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">82</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40959-025-00347-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Fruquintinib is a highly selective tyrosine kinase inhibitor that targets vascular endothelial growth factor receptors (VEGFR) 1, 2, and 3, which play a critical role in angiogenesis and tumor growth. As a novel anti-angiogenic agent, Fruquintinib has demonstrated promising efficacy in the treatment of various advanced malignancies, including metastatic colorectal cancer. However, concerns about its cardiovascular safety have emerged, given that VEGFR inhibition is often associated with cardiovascular adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a systematic search through PubMed, Scopus, Embase, and Web of Science to identify randomized controlled trials and cohort studies that assessed the safety of Fruquintinib compared with placebo in patients with metastatic colorectal and other cancers. The evaluated outcomes included hypertension, coronary artery disease, cerebrovascular accidents, peripheral artery disease, heart failure, thromboembolism, arrhythmias, aortic dissection, and superior vena cava syndrome. Two independent reviewers screened the titles/abstracts based on predefined inclusion and exclusion criteria, followed by a full-text review of potentially relevant studies. Any disagreements between the reviewers were resolved through consultation with a third reviewer to ensure the accuracy and consistency of the study selection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifteen reports were included in our study. Out of 3832 patients taking Fruquintinib monotherapy, a total of 997 developed hypertension with a pooled estimate incidence of 0.329 (95% CI: 0.248, 0.410; P &lt; 0.001). In comparison to placebo, Fruquintinib was associated with significantly higher odds of developing hypertension (OR: 6.856; 95% CI: 5.071, 9.268; P &lt; 0.001). Compared to Regorafenib, Fruquintinib demonstrated an OR of 1.549 (95% CI: 0.804, 2.983; P = 0.191) for the development of hypertension. Additionally, patients taking Fruquintinib had a pooled estimate incidence of 0.041 (95% CI: 0.021, 0.060, P &lt; 0.001) for thromboembolism development with an OR of 2.092 (95% CI: 0.813, 5.385; P = 0.126) compared to placebo. Other reported cardiovascular side effects included sinus tachycardia, superior vena cava syndrome, peripheral edema, heart failure, myocardial enzymes elevation, and vascular access complications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study found that Fruquintinib is associated with significant cardiovascular risks, with hypertension being the most common adverse event, while thromboembolism did not reach statistical significance. Therefore, close monitoring for treatment-related cardiovascular events should be considered in these patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Nouri</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, An-Najah National University, Nablus, Palestine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Awashra</LastName><ForeName>Ameer</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, An-Najah National University, Nablus, Palestine. Ameer.awashra7@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hamdan</LastName><ForeName>Dawoud</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, An-Najah National University, Nablus, Palestine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajab</LastName><ForeName>Islam</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, St. Joseph's University Medical Center, Paterson, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shubietah</LastName><ForeName>Abdalhakim</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Advocate Illinois Masonic Medical Center, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>Yahya</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, An-Najah National University, Nablus, Palestine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, An-Najah National University Hospital, Nablus, Palestine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rmilah</LastName><ForeName>Anan Abu</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Mayo Clinic, 200 1st St SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiooncology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101689938</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2057-3804</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arrhythmia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular toxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Colorectal cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fruquintinib</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malignancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oncology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40993794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40959-025-00347-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40959-025-00347-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12462324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cutsem EV, Cervantes A, Adam R, et al. ESMO consensus guidelines for the management of patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. Ann Oncol. 2016;27:1386&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, Laversanne M, Soerjomataram I, Jemal A, Bray F. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71:209&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan E, Arnold M, Gini A, Lorenzoni V, Cabasag CJ, Laversanne M, Vignat J, Ferlay J, Murphy N, Bray F. Global burden of colorectal cancer in 2020 and 2040: incidence and mortality estimates from GLOBOCAN. Gut. 2023;72:338&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36604116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zou J-Y, Wang Z, Wang Y. Fruquintinib: a novel antivascular endothelial growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor for the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer. Cancer Manag Res. 2019;11:7787&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31496821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Qin S, Xu R-H, et al. Effect of Fruquintinib vs placebo on overall survival in patients with previously treated metastatic colorectal cancer: the FRESCO randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2018;319:2486&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Wang W, Li J, Li Z, Liu Z, Zhang S, Chen Z, Wang H, Wang X, Wang J. Clinical research progress of fruquintinib in the treatment of malignant tumors. Invest New Drugs. 2024. 10.1007/s10637-024-01476-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11625063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39352649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fruquintinib Monograph for Professionals. In: Drugs.com. https://www.drugs.com/monograph/fruquintinib.html. Accessed 21 Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahani H, Mahmoudi T, Asadi A, Nobakht H, Dabiri R, Hamta A. Insulin resistance and colorectal cancer risk: the role of elevated plasma resistin levels. J Gastrointest Cancer. 2020;51:478&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31168777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramandi A, George J, Behnoush AH, Delavari A, Mohammadi Z, Poustchi H, Malekzadeh R. The association between serum gamma-glutamyl transferase and gastrointestinal cancer risk: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cancer Med. 2025;14:e70581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11736428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39817495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2021;10:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J, Zhang J, Peng W, Chen Z, Fan S, Su W, Li K, Li J. A Phase I study of safety and pharmacokinetics of fruquintinib, a novel selective inhibitor of vascular endothelial growth factor receptor-1, -2, and -3 tyrosine kinases in Chinese patients with advanced solid tumors. Cancer Chemother Pharmacol. 2016;78:259&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27299749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasari A, Lonardi S, Garcia-Carbonero R, et al. Fruquintinib versus placebo in patients with refractory metastatic colorectal cancer (FRESCO-2): an international, multicentre, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 study. The Lancet. 2023;402:41&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37331369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Chang J, Liu X, et al. Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter Phase II study of fruquintinib after two prior chemotherapy regimens in Chinese patients with advanced nonsquamous non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36:1207&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29528793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Chen G, Sun Y, et al. A Phase III, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter study of fruquintinib in Chinese patients with advanced nonsquamous non-small-cell lung cancer &#x2013; The FALUCA study. Lung Cancer. 2020;146:252&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan S, Zhang S, Zhou N, Cai X, Yi C, Gou H. Efficacy and safety of fruquintinib dose-escalation strategy for elderly patients with refractory metastatic colorectal cancer: a single-arm, multicenter, phase II study. Cancer Med. 2023;12:22038&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10757135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38063405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang-Gillam A, Schelman W, Ukrainskyj S, Chien C, Gonzalez M, Yang Z, Kania M, Yeckes-Rodin H. Phase 1/1b open-label, dose-escalation study of fruquintinib in patients with advanced solid tumors in the United States. Invest New Drugs. 2023;41:851&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10663261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37796398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R-H, Li J, Bai Y, et al. Safety and efficacy of fruquintinib in patients with previously treated metastatic colorectal cancer: a phase Ib study and a randomized double-blind phase II study. J Hematol OncolJ Hematol Oncol. 2017;10:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5244709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An TQ, Qiu H, Zhou QB, Zong H, Hu S, Lian YG, Zhao RH. Efficacy comparison of fruquintinib, regorafenib monotherapy or plus programmed death-1 inhibitors for microsatellite stable metastatic colorectal cancer. World J Gastrointest Oncol. 2024;16:2449&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11236229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38994132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y, Sun L, Zhuang L, Zhang M, Zou Y, Yuan X, Qiu H. Efficacy and safety of low-dose apatinib plus S-1 versus regorafenib and fruquintinib for refractory metastatic colorectal cancer: a retrospective cohort study. J Gastrointest Oncol. 2022;13:722&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9086039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35557597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wang Z, Zhong H, et al. A phase IV study to evaluate the safety of fruquintinib in Chinese patients in real-world clinical practice. Oncologist. 2024;29:e1012&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11299944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38642091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Lu L, Pan F, Yang C, Liang J, Liu J, Wang J, Shen R, Xin F-Z, Zhang N. Real-world data: fruquintinib in treating metastatic colorectal cancer. Oncol Res Featur Preclin Clin Cancer Ther. 2022;29:25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Qu T, Zhang H, Sun Y, Cui C, Chi Y, Zhang W, Wang X, Yang L. The real-world practice of Fruquintinib for Chinese patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. Cancer Manag Res. 2021;13:6199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8357312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34393513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Cao H, Jiang C, He W, You Y, Peng K, Jin Y, Xia L. Previous use of anti-vascular endothelial growth factor receptor agents decreases efficacy of fruquintinib in metastatic colorectal cancer refractory to standard therapies. Front Oncol. 2020;10:587692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7691567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33282739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Chen M, Wang Z, et al. Efficacy and safety comparison of regorafenib and fruquintinib in metastatic colorectal cancer-an observational cohort study in the real world. Clin Colorectal Cancer. 2022;21:e152&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GA Wells, B Shea, D O&#x2019;Connell, J Peterson, V Welch, M Losos, P Tugwell The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses. https://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epidemiology/oxford.asp. Accessed 21 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness LA, Higgins JPT. Risk-of-bias VISualization (robvis): An R package and Shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Res Synth Methods. 2021;12:55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasari A, Sobrero A, Yao J, Yoshino T, Schelman W, Yang Z, Chien C, Kania M, Tabernero J, Eng C. FRESCO-2: a global phase III study investigating the efficacy and safety of fruquintinib in metastatic colorectal cancer. Future Oncol. 2021;17:3151&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Zhou J, Zhang Z, et al. Discovery of fruquintinib, a potent and highly selective small molecule inhibitor of VEGFR 1, 2, 3 tyrosine kinases for cancer therapy. Cancer Biol Ther. 2014;15:1635&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4622458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25482937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bester J, Pretorius E. Effects of IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6 and IL-8 on erythrocytes, platelets and clot viscoelasticity. Sci Rep. 2016;6:32188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27561337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moens S, Goveia J, Stapor PC, Cantelmo AR, Carmeliet P. The multifaceted activity of VEGF in angiogenesis - implications for therapy responses. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2014;25:473&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25169850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferroni P, Formica V, Roselli M, Guadagni F. Thromboembolic events in patients treated with anti-angiogenic drugs. Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2010;8:102&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19485903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanigaimani S, Kichenadasse G, Mangoni AA. The emerging role of vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) in vascular homeostasis: lessons from recent trials with anti-VEGF drugs. Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2011;9:358&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde PS, Wallin JJ, Mancao C. Predictive markers of anti-VEGF and emerging role of angiogenesis inhibitors as immunotherapeutics. Semin Cancer Biol. 2018;52:117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29229461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riondino S, Del Monte G, Fratangeli F, Guadagni F, Roselli M, Ferroni P. Anti-angiogenic drugs, vascular toxicity and thromboembolism in solid cancer. Cardiovasc Hematol Agents Med Chem. 2017;15:3&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Zhang X, Zhang J, et al. Vascular endothelial growth factor and the risk of venous thromboembolism: a genetic correlation and two-sample Mendelian randomization study. Thromb J. 2022;20:67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9644522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36348399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y-Y, Chen Y-W, Wang M-X, Zhu P-F, Pan S-Y, Jiang D-Y, Chen Z-L, Yang L. Acute aortic dissection caused by fruquintinib for metastatic colorectal cancer&#x2014;a case report and literature review. Transl Cancer Res. 2023;12:177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9906055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36760383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y-Y, Zhang X-Y, Zhu P-F, Lu H-R, Liu Q, Pan S-Y, Chen Z-L, Yang L. Comparison of the efficacy and safety of fruquintinib and regorafenib in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer: A real-world study. Front Oncol. 2023. 10.3389/fonc.2023.1097911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36937443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott SS, et al. Intracellular Cardiac Signaling Pathways Altered by Cancer Therapies. In: Parinandi NL, Hund TJ, editors. Cardiovascular Signaling in Health and Disease. Cham: Springer; 2022. 10.1007/978-3-031-08309-9_4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37988531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>