<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41024970</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1949-8462</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coronary computed tomography angiography <i>vs</i> stress testing for stable angina evaluation: Diagnostic and prognostic superiority.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>110061</StartPage><MedlinePgn>110061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">110061</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4330/wjc.v17.i9.110061</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Stable angina pectoris, a clinical manifestation of coronary artery disease (CAD), is commonly evaluated using non-invasive diagnostic tools. Traditionally, stress testing modalities such as exercise electrocardiography (ECG), myocardial perfusion imaging (MPI), and stress echocardiography have been the first-line strategies. However, coronary computed tomography angiography (CCTA), an anatomic imaging modality, is increasingly used for its ability to directly visualize coronary artery stenoses and plaque burden. Despite growing adoption, the comparative effectiveness of CCTA and stress testing in terms of diagnostic accuracy, prognostic value, and clinical outcomes in stable angina remains an area of active debate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the diagnostic and prognostic performance of CCTA with various forms of stress testing in adult patients presenting with suspected or confirmed stable angina.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive literature search was performed across PubMed, EMBASE, Scopus, and the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials in accordance with the PRISMA guidelines. Only randomized controlled trials (RCT) published in English within the last 15 years were included. Studies involving adult patients (&#x2265; 18 years) with stable angina or low-risk chest pain were selected. The intervention was CCTA, and the comparators included ECG, MPI, and stress echocardiography. Data were extracted using a standardized process, and study quality was assessed using the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2.0 tool. Due to heterogeneity in outcome measures and modalities, narrative synthesis was employed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Five high-quality RCTs encompassing a total of 5551 patients were included. CCTA demonstrated superior diagnostic accuracy and prognostic capability across multiple studies. It was more effective in predicting major adverse cardiac events, including myocardial infarction and cardiac death, and was associated with fewer unnecessary invasive coronary angiographies and better event-free survival. Studies also reported improved revascularization rates in patients evaluated with CCTA, particularly within tiered diagnostic protocols. Stress testing, while useful, showed limitations in sensitivity and downstream clinical decision-making.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">CCTA offers a diagnostically superior and clinically impactful strategy for the initial evaluation of patients with stable angina, especially those with intermediate pretest probability of CAD. Compared to conventional stress testing, it enhances risk stratification, reduces unnecessary procedures, and may improve long-term outcomes. These findings support its broader integration into diagnostic pathways for stable angina.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gundareddy</LastName><ForeName>Vinay</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nathan Kline Institute for Psychiatric Research, Orangeburg, NY 10962, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singla</LastName><ForeName>Shivam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Tidal Health Peninsula Regional, Salisbury, NC 21801, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mounika</LastName><ForeName>Jupalle</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Kurnool Medical College, Kurnool 518002, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owona</LastName><ForeName>Okello</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ministry of Health, Lusaka 10101, Zambia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singla</LastName><ForeName>Bhavna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Erie County Medical Center, Buffalo, NY 14215, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Taranpreet</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Mahatma Gandhi Mission Medical College and Hospital, Navi Mumbai 410209, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anwar</LastName><ForeName>Sidra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Shaikh Zayed Hospital, Lahore 54600, Punjab, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramachandran</LastName><ForeName>Vignesh</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Melmaruvathur Adhiparasakthi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research, Melmaruvathur 603319, Tamil N&#x101;du, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ullah</LastName><ForeName>Hikmat</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Allama Iqbal Medical College, Lahore 54550, Punjab, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazari</LastName><ForeName>Shabbir</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Kabul Medical University, Kabul 100306, Afghanistan. shabbirmazari826@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101537090</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary computed tomography angiography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnostic accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Event-free survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardial perfusion imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-invasive cardiac imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Revascularization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stable angina</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress testing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41024970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12476583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4330/wjc.v17.i9.110061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gillen C, Goyal A. Stable Angina. 2022 Dec 19. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025 Jan-</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senior R, Monaghan M, Becher H, Mayet J, Nihoyannopoulos P British Society of Echocardiography. Stress echocardiography for the diagnosis and risk stratification of patients with suspected or known coronary artery disease: a critical appraisal. Supported by the British Society of Echocardiography. Heart. 2005;91:427&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1768798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15772187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ananthasubramaniam G, Ananthasubramaniam K. Stress electrocardiography testing in coronary artery disease: Is it time for its swan song or to redefine its role in the modern era? Indian Heart J. 2022;74:81&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9039687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35167825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh R, Patel A, Lu B, Senapati A, Mahmarian J, Chang SM. Cardiac Computed Tomography for Comprehensive Coronary Assessment: Beyond Diagnosis of Anatomic Stenosis. Methodist Debakey Cardiovasc J. 2020;16:77&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7350823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32670467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budoff MJ, Lakshmanan S, Toth PP, Hecht HS, Shaw LJ, Maron DJ, Michos ED, Williams KA, Nasir K, Choi AD, Chinnaiyan K, Min J, Blaha M. Cardiac CT angiography in current practice: An American society for preventive cardiology clinical practice statement(&#x2730;) Am J Prev Cardiol. 2022;9:100318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8802838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35146468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahsepar AA, Arbab-Zadeh A. Cardiac CT vs. Stress Testing in Patients with Suspected Coronary Artery Disease: Review and Expert Recommendations. Curr Cardiovasc Imaging Rep. 2015;8:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4613789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26500716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa MF, Canan A, Xi Y, Litt H, Diercks DB, Abbara S, Kay FU. Comparative Effectiveness of Coronary CT Angiography and Standard of Care for Evaluating Acute Chest Pain: A Living Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Radiol Cardiothorac Imaging. 2023;5:e230022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10483255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37693194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown D. A Review of the PubMed PICO Tool: Using Evidence-Based Practice in Health Education. Health Promot Pract. 2020;21:496&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31874567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6:e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane Bias.  RoB 2: A revised Cochrane risk-of-bias tool for randomized trials. [cited 2 April 2025]. Available from: https://methods.cochrane.org/bias/resources/rob-2-revised-cochrane-risk-bias-tool-randomized-trials .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh T, Bing R, Dweck MR, van Beek EJR, Mills NL, Williams MC, Villines TC, Newby DE, Adamson PD. Exercise Electrocardiography and Computed Tomography Coronary Angiography for Patients With Suspected Stable Angina Pectoris: A Post Hoc Analysis of the Randomized SCOT-HEART Trial. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:920&#x2013;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillman AE, Gatsonis C, Lima JAC, Liu T, Snyder BS, Cormack J, Malholtra V, Schnall MD, Udelson JE, Hoffmann U, Woodard PK RESCUE investigators *. Coronary Computed Tomography Angiography Compared With Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography Myocardial Perfusion Imaging as a Guide to Optimal Medical Therapy in Patients Presenting With Stable Angina: The RESCUE Trial. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:e017993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7955393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubbers M, Dedic A, Coenen A, Galema T, Akkerhuis J, Bruning T, Krenning B, Musters P, Ouhlous M, Liem A, Niezen A, Hunink M, de Feijter P, Nieman K. Calcium imaging and selective computed tomography angiography in comparison to functional testing for suspected coronary artery disease: the multicentre, randomized CRESCENT trial. Eur Heart J. 2016;37:1232&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubbers M, Coenen A, Kofflard M, Bruning T, Kietselaer B, Galema T, Kock M, Niezen A, Das M, van Gent M, van den Bos EJ, van Woerkens L, Musters P, Kooij S, Nous F, Budde R, Hunink M, Nieman K. Comprehensive Cardiac CT With Myocardial Perfusion Imaging Versus Functional Testing in Suspected Coronary Artery Disease: The Multicenter, Randomized CRESCENT-II Trial. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2018;11:1625&#x2013;1636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29248657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linde JJ, Hove JD, S&#xf8;rgaard M, Kelb&#xe6;k H, Jensen GB, K&#xfc;hl JT, Hinds&#xf8; L, K&#xf8;ber L, Nielsen WB, Kofoed KF. Long-Term Clinical Impact of Coronary CT Angiography in Patients With Recent Acute-Onset Chest Pain: The Randomized Controlled CATCH Trial. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2015;8:1404&#x2013;1413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26577263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mark DB, Anstrom KJ, Sheng S, Baloch KN, Daniels MR, Hoffmann U, Patel MR, Cooper LS, Lee KL, Douglas PS PROMISE Investigators. Quality-of-Life Outcomes With Anatomic Versus Functional Diagnostic Testing Strategies in Symptomatic Patients With Suspected Coronary Artery Disease: Results From the PROMISE Randomized Trial. Circulation. 2016;133:1995&#x2013;2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27143676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods E, Bennett J, Chandrasekhar S, Newman N, Rizwan A, Siddiqui R, Khan R, Khawaja M, Krittanawong C. Efficacy of Diagnostic Testing of Suspected Coronary Artery Disease: A Contemporary Review. Cardiology. 2025;150:111&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11965859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39013364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trost J, Ferraro RA, Sharma G, Hays AG, Boden WE, Blumenthal RS, Arbab-Zadeh A. CCTA Should Be the New Diagnostic Gateway for Evaluating Intermediate-Risk Stable Angina Patients. JACC Adv. 2022;1:100116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11198657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38939715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marwick TH, Cho I, &#xd3; Hartaigh B, Min JK. Finding the Gatekeeper to the Cardiac Catheterization Laboratory: Coronary CT Angiography or Stress Testing? J Am Coll Cardiol. 2015;65:2747&#x2013;2756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4618380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rosendael SE, Shiyovich A, Cardoso RN, Souza Freire CV, van Rosendael AR, Lin FY, Larocca G, Bienstock SW, Blankstein R, Shaw LJ. The Role of Cardiac Computed Tomography Angiography in Risk Stratification for Coronary Artery Disease. J Soc Cardiovasc Angiogr Interv. 2024;3:102230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11624369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, Cates CJ, Cheng HY, Corbett MS, Eldridge SM, Emberson JR, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Hopewell S, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Junqueira DR, J&#xfc;ni P, Kirkham JJ, Lasserson T, Li T, McAleenan A, Reeves BC, Shepperd S, Shrier I, Stewart LA, Tilling K, White IR, Whiting PF, Higgins JPT. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danad I, Raijmakers PG, Driessen RS, Leipsic J, Raju R, Naoum C, Knuuti J, M&#xe4;ki M, Underwood RS, Min JK, Elmore K, Stuijfzand WJ, van Royen N, Tulevski II, Somsen AG, Huisman MC, van Lingen AA, Heymans MW, van de Ven PM, van Kuijk C, Lammertsma AA, van Rossum AC, Knaapen P. Comparison of Coronary CT Angiography, SPECT, PET, and Hybrid Imaging for Diagnosis of Ischemic Heart Disease Determined by Fractional Flow Reserve. JAMA Cardiol. 2017;2:1100&#x2013;1107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28813561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thribhuvan Reddy D, Grewal I, Garc&#xed;a Pinzon LF, Latchireddy B, Goraya S, Ali Alansari B, Gadwal A. The Role of Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare: Enhancing Coronary Computed Tomography Angiography for Coronary Artery Disease Management. Cureus. 2024;16:e61523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11218716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38957241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>