<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40610934</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2261</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cardiovascular disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative efficacy and safety of anticoagulant therapies in coronary artery disease: a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>456</StartPage><MedlinePgn>456</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">456</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12872-025-04908-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The most efficacious anticoagulant intervention for people with coronary artery disease (CAD) is still not clearly defined, highlighting the need for a comprehensive assessment of the available alternatives. Previous studies have assessed individual treatments, but a lack of integrated comparisons limits clinical decision-making. This investigation seeks to check how safe and effective a range of anticoagulant therapies for individuals suffering from CAD are through a network meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive study and NMA were performed, including data from Embase, MEDLINE, PubMed, and WoS through May 20, 2024. 11 RCTs were incorporated, encompassing 118,870 individuals suffering from CAD. Outcome measures focused on stroke, myocardial infarction, all-cause mortality, cardiovascular mortality, and bleeding risks. Effect sizes for categorical variables were measured by odds ratios (OR) with 95% CrIs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The administration of Rivaroxaban at a dosage of 2.5&#xa0;mg BID, in conjunction with Aspirin at 100&#xa0;mg OD, has been shown to markedly diminish the incidence of stroke (OR: 0.56, 95% CrI: 0.48 to 0.66), myocardial infarction (OR: 0.72, 95% CrI: 0.57 to 0.90), all-cause mortality (OR: 0.77, 95% CrI: 0.60 to 0.98), and cardiovascular mortality (OR: 0.77, 95% CrI: 0.66 to 0.90) however, there is an elevated risk of bleeding. The administration of Rivaroxaban in dose of 2.5&#xa0;mg BID demonstrated elevated SUCRA rankings in terms of both efficacy and safety, indicating a well-rounded profile.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The administration of Rivaroxaban in dose of 2.5&#xa0;mg BID, in conjunction with Aspirin at 100&#xa0;mg OD, demonstrates efficacy in mitigating thrombotic occurrences among individuals with CAD; however, it concomitantly elevates the risk of bleeding complications. Administering Rivaroxaban in dose of 2.5&#xa0;mg two times per day stands as a plausible alternative, achieving a commendable equilibrium between efficacy and safety. This study helps fill an important evidence gap in guiding optimal anticoagulant strategies for CAD patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Huahua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangxi Medical University, No. 22, Shuangyong Road, Qingxiu District, Nanning, Guangxi, 530021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>An</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Liuzhou Worker's Hospital, Liuzhou, Guangxi, 545005, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhong</LastName><ForeName>Guoqiang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangxi Medical University, No. 22, Shuangyong Road, Qingxiu District, Nanning, Guangxi, 530021, China. 645920840@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968539</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2261</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003324" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronary Artery Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009203" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardial Infarction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulant therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aspirin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rivaroxaban</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This is a systematic review and meta-analysis, ethics approval and consent to participate are not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. The manuscript does not include the participant&#x2019;s identification image or other personal or clinical details. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40610934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12226872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-025-04908-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12872-025-04908-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roth GA, Mensah GA, Johnson CO, Addolorato G, Ammirati E, Baddour LM, et al. Global burden of cardiovascular diseases and risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2019: update from the GBD 2019 study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(25):2982&#x2013;3021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33309175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmis A, Townsend N, Gale CP, Torbica A, Lettino M, Petersen SE, et al. European society of cardiology: cardiovascular disease statistics 2019. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(1):12&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31820000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virani SS, Alonso A, Benjamin EJ, Bittencourt MS, Callaway CW, Carson AP, et al. Heart disease and stroke Statistics-2020 update: A report from the American heart association. Circulation. 2020;141(9):e139&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31992061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global burden of 369 diseases and injuries in 204 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet (London, England). 2020;396(10258):1204-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collet JP, Thiele H, Barbato E, Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my O, Bauersachs J, Bhatt DL, et al. 2020 ESC guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes in patients presenting without persistent ST-segment elevation. Eur Heart J. 2021;42(14):1289&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding D, Lawson KD, Kolbe-Alexander TL, Finkelstein EA, Katzmarzyk PT, van Mechelen W, et al. The economic burden of physical inactivity: a global analysis of major non-communicable diseases. Lancet (London England). 2016;388(10051):1311&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27475266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuster V, Ryd&#xe9;n LE, Cannom DS, Crijns HJ, Curtis AB, Ellenbogen KA, et al. ACC/AHA/ESC 2006 guidelines for the management of patients with atrial fibrillation&#x2013;executive summary: a report of the American college of cardiology/american heart association task force on practice guidelines and the European society of cardiology committee for practice guidelines (Writing committee to revise the 2001 guidelines for the management of patients with atrial Fibrillation). J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;48(4):854&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16904574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly SJ, Ezekowitz MD, Yusuf S, Eikelboom J, Oldgren J, Parekh A, et al. Dabigatran versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2009;361(12):1139&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19717844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MR, Mahaffey KW, Garg J, Pan G, Singer DE, Hacke W, et al. Rivaroxaban versus warfarin in nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2011;365(10):883&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21830957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granger CB, Alexander JH, McMurray JJ, Lopes RD, Hylek EM, Hanna M, et al. Apixaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2011;365(11):981&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21870978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruff CT, Giugliano RP, Braunwald E, Hoffman EB, Deenadayalu N, Ezekowitz MD, et al. Comparison of the efficacy and safety of new oral anticoagulants with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: a meta-analysis of randomised trials. Lancet (London England). 2014;383(9921):955&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24315724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chugh SS, Havmoeller R, Narayanan K, Singh D, Rienstra M, Benjamin EJ, et al. Worldwide epidemiology of atrial fibrillation: a global burden of disease 2010 study. Circulation. 2014;129(8):837&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24345399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2021;372:n160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaimani A, Higgins JP, Mavridis D, Spyridonos P, Salanti G. Graphical tools for network meta-analysis in STATA. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(10):e76654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mega JL, Braunwald E, Mohanavelu S, Burton P, Poulter R, Misselwitz F, et al. Rivaroxaban versus placebo in patients with acute coronary syndromes (ATLAS ACS-TIMI 46): a randomised, double-blind, phase II trial. Lancet. 2009;374(9683):29&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19539361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly SJ, Eikelboom JW, Bosch J, Dagenais G, Dyal L, Lanas F, et al. Rivaroxaban with or without aspirin in patients with stable coronary artery disease: an international, randomised, double-blind, placebocontrolled trial. Lancet. 2018;391(10117):205&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29132879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zannad F, Anker SD, Byra WM, Cleland JGF, Fu M, Gheorghiade M, et al. Rivaroxaban in Patients with Heart Failure, Sinus Rhythm, and Coronary Disease. N Engl J Med. 2018;379(14):1332&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30146935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mega JL, Braunwald E, Wiviott SD, Bassand JP, Bhatt DL, Bode C, et al. Rivaroxaban in patients with a recent acute coronary syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2012;366(1):9&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22077192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahaffey KW, Stevens SR, White HD, Nessel CC, Goodman SG, Piccini JP, et al. Ischaemic cardiac outcomes in patients with atrial fibrillation treated with vitamin K antagonism or factor Xa inhibition: results from the ROCKET AF trial. Eur Heart J. 2014;35(4):233&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3896862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24132190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korjian S, Braunwald E, Daaboul Y, Mi M, Bhatt DL, Verheugt FWA, et al. Usefulness of Rivaroxaban for Secondary Prevention of Acute Coronary Syndrome in Patients With History of Congestive Heart Failure (from the ATLAS-ACS-2 TIMI-51 Trial). Am J Cardiol. 2018;122(11):1896&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30340765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branch KRH, Probstfield JL, Bosch J, Bhatt DL, Maggioni AP, Muehlhofer E, et al. Total events and net clinical benefit of rivaroxaban and aspirin in patients with chronic coronary or peripheral artery disease: The COMPASS trial. Am Heart J. 2023;258(4):60&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcalai R, Butnaru A, Moravsky G, Yagel O, Rashad R, Ibrahimli M, et al. Apixaban vs. warfarin in patients with left ventricular thrombus: a prospective multicentre randomized clinical trial&#x2021;. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Pharmacother. 2022;8(7):660&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34279598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eikelboom JW, Bhatt DL, Fox KAA, Bosch J, Connolly SJ, Anand SS, et al. Mortality Benefit of Rivaroxaban Plus Aspirin in Patients With Chronic Coronary or Peripheral Artery Disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;78(1):14&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Xiao Y, Zhou C, Zheng Z, Jiang W, Shen Q, et al. Effect of Rivaroxaban vs Enoxaparin on Major Cardiac Adverse Events and Bleeding Risk in the Acute Phase of Acute Coronary Syndrome: The H-REPLACE Randomized Equivalence and Noninferiority Trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(2):e2255709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9918885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36763358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Zhu J, Liu L, Anand SS, Connolly SJ, Bosch J, et al. Efficacy and safety of rivaroxaban plus aspirin in women and men with chronic coronary or peripheral artery disease. Cardiovasc Res. 2021;117(3):942&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M, Cui W, Li L. Comparison of clinical outcomes between Ticagrelor and clopidogrel in acute coronary syndrome: A comprehensive Meta-Analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:818215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8829718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35155618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse TA, Tegegne GT, Yadeta D, Chelkaba L, Fenta TG. Anticoagulation control, outcomes, and associated factors in long-term-care patients receiving warfarin in africa: a systematic review. Thromb J. 2022;20(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deiveegan DS, Salahie M, Subhan M, Ismail S, Khan MA, Raval DM, et al. Optimizing anticoagulation strategies in patients with atrial fibrillation and valvular heart disease: A comprehensive Evidence-Based review. Cureus. 2025;17(3):e81319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12033385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40291263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CAPRIE Steering Committee. A randomised, blinded, trial of clopidogrel versus aspirin in patients at risk of ischaemic events (CAPRIE). Lancet (London England). 1996;348(9038):1329&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8918275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DR, Morgano GP, Bennett C, Dentali F, Francis CW, Garcia DA, et al. American society of hematology 2019 guidelines for management of venous thromboembolism: prevention of venous thromboembolism in surgical hospitalized patients. Blood Adv. 2019;3(23):3898&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6963238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31794602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia D, Libby E, Crowther MA. The new oral anticoagulants. Blood. 2010;115(1):15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19880491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrono C, Garc&#xed;a Rodr&#xed;guez LA, Landolfi R, Baigent C. Low-dose aspirin for the prevention of atherothrombosis. N Engl J Med. 2005;353(22):2373&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16319386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly SJ, Eikelboom J, Joyner C, Diener HC, Hart R, Golitsyn S, et al. Apixaban in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2011;364(9):806&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21309657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perzborn E, Roehrig S, Straub A, Kubitza D, Misselwitz F. The discovery and development of rivaroxaban, an oral, direct factor Xa inhibitor. Nat Rev Drug Discovery. 2011;10(1):61&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>