<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40945998</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-114X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical therapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Phase III Randomized Controlled Trial Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Azilsartan Medoxomil and Amlodipine Combination Therapy in Patients With Mild-to-Moderate Essential Hypertension Inadequately Controlled on Monotherapy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0149-2918(25)00285-1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.clinthera.2025.08.003</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the antihypertensive efficacy and safety of azilsartan medoxomil (AZM) and amlodipine (AML) combination therapy in patients with mild-to-moderate hypertension inadequately controlled by AZM or AML monotherapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this multicenter, randomized, double-blind Phase III study (NCT05385770), patients with mild-to-moderate hypertension inadequately controlled with AZM 40/80 mg or AML 5/10 mg were randomized (1:1:1) to receive low-dose or high-dose AZM/AML combination therapy or continued monotherapy as control. Eligible patients completed a 4-week active run-in period before randomization. The primary endpoint was change from baseline in mean sitting systolic blood pressure (SBP) after 8 weeks of treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 890 patients were randomized. AZM/AML combination therapy resulted in significantly greater reductions in mean sitting SBP compared with AZM or AML monotherapy across all dose groups. Least-squares mean reductions in mean sitting SBP at week 8 ranged from 5.2 to 9.0 mm Hg across all monotherapy nonresponder groups, with all comparisons showing statistical significance (P &lt; 0.05). Reductions in mean sitting diastolic blood pressure also favored combination therapy. Safety profiles were comparable across all treatment arms, with most adverse events mild or moderate in severity. No additional safety concerns were identified compared with monotherapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">AZM/AML combination therapy was more effective than monotherapy in patients with mild-to-moderate hypertension inadequately controlled with either agent alone, even at maximum doses. Both low-dose and high-dose combinations were well tolerated. AZM/AML combination therapy may offer enhanced BP-lowering efficacy compared with other angiotensin II receptor blocker-based regimens.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Dae-Hee</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Asan Medical Center, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sang Hyun</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine and Research Institute for Convergence of Biomedical Science and Technology, Pusan National University Yangsan Hospital, Pusan National University School of Medicine, Yangsan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Kyung Ah</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Nowon Eulji Medical Center, Eulji University School of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Moo Hyun</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Dong-A University Hospital, Busan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Dong-Ju</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Gyeonggi, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grabowski</LastName><ForeName>Marcin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1st Department of Cardiology, Medical University of Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miekus</LastName><ForeName>Pawel</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NZOZ Pro Cordis Sopockie Centrum Badan Kardiologicznych Pawel Miekus, Sopot, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Tzung-Dau</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Center and Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, National Taiwan University Hospital and National Taiwan University College of Medicine, Taipei City, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Pei</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Heart Center, Cheng Hsin General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sungha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Severance Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea. Electronic address: shpark0530@yuhs.ac.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7706726</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0149-2918</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amlodipine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Azilsartan medoxomil</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combination therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: all authors report article publishing charges and writing assistance were provided by Celltrion, Inc.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40945998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2025.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0149-2918(25)00285-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>