<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40295308</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of neuromuscular control exercise program using non-elastic taping on the knee joint in patients with knee osteoarthritis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e42173</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e42173</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e42173</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000042173</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study aimed to investigate the effects of a neuromuscular control exercise program for the knee joint using non-elastic taping on pain, functional disability, quality of life, balance ability, thickness, and contraction ratio of the rectus femoris (RF), vastus medialis (VM), vastus lateralis (VL), and vastus medialis obliquus (VMO) muscles in adults aged 65 years and older with knee osteoarthritis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study was a randomized controlled trial. A total of 44 elderly individuals (aged&#x2005;&#x2265;&#x2005;65 years) with knee osteoarthritis were randomly assigned to an experimental group (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;22) and a control group (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;22). Both groups underwent a neuromuscular control exercise program, with the experimental group receiving non-elastic taping and the control group receiving sham taping. Repeated measures ANOVA was performed to examine the main effect of time and the interaction effect between time and group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both groups showed significant differences in VAS, K-WOMAC, EQ-5D, BBS, muscle thickness, and contraction ratio before and after intervention (P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.05). In addition, the experimental group showed more significant differences in the amount of change in K-WOMAC stiffness, K-WOMAC function, EQ-5D, BBS, muscle thickness, and contraction ratio values than the control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A neuromuscular control exercise program using non-elastic taping for knee joints is an effective intervention method for improving knee joint pain, function, quality of life, balance ability, muscle thickness and contraction ratio in elderly patients aged&#x2005;&#x2265;&#x2005;65 years, with knee osteoarthritis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Sang-Woo</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7490-9231</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Graduate School, Daejeon University, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Suhn-Yeop</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0558-7125</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Health and Medical Science, Daejeon University, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007719" MajorTopicYN="Y">Knee Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">balance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-elastic taping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training program</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40295308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12040024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000042173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202504250-00081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kim KH, Lee JM. The level of pain, gait speed, and ROM in community-dwelling older adults with knee joint pain. J Korean Acad Community Health Nurs. 2017;28:156&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelbourne KD, Freeman H, Gray T. Osteoarthritis after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the importance of regaining and maintaining full range of motion. Sports Health. 2012;4:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3435893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23016073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice DA, McNair PJ, Lewis GN. Mechanisms of quadriceps muscle weakness in knee joint osteoarthritis: the effects of prolonged vibration on torque and muscle activation in osteoarthritic and healthy control subjects. Arthritis Res Ther. 2011;13:R151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3308081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21933392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taruc Uy RL, Lynch SA. Diagnosis and treatment of osteoarthritis. Prim Care. 2013;40:821&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24209720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY. Muscle strength ratio and q-angle in patients with osteoarthritis of the knee: a comparative study with healthy persons. Phys Ther Korea. 2005;12:45&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pua YH, Seah FJT, Seet FJH, Tan JW, Liaw JS, Chong H-C. Sex differences and impact of body mass index on the time course of knee range of motion, knee strength, and gait speed after total knee arthroplasty. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2015;67:1397&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25776869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevermer CA. Functional movement assessment for individuals with knee osteoarthritis. Iowa State University; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JE, Kim SY. Effects of lower extremity strengthening exercise combined with balance exercise on lower extremity function, range of motion, muscle strength, and balance in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Korean Soc Phys Med. 2017;12:147&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielen MMJ, Van Sijl AM, Peters MJL, et al. . Cardiovascular disease prevalence in patients with inflammatory arthritis, diabetes mellitus and osteoarthritis: a cross-sectional study in primary care. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2012;13:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3493278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22906083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon YA, Park HJ. Effect of sexual function and sexual distress on quality of life in middle aged women with osteoarthritis. J Korea Acad Coop Soc. 2020;21:209&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkan BM, Fidan F, Tosun A, Ardi&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu O. Quality of life and self-reported disability in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Mod Rheumatol. 2014;24:166&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24261774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn SY, Park HJ. A study on sexual function, sexual stress, and quality of life in middle aged women patients with diabetes mellitus. J Korean Acad Fundam Nurs. 2016;23:393&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong DK, Yoon JH, Park SH. The effect of whole-body vibration on pulmonary function and cerebral cortical activity in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Ann Appl Sport Sci. 2023;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks R. Muscle and osteoarthritis joint status: current research highlights and their implications. SM J Orthop. 2017;3:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheon S, Chang EW. Inter-rater reliability of a portable ultrasound for the quadriceps and hamstrings thickness measurement in healthy adults. Exerc Sci. 2020;29:71&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon MS, Jeon HR, Lee H-J. Comparing persons with neck pain experience to persons without neck pain experience in deep neck muscle size using ultrasonography images and neck muscle endurance time. J Korea Contents Assoc. 2011;11:326&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saliba SA, Croy T, Guthrie R, Grooms D, Weltman A, Grindstaff TL. Differences in transverse abdominis activation with stable and unstable bridging exercises in individuals with low back pain. N Am J Sports Phys Ther. 2010;5:63&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21589663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ageberg E, Roos EM. Neuromuscular exercise as treatment of degenerative knee disease. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2015;43:14&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25390299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EJ, Choi YD, Kim MJ. The effects of unstable surface training on balance and lower extremity muscle activity of elderly women. Neurotherapy. 2016;20:17&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SK, Yu WJ. The effect of complex balance exercise on unstable surfaces on functional ability and daily living ability in patients with total knee arthroplasty. J Korean Acad Phys Ther Sci. 2021;28:88&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HW, Park YH. Effects of incorporating non-elastic taping into PNF techniques on muscle activities, balance, and gait in patients with chronic stroke. J Korean Soc Phys Med. 2020;15:113&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang JH, Kim SY. The influence of unloading taping method using non-elastic tape on the pain, opening mouth, functional level, quality of life in patients with temporomandibular joint disorder. Phys Ther Korea. 2016;23:29&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell J. A novel approach to pain relief pre-therapeutic exercise. J Sci Med Sport. 2000;3:325&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11101271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campolo M, Babu J, Dmochowska K, Scariah S, Varughese J. A comparison of two taping techniques (kinesio and McConnell) and their effect on anterior knee pain during functional activities. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2013;8:105&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3625789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23593548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuperus N, Vliet Vlieland TPM, Mahler EAM, et al. . The clinical burden of generalized osteoarthritis represented by self-reported health-related quality of life and activity limitations: a cross-sectional study. Rheumatol Int. 2015;35:871&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song MS, Yoo YK, Kim NC. Effects of aquatic exercise on joint angle, pain, stiffness, and physical function in elderly women with osteoarthritis. J Korean Gerontol Nurs. 2015;17:89&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pa&#x17e;emeckas T, Jurgelaitien&#x117; G, Janu&#x161;onien&#x117; L. Effect of mobilization with movement and kinesio taping on knee function and pain in gonarthrosis. Reabilitacijos Mokslai. 2021;25:40&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon DH, Lee EJ, So HW, et al. . Preliminary study to develop the instrument on pattern identifications for insomnia. J Korean Med Rehabil. 2017;27:77&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko TS, Kim SY, Lee JS. Reliability and validity of the Korean Western Ontario and McMaster universities (WOMAC) osteoarthritis index in patients with osteoarthritis of the knee. J Orient Rehab Med. 2009;19:251&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Lee DW, Jeong MB. Effect of a telerehabilitation exercise program on the gait, knee function and quality of life in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Korean Soc Phys Med. 2020;15:143&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae EM, Choi SE, Lee HY, Shin G, Kang D. Validity of EQ-5D utility index and minimal clinically important difference estimation among patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. BMC Pulm Med. 2020;20:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32293387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang SJ, Lee SY. Effects of balance control and functional activities during gym ball exercises in elderly people. Phys Ther Korea. 2004;11:25&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogle Thorbahn LD, Newton RA. Use of the berg balance test to predict falls in elderly persons. Phys Ther. 1996;76:576&#x2013;83; discussion 584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8650273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Ettema G. A comparison of overarm throwing with the dominant and nondominant arm in experienced team handball players. Percept Mot Skills. 2009;109:315&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19831111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, Zhang W, Zhang J, et al. . Diaphragmatic motion studied by m-mode ultrasonography in combined pulmonary fibrosis and emphysema. Lung. 2014;192:553&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24818955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CH, Heo SJ. Effects of taping therapy on the improvement of daily life of the elderly with degenerative arthritis. J Korea Entertain Ind Assoc. 2023;17:257&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang KR, Kim MK, Kim HJ, et al. . Effects of gluteus medius exercise for total knee replacement on knee joint function, disability, and strength. Korea J Sport Sci. 2023;32:947&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Um HM, Si JW, Lee HJ. Effects of resistance exercise with elasticity of tubes on the gait, balance and strength in the elderly of the daycare center. J Korea Acad Coop Soc. 2019;20:102&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TH, Choi HS. Effects of 4 weeks bridging stabilization exercise using swiss ball and whole body vibration on balance and gait function in elderly women. Phys Ther Korea. 2011;18:49&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Campbell PK, Egerton T, et al. . Telephone coaching to enhance a home-based physical activity program for knee osteoarthritis: a randomised clinical trial. Arthritis Care Res. 2017;69:84&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27111441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YL, Kim BK, Hwang YP, Moon OK, Choi WS. Effects of isometric exercise using biofeedback on maximum voluntary isometric contraction, pain, and muscle thickness in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:149&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4305548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25642061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Park DH. A study on effect of whole body vibration exercise combined with weight vests on leg muscle thickness, balance ability, and functional mobility in elderly. J Korea Acad Ind Cooperation Soc. 2023;24:487&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>