<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40900983</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lambl's Excrescences and Cardiac Papillary Fibroelastoma, an Unusual Cause of Embolic Strokes: Extended Data From a Single Center Case Series.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e89162</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e89162</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e89162</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.89162</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Lambl's excrescences (LE) and cardiac papillary fibroelastomas (CPF) are valvular structures that have been associated with cryptogenic strokes, potentially acting as embolic sources or sites of thrombus formation. However, the management of LE and CPF - whether discovered incidentally or in the setting of cerebrovascular events (cardiovascular accident (CVA)/transient ischemic attack (TIA)) - remains poorly defined, with no randomized trials to guide treatment. Methods We conducted a retrospective case series at a single center from July 2018 to June 2024, identifying 10 patients with LE or CPF. Nine patients presented with CVA/TIA; one had an incidental CPF finding. All patients were followed for a minimum of six months. The cohort had a mean age of 69.4 years (range 58-79 years), and common comorbidities included hypertension (7/10), diabetes (5/10), hyperlipidemia (4/10), coronary artery disease (2/10), and chronic kidney disease (1/10). Results No alternative stroke etiology was identified in CVA/TIA cases after standard evaluation. Management strategies included direct oral anticoagulants (n=5), warfarin (n=1), dual antiplatelet therapy (n=3), and surgical valve replacement (n=1). No recurrent strokes related to LE or CPF were observed during follow-up. Two patients later experienced strokes due to progressive carotid artery stenosis. Conclusions In this small, descriptive case series, individualized management strategies for LE and CPF appeared safe over short- to mid-term follow-up. Given the absence of consensus guidelines and randomized data, further research is needed to define optimal treatment and clarify causal relationships.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Rana et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rana</LastName><ForeName>Dhara</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Inspira Medical Center Vineland, Vineland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pietrandrea</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Deborah Heart and Lung Center, Browns Mills, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isaac</LastName><ForeName>Rea</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Osteopathic Medicine, Rowan-Virtua School of Osteopathic Medicine, Glassboro, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Husain</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Inspira Medical Center Vineland, Vineland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rainear</LastName><ForeName>Kristen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Penn Cardiology, Vineland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac papillary fibroelastomas (cpf)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease (ckd)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary arterial disease (cad)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus (dm)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperlipidemia (hld)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension (htn)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lambl&#x2019;s excrescences (le)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transesophageal echocardiogram (tee)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40900983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12400005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.89162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kondamareddy D, Masood W. StatPearls. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Lambl excrescences.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29939563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of cryptogenic stroke. Finsterer J. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20873443/ Acta Neurol Belg. 2010;110:135&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20873443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroke prevention after cryptogenic stroke. Ibeh C, Elkind MS. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2021;23:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8520343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambl's excrescences: current diagnosis and management. Ammannaya GK. Cardiol Res. 2019;10:207&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31413776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines for the use of echocardiography in the evaluation of a cardiac source of embolism. Saric M, Armour AC, Arnaout MS, et al. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2016;29:1&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26765302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KRAS mutations in papillary fibroelastomas: a study of 50 cases with etiologic and diagnostic implications. Bois MC, Milosevic D, Kipp BR, Maleszewski JJ. Am J Surg Pathol. 2020;44:626&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32141886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambl's excrescences and papillary fibroelastomas: are they different? Boone SA, Campagna M, Walley VM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1617520/ Can J Cardiol. 1992;8:372&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1617520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambl's excrescences: an enigma of modern diagnostic cardiology. Amin H, Jilani MH, Villarreal D. Cureus. 2019;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6968828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31970037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardioembolic stroke secondary to Lambl&#x2019;s excrescence on the aortic valve: a case report. Yacoub HA, Walsh AL, Pineda CC. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4188260/ J Vasc Interv Neurol. 2014;7:23&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4188260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambl&#x2019;s excrescences and stroke: a scoping study. Kariyanna PT, Jayarangaiah A, Rednam C, et al. International Journal of Clinical Research and Trials. 2018;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Embolic strokes of undetermined source: a clinical consensus statement of the ESC Council on Stroke, the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging and the European Heart Rhythm Association of the ESC. Ntaios G, Baumgartner H, Doehner W, et al. Eur Heart J. 2024;45:1701&#x2013;1715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11107123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38685132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical experience with cardiac papillary fibroelastoma over a 15-year period. Anastacio MM, Moon MR, Damiano RJ Jr, Pasque MK, Maniar HS, Lawton JS. Ann Thorac Surg. 2012;94:537&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4329773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22626753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unusual locations for cardiac papillary fibroelastomas. Carino D, Nicolini F, Molardi A, Indira Dadamo C, Gherli T. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28820556/ J Heart Valve Dis. 2017;26:226&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28820556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papillary fibroelastoma: clinical and echocardiographic features and initial approach in 54 cases. Cianciulli TF, Soumoulou JB, Lax JA, et al. Echocardiography. 2016;33:1811&#x2013;1817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27566126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac papillary fibroelastoma: a comprehensive analysis of 725 cases. Gowda RM, Khan IA, Nair CK, Mehta NJ, Vasavada BC, Sacchi TJ. Am Heart J. 2003;146:404&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12947356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Operative management of cardiac papillary fibroelastomas. Mazur P, Kurmann R, Klarich KW, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtcvs.2022.06.022. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2024;167:1088&#x2013;1097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35989118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and echocardiographic characteristics of papillary fibroelastomas: a retrospective and prospective study in 162 patients. Sun JP, Asher CR, Yang XS, et al. Circulation. 2001;103:2687&#x2013;2693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recurrence of pathologically proven papillary fibroelastoma. Sorour AA, Kurmann RD, El-Am EA, et al. Ann Thorac Surg. 2022;113:1208&#x2013;1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambl's excrescences: association with cerebrovascular disease and pathogenesis. Roldan CA, Schevchuck O, Tolstrup K, et al. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2015;40:18&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4592773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26044080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2022 ACC Expert Consensus Decision Pathway for Integrating Atherosclerotic Cardiovascular Disease and Multimorbidity Treatment: A Framework for Pragmatic, Patient-Centered Care: A Report of the American College of Cardiology Solution Set Oversight Committee. Birtcher KK, Allen LA, Anderson JL, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81:292&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36307329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comparison of the recording of comorbidity in primary and secondary care by using the Charlson Index to predict short-term and long-term survival in a routine linked data cohort. Crooks CJ, West J, Card TR. BMJ Open. 2015;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26048212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Charlson Comorbidity Index: problems with use in epidemiological research. Drosdowsky A, Gough K. J Clin Epidemiol. 2022;148:174&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35395393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>