<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40909091</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Relationship Between Gut Health and Autoimmune Diseases: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e89300</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e89300</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e89300</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.89300</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Autoimmune diseases (AIDs) are multifaceted, chronic illnesses characterized by immune dysregulation and systemic inflammation. Newer evidence has pointed a finger at the human gut microbiota, a trillion-fold population of microorganisms that inhabits the human GI tract, as a major influential modulator of immune reactivity and a significant contributor to autoimmune pathogenesis. This systematic review will seek to address how the literature correlates with systematic changes in the gut microbiota in AIDs as well as explore mechanistic associations with biological processes like intestinal permeability and modulation of the immune system, coupled with determining the effectiveness of microbiota-directed interventions. An extensive literature search was conducted in PubMed, Embase, Cochrane Central, and Web of Science, involving the availability of studies until May 2025. The eligible studies included observational studies, randomized controlled trials, and relevant mechanistic research regarding autoimmune diseases and alterations of the gut microbiome or administered interventions. Data extraction and risk of bias (ROB) assessments were performed by two independent reviewers, and a narrative synthesis with an illustrative meta-analysis was applied. Inclusion criteria were met by 10 studies, encompassing various autoimmune diseases, including systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), rheumatoid arthritis (RA), multiple sclerosis (MS), type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM), autoimmune thyroid diseases (AITDs), and psoriasis. Familiar patterns of microbiome dysbiosis were identified, such as a reduction in microbial diversity, increased intestinal permeability, and the expansion of pro-inflammatory species like <i>Ruminococcus gnavus</i>. Dietary interventions, fecal microbiota transplantation, and probiotics demonstrated positive effects on clinical outcomes and immune measures across multiple studies. The meta-analysis revealed that microbiota-directed interventions significantly improved disease activity and immune response markers in AIDs, indicating a robust link between gut microbiota composition and autoimmune pathology. In autoimmune disorders, gut microbiota is a key factor in immunopathology. Gut biology as an adjunct interventional strategy provides potential in managing these diseases. Additional studies are required to help standardize methods and identify microbial targets specific to diseases that can then be addressed through therapeutic interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Vineesh et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vineesh</LastName><ForeName>Allenki</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Mallareddy Institute of Medical Sciences, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Shivani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Caribbean Medical University School of Medicine, Willemstad, CUW.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Kinjal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Administration, Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy, New Brunswick, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaigham Hassan</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology, Harlem Hospital Centre, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sapkota</LastName><ForeName>Ashbin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Medicine, Bharatpur Hospital Bharatpur, Chitwan, NPL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khadka</LastName><ForeName>Subodh Raj</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Croydon University Hospital, London, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rizwanullah</LastName><ForeName>Fnu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Hayatabad Medical Complex Peshawar, Peshawar, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dare Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Abdulgafar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Mississippi Baptist Medical Center, Jackson, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanduri Hanumantharayudu</LastName><ForeName>Sneha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, The Partners Care, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar Makam Surendraiah</LastName><ForeName>Pavan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Westchester Medical Center, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Bubli</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Jalalabad Ragib Rabeya Medical College and Hospital, Sylhet, BGD.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gyullu</LastName><ForeName>Niftalieva</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Donesk National Medical University, Donesk, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fecal microbiota transplantation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut microbiota</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immune dysregulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intestinal permeability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbiome dysbiosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbiota-directed interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40909091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12404852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.89300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dysbiosis may trigger autoimmune diseases via inappropriate post-translational modification of host proteins. Lerner A, Aminov R, Matthias T. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4742538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zonulin and its regulation of intestinal barrier function: the biological door to inflammation, autoimmunity, and cancer. Fasano A. Physiol Rev. 2011;91:151&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21248165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of infections on susceptibility to autoimmune and allergic diseases. Bach JF. N Engl J Med. 2002;347:911&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12239261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Updated assessment of the prevalence, spectrum and case definition of autoimmune disease. Hayter SM, Cook MC. Autoimmun Rev. 2012;11:754&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22387972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forms and methods for interferon&#x2019;s encapsulation. Ramos TI, Villacis-Aguirre CA, Santiago Vispo N, Santiago Padilla L, Pedroso Santana S, Parra NC, Alonso JR. Pharmaceutics. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8538586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34683824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The microbiome in autoimmune diseases. De Luca F, Shoenfeld Y. Clin Exp Immunol. 2019;195:74&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6300652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29920643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role of the microbiota in immunity and inflammation. Belkaid Y, Hand TW. Cell. 2014;157:121&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4056765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24679531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The microbiota in adaptive immune homeostasis and disease. Honda K, Littman DR. Nature. 2016;535:75&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27383982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Large-scale sequencing identifies multiple genes and rare variants associated with Crohn's disease susceptibility. Sazonovs A, Stevens CR, Venkataraman GR, et al. Nat Genet. 2022;54:1275&#x2013;1283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9700438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36038634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Microbiota and autoimmunity: exploring new avenues. Yurkovetskiy LA, Pickard JM, Chervonsky AV. Cell Host Microbe. 2015;17:548&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4535992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25974297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intestinal dysbiosis associated with systemic lupus erythematosus. Hevia A, Milani C, L&#xf3;pez P, et al. mBio. 2014;5:0&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4196225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25271284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thymic development of gut-microbiota-specific T cells. Zegarra-Ruiz DF, Kim DV, Norwood K, et al. Nature. 2021;594:413&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8323488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of fungal and bacterial co-infection in pulmonary fungal infections: a metagenomic next generation sequencing-based study. Zhao Z, Song J, Yang C, et al. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021;11:749905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8591235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leaky gut and autoimmunity: an intricate balance in individuals health and the diseased state. Paray BA, Albeshr MF, Jan AT, Rather IA. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33371435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quercetin: a savior of alveolar barrier integrity under hypoxic microenvironment. Tripathi A, Hazari PP, Mishra AK, Kumar B, Sagi SS. Tissue Barriers. 2021;9:1883963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8078770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33632082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gut microbiota, metabolites and host immunity. Rooks MG, Garrett WS. Nat Rev Immunol. 2016;16:341&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5541232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27231050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innate immune signaling organelles display natural and programmable signaling flexibility. Tan Y, Kagan JC. Cell. 2019;177:384&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6710629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30853218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metabolites produced by commensal bacteria promote peripheral regulatory T-cell generation. Arpaia N, Campbell C, Fan X, et al. Nature. 2013;504:451&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3869884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24226773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>For the assessment of intestinal permeability, size matters. Vojdani A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23341423/ Altern Ther Health Med. 2013;19:12&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23341423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of gut microbiota in immune homeostasis and autoimmunity. Wu HJ, Wu E. Gut Microbes. 2012;3:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3337124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22356853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A systematic approach to searching: an efficient and complete method to develop literature searches. Bramer WM, de Jonge GB, Rethlefsen ML, Mast F, Kleijnen J. J Med Libr Assoc. 2018;106:531&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6148622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30271302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Most Cochrane systematic reviews and protocols did not adhere to the Cochrane's risk of bias 2.0 tool. Martimbianco AL, S&#xe1; KM, Santos GM, Santos EM, Pacheco RL, Riera R. Rev Assoc Med Bras (1992) 2023;69:469&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10004297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36820779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Causal inference in public health. Glass TA, Goodman SN, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Samet JM. Annu Rev Public Health. 2013;34:61&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4079266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23297653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Int J Surg. 2010;8:336&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strengthening systematic reviews in public health: guidance in the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions, 2nd edition. Cumpston MS, McKenzie JE, Welch VA, Brennan SE. J Public Health (Oxf) 2022;44:0&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35352103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Composition, variability, and temporal stability of the intestinal microbiota of the elderly. Claesson MJ, Cusack S, O'Sullivan O, et al. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108 Suppl 1:4586&#x2013;4591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3063589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20571116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. BMJ. 2019;366:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. BMJ. 2016;355:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Stang A. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20652370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meta-analysis of binary outcomes from two-by-two tables when the length of follow-up varies and hazards are proportional. Combescure C, Courvoisier DS, Haller G, Perneger TV. Stat Methods Med Res. 2011;20:531&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20716589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of Lactobacillus casei supplementation on disease activity and inflammatory cytokines in rheumatoid arthritis patients: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. Alipour B, Homayouni-Rad A, Vaghef-Mehrabany E, et al. Int J Rheum Dis. 2014;17:519&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24673738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of gluten-free diet on thyroid autoimmunity in drug-na&#xef;ve women with Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis: a pilot study. Krysiak R, Szkr&#xf3;bka W, Okopie&#x144; B. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes. 2019;127:417&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30060266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brief report: intestinal dysbiosis in ankylosing spondylitis. Costello ME, Ciccia F, Willner D, et al. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67:686&#x2013;691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gut microbiota alteration and its modulation with probiotics in celiac disease. Saviano A, Petruzziello C, Brigida M, Morabito Loprete MR, Savioli G, Migneco A, Ojetti V. Biomedicines. 2023;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10603901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37893012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes in gut microbiota and systemic inflammation after synbiotic supplementation in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Widhani A, Djauzi S, Suyatna FD, Dewi BE. Cells. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9658918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36359816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>