<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40958692</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1336-0329</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>59</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Endocrine regulations</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Endocr Regul</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thus far there are no statistically significant differences between various apolipoprotein E genotypes in the cluster of seven responsiveness to a flaxseed oil supplement in persons with type 2 diabetes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>141</StartPage><EndPage>146</EndPage><MedlinePgn>141-146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/enr-2025-0016</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Objective.</b> The objective of the present study was to determine if there would be statistically significant differences among apolipoprotein E genotypes in the responsiveness of members of a cluster of seven measures in persons with type 2 diabetes consuming a flaxseed oil supplement (FOS). The cluster of seven are: abdominal obesity, hypertension, platelet hyperaggregability, hyperglycemia, dyslipidemia (decreased serum levels of high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDLc) and increased serum levels of triglycerides), increased serum low-density lipoprotein (LDL) oxidation (LDL conjugated dienes) and increased inflammation. All cluster members exacerbate type 2 diabetes. <b>Methods.</b> Thirty-two patients with well-controlled type 2 diabetes participated in this double-blind, placebo (safflower oil supplementation (SOS))-controlled study consisting of three visits. Apolipoprotein E genotyping was done at visit one. The cluster of seven was assessed at each visit. <b>Results.</b> Only platelet aggregability decreased as the result of the FOS relative to placebo while it appeared that there might be some potential for FOS to decrease LDL conjugated dienes. No apolipoprotein E genotype affected any of the cluster of seven responsiveness. <b>Conclusions.</b> Identified apolipoprotein E genotypes played no role in the responsiveness of any member of the cluster of seven to FOS in this study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Douglas E. Barre et al., published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barre</LastName><ForeName>Douglas E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Cape Breton University, Sydney, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mizier-Barre</LastName><ForeName>Kazimiera A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Cape Breton University, Sydney, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griscti</LastName><ForeName>Odette</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Cape Breton University, Sydney, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Endocr Regul</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112018</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1210-0668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8001-26-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008043">Linseed Oil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001057">Apolipoproteins E</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008043" MajorTopicYN="Y">Linseed Oil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001057" MajorTopicYN="Y">Apolipoproteins E</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050171" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyslipidemias</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010974" MajorTopicYN="N">Platelet Aggregation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056128" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity, Abdominal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006943" MajorTopicYN="N">Hyperglycemia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apolipoprotein E genotype polymorphisms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bleeding time</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">c-reactive protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flaxseed oil supplementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high density lipoprotein cholesterol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-density lipo-protein conjugated dienes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serum glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">triglycerides</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">waist circumference</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40958692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/enr-2025-0016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">enr-2025-0016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahotupa M, Ruutu M, Mantyla E. Simple methods of quantifying oxidation products and antioxidant potential of low-density lipoproteins. Clin Biochem 29, 139&#x2013;144, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahotupa M, Marniemi J, Lehtimaki T, Talvinen K, Raitakari OT, Vasankari T, Viikari J, Luoma J, Yla-Herttuala S, Baseline diene conjugation in LDL lipids as a direct measure of in vivo LDL oxidation. Clin Biochem 31, 257&#x2013;261, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asghar S, Asghar S, Shahid S, Fatima M, Bukhari SMH, Nadeem Siddiqui S. Metabolic syndrome in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients: prevalence, risk factors, and associated microvascular complications. Cureus 15, e39076, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barre, DE, Mizier-Barre, KA, Griscti, O, Hafez, K. Gender differential in apo E genotypes&#x2019; correlative tendency to dyslipidaemia responsiveness upon flaxseed oil administration in adult type 2 diabetic patients not meeting the 2008 Canadian Practice Guidelines. Int J Diabetes Metabol 18, 99&#x2013;113, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barre DE, Mizier-Barre KA, Griscti O, Hafez K. Relationships of apolipoprotein E genotypes with a cluster of seven in persons with type 2 diabetes. Endocr Regul 58, 40&#x2013;46, 2024a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barre DE, Mizier-Barre KA, Griscti O. Various apolipoprotein E genotypes relate to responsiveness to flaxseed lignan complex in older persons with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Endocr Regul 58, 220&#x2013;224, 2024b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boren J, Chapman MJ, Krauss RM, Packard CJ, Bentzon JF, Binder CJ, Daemen MJ, Demer LL, Hegele RA, Nicholls SJ, Nordestgaard BG, Watts GF, Bruckert E, Fazio S, Ference BA, Graham I, Horton JD, Landmesser U, Laufs U, Masana L, Pasterkamp G, Raal FJ, Ray KK, Schunkert H, Taskinen MR, van de Sluis B, Wiklund O, Tokgozoglu L, Catapano AL, Ginsberg HN. Low-density lipoproteins cause atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: pathophysiological, genetic, and therapeutic insights: a consensus statement from the European Atherosclerosis Society Consensus Panel. Eur Heart J 41, 2313&#x2013;2330, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Wells AL, Jackson KG, Lockyer S, Lovegrove JA, Minihane AM. APOE genotype influences triglyceride and C-reactive protein responses to altered dietary fat intake in UK adults. Am J Clin Nutr 96, 1447&#x2013;1453, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dongway A, Faggad AS, Zaki HY, Abdalla BE. C-reactive protein is associated with low-density lipoprotein cholesterol and obesity in type 2 diabetic sudanese. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes 8, 427&#x2013;435, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller CJ, Chandalia M, Garg A, Grundy SM, Jialal I. RRR-alpha-tocopheryl acetate supplementation at pharmacologic doses decreases low-density-lipoprotein oxidative susceptibility but not protein glycation in patients with diabetes mellitus. Am J Clin Nutr 63, 753&#x2013;759, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H, Qiu F, Zhao H, Tang H, Li X, Shi D. Dietary flaxseed oil improved western-type diet-induced atherosclerosis in apolipoprotein-E knockout mice. J Funct Foods 40, 417&#x2013;425, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hixson JE, Vernier DT. Restriction isotyping of human apolipoprotein E by gene amplification and cleavage with HhaI. J Lipid Res 31, 545&#x2013;548, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemieux S, Prud&#x2019;homme D, Bouchard C, Tremblay A, Despres JP. A single threshold value of waist girth identifies normal-weight and overweight subjects with excess visceral adipose tissue. Am J Clin Nutr 64, 685&#x2013;693, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Listgarten J, Stegle O, Morris Q, Brenner SE, Parts L. Personalized medicine: from genotypes and molecular pheno-types towards therapy- session introduction. Pac Symp Biocomput 19, 224&#x2013;228, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lugrin J, Rosenblatt-Velin N, Parapanov R, Liaudet L. The role of oxidative stress during inflammatory processes. Biol Chem 395, 203&#x2013;230, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielke CH, Kaneshiro MM, Maher IA, Weiner, JM, Rapaport, SI. The standardized normal Ivy bleeding time and its prolongation by aspirin. Blood 34, 204&#x2013;215, 1969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishigaki I, Haghara M, Taunekawa H, Maseki M, Yagi K. Lipid peroxide levels of serum lipoprotein fractions of diabetic patients. Biochem Med 25, 373&#x2013;378, 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Lopez O. Genotype-based precision nutrition strategies for the prediction and clinical management of type 2 diabetes mellitus. World J Diabetes 15,142&#x2013;153, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito M, Eto M, Nitta H, Kanda Y, Shigeto M, Nakayama K, Tawaramoto K, Kawasaki F, Kamei S, Kohara K, Matsuda M, Matsuki M, Kaku K. Effect of apolipoprotein E4 allele on plasma LDL cholesterol response to diet therapy in type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetes Care 27, 1276&#x2013;1280, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkota B, Subramanian A, Priamvada G, Finely H, Blackett PR, Aston CE, Sanghera DK. Association of APOE polymorphisms with diabetes and cardiometabolic risk factors and the role of APOE genotypes in response to anti-diabetic therapy: results from the AIDHS/SDS on a South Asian population. J Diabetes Complications 29, 1191&#x2013;1197, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider DJ. Factors contributing to increased platelet reactivity in people with diabetes. Diabetes Care 32, 525&#x2013;527, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sproston NR, Ashworth JJ. Role of C-reactive protein at sites of inflammation and infection. Front Immunol 9, 754, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei-Malazy O, Fakhrzadeh H, Qorbani M, Amiri P, Larijani B, Tavakkoly-Bazzaz J, Amoli MM. Apolipoprotein E gene polymorphism and its effect on anthropometric measures in normoglycemic subjects and T2D. J Diabetes Metab Disord 11, 18, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamasawa N, Murakami H, Yamato K, Matsui J, Tanabe J, Suda T. Influence of apolipoprotein E genotype on the response to caloric restriction in type 2 diabetic patients with hyperlipidemia. Diabetes Obes Metab 5, 345&#x2013;348, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan KC, Ai VH, Chow WS, Chau MT, Leong L, Lam KS. Influence of low density lipoprotein (LDL) subfraction profile and LDL oxidation on endothelium-dependent and independent vasodilation in patients with type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 84, 3212&#x2013;3216, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tangvarasittichai S. Oxidative stress, insulin resistance, dyslipidemia and type 2 diabetes mellitus. World J Diabetes 6, 456&#x2013;480, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavintharan S, Lim SC, Chan YH, Sum CF. Apolipoprotein E genotype affects the response to lipid-lowering therapy in Chinese patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Obes Metab 9, 81&#x2013;86, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utermann G, Hees M, Steinmetz A. Polymorphism of apolipoprotein E and occurrence of dysbetalipoproteinaemia in man. Nature 269, 604&#x2013;607, 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gaal LF, Vansant GA, De Leeuw IH. Upper body adiposity and the risk for atherosclerosis. J Am Coll Nutr 8, 504&#x2013;514, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yassine HN, Anderson A, Brinton R, Carmichael O, Espeland MA, Hoscheidt S, Hugenschmidt CE, Keller JN, Peters A, Pi-Sunyer X. Do menopausal status and APOE4 genotype alter the long-term effects of intensive lifestyle intervention on cognitive function in women with type 2 diabetes mellitus? Neurobiol Aging 92, 61&#x2013;72, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>