<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41023665</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Progressive muscle relaxation to reduce anxiety before electroconvulsive therapy (ECT).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1217</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1217</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-025-03874-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ECT is a well-established treatment modality for severe psychiatric disorders, particularly major depressive disorder and bipolar disorder. It is well-documented that patients experience significant anxiety before treatment, which can adversely affect nursing care and the treatment process. This study aims to determine the effect of progressive muscle relaxation exercises on anxiety levels among patients with bipolar and depressive disorders prior to their first ECT session.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data for this quasi-experimental study were collected from 30 in-patients with bipolar disorder and depression who received ECT for the first time in the hospital between May 29 and October 29, 2020. Data collection involved an information form, the STAXI State Anxiety Scale, and the Visual Analogue Scale for Anxiety. The data were analyzed using descriptive statistics, the Friedman test, and the Wilcoxon test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean VAS-A score decreased from 4.93&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.88 before PMR to 2.83&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.76 after PMR, and further to 1.43&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.21 after ECT (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001). However, STAI-S scores did not show a statistically significant difference before and after PMR (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;.05). Heart rate and respiratory rate also significantly decreased after PMR exercises (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05), while oxygen saturation remained unchanged. Prior to the next ECT session, the mean VAS-A score increased to 5.10&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.77, and no significant changes were observed in either physiological parameters or anxiety measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">While a short-term effect on VAS Anxiety levels was observed following PMR exercises before ECT, patients still exhibited high levels of anxiety before subsequent ECT sessions. Therefore, it is recommended that PMR exercises be performed before each ECT session, and the effects of long-term application should be further investigated. Future studies should employ a randomized controlled design to compare results with a control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Not applicable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zyi&#x11f;it</LastName><ForeName>Gamze</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatry Clinic, Nam&#x131;k Kemal University Training and Research Hospital, Tekirda&#x11f;, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Graduate Studies, Okan University, &#x130;stanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sukut</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;zge</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florence Nightingale Nursing Faculty, Mental Health and Psychiatry Nursing Department, &#x130;stanbul University-Cerrahpa&#x15f;a, &#x130;stanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye. ozge.sukut@iuc.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electroconvulsive therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Progressive muscle relaxation exercise</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study received approval from the scientific research ethics committee of Nam&#x131;k Kemal University Training and Research Hospital (Date: 26.11.2019, Decision No: 13, Protocol No: 2019.216.11.13). The research adhered to the ethical principles outlined in the World Medical Association&#x2019;s Declaration of Helsinki. Patients participating in the study were informed about the research objectives. Both written and verbal consent were obtained from the patients prior to data collection. Additionally, the patients&#x2019; relatives were verbally informed about the research. All patients and their relatives provided their consent for the study to proceed. Informed consent: Written informed consent for publication was obtained from the patients and relatives. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41023665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-03874-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-025-03874-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Perugi G, Medda P, Toni C, Mariani M, Socci C, Mauri M. The role of electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) in bipolar disorder: effectiveness in 522 patients with bipolar depression, mixed-state, mania and catatonic features. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2017;15(3):359&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X14666161017233642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28503107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5405614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinoza RT, Kellner CH, Electroconvulsive therapy. Ropper AH, editor. N Engl J Med [Internet]. 2022 Feb 17;386(7):667&#x2013;72. Available from: https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0025619611640779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovers JJE, Vissers P, Loef D, van Waarde JA, Verdijk JPAJ, Broekman BFP, et al. The impact of treatment resistance on outcome and course of electroconvulsive therapy in major depressive disorder. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2023;147(6):570&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37020420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazdag G, Ungvari GS. Electroconvulsive therapy: 80 years old and still going strong. World J Psychiatry. 2019;9(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v9.i1.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30631748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6323557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross EC, Zivin K, Maixner DF. Cost-effectiveness of electroconvulsive therapy vs pharmacotherapy/psychotherapy for treatment-resistant depression in the United States. JAMA Psychiatry. 2018;75(7):713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2018.0768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6145669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C, Huang CJ, Chen C. ECT has greater efficacy than fluoxetine in alleviating the burden of illness for patients with major depressive disorder: a Taiwanese pooled analysis. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol. 2017;21(1):63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ijnp/pyx114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5795346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahji A, Hawken ER, Sepehry AA, Cabrera C, V&#xe1;zquez G. ECT&#x2009;Beyond unipolar major depression: systematic review and meta-analysis of electroconvulsive therapy in bipolar depression. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2018;139(3):214&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.12994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30506992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Ardalan M, Elfving B, Wegener G, Mads&#xe9;n T, Nyengaard JR. Mitochondria are critical for BDNF-mediated synaptic and vascular plasticity of hippocampus following repeated electroconvulsive seizures. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol. 2017;21(3):291&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ijnp/pyx115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5838811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swartz CM. What is brain damage and does electroconvulsive therapy cause it? J ECT [Internet]. 2024 Jun;40(2):72&#x2013;7. Available from: https://journals.lww.com/10.1097/YCT.0000000000001019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obbels J, Verwijk E, Bouckaert F, Sienaert P. ECT-related anxiety. J Ect. 2017;33(4):229&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCT.0000000000000383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28009627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonergan A, Timmins F, Donohue G. Mental health nurse experiences of delivering care to severely depressed adults receiving electroconvulsive therapy. J Psychiatr Ment Health Nurs. 2020;28(3):309&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpm.12692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32976647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells KC, Hancock N, Honey A. The experience of living after ECT: a qualitative meta-synthesis. J Mental Health. 2020;30(4):526&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638237.2020.1739244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navidian A, Ebrahimi H, Keykha R. Supportive nursing care and satisfaction of patients receiving electroconvulsive therapy: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Iran Red Crescent Med J. 2015;17:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ircmj.27492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora V, Tuttle K, Borisovskaya A. Postanesthesia recovery unit optimization for patients with postictal agitation secondary to electroconvulsive therapy. J Ect. 2022;39(2):91&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCT.0000000000000891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma S, Hussain B, Gigante T, Davies A, Watson R, Branjerdporn G. Challenging stigma and attitudes towards ECT via an educational video. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2023;32(3):884&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inm.13134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36861759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basogul C, Kalenderoglu A. The effect of psychoeducation applied before electroconvulsive therapy on the anxiety levels of psychiatric patients. Int J Caring Sci [Internet]. 2022;15(2):1384&#x2013;92. Available from: www.internationaljournalofcaringsciences.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadam ZE, Delmoradi F, Aemmi SZ, Vaghee S, Vashani HB. Effectiveness of aromatherapy with inhaled lavender essential oil and breathing exercises on ECT-related anxiety in depressed patients. EXPLORE [Internet]. 2022 Nov;18(6):683&#x2013;7. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1550830721002731</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuboi T, Takaesu Y, Hasegawa N, Ochi S, Fukumoto K, Ohi K, et al. Effects of electroconvulsive therapy on the use of anxiolytics and sleep medications: a propensity score-matched analysis. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2022;77(1):30&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pcn.13489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CJ, Lin CH, Wu JI, Yang WC. The relationship between depression symptoms and anxiety symptoms during acute ECT for patients with major depressive disorder. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol [Internet]. 2019 Oct 1;22(10):609&#x2013;15. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1093/ijnp/pyz038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purnomo E, Sari SN, Marheni E. The influence of progressive muscle relaxation exercises on the level of anxiety an athlete the high jump. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;se Kabakc&#x131;o&#x11f;lu N, Ayaz-Alkaya S. The effect of progressive muscle relaxation on stress, anxiety, and depression in adolescents: a quasi-experimental design. J Pediatr Nurs. 2024;78:89&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pedn.2024.06.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38905787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siregar T, Rabani AI. Application of progressive muscle relaxation therapy in overcoming nurse&#x2019;s work stress in Depok City regional general hospitals. Jurnal Ilmiah Ilmu Keperawatan Indonesia. 2022;12(02):74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33221/jiiki.v12i02.1744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toqan D, Ayed A, Joudallah H, Amoudi M, Malak MZ, Thultheen I, et al. Effect of progressive muscle relaxation exercise on anxiety reduction among nursing students during their initial clinical training: a quasi-experimental study. Inq J Health Care Organ Provis Financing. 2022;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanad HS, Aziz H, Hassan SS, Mohamed AA. Effect of progressive muscle relaxation technique on anxiety and sleep quality among hemodialysis patients. Int J Adv Psychiatric Nurs. 2023;5(2):21&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/26641348.2023.v5.i2a.127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicaturatmashudi S, Putri P. The effect of progressive muscle relaxation exercise and diaphragmatic breath on quality of life in diabetes mellitus patients. Int J Health Eng Technol. 2022;1(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo-Dias C, Lopes RC, Cardoso DFB, Bobrowicz-Campos E, Ap&#xf3;stolo JLA. Schizophrenia and progressive muscle relaxation &#x2013; a systematic review of effectiveness. Heliyon. 2019;5(4):e01484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e01484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31049425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6479115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uysal D, Sukut &#xd6;, Demirgil BT. The effects of progressive muscle relaxation on preoperative anxiety and blood pressure in patient with aneurysm. Nurs Health Sci J (NHSJ). 2023;3(4):392&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53713/nhsj.v3i4.274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khir SM, Yunus WMAWM, Mahmud N, Wang R, Panatik SA, Sukor MSM, et al. Efficacy of progressive muscle relaxation in adults for stress, anxiety, and depression: a systematic review. Psychol Res Behav Manag. 2024;17:345&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PRBM.S437277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan L, Fang P, Cui J, Yu H, Yu L. Effects of progressive muscle relaxation on health-related outcomes in cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Complement Ther Clin Pract [Internet]. 2022;49:101676. Available from: https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S174438812200144X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farris PC, Lynch ST, Groenendaal E, Klepacz L, Bambina Meyers L, Ferrando SJ. Impact of progressive muscle relaxation on psychological symptoms on an inpatient psychiatric unit. Brain Behav Immun Integ [Internet]. 2023;4:100033. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2949834123000326</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielberger CD, Gorsuch RL, Lushene R. State-trait anxiety inventory. Manual for the state-trait anxiety inventory. Polo Alto, CA: Consulting Psychologists; 1970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oner N, Le Compte A. Durumluk Surekli Kaygi Envanteri. &#x130;stanbul, Bogazici Universitesi Yayinlari; 1983. 1&#x2013;26 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams VS, Morlock RJ, Feltner D. Psychometric evaluation of a visual analog scale for the assessment of anxiety. Health Qual Life Outcomes [Internet]. 2010;8(1):57. Available from: http://hqlo.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1477-7525-8-57</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santamar&#xed;a AL, Masot O, V&#xe9;lez OC, Botigu&#xe9; T, Cemeli T, Roca J. Diagnostic concordance between the visual analogue anxiety scale (VAS-A) and the State-trait anxiety inventory (STAI) in nursing students during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(12):7053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19127053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducoulombier V, Chiquet R, Graf S, Leroy B, Bouquet G, Verdun S, et al. Usefulness of a visual analog scale for measuring anxiety in hospitalized patients experiencing pain: a multicenter cross-sectional study. Pain Manag Nurs [Internet]. 2020 Dec;21(6):572&#x2013;8. Available from: https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1524904220301090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulam&#x131;&#x15f; B, Vermi&#x15f;li Peker S, Orbatu D, Y&#x131;lmaz &#xd6;zkalay N, Alaygut D. How does waiting time affect anxiety and pain in adult individuals undergoing venous blood drawing? J Tepecik Educ Res Hosp [Internet]. 2020;30(2). Available from: http://www.tepecikdergisi.com/jvi.aspx?pdir=terh%26plng=tur%26un=TERH-71676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi V, Pourtois G. Transient State-dependent fluctuations in anxiety measured using STAI, POMS, PANAS or VAS: a comparative review. Anxiety Stress Coping. 2012;25(6):603&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10615806.2011.582948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21827372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abend R, Dan O, Maoz K, Raz S, Bar-Haim Y, Reliability. Validity and sensitivity of a computerized visual analog scale measuring state anxiety. J Behav Ther Exp Psychiatry. 2014;45(4):447&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbtep.2014.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24978117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud A, Abd Elbary A, Berma A. Effect of progressive relaxation technique on the anxiety level of the psychiatric patients before electro convulsive therapy. Port Said Sci J Nurs [Internet]. 2019 Dec 30;6(2):46&#x2013;60. Available from: https://pssjn.journals.ekb.eg/article_66919.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundar S, Sarkar S, Ezhumalai G, Varghese JK. Effect of adjuvant music therapy on anxiety, depressive symptoms, and cognitive functions of patients receiving electroconvulsive therapy: a preliminary study. SBV J Basic Clin Appl Health Sci. 2019;2(4):142&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5005/jp-journals-10082-02225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker S, Rasmussen KG, Best AM. Effect of aquariums on electroconvulsive therapy patients. Anthrozoos. 2003;16(3):229&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2752/089279303786992071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>