<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40898048</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of aquatic therapy combined with transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) on proprioception and gait speed in older adults with knee osteoarthritis: an eight-week randomized sham-controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>676</StartPage><MedlinePgn>676</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">676</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-025-06253-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Knee osteoarthritis (KOA) is a prevalent condition among older adults, leading to impaired proprioception and reduced gait speed, which compromise mobility and quality of life. While aquatic therapy and transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) have individually shown potential for enhancing motor and sensory functions, their combined effects are not well understood.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate the combined effects of aquatic therapy and tDCS on knee proprioception and gait speed in older women with KOA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A randomized, triple-blind, parallel-group, sham-controlled clinical trial was conducted with 68 elderly women with KOA (aged 63-68 years). Participants were allocated into four groups: (1) Aquatic Therapy&#x2009;+&#x2009;Sham tDCS (2), Aquatic Therapy&#x2009;+&#x2009;Real tDCS (3), Real tDCS, and (4) Sham tDCS. Interventions were conducted twice weekly over an 8-week period. Knee proprioception was assessed using a digital goniometer, and gait speed was measured via the 10-Meter Walk Test under normal and dual-task conditions. Data were analyzed using analysis of covariance (ANCOVA), controlling for height and baseline scores.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Paired t-tests revealed significant improvements in gait speed (under both normal and dual-task conditions) and knee proprioception in all intervention groups, except the Sham tDCS group (p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.05). Analysis of covariance (ANCOVA), controlling for height and pre-test scores, showed significant between-group differences in both gait speed and knee proprioception. Post hoc comparisons indicated that the Aquatic Therapy&#x2009;+&#x2009;Real tDCS group exhibited significantly greater improvements in knee proprioception compared to both the Aquatic Therapy&#x2009;+&#x2009;Sham tDCS and Real tDCS groups (p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.05), supporting the additive effect of real tDCS on sensory outcomes. However, no significant differences in gait speed were observed between the Aquatic Therapy&#x2009;+&#x2009;Real tDCS and Aquatic Therapy&#x2009;+&#x2009;Sham tDCS groups under either normal or dual-task conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The combined use of aquatic therapy and tDCS appears to enhance proprioceptive function more effectively than either intervention alone, while improvements in gait speed seem primarily driven by aquatic therapy. These findings suggest that tDCS may offer sensory-specific benefits in multimodal rehabilitation for older adults with KOA. Further research is warranted to assess the long-term effects, evaluate outcomes under varied task demands, and examine the generalizability to broader populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This clinical trial was registered with Iran's Clinical Trial Registration Center (IRCT)[IRCT20190908044722N8] on 8 January 2025.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalkhoran</LastName><ForeName>Zahra Bagherpoor</ForeName><Initials>ZB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Motor Behavior and Sport Management, Faculty of Sports Science, Urmia University, Urmia, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khanmohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Razieh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Motor Behavior and Sport Management, Faculty of Sports Science, Urmia University, Urmia, Iran. r.khanmohamadi@urmia.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011434" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proprioception</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking Speed</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003131" MajorTopicYN="N">Combined Modality Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006875" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hydrotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aquatic therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly women</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gait speed</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroplasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proprioception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Urmia University (Approval ID:(IR.URMIA.REC.1402.026)). It was retrospectively registered as a clinical trial on the&#x2026; Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT ID: (IRCT20190908044722N8)) on January 8, 2025, due to administrative delays unrelated to the study design or execution. All participants provided written informed consent prior to participation, with the assurance that they could withdraw from the study at any time. This trial adhered to the CONSORT 2010 guidelines to ensure rigorous reporting and transparency. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40898048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12403502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-025-06253-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-025-06253-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Driban JB, McAlindon TE, Amin M, Price LL, Eaton CB, Davis JE, et al. Risk factors can classify individuals who develop accelerated knee osteoarthritis: data from the osteoarthritis initiative. J Orthop Research<sup>&#xae;</sup>. 2018;36(3):876&#x2013;80.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5797506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28776751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li E, Tan J, Xu K, Pan Y, Xu P. Global burden and socioeconomic impact of knee osteoarthritis: a comprehensive analysis. Front Med. 2024;11: 1323091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11137242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38818397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamsi M, Safari A, Soroush A, Safari Y. The survey of knee osteoarthritis in the population over age 50 visited in the health bus in kermanshah, Iran. J Aging Res. 2021;2021(1):9809565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34804610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir UG, Demir AN, Toraman NF. Neuropathic pain in knee osteoarthritis. Adv Rheumatol. 2021;61:67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34743761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcieszek A, Kurowska A, Majda A, Liszka H, G&#x105;dek A. The impact of chronic pain, stiffness and difficulties in performing daily activities on the quality of life of older patients with knee osteoarthritis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(24): 16815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9779661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36554695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S, Lee K, Ju JH. Recent updates of diagnosis, pathophysiology, and treatment on osteoarthritis of the knee. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(5): 2619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7961389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander NB. Gait disorders in older adults. 1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8636592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panza F, Custodero C, Solfrizzi V. Physical activity, interleukin-6 change, and gait speed. Aging. 2023;15(11):4568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10292889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37286191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morone NE, Abebe KZ, Morrow LA, Weiner DK. Pain and decreased cognitive function negatively impact physical functioning in older adults with knee osteoarthritis. Pain Med. 2014;15(9):1481&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25040845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesari M. Role of gait speed in the assessment of older patients. JAMA. 2011;305(1):93&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21205972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutner NG, Zhang R, Huang Y, Painter P. Gait speed and mortality, hospitalization, and functional status change among hemodialysis patients: a US renal data system special study. Am J Kidney Dis. 2015;66(2):297&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4516659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25824124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raizah A, Reddy RS, Alshahrani MS, Tedla JS, Dixit S, Gular K, et al. Investigating knee joint proprioception and its impact on limits of stability using dynamic posturography in individuals with bilateral knee osteoarthritis&#x2014;a cross-sectional study of comparisons and correlations. J Clin Med. 2023;12(8):2764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10146398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37109102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosadi R, Jankaew A, Wu P-T, Kuo L-C, Lin C-F. Factors associated with falls in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a cross-sectional study. Medicine (Baltimore). 2022;101(48):e32146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9726291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36482638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gayretli Atan S, Pehlivan E, Ba&#x11f;&#xe7;ac&#x131; S. Evaluation of the effectiveness of proprioceptive training according to radiological stages in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Medicina (Kaunas). 2025;61(3): 546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11944215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40142357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams VJ, Piva SR, Irrgang JJ, Crossley C, Fitzgerald GK. Comparison of reliability and responsiveness of patient-reported clinical outcome measures in knee osteoarthritis rehabilitation. J Orthop Sports Phys Therapy. 2012;42(8):716&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3435439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22402677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao J, Jing Z, Xuehua B, Peilei Y, Qi G. Effect of systematic exercise rehabilitation on patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Cartilage. 2021;13(1suppl):S1734&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8808852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32037857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamtvedt G, Dahm KT, Christie A, Moe RH, Haavardsholm E, Holm I, et al. Physical therapy interventions for patients with osteoarthritis of the knee: an overview of systematic reviews. Phys Ther. 2008;88(1):123&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wu Z, Chen Z, Ye X, Chen G, Yang J, et al. Proprioceptive training for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Med. 2021;8: 699921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8581183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34778281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kumar A, Kumar R. Proprioceptive training as an adjunct in osteoarthritis of knee. J Musculoskelet Res. 2013;16(01): 1350002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal NA, Glass NA, Teran-Yengle P, Singh B, Wallace RB, Yack HJ. Intensive gait training for older adults with symptomatic knee osteoarthritis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;94(10S):848&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4567520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25768068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota S, Fujita R, Ohko H, Imai A. Effects of gait and activities of daily, living modifications for improving knee joint function in community-dwelling middle-aged and older people. A randomized control study. J Musculoskelet Res. 2021;24(02): 2150007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lozano-Meca J, Montilla-Herrador J, Gacto-S&#xe1;nchez M. The effects of combined transcranial direct current stimulation with physiotherapy for physical function in subjects with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiother Theory Pract. 2025;41(4):844&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38818760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coons JM, Theiss C, Barry VW, Stevens S. An exploratory study of the effects of aquatic walking on function and muscle activity in knee osteoarthritis: part 2. Int J Aquat Res Educ. 2023;14(1):5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;Jain P, Shinde S. Effect of aquatic resistance, balance, and proprioception training on lower limb muscle performance in bilateral knee osteoarthritis. J Musculoskelet Surg Res. 2025;9(1):104-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldaihan MM. The impact of aquatic therapy on balance and mobility in individuals with spinal cord injury-a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pioneer Med Sci. 2023;12(2):27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobanov AA, Grishechkina IA, Andronov SV, Barashkov GN, Popov AI, Fesyun AD, Ivanova EP, Maccarone MC, Masiero S. Can aquatic exercises contribute to the improvement of the gait stereotype function in patients with Long COVID outcomes?. Eur J Transl Myol. 2022;32(3):10698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35833897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C-g. Effect of underwater treadmill gait training with water-jet resistance on balance and gait ability in patients with chronic stroke: a randomized controlled pilot trial. Front Neurol. 2020;10:1246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7029734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32116977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamebozorgi A, Rahimi A, Daryabor A, Kazemi SM, Jamebozorgi F. The effects of transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) and biofeedback on proprioception and functional balance in athletes with ACL-deficiency. Health Stud. 2023;10:e130364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toktas N, Duruturk N, G&#xfc;zel &#x15e;, Y&#xfc;r&#xfc;k &#xd6;, &#xd6;zen S. The effect of transcranial direct current stimulation on balance, gait function and quality of life in patients with stroke. Neurol Res. 2024. 10.1080/01616412.2024.2362583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38825035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JM, Li CC, Wang Y, Li JY, Xu JM, Liang MG, et al. Transcranial direct current stimulation for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arthritis Care Res. 2024;76(3):376&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37779486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y-l, Luo Y, Yang J-m, Wu Y-q, Zhu Q, Li Y, et al. Effects of transcranial direct current stimulation on pain and physical function in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25(1): 703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11370230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39227806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao S, Wang B, Yu C, Shen B, Zhang X, Ye D, et al. Effects of intervention combining transcranial direct current stimulation and foot core exercise on sensorimotor function in foot and static balance. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2022;19(1): 98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9476283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36104787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi F, Nejati V, Nassadj G, Ziaei B, Mohammadi HK. The effect of transcranial direct stimulation as an add-on treatment to conventional physical therapy on pain intensity and functional ability in individuals with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Neurophysiol Clin. 2021;51(6):507&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira PE, Alawdah L, Alhassan HAA, Guidetti M, Priori A, Papatheodorou S, et al. The analgesic effect of transcranial direct current stimulation (tdcs) combined with physical therapy on common musculoskeletal conditions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Principles and practice of clinical research. 2015;6(1):23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7406123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebetanz D, Nitsche MA, Tergau F, Paulus W. Pharmacological approach to the mechanisms of transcranial DC-stimulation&#x2010;induced after&#x2010;effects of human motor cortex excitability. Brain. 2002;125(10):2238&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12244081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsche MA, Seeber A, Frommann K, Klein CC, Rochford C, Nitsche MS, et al. Modulating parameters of excitability during and after transcranial direct current stimulation of the human motor cortex. J Physiol. 2005;568(1):291&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaje S, Daneshjoo A, Sahebozamani M, Karimi Afshar F. The effects of Water-based neuromuscular exercises on knee proprioception and pain in older women with 2nd/3rd grade knee osteoarthritis: A clinical trial. Sci J Rehabilitation Med. 2024;13(5):948&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puspita WH, Tamtomo DG, Prasetya H. Meta-analysis the effect of aquatic therapy on functional ability in patients with knee osteoarthritis. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X, Zhong X, Wang C, Yang Y, Jiang C. Evaluation of transcranial direct current stimulation in motor function and neural rehabilitation. J ECT. 2023;39(4):235&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World health organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn MD, Sassoon AA, Fernando ND. Classifications in brief: Kellgren-Lawrence classification of osteoarthritis. Clin Orthop Relat Research<sup>&#xae;</sup>. 2016;474:1886&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4925407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26872913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corr&#xea;a FI, Carneiro Costa G, Leite Souza P, Marduy A, Parente J, Ferreira da Cruz S, et al. Additive effect of transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) in combination with multicomponent training on elderly physical function capacity: a randomized, triple blind, controlled trial. Physiother Theory Pract. 2023;39(11):2352&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyle GD, Allison SC, Matekel RL, Ryder MG, Stang JM, Gohdes DD, et al. Physical therapy treatment effectiveness for osteoarthritis of the knee: a randomized comparison of supervised clinical exercise and manual therapy procedures versus a home exercise program. Phys Ther. 2005;85(12):1301&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16305269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niknam H, Sarmadi, Salavati, Mahyar M. The effect of Kinesio taping on weight distribution and proprioception in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Med Scholar. 2011;19(1):19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino Y, Yoshida T, Mori T, Hirota S, Iga J, Ueno S-i. Risk of idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus in older inpatients with schizophrenia. Int Psychogeriatr. 2016;28(5):863&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26555031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaski D, Dominguez R, Allum J, Islam A, Bronstein A. Combining physical training with transcranial direct current stimulation to improve gait in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a pilot randomized controlled study. Clin Rehabil. 2014;28(11):1115&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24849794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffaelli C, Lanza M, Zanolla L, Zamparo P. Exercise intensity of head-out water-based activities (water fitness). Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(5):829&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20229021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persiyanova-Dubrova A, Marphina T, Badalov N. Water aerobics training: selection and control of the exercise intensity using the Borg scale. Vopr Kurortol Fizioter Lech Fiz Kult. 2021;98(2):39&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33899451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan K, Abadi FH, Zainudin FF, Barati AH, Elumalai G. Comparison of the effect of aquatic and Thera-band exercise on pain and quality of life in obese people with knee osteoarthritis. J Pain Manag. 2021;14(3):221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baharlouei H, Salehinejad MA, Talimkhani A, Nitsche MA. The effect of non-invasive brain stimulation on gait in healthy young and older adults: a systematic review of the literature. Neuroscience. 2023;516:125&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36720301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamii Y, Kojima S, Onishi H. Transcranial direct current stimulation over the posterior parietal cortex improves visuomotor performance and proprioception in the lower extremities. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16: 876083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9434688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36061503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFadyen BJ, Gagn&#xe9; M-&#xc8;, Cossette I, Ouellet M-C. Using dual task walking as an aid to assess executive dysfunction ecologically in neurological populations: A narrative review. Neuropsychological Rehabilitation. 2017;27(5):722&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26487095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agathos CP, Ramano&#xeb;l S, B&#xe9;cu M, Baranton K, Bernardin D, Arleo A. An alternative view of dual-tasking in older adults: cognitive-motor interference while navigating in an ecological environment. Neurophysiol Clin. 2019;49(6):414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali N, Liu J, Tian H, Pan W, Tang Y, Zhong Q, et al. A novel dual-task paradigm with story recall shows significant differences in the gait kinematics in older adults with cognitive impairment: a cross-sectional study. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14: 992873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9797676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez F, Guti&#xe9;rrez M. Dual-task gait as a predictive tool for cognitive impairment in older adults: a systematic review. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13: 769462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35002676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marotta N, de Sire A, Marinaro C, Moggio L, Inzitari MT, Russo I, et al. Efficacy of transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) on balance and gait in multiple sclerosis patients: A machine learning approach. Journal of Clinical Medicine. 2022;11(12):3505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9224780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35743575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo RS, Cardeira CSF, Rezende DSA, Guimar&#xe3;es-do-Carmo VJ, Lemos A, de Moura-Filho AG. Effectiveness of the aquatic physical therapy exercises to improve balance, gait, quality of life and reduce fall-related outcomes in healthy community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2023;18(9): e0291193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10490910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37683025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mattos F, Pereira G, Bento PCB. Water-based exercises performed with high-speed movement improves strength and physical function in older women with knee osteoarthritis. Phys Occup Therapy Geriatr. 2020;39(1):22&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assar S, Gandomi F, Mozafari M, Sohaili F. The effect of total resistance exercise vs. aquatic training on self-reported knee instability, pain, and stiffness in women with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2020;12:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32368344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kum D-M, Shin W-S. Effect of backward walking training using an underwater treadmill on muscle strength, proprioception and gait ability in persons with stroke. Physical therapy rehabilitation science. 2017;6(3):120&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizi S, Dadarkhah A, Rezasoltani Z, Raeissadat SA, Mofrad RK, Najafi S. Randomized controlled trial of aquatic exercise for treatment of knee osteoarthritis in elderly people. Interventional Medicine and Applied Science. 2020;11(3):161&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9467329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36343293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajouj E, Hadian MR, Mir SM, Talebian S, Ghazi S. Effects of innovative aquatic proprioceptive training on knee proprioception in athletes with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Bone Jt Surg. 2021;9(5):519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8503762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34692934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aneksan B, Sawatdipan M, Bovonsunthonchai S, Tretriluxana J, Vachalathiti R, Auvichayapat P, et al. Five-session dual-transcranial direct current stimulation with task-specific training does not improve gait and lower limb performance over training alone in subacute stroke: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Neuromodulation: Technology at the Neural Interface. 2022;25(4):558&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35667771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu T-Y, Juan C-H, Tseng P. Individual differences and state-dependent responses in transcranial direct current stimulation. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10: 643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5174116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28066214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Kuhn A, P&#xe9;rez-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Moreno M, Flores P, S&#xe1;nchez-Santed F. Differential effects of transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) depending on previous musical training. Front Psychol. 2018;9: 1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6139306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30250439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay S, Larochelle-Brunet F, Lafleur LP, El Mouderrib S, Lepage JF, Th&#xe9;oret H. Systematic assessment of duration and intensity of anodal transcranial direct current stimulation on primary motor cortex excitability. European Journal of Neuroscience. 2016;44(5):2184&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27336413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Yoo YJ. A literature review on optimal stimulation parameters of transcranial direct current stimulation for motor recovery after stroke. Brain NeuroRehabilitation. 2024;17(3):e24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11621672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryhill ME. Longitudinal tDCS: consistency across working memory training studies. Aims Neurosci. 2017;4(2):71&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury NH, Tyler DJ. Utilization of peripheral nerve feedback at a preconscious level. Front Neurosci. 2024;18: 1336431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10977079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38550562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suminski AJ, Mardoum P, Lillicrap TP, Hatsopoulos NG. Temporal evolution of both premotor and motor cortical tuning properties reflect changes in limb biomechanics. J Neurophysiol. 2015;113(7):2812&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4416622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25673733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa H, Tanji J. Corticocortical and thalamocortical responses of neurons in the monkey primary motor cortex and their relation to a trained motor task. J Neurophysiol. 1994;71(2):550&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8176424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollonini L, Miao H, Ahn H. Longitudinal effect of transcranial direct current stimulation on knee osteoarthritis patients measured by functional infrared spectroscopy: a pilot study. Neurophotonics. 2020;7(2): 025004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7203445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn H, Suchting R, Woods AJ, Miao H, Green C, Cho RY, et al. Bayesian analysis of the effect of transcranial direct current stimulation on experimental pain sensitivity in older adults with knee osteoarthritis: randomized sham-controlled pilot clinical study. J Pain Res. 2018. 10.2147/JPR.S173080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6166765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30310309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min D-k. Changes in sensory function after transcranial direct current stimulation on primary motor cortex area. Physical Therapy Korea. 2014;21(4):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares DRB, Okazaki JEF, de Andrade Santana MV, Pinto ACPN, Tutiya KK, Gazoni FM, et al. Motor cortex transcranial direct current stimulation effects on knee osteoarthritis pain in elderly subjects with dysfunctional descending pain inhibitory system: A randomized controlled trial. Brain stimulation. 2021;14(3):477&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33684598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir S, Ahmad S, Alatefi M, Hamza A, Sharaf M, Fecteau S, et al. Effects of anodal transcranial direct current stimulation on motor evoked potentials variability in humans. Physiological Reports. 2019;7(13):e14087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6640590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31301123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendy AM, Kidgell DJ. Anodal tDCS applied during strength training enhances motor cortical plasticity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(9):1721&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23470308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce AS, Howard JS, Van Werkhoven H, McBride JM, Needle AR. The effects of transcranial direct current stimulation on chronic ankle instability. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(2):335&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31453883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Cha S, Yun D, An J, editors. Effects of tDCS on Cortical Motor Facilitation in Performing Motor Execution. 2021 9th International Winter Conference on Brain-Computer Interface (BCI); 2021: IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenkranz K, Butler K, Williamon A, Cordivari C, Lees A, Rothwell J. Sensorimotor reorganization by proprioceptive training in musician&#x2019;s dystonia and writer&#x2019;s cramp. Neurology. 2008;70(4):304&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18160672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsche MA, Paulus W. Excitability changes induced in the human motor cortex by weak transcranial direct current stimulation. J Physiol. 2000;527(Pt 3):633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10990547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fregni F, Liebetanz D, Monte-Silva KK, Oliveira MB, Santos AA, Nitsche MA, et al. Effects of transcranial direct current stimulation coupled with repetitive electrical stimulation on cortical spreading depression. Exp Neurol. 2007;204(1):462&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17113079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Sumiyoshi T. Neurobiological mechanisms of transcranial direct current stimulation for psychiatric disorders; neurophysiological, chemical, and anatomical considerations. Front Hum Neurosci. 2021;15: 631838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa FI, Costa GC, Souza PL, Marduy A, Silva SM, Fregni F, et al. Additive effect of tDCS in combination with multicomponent training on elderly physical function capacity: a randomized, triple-blind, controlled trial. Gait Posture. 2023;106:S62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung J, Salazar Fajardo JC, Kim S, Kim B, Oh S, Yoon B. Effect of tDCS combined with physical training on physical performance in a healthy population. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2024;95(1):149&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37036388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>