<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40649164</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2077-0383</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Complete Revascularization in STEMI: Ischemia-Driven Rehospitalization and Cardiovascular Mortality.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4793</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/jcm14134793</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background</b>: Patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) and multivessel coronary artery disease (MVD) who undergo complete revascularization (CR) have a more favorable prognosis than those who receive incomplete revascularization (IR), as evidenced by recent randomized controlled trials. Despite the absence of a survival benefit associated with CR in these trials, positive outcomes were ascribed to combined endpoints, such as repeat revascularization, myocardial infarction, or ischemia-driven rehospitalization. In light of the significant burden that rehospitalization from STEMI imposes on healthcare systems, we examined the long-term effects of CR on ischemia-driven rehospitalization and cardiovascular (CV) mortality in STEMI patients with MVD. <b>Methods</b>: In our retrospective study, we included patients with STEMI and MVD who underwent successful primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) at the University Medical Centre Ljubljana between 1 January 2009, and 11 April 2011. The combined endpoint was ischemia-driven rehospitalization and CV mortality, with a minimum follow-up period of six years. <b>Results</b>: We included 235 participants who underwent CR (N = 70) or IR (N = 165) at index hospitalization, with a median follow-up time of 7 years (interquartile range 6.0-8.2). The primary endpoint was significantly higher in the IR group than in the CR group (47.3% vs. 32.9%, log-rank <i>p</i> = 0.025), driven by CV mortality (23.6% vs. 12.9%, log-rank <i>p</i> = 0.047), as there was no difference in ischemia-driven rehospitalization rate (log-rank <i>p</i> = 0.206). Ischemia-driven rehospitalization did not influence CV mortality in the CR group (<i>p</i> = 0.49), while it significantly impacted CV mortality in the IR group (<i>p</i> = 0.03). After adjusting for confounders, there were no differences in CV mortality between CR and IR groups (<i>p</i> = 0.622). Predictors of the combined endpoint included age (<i>p</i> = 0.014), diabetes (<i>p</i> = 0.006), chronic kidney disease (CKD) (<i>p</i> = 0.001), cardiogenic shock at presentation (<i>p</i> = 0.003), chronic total occlusion (CTO) (<i>p</i> = 0.046), and ischemia-driven rehospitalization (<i>p</i> = 0.0001). Significant risk factors for the combined endpoint were cardiogenic shock at presentation (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001), stage 4 kidney failure (<i>p</i> = 0.001), age over 70 years (<i>p</i> = 0.004), female gender (<i>p</i> = 0.008), and residual SYNTAX I score &gt; 5.5 (<i>p</i> = 0.017). <b>Conclusions</b>: Patients with STEMI and MVD who underwent CR had a lower combined endpoint of ischemia-driven rehospitalizations and CV mortality than IR patients, but after adjustments for confounders, the true determinants of the combined endpoint and risk factors for the combined endpoint were independent of the revascularization method.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sustersic</LastName><ForeName>Miha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Zaloska 7, 1000 Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bunc</LastName><ForeName>Matjaz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7269-8944</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Zaloska 7, 1000 Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Pathological Physiology, Medical Faculty, University of Ljubljana, Vrazov trg 2, 1000 Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101606588</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2077-0383</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ST-elevation myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complete percutaneous revascularization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemia-driven rehospitalization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multivessel coronary artery disease</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40649164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12250939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14134793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jcm14134793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sorajja P., Gersh B.J., Cox D.A., McLaughlin M.G., Zimetbaum P., Costantini C., Stuckey T., Tcheng J.E., Mehran R., Lansky A.J., et al. Impact of multivessel disease on reperfusion success and clinical outcomes in patients undergoing primary percutaneous coronary intervention for acute myocardial infarction. Eur. Heart J. 2007;28:1709&#x2013;1716. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehm184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehm184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17556348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavender M.A., Milford-Beland S., Roe M.T., Peterson E.D., Weintraub W.S., Rao S.V. Prevalence, predictors, and in-hospital outcomes of non-infarct artery intervention during primary percutaneous coronary intervention for ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction (from the National Cardiovascular Data Registry) Am. J. Cardiol. 2009;104:507&#x2013;513. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2009.04.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2009.04.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19660603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannan E.L., Samadashvili Z., Walford G., Holmes D.R., Jr., Jacobs A.K., Stamato N.J., Venditti F.J., Sharma S., King S.B., 3rd Culprit vessel percutaneous coronary intervention versus multivessel and staged percutaneous coronary intervention for ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction patients with multivessel disease. JACC Cardiovasc. Interv. 2010;3:22&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.jcin.2009.10.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcin.2009.10.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20129564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal M.B., Ilsley C., Kabir T., Smith R., Lane R., Mason M., Clifford P., Crake T., Firoozi S., Kalra S., et al. Culprit vessel versus multivessel intervention at the time of primary percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with ST-segment-elevation myocardial infarction and multivessel disease: Real-world analysis of 3984 patients in London. Circ. Cardiovasc. Qual. Outcomes. 2014;7:936&#x2013;943. doi: 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.114.001194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.114.001194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25371542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal M.B., Nadra I.J., Ding L., Fung A., Aymong E., Chan A.W., Hodge S., Della Siega A., Robinson S.D., British Columbia Cardiac Registry Investigators Culprit Vessel Versus Multivessel Versus In-Hospital Staged Intervention for Patients With ST-Segment Elevation Myocardial Infarction and Multivessel Disease: Stratified Analyses in High-Risk Patient Groups and Anatomic Subsets of Nonculprit Disease. JACC Cardiovasc. Interv. 2017;10:11&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/j.jcin.2016.10.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcin.2016.10.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald D.S., Morris J.K., Wald N.J., Chase A.J., Edwards R.J., Hughes L.O., Berry C., Oldroyd K.G., PRAMI Investigators Randomized trial of preventive angioplasty in myocardial infarction. N. Engl. J. Med. 2013;369:1115&#x2013;1123. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1305520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1305520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engstrom T., Kelbaek H., Helqvist S., Hofsten D.E., Klovgaard L., Holmvang L., Jorgensen E., Pedersen F., Saunamaki K., Clemmensen P., et al. Complete revascularisation versus treatment of the culprit lesion only in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction and multivessel disease (DANAMI-3-PRIMULTI): An open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2015;386:665&#x2013;671. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60648-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60648-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26347918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershlick A.H., Khan J.N., Kelly D.J., Greenwood J.P., Sasikaran T., Curzen N., Blackman D.J., Dalby M., Fairbrother K.L., Banya W., et al. Randomized trial of complete versus lesion-only revascularization in patients undergoing primary percutaneous coronary intervention for STEMI and multivessel disease: The CvLPRIT trial. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 2015;65:963&#x2013;972. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2014.12.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2014.12.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smits P.C., Abdel-Wahab M., Neumann F.J., Boxma-de Klerk B.M., Lunde K., Schotborgh C.E., Piroth Z., Horak D., Wlodarczak A., Ong P.J., et al. Fractional Flow Reserve-Guided Multivessel Angioplasty in Myocardial Infarction. N. Engl. J. Med. 2017;376:1234&#x2013;1244. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1701067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1701067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28317428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta S.R., Wood D.A., Storey R.F., Mehran R., Bainey K.R., Nguyen H., Meeks B., Di Pasquale G., Lopez-Sendon J., Faxon D.P., et al. Complete Revascularization with Multivessel PCI for Myocardial Infarction. N. Engl. J. Med. 2019;381:1411&#x2013;1421. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1907775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1907775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31475795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuuti J., Wijns W., Saraste A., Capodanno D., Barbato E., Funck-Brentano C., Prescott E., Storey R.F., Deaton C., Cuisset T., et al. 2019 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of chronic coronary syndromes. Eur. Heart J. 2020;41:407&#x2013;477. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehz425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehz425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boden W.E., O&#x2019;Rourke R.A., Teo K.K., Hartigan P.M., Maron D.J., Kostuk W.J., Knudtson M., Dada M., Casperson P., Harris C.L., et al. Optimal Medical Therapy with or without PCI for Stable Coronary Disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 2007;356:1503&#x2013;1516. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa070829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa070829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17387127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron D.J., Hochman J.S., Reynolds H.R., Bangalore S., O&#x2019;Brien S.M., Boden W.E., Chaitman B.R., Senior R., L&#xf3;pez-Send&#xf3;n J., Alexander K.P., et al. Initial Invasive or Conservative Strategy for Stable Coronary Disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382:1395&#x2013;1407. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1915922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1915922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7263833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32227755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera D., Clayton T., O&#x2019;Kane P.D., Greenwood J.P., Weerackody R., Ryan M., Morgan H.P., Dodd M., Evans R., Canter R., et al. Percutaneous Revascularization for Ischemic Left Ventricular Dysfunction. N. Engl. J. Med. 2022;387:1351&#x2013;1360. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2206606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2206606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36027563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada K., Kubo T., Kameyama T., Matsuo Y., Ino Y., Emori H., Higashioka D., Katayama Y., Khalifa A.K.M., Takahata M., et al. NIRS-IVUS for Differentiating Coronary Plaque Rupture, Erosion, and Calcified Nodule in Acute Myocardial Infarction. JACC Cardiovasc. Imaging. 2021;14:1440&#x2013;1450. doi: 10.1016/j.jcmg.2020.08.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcmg.2020.08.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33221211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuku K.O., Singh M., Ozaki Y., Dan K., Chezar-Azerrad C., Waksman R., Garcia-Garcia H.M. Near-Infrared Spectroscopy Intravascular Ultrasound Imaging: State of the Art. Front. Cardiovasc. Med. 2020;7:107. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2020.00107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2020.00107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7338425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32695796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinilla-Echeverri N., Mehta S.R., Wang J., Lavi S., Schampaert E., Cantor W.J., Bainey K.R., Welsh R.C., Kassam S., Mehran R., et al. Nonculprit Lesion Plaque Morphology in Patients With ST-Segment-Elevation Myocardial Infarction: Results From the COMPLETE Trial Optical Coherence Tomography Substudys. Circ. Cardiovasc. Interv. 2020;13:e008768. doi: 10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.119.008768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.119.008768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thim T., van der Hoeven N.W., Musto C., Nijveldt R., G&#xf6;tberg M., Engstr&#xf8;m T., Smits P.C., Oldroyd K.G., Gershlick A.H., Escaned J., et al. Evaluation and Management of Nonculprit Lesions in STEMI. JACC Cardiovasc. Interv. 2020;13:1145&#x2013;1154. doi: 10.1016/j.jcin.2020.02.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcin.2020.02.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32438985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sustersic M., Mrak M., Svegl P., Kodre A.R., Kranjec I., Fras Z., Bunc M. Complete Revascularization and Survival in STEMI. Glob. Heart. 2021;16:64. doi: 10.5334/gh.1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/gh.1040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8485869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34692389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thygesen K., Alpert J.S., Jaffe A.S., Chaitman B.R., Bax J.J., Morrow D.A., White H.D., Executive Group on behalf of the Joint European Society of Cardiology/American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association/World Heart Federation Task Force for the Universal Definition of Myocardial Infarction Fourth Universal Definition of Myocardial Infarction (2018) J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 2018;72:2231&#x2013;2264. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.08.1038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2018.08.1038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriu-Leen A.C., Hermans M.P., Veltman C.E., van der Hoeven B.L., van Rosendael A.R., van Zwet E.W., Schalij M.J., Delgado V., Bax J.J., Scholte A.J. Prognosis of complete versus incomplete revascularisation of patients with STEMI with multivessel coronary artery disease: An observational study. Open Heart. 2017;4:e000541. doi: 10.1136/openhrt-2016-000541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/openhrt-2016-000541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvao Braga C., Cid-Alvarez A.B., Redondo Dieguez A., Trillo-Nouche R., Alvarez Alvarez B., Lopez Otero D., Ocaranza Sanchez R., Gestal Romani S., Gonzalez Ferreiro R., Gonzalez-Juanatey J.R. Multivessel Versus Culprit-only Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in ST-segment Elevation Acute Myocardial Infarction: Analysis of an 8-year Registry. Rev. Esp. Cardiol. (Engl. Ed.) 2017;70:425&#x2013;432. doi: 10.1016/j.rec.2016.09.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rec.2016.09.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27825718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hlinomaz O., Groch L., Polokov&#xe1; K., Lehar F., Vekov T., Petkov R., Stojnev M., G&#x159;iva M., Sit&#xe1;r J., Rezek M., et al. Multivessel coronary disease diagnosed at the time of primary PCI for STEMI: Complete revascularisation versus conservative strategy. Prague-13 trial. Kardiol. Rev. Int. Med. 2015;17:214&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bravo C.A., Hirji S.A., Bhatt D.L., Kataria R., Faxon D.P., Ohman E.M., Anderson K.L., Sidi A.I., Sketch M.H., Jr., Zarich S.W., et al. Complete versus culprit-only revascularisation in ST elevation myocardial infarction with multi-vessel disease. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2017;5:CD011986. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD011986.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011986.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6481381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28470696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B., Yang Y., Han Y.-l., Lu S.-Z., Li B., Liu Q., Zhu G.-Y., Cui J.-Y., Li L., Zhao Y.-L., et al. Validation of residual SYNTAX score with second-generation drug-eluting stents: One-year results from the prospective multicentre SEEDS study. EuroIntervention. 2014;10:65&#x2013;73. doi: 10.4244/EIJV10I1A12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4244/EIJV10I1A12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24603020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed T.A.N., Othman A.A.A., Demitry S.R., Elmaghraby K.M. Impact of residual coronary lesions on outcomes of myocardial infarction patients with multi-vessel disease. BMC Cardiovasc. Disord. 2024;24:68. doi: 10.1186/s12872-023-03657-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-023-03657-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10804526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38262995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altekin R.E., Kilinc A.Y., Onac M., Cicekcibasi O. Prognostic Value of the Residual SYNTAX Score on In-Hospital and Follow-Up Clinical Outcomes in ST Elevation Myocardial Infarction Patients Undergoing Percutaneous Coronary Interventions. Cardiol. Res. Pract. 2020;2020:9245431. doi: 10.1155/2020/9245431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/9245431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33178454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim L.K., Yeo I., Cheung J.W., Swaminathan R.V., Wong S.C., Charitakis K., Adejumo O., Chae J., Minutello R.M., Bergman G., et al. Thirty-Day Readmission Rates, Timing, Causes, and Costs after ST-Segment-Elevation Myocardial Infarction in the United States: A National Readmission Database Analysis 2010&#x2013;2014. J. Am. Heart Assoc. 2018;7:e009863. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.118.009863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.118.009863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6222940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer E., Frei M., Zaugg S., Hadorn S., Kelbaek H., Ostojic M., Baumbach A., T&#xfc;ller D., Roffi M., Engstrom T., et al. Rehospitalizations Following Primary Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in Patients With ST-Elevation Myocardial Infarction: Results From a Multi-Center Randomized Trial. J. Am. Heart Assoc. 2017;6:e005926. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.117.005926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.117.005926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5586438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown J.R., Conley S.M., Niles N.W., 2nd Predicting readmission or death after acute ST-elevation myocardial infarction. Clin. Cardiol. 2013;36:570&#x2013;575. doi: 10.1002/clc.22156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.22156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5585865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23754777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laudani C., Occhipinti G., Greco A., Spagnolo M., Giacoppo D., Capodanno D. Completeness, timing, and guidance of percutaneous coronary intervention for myocardial infarction and multivessel disease: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. EuroIntervention. 2025;21:e203&#x2013;e216. doi: 10.4244/EIJ-D-24-00814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4244/EIJ-D-24-00814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11809220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39962946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>