<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40965410</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1752-2978</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in endocrinology, diabetes, and obesity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Personalizing therapy in early gestational diabetes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MED.0000000000000931</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Early gestational diabetes mellitus (eGDM) is being increasingly detected on the background of rising obesity rates and widespread early pregnancy screening. However, diagnostic criteria and management strategies remain uncertain. This review summarizes current evidence on diagnostic thresholds, maternal and fetal outcomes, and the impact of early treatment, with an emphasis on balancing benefits and risks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">While observational studies link eGDM to adverse maternal and fetal outcomes, evidence from intervention studies remains limited. The Treatment of Booking Gestational Diabetes Mellitus (TOBOGM) is the only large multicenter randomized controlled trial (RCT) published till date. The early intervention arm in the study received education on dietary counseling and capillary blood glucose monitoring, with pharmacotherapy using insulin or metformin introduced when indicated. The trial reported that treatment before 14&#x200a;weeks reduced neonatal respiratory distress in higher glycemic bands but increased the risk of small-for-gestational-age state at lower glycemic bands. Notably, one-third of the untreated control group reverted to normoglycemia at 24-28&#x200a;weeks. Given the uncertainties in diagnostic thresholds used in TOBOGM, a composite risk score-based approach integrating clinical and biochemical parameters may provide an alternative for identifying pregnancies in need of intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Current diagnostic criteria may not identify eGDM pregnancies that would benefit from intervention. Redefining diagnostic thresholds and integrating them with clinical risk factors could categorize pregnancies in need of intervention. Appropriately designed RCTs are required to generate evidence for accurate identification and optimal treatment of eGDM.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thakkar</LastName><ForeName>Simran</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Indraprastha Apollo Hospitals, New Delhi, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saravanan</LastName><ForeName>Ponnusamy</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Warwick Medical School, Warwick Applied Health.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Global Health, University of Warwick, Coventry.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes, Endocrinology and Metabolism, George Eliot Hospital NHS Trust, Nuneaton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagendra</LastName><ForeName>Lakshmi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, JSS Medical College, JSS Academy of Higher Education and Research, Mysore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattacharya</LastName><ForeName>Saptarshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Indraprastha Apollo Hospitals, New Delhi, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101308636</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1752-296X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">composite risk scores</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">first-trimester hyperglycemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gestational diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neonatal outcome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral glucose tolerance test</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40965410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MED.0000000000000931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01266029-990000000-00140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya S, Nagendra L, Krishnamurthy A, et al. Early gestational diabetes mellitus: diagnostic strategies and clinical implications. Med Sci (Basel) 2021; 9:59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons D, Gupta Y, Hernandez TL, et al. Call to action for a life course approach. Lancet 2024; 404:193&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Li N, Chivese T, et al. IDF Diabetes Atlas: estimation of global and regional gestational diabetes mellitus prevalence for 2021 by International Association of Diabetes in Pregnancy Study Group's Criteria. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2022; 183:109050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting AN, Ross GP, Hyett J, et al. Gestational diabetes in the first trimester: is early testing justified? Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2017; 5:571&#x2013;573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powe CE. One step closer to a definition of early gestational diabetes mellitus: secondary analyses from the Treatment of Booking Gestational Diabetes Mellitus (TOBOGM) Randomized Trial. Diabetes Care 2024; 47:2076&#x2013;2078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya S, Nagendra L, Dutta D, et al. First-trimester fasting plasma glucose as a predictor of subsequent gestational diabetes mellitus and adverse fetomaternal outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab Syndr 2024; 18:103051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkataraman H, Ram U, Craik S, et al. Increased fetal adiposity prior to diagnosis of gestational diabetes in South Asians: more evidence for the &#x2018;thin-fat&#x2019; baby. Diabetologia 2017; 60:399&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons D, Immanuel J, Hague WM, et al. Treatment of gestational diabetes mellitus diagnosed early in pregnancy. N Engl J Med 2023; 388:2132&#x2013;2144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons D, Nema J, Parton C, et al. The treatment of booking gestational diabetes mellitus (TOBOGM) pilot randomised controlled trial. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 2018; 18:151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah W, Bhavadharini B, Beks H, et al. Global burden of early pregnancy gestational diabetes mellitus (eGDM): a systematic review. Acta Diabetol 2022; 59:403&#x2013;427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuen L, Wong V, Immanuel J, et al. Ethnic differences in characteristics of women diagnosed with early gestational diabetes: findings from the TOBOGM Study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2024; 110:e2471&#x2013;e2484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong J-N, Wu L-L, Chen Y-X, et al. Fasting plasma glucose in the first trimester is related to gestational diabetes mellitus and adverse pregnancy outcomes. Endocrine 2022; 75:70&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan P, Deepa M, Ahmed Z, et al. Early pregnancy HbA1c as the first screening test for gestational diabetes: results from three prospective cohorts. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2024; 12:535&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani Tehrani F, Behboudi-Gandevani S, Farzadfar F, et al. A cluster randomized noninferiority field trial of gestational diabetes mellitus screening. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2022; 107:e2906&#x2013;e2920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Cai J, Xu Y, et al. Early diagnosed gestational diabetes mellitus is associated with adverse pregnancy outcomes: a prospective cohort study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2020; 105:dgaa633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riskin-Mashiah S, Younes G, Damti A, et al. First-trimester fasting hyperglycemia and adverse pregnancy outcomes. Diabetes Care 2009; 32:1639&#x2013;1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sesmilo G, Prats P, Garcia S, et al. First-trimester fasting glycemia as a predictor of gestational diabetes (GDM) and adverse pregnancy outcomes. Acta Diabetol 2020; 57:697&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punnose J, Malhotra RK, Sukhija K, et al. Gestational diabetes mellitus in early pregnancy amongst Asian Indian women: evidence for poor pregnancy outcomes despite treatment. Diabet Med 2023; 40:e14993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting AN, Ross GP, Hyett J, et al. Gestational diabetes mellitus in early pregnancy: evidence for poor pregnancy outcomes despite treatment. Diabetes Care 2015; 39:75&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#xf1;&#xe9; L, Flores-Le Roux JA, Benaiges D, et al. Role of first-trimester HbA1c as a predictor of adverse obstetric outcomes in a multiethnic cohort. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2017; 102:390&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting A, Enticott J, Immanuel J, et al. Relationship between early-pregnancy glycemia and adverse outcomes: findings from the TOBOGM Study. Diabetes Care 2024; 47:2085&#x2013;2092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes RCE, Moore MP, Gullam JE, et al. An early pregnancy HbA1c &#x2265;5.9% (41&#x200a;mmol/mol) is optimal for detecting diabetes and identifies women at increased risk of adverse pregnancy outcomes. Diabetes Care 2014; 37:2953&#x2013;2959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt L, G&#xf6;bl CS, Leitner K, et al. HbA1c during early pregnancy reflects beta-cell dysfunction in women developing GDM. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care 2020; 8:e001751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immanuel J, Simmons D, Desoye G, et al. Performance of early pregnancy HbA1c for predicting gestational diabetes mellitus and adverse pregnancy outcomes in obese European women. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2020; 168:108378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punnose J, Malhotra RK, Sukhija K, et al. Glycated haemoglobin in the first trimester: a predictor of gestational diabetes mellitus in pregnant Asian Indian women. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2020; 159:107953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelson PK, James KE, Leong A, et al. Longitudinal changes in the relationship between hemoglobin A1c and glucose tolerance across pregnancy and postpartum. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2020; 105:e1999&#x2013;e2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#xf1;&#xe9; L, Navarro H, Pedro-Botet J, et al. Early HbA1c levels as a predictor of adverse obstetric outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med 2024; 13:1732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir M, Baagar K, Naem E, et al. Pregnancy outcomes of early detected gestational diabetes: a retrospective comparison cohort study, Qatar. BMJ Open 2019; 9:e023612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons D, Immanuel J, Hague WM, et al. Regression from early GDM to normal glucose tolerance and adverse pregnancy outcomes in the treatment of booking Gestational Diabetes Mellitus Study. Diabetes Care 2024; 47:2079&#x2013;2084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lappharat S, Rothmanee P, Jandee K, et al. A model for predicting gestational diabetes mellitus in early pregnancy: a prospective study in Thailand. Obstet Gynecol Sci 2022; 65:156&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu Z-R, Bai L-W, Lu Q. Establishment of gestational diabetes risk prediction model and clinical verification. J Endocrinol Invest 2024; 47:1281&#x2013;1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basil B, Mba IN, Myke-Mbata BK, et al. A first trimester prediction model and nomogram for gestational diabetes mellitus based on maternal clinical risk factors in a resource-poor setting. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 2024; 24:346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmundson SS, Norton ME, El-Sayed YY, et al. Early screening and treatment of women with prediabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Perinatol 2016; 33:172&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes RCE, Rowan J, Williman J. Prediabetes in pregnancy, can early intervention improve outcomes? A feasibility study for a parallel randomised clinical trial. BMJ Open 2018; 8:e018493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinter CA, Tanvig MH, Christensen MH, et al. Lifestyle intervention in Danish obese pregnant women with early gestational diabetes mellitus according to WHO 2013 Criteria does not change pregnancy outcomes: results from the LiP (Lifestyle in Pregnancy) Study. Diabetes Care 2018; 41:2079&#x2013;2085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roeder HA, Moore TR, Wolfson MT, et al. Treating hyperglycemia in early pregnancy: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM 2019; 1:33&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani Tehrani F, Farzadfar F, Hosseinpanah F, et al. Does fasting plasma glucose values 5.1-56&#x200a;mmol/l in the first trimester of gestation a matter? Front Endocrinol 2023; 14:1155007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya S, Nagendra L, Dutta D, et al. Treatment versus observation in early gestational diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2025; 110:1781&#x2013;1791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan LE, Boyle SL, McNeil DA, et al. Label of gestational diabetes mellitus affects caesarean section and neonatal intensive care unit admission without conventional indications. Can J Diabetes 2012; 36:58&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong J-N, Chen Y-X, Guan X-N, et al. Association between the cut-off value of the first trimester fasting plasma glucose level and gestational diabetes mellitus: a retrospective study from southern China. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 2022; 22:540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weingarten SJ, Levy AT, Al-Kouatly HB, et al. Postpartum diabetes mellitus among patients with early gestational diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Diabetes Complications 2025; 39:109038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung NW, Rhou YJJ, Immanuel J, et al. Postpartum dysglycaemia after early gestational diabetes: follow-up of women in the TOBOGM randomised controlled trial. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2024; 218:111929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta Y, Goyal A, Tandon N. Postpartum diabetes and cardiometabolic outcomes among Indian (South Asian) women with early Gestational diabetes mellitus: insights from the CHIP-F study. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2024; 212:111710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maor-Sagie E, Hallak M, Twig G, et al. First-trimester fasting plasma glucose levels and progression to type 2 diabetes: a 5-year cohort study. Int J Gynecol Obstet 2024; 167:728&#x2013;735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee. 2. Diagnosis and Classification of Diabetes: Standards of Care in Diabetes&#x2014;2025. Diabetes Care 2024; 48:S27&#x2013;S49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, International Diabetes Federation. Definition and diagnosis of diabetes mellitus and intermediate hyperglycaemia: report of a WHO/IDF consultation [Internet]. 2006. http://www.who.int/diabetes/publications/diagnosis_diabetes2006/en/. [Accessed 16 June 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>15. Management of Diabetes in Pregnancy: Standards of Care in Diabetes-2025. Diabetes Care 2025; 48:S306&#x2013;S320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Association of Diabetes and Pregnancy Study Groups Consensus Panel. International Association of Diabetes and Pregnancy Study Groups Recommendations on the Diagnosis and Classification of Hyperglycemia in Pregnancy. Diabetes Care 2010; 33:676&#x2013;682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkie G, Delpapa E, Leftwich H. Early diagnosis of prediabetes among pregnant women that develop gestational diabetes mellitus and its influence on perinatal outcomes. Am J Perinatol 2024; 41:343&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiller T, Barak O, Winter Shafran Y, et al. Prediabetes in pregnancy &#x2013; follow-up, treatment, and outcomes compared to overt pregestational diabetes. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med 2023; 36:2191153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y-M, Liu X-Y, Shou C, et al. Value of fasting plasma glucose to screen gestational diabetes mellitus before the 24th gestational week in women with different prepregnancy body mass index. Chin Med J (Engl) 2019; 132:883&#x2013;888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riskin-Mashiah S, Damti A, Younes G, et al. First trimester fasting hyperglycemia as a predictor for the development of gestational diabetes mellitus. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 2010; 152:163&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao M, Lin L. Fasting plasma glucose and body mass index during the first trimester of pregnancy as predictors of gestational diabetes mellitus in a Chinese population. Endocr J 2017; 64:561&#x2013;569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alunni ML, Roeder HA, Moore TR, et al. First trimester gestational diabetes screening - change in incidence and pharmacotherapy need. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2015; 109:135&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal A, Gupta Y. Current approach to early gestational diabetes mellitus: a clinical update. Diabetes Metab Syndr 2025; 19:103256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee AC, Katz J, Blencowe H, et al. National and regional estimates of term and preterm babies born small for gestational age in 138 low-income and middle-income countries in 2010. Lancet Glob Health 2013; 1:e26&#x2013;e36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Champion ML, Battarbee AN, Biggio JR, et al. Postpartum glucose intolerance following early gestational diabetes mellitus. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM 2022; 4:100609.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>