<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40947318</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-114X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical therapeutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of Fimasartan, Atorvastatin, and Ezetimibe Combination Therapy in Patients With Hypertension and Dyslipidemia: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Multicenter, Therapeutic Confirmatory, Phase III Clinical Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0149-2918(25)00294-2</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.clinthera.2025.08.012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Essential hypertension and primary hypercholesterolemia are common and independent cardiovascular risk factors that frequently coexist and warrant integrated management. This study aimed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of triple combination therapy (FMS + ATO/EZE) with Fimasartan (FMS), atorvastatin (ATV), and ezetimibe (EZE) compared with atorvastatin/ezetimibe (ATO/EZE) dual therapy or Fimasartan (FMS) monotherapy in patients with hypertension and hypercholesterolemia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This multicenter, randomized clinical trial was conducted across 25 clinical trial institutions in the Republic of Korea. A total of 315 participants were screened, of whom 148 eligible participants were randomized to receive FMS + ATO/EZE (n = 49), ATO/EZE (n = 49), or FMS (n = 50). The primary efficacy endpoints were the change in mean sitting systolic blood pressure (msSBP) from baseline to week 8 in the FMS + ATO/EZE group compared with that in the ATO/EZE group and the percentage change in low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) from baseline to week 8 in the FMS + ATO/EZE group compared with that in the FMS group. Safety was assessed based on treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In the full analysis set, the FMS + ATO/EZE group demonstrated superior reduction in msSBP compared to the ATO/EZE group (least squares [LS] mean difference: -7.26 &#xb1; 2.84 mm Hg; 95% confidence interval [CI]: -12.91, -1.61; P = 0.0124). Similarly, the percentage reduction in LDL-C was significantly greater in the FMS + ATO/EZE group than in the FMS group (LS mean difference: -58.02% &#xb1; 4.03%; 95% CI: -66.03, -50.02; P &lt; 0.0001). The incidence of TEAEs was comparable across treatment groups: FMS + ATO/EZE (20.83%), ATO/EZE (22.45%), and FMS (16.00%) (P = 0.7030). Serious adverse events occurred in 1.36% of the total safety population, without significant difference between the groups (P = 0.5480).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Triple combination therapy with FMS + ATO/EZE was superior to dual therapy or monotherapy in reducing both BP and LDL-C levels in patients with essential hypertension accompanied by primary hypercholesterolemia. The safety profile was comparable with that of the individual components, confirming the tolerability and safety of FMS + ATO/EZE therapy. However, the 8-week follow-up period and enrollment of an exclusively Korean cohort may limit the assessment of long-term effects and generalizability to other ethnic populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Soon Jun</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Cardiovascular Center, Korea University Anam Hospital, Korea University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ju Hyeon</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cha</LastName><ForeName>Kwang Soo</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Pusan National University Hospital, Pusan National University School of Medicine, Busan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jin Bae</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Daegu Catholic University Medical Center, Daegu, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moon</LastName><ForeName>Jae Youn</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, CHA Bundang Medical Center, CHA University, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Goo-Yeong</ForeName><Initials>GY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Cardiovascular Center, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Deok-Kyu</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine and Cardiovascular Center, Yongin Severance Hospital, Yongin, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Jong-Pil</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Presbyterian Medical Center, Jeonju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Jeong-Eun</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Eunpyeong St. Mary's Hospital, The Catholic University of Korea, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Kye Hun</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Chonnam National University Hospital, Chonnam National University Medical School, Gwangju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Hyeonju</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Myongji Hospital, Hanyang University Medical Center, Goyang, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rhee</LastName><ForeName>Moo-Yong</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Center, Dongguk University Ilsan Hospital, Goyang, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jung-Hee</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Wonju Severance Christian Hospital, Yonsei University Wonju College of Medicine, Wonju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahn</LastName><ForeName>Kye Tack</ForeName><Initials>KT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Chungnam National University Hospital, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Young Won</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Gangnam Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sang-Yeub</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chung-Ang University College of Medicine, Chung-Ang University Gwangmyeong Hospital, Gwangmyeong, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sung</LastName><ForeName>Ki-Chul</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kangbuk Samsung Hospital, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cha</LastName><ForeName>Tae-Joon</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kosin University Gospel Hospital, Busan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Jinho</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Hanyang University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Yoon Haeng</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Divisions of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Soonchunhyang University Bucheon Hospital, Soonchunhyang University College of Medicine, Bucheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Son</LastName><ForeName>Jang-Won</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Yeungnam University Medical Center, Daegu, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahn</LastName><ForeName>Jong-Hwa</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Gyeongsang National University School of Medicine and Gyeongsang National University Changwon Hospital, Changwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sang-Don</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Inha University College of Medicine, Incheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Woong Chol</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, Gil Medical Center, Gachon University College of Medicine, Incheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hahn</LastName><ForeName>Joo-Yong</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ha</LastName><ForeName>Jong-Won</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Severance Hospital, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea. Electronic address: jwha@yuhs.ac.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7706726</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0149-2918</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atorvastatin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Essential hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ezetimibe</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fimasartan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary hypercholesterolemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triple combination therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have influenced the work reported in this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40947318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2025.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0149-2918(25)00294-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>