<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38646212</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Review of the Efficacy of the Low Fermentable Oligosaccharides, Disaccharides, Monosaccharides, and Polyols (FODMAP) Diet in Managing Gastrointestinal Symptoms Related to Cancer Treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e56579</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e56579</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e56579</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.56579</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The low fermentable oligosaccharides, disaccharides, monosaccharides, and polyols (FODMAP) diet, designed to alleviate symptoms in individuals with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), focuses on limiting the consumption of poorly absorbed fermentable carbohydrates known as FODMAP. These FODMAP are believed to be the primary triggers for food-related gastrointestinal symptoms in functional gastrointestinal disorders. However, there is currently insufficient direct evidence investigating the role of low FODMAP diets in cancer patients undergoing treatment. This review aims to summarize the current evidence on the low FODMAP diet and its potential implications for cancer patients in terms of treatment outcomes, alleviating gastrointestinal symptoms, and overall health. A systematic literature search was conducted using databases, including PubMed, Scopus, Google Scholar, Web of Science, and Cochrane. Five studies met the criteria for inclusion in the review, and these studies covered rectal toxicity during radiotherapy, gastrointestinal symptoms in colorectal cancer patients, acute gastrointestinal toxicity during pelvic external beam radiotherapy, symptoms in patients with radiation-induced enteropathy, and chronic gastrointestinal sequelae resulting from pelvic organ cancer treatment. The available evidence suggests that a low FODMAP diet may offer advantages in reducing rectal gas and volume during radiotherapy, alleviating diarrhea symptoms, reducing symptom deterioration, and improving quality of life. However, these studies highlight the need for large-scale randomized trials, long-term follow-up, and guidelines to establish the efficacy, safety, and implementation strategies of the low FODMAP diet in different cancer contexts and patient populations. While preliminary findings reported some possible benefits of a low FODMAP diet for certain cancer patients, rigorous studies with large sample sizes are needed to provide more robust evidence. Further research is warranted to optimize the utilization of this diet as an adjunctive intervention for managing gastrointestinal symptoms in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Almasaudi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almasaudi</LastName><ForeName>Arwa S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Nutrition Department, Faculty of Applied Medical Sciences, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrointestinal symptom</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low fodmap diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oncology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38646212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11027021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.56579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Review of cancer from the perspective of molecular. Hassanpour SH, Dehghani M. JCRP. 2017;4:127&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer statistics, 2016. Siegel RL, Miller KD, Jemal A. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21332. CA Cancer J Clin. 2016;66:7&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26742998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didkowska J, Koczkodaj P. Handbook of Cancer and Immunology. Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing; 2022. Cancer epidemiology and prevention.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exposure to environmental chemicals and heavy metals, and risk of pancreatic cancer. Antwi SO, Eckert EC, Sabaque CV, et al. Cancer Causes Control. 2015;26:1583&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4624268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26293241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global burden of cancer. Ma X, Yu H. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1994799/ Yale J Biol Med. 2006;79:85&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1994799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17940618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diversity of genome profiles in malignant lymphoma. Seto M, Honma K, Nakagawa M. Cancer Sci. 2010;101:573&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11159680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20070305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptoms of Cancer - NCI. Symptoms of cancer.  [
Jul;
2023 
]. 2015. https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/symptoms https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/diagnosis-staging/symptoms</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preventable incidence and mortality of carcinoma associated with lifestyle factors among white adults in the United States. Song M, Giovannucci E. JAMA Oncol. 2016;2:1154&#x2013;1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5016199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27196525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A framework for examining how diet impacts tumour metabolism. Lien EC, Vander Heiden MG. Nat Rev Cancer. 2019;19:651&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31530936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary factors and growth and metabolism in experimental tumors. Sauer LA, Blask DE, Dauchy RT. J Nutr Biochem. 2007;18:637&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17418560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of different types of diet on gut microbiota profiles and cancer prevention and treatment. Klement RJ, Pazienza V. Medicina (Kaunas) 2019;55:84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30934960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketogenic diet in the treatment of cancer - where do we stand? Weber DD, Aminzadeh-Gohari S, Tulipan J, Catalano L, Feichtinger RG, Kofler B. Mol Metab. 2020;33:102&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7056920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31399389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketogenic diet for cancer: critical assessment and research recommendations. Lane J, Brown NI, Williams S, Plaisance EP, Fontaine KR. Nutrients. 2021;13:3562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8539953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starvation-dependent differential stress resistance protects normal but not cancer cells against high-dose chemotherapy. Raffaghello L, Lee C, Safdie FM, Wei M, Madia F, Bianchi G, Longo VD. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105:8215&#x2013;8220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2448817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18378900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasting and cancer: molecular mechanisms and clinical application. Nencioni A, Caffa I, Cortellino S, Longo VD. Nat Rev Cancer. 2018;18:707&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6938162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30327499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasting-mimicking diet reduces HO-1 to promote T cell-mediated tumor cytotoxicity. Di Biase S, Lee C, Brandhorst S, et al. Cancer Cell. 2016;30:136&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27411588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary modifications for enhanced cancer therapy. Kanarek N, Petrova B, Sabatini DM. Nature. 2020;579:507&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32214253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>History of the low FODMAP diet. Gibson PR. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32 Suppl 1:5&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28244673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low FODMAP diet: evidence, doubts, and hopes. Bellini M, Tonarelli S, Nagy AG, et al. Nutrients. 2020;12:148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31947991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The low FODMAP diet in the management of irritable bowel syndrome: an evidence-based review of FODMAP restriction, reintroduction and personalisation in clinical practice. Whelan K, Martin LD, Staudacher HM, Lomer MC. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2018;31:239&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29336079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FODMAPs: food composition, defining cutoff values and international application. Varney J, Barrett J, Scarlata K, Catsos P, Gibson PR, Muir JG. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32 Suppl 1:53&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28244665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of the low FODMAP diet for treating irritable bowel syndrome: the evidence to date. Nanayakkara WS, Skidmore PM, O'Brien L, Wilkinson TJ, Gearry RB. Clin Exp Gastroenterol. 2016;9:131&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4918736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27382323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is a low FODMAP diet beneficial for patients with inflammatory bowel disease? A meta-analysis and systematic review. Zhan YL, Zhan YA, Dai SX. Clin Nutr. 2018;37:123&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28587774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The low-FODMAP diet for irritable bowel syndrome: lights and shadows. Molina-Infante J, Serra J, Fernandez-Ba&#xf1;ares F, Mearin F. Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;39:55&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26548734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized, 6-wk trial of a low FODMAP diet in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Bodini G, Zanella C, Crespi M, et al. Nutrition. 2019;67-68:110542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31470260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of a low FODMAP diet on the amount of rectal gas and rectal volume during radiotherapy in patients with prostate cancer - a prospective pilot study. Schaefer C, Zamboglou C, Volegova-Neher N, et al. Radiat Oncol. 2020;15:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6993432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32000818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consumption of lactose, other FODMAPs and diarrhoea during adjuvant 5-fluorouracil chemotherapy for colorectal cancer. Holma R, Laatikainen R, Orell H, et al. Nutrients. 2020;12:407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does the low FODMAP diet improve symptoms of radiation-induced enteropathy? A pilot study. Larsen T, Hausken T, Otteraaen Ystad S, Hovdenak N, Mueller B, Lied GA. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2018;53:541&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29113519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of nutritional intervention in reduction of gastrointestinal toxicity during external beam radiotherapy in women with gynecological tumors. Soto-Lugo JH, Souto-Del Bosque MA, V&#xe1;zquez-Mart&#xed;nez CA. https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/becb/515ed146ed4494290a48dabeb8e60c7196d2.pdf Gaceta Mexicana de Oncologia. 2017;16:84&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary intervention improves gastrointestinal symptoms after treatment of cancer in the pelvic organs. Borre M, Fassov J, Poulsen JL, Christensen P, Laurberg S, Drewes AM, Krogh K. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm12144766. J Clin Med. 2023;12:4766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10380860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37510881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FODMAPs or gluten as inducers of symptoms in irritable bowel syndrome: separating the wheat from the chaff. Whelan K. Am J Clin Nutr. 2022;115:327&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34910099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanisms underlying food-triggered symptoms in disorders of gut-brain interactions. Van den Houte K, Bercik P, Simren M, Tack J, Vanner S. Am J Gastroenterol. 2022;117:937&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9169752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fermentable oligosaccharides, disaccharides, monosaccharides, and polyols (FODMAPs) and cancer risk in the prospective NutriNet-Sant&#xe9; cohort. Debras C, Chazelas E, Srour B, et al. J Nutr. 2022;152:1059&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34718693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inflammatory bowel diseases and fermentable oligosaccharides, disaccharides, monosaccharides, and polyols: an overview. Barbalho SM, Goulart RA, Aran&#xe3;o AL, de Oliveira PG. J Med Food. 2018;21:633&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29328869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The relation between Malnutrition Universal Screening Tool (MUST), computed tomography-derived body composition, systemic inflammation, and clinical outcomes in patients undergoing surgery for colorectal cancer. Almasaudi AS, McSorley ST, Dolan RD, Edwards CA, McMillan DC. Am J Clin Nutr. 2019;110:1327&#x2013;1334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31529042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of low and high FODMAP diets on human gastrointestinal microbiota composition in adults with intestinal diseases: a systematic review. Vandeputte D, Joossens M. Microorganisms. 2020;8:1638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The low FODMAP diet: many question marks for a catchy acronym. Catassi G, Lionetti E, Gatti S, Catassi C. Nutrients. 2017;9:292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5372955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28300773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Controversies and reality of the FODMAP diet for patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Halmos EP, Gibson PR. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;34:1134&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30945376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>