<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40785820</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2434-0790</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Circulation reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Circ Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of Long-Term Outcomes Between Second-Generation Single Long Stents and Overlapping Stents for Long-Diffuse Coronary Artery Disease&#x3000;- Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>604</StartPage><EndPage>611</EndPage><MedlinePgn>604-611</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1253/circrep.CR-25-0075</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Coronary artery disease (CAD) is becoming increasingly prevalent in aging populations. Long-diffuse CAD (ldCAD), characterized by lesions &#x2265;30 mm, poses significant treatment challenges. This study aimed to evaluate the long-term prognostic differences between single long stents (SLS) and overlapping stents (OLS) in patients with ldCAD using second-generation and later drug-eluting stents (DES).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies published between 2000 and October 2024 in PubMed, Embase, Web of Science, and the Cochrane Library was conducted. The primary outcome was major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE) over 1 year. The secondary outcomes were cardiac death, target lesion revascularization, target vessel revascularization (TVR), and fatal or non-fatal myocardial infarction (MI). The analysis included 5 studies with 2,756 patients, indicating no significant differences between SLS and OLS regarding MACE and TVR. However, MI incidence was significantly lower with SLS, whereas OLS showed a higher MI incidence, likely due to differences in lesion length rather than the strategy itself. Subanalyses indicated that SLS significantly reduced contrast volume compared with OLS, with a trend toward shorter lesions and stent lengths.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Stent overlap has minimal impact on prognosis with newer DES. Despite limitations from non-randomized data, further research is needed to optimize ldCAD treatment strategies and guide clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, THE JAPANESE CIRCULATION SOCIETY.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikehara</LastName><ForeName>Masaaki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cooperative Major in Advanced Biomedical Sciences, Joint Graduate School of Tokyo Women's Medical University and Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Tokyo Women's Medical University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hattori</LastName><ForeName>Kaoru</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Tokyo Women's Medical University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Bioscience and Biomedical Engineering, Graduate School of Advanced Science and Engineering, Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Modern Mechanical Engineering, School of Creative Science and Engineering, Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niinami</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Tokyo Women's Medical University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Bioscience and Biomedical Engineering, Graduate School of Advanced Science and Engineering, Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwasaki</LastName><ForeName>Kiyotaka</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cooperative Major in Advanced Biomedical Sciences, Joint Graduate School of Tokyo Women's Medical University and Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Bioscience and Biomedical Engineering, Graduate School of Advanced Science and Engineering, Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Modern Mechanical Engineering, School of Creative Science and Engineering, Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Medical Regulatory Science, Waseda University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Circ Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101746642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2434-0790</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffuse coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug-eluting stent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Overlapping stent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Single long stent</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>K.I. is a member of Circulation Reports&#x2019; Editorial Team. The other authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40785820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12331351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circrep.CR-25-0075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare of Japan.. Part 1, Chapter 1, Section 2: Aging of the Population and Medical Care. Health and Welfare White Paper 2006. Available from: https://www.mhlw.go.jp/stf/wp/hakusyo/kousei/18/backdata/01-01-02-07.html (accessed March 6, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tsao CW, Aday AW, Almarzooq ZI, Anderson CAM, Arora P, Avery CL, et al.. 
Heart disease and stroke statistics-2023 update: A report from the American Heart Association. <i>Circulation</i>
2023; 147: e93&#x2013;e621, doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001123.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12135016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36695182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ryan TJ, Faxon DP, Gunnar RM, Kennedy JW, King SB, Loop FD, et al.. 
Guidelines for percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty. A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Assessment of Diagnostic and Therapeutic Cardiovascular Procedures (Subcommittee on Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty).
<i>Circulation</i>
1988; 78: 486&#x2013;502, doi:10.1161/01.cir.78.2.486.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2969312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Neumann FJ, Sousa-Uva M, Ahlsson A, Alfonso F, Banning AP, Benedetto U, et al.. 
2018 ESC/EACTS guidelines on myocardial revascularization.
<i>Eur Heart J</i>
2019; 40: 87&#x2013;165, doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehy394.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sharp ASP, Latib A, Ielasi A, Larosa C, Godino C, Saolini M, et al.. 
Long-term follow-up on a large cohort of &#x2018;full-metal jacket&#x2019; percutaneous coronary intervention procedures.
<i>Circ Cardiovasc Interv</i>
2009; 2: 416&#x2013;422, doi:10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.109.886945.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Costopoulos C, Latib A, Naganuma T, Sticchi A, Figini F, Basavarajaiah S, et al.. 
The role of drug-eluting balloons alone or in combination with drug-eluting stents in the treatment of de novo diffuse coronary disease.
<i>JACC Cardiovasc Interv</i>
2013; 6: 1153&#x2013;1159, doi:10.1016/j.jcin.2013.07.005.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24262615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Mori N, Okamoto N, Tanaka A, Yano M, Makino N, Egami Y, et al.. 
Comparison of angiographic and 1-year outcomes between a long single stent and overlapping double stents in patients with newer-generation drug-eluting stents for long narrowings.
<i>Am J Cardiol</i>
2016; 117: 1724&#x2013;1728, doi:10.1016/j.amjcard.2016.03.004.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27062939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kubo T, Takahara M, Terada K, Mori K, Arita Y, Ino Y, et al.. 
Retrospective comparison of long-term clinical outcomes between percutaneous coronary intervention and medical therapy in stable coronary artery disease with gray zone fractional flow reserve: COMFORTABLE retrospective study. <i>Circ J</i>
2018; 82: 3044&#x2013;3051, doi:10.1253/circj.CJ-18-0672.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30318503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Stathogiannis K, Fearon WF.. 
Untangling diffuse CAD: Light at the end of the tunnel? <i>Int J Cardiol</i>
2022; 362: 20&#x2013;21, doi:10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.05.042.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35609713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Lawton JS, Tamis-Holland JE, Bangalore S, Bates ER, Beckie TM, Bischoff JM, et al.. 
2021 ACC/AHA/SCAI Guideline for coronary artery revascularization: Executive summary: A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on clinical practice guidelines. <i>Circulation</i>
2022; 145: e4&#x2013;e17, doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001039.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Thuijs DJFM, Kappetein AP, Serruys PW, Mohr FW, Morice MC, Mack MJ, et al.. 
Percutaneous coronary intervention versus coronary artery bypass grafting in patients with three-vessel or left main coronary artery disease: 10-year follow-up of the multicentre randomised controlled SYNTAX trial. <i>Lancet</i>
2019; 394: 1325&#x2013;1334, doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31997-X.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31488373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Endo H, Dohi T, Miyauchi K, Takahashi D, Funamizu T, Shitara J, et al.. 
Clinical impact of complex percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with coronary artery disease.
<i>Cardiovasc Interv Ther</i>
2020; 35: 234&#x2013;241, doi:10.1007/s12928-019-00608-7.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31350706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ortega-Paz L, Brugaletta S, Giacchi G, Ishida K, Cequier A, I&#xf1;iguez A, et al.. 
Impact of stent overlapping on long-term clinical outcomes in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction: Insights from the five-year follow-up of the EXAMINATION trial. <i>EuroIntervention</i>
2017; 13: e557&#x2013;e563, doi:10.4244/EIJ-D-16-00512.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28242584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
R&#xe4;ber L, J&#xfc;ni P, L&#xf6;ffel L, Wandel S, Cook S, Wenaweser P, et al.. 
Impact of stent overlap on angiographic and long-term clinical outcome in patients undergoing drug-eluting stent implantation.
<i>J Am Coll Cardiol</i>
2010; 55: 1178&#x2013;1188, doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2009.11.052.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20298923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hsiao FC, Tsai CT, Hsu LA, Tung YC, Yu FC, Lin CP, et al.. 
Procedural and one-year clinical outcomes of long 48 mm Xience Xpedition everolimus-eluting stent in complex long diffuse coronary artery lesions.
<i>J Invasive Cardiol</i>
2022; 34: E80&#x2013;E86, doi:10.25270/jic/21.00115.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35058374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Pamidimukkala V, Polavarapu AR, Polavarapu NR, Gangasani S, Gali D, Bolinera SV, et al.. 
Impact of ultra-long sirolimus-eluting stents on coronary artery lesions: One-year results of real-world FLEX-LONG Study. <i>Minerva Med</i>
2020; 111: 529&#x2013;535, doi:10.23736/S0026-4806.20.06333-8.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32323934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
&#x15e;ayl&#x131;k F, &#xc7;&#x131;nar T, Sel&#xe7;uk M, &#xc7;i&#xe7;ek V, Hay&#x131;ro&#x11f;lu MI, Orhan AL.. 
Comparison of outcomes between single long stent and overlapping stents: A meta-analysis of the literature. <i>Herz</i>
2023; 48: 376&#x2013;383, doi:10.1007/s00059-022-05152-4.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36629881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Naguib AM, Sobhi MA, Zaki A, El Amrawy AM.. 
Very long versus overlapping drug eluting stents for the management of long coronary artery lesions.
<i>Acta Cardiol</i>
2024; 79: 187&#x2013;193, doi:10.1080/00015385.2023.2289722.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38085257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al.. 
The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. <i>BMJ</i>
2021; 372: n71, doi:10.1136/bmj.n71.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Higgins JPT, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al.. 
The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials.
<i>BMJ</i>
2011; 343: d5928, doi:10.1136/bmj.d5928.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells GA, Shea B, O&#x2019;Connell D, Peterson J, Welch V, Losos M, et al.. The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses. Ottawa: Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2011. Available from: http://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epidemiology/oxford.asp (accessed March 6, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Amirzadegan A, Hasanabadi M, Saadatagah S, Afarideh M, Omidi N, Aghajani H, et al.. 
Single long stents versus overlapping multiple stents in the management of very long coronary lesions: Comparisons of procedures and clinical outcomes. <i>J Tehran Heart Cent</i>
2019; 14: 94&#x2013;102, doi:10.18502/jthc.v14i3.1427.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6981347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31998385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sim HW, Thong EH, Loh PH, Lee CH, Chan MY, Low AF, et al.. 
Treating very long coronary artery lesions in the contemporary drug-eluting-stent era: Single long 48 mm stent versus 2 overlapping stents showed comparable clinical outcomes. <i>Cardiovasc Revasc Med</i>
2020; 21: 1115&#x2013;1118, doi:10.1016/j.carrev.2020.02.005.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32085945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Navarese EP, Tandjung K, Claessen B, Andreotti F, Kowalewski M, Kandzari DE, et al.. 
Safety and efficacy outcomes of first- and second-generation durable polymer drug eluting stents and biodegradable polymer biolimus eluting stents in clinical practice: comprehensive network meta-analysis. <i>BMJ</i>
2013; 347: f6530, doi:10.1136/bmj.f6530.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3819044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24196498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Finn AV, Kolodgie FD, Harnek J, Guerrero LJ, Acampado E, Tefera K, et al.. 
Differential response of delayed healing and persistent inflammation at sites of overlapping sirolimus- or paclitaxel-eluting stents.
<i>Circulation</i>
2005; 112: 270&#x2013;278, doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.104.508937.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15998681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Matsuura T, Ueno M, Watanabe H, Yasuda M, Takase T, Nakamura T, et al.. 
Impact of neointimal condition and platelet reactivity on intrastent thrombus at long-term follow-up after 2nd- and 3rd-generation drug-eluting stent implantation: Insights from a coronary angioscopy and pharmacodynamic study. <i>Circ J</i>
2020; 84: 2244&#x2013;2252, doi:10.1253/circj.CJ-20-0796.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33162462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Muramatsu T, Kozuma K, Tanabe K, Morino Y, Ako J, Nakamura S, et al.. 
Clinical expert consensus document on drug-coated balloon for coronary artery disease from the Japanese Association of Cardiovascular Intervention and Therapeutics.
<i>Cardiovasc Interv Ther</i>
2023; 38: 166&#x2013;176, doi:10.1007/s12928-023-00921-2.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36847902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Nakamura M, Isawa T, Nakamura S, Ando K, Namiki A, Shibata Y, et al.. 
Drug-coated balloon for the treatment of small vessel coronary artery disease: A randomized non-inferiority trial. <i>Circ J</i>
2023; 87: 287&#x2013;295, doi:10.1253/circj.CJ-22-0584.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36450540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sakakura K, Jinnouchi, Taniguchi Y, Yamamoto K, Fujita H.. 
Lifetime management of severely calcified coronary lesions: The treatment algorithm focused on the shape of calcification. <i>Cardiovasc Interv Ther</i>
2023; 38: 375&#x2013;380, doi:10.1007/s12928-023-00950-x.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37542662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Buono A, Di Palma G, Leone AM, Maddestra N, Viola N, Picchi A, et al.. 
Procedural and one-year outcomes following drug-eluting stent and drug-coated balloon combination for the treatment of de novo diffuse coronary artery disease: The HYPER Study. <i>Minerva Cardiol Angiol</i>
2024; 72: 163&#x2013;171, doi:10.23736/S2724-5683.23.06352-4.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37705369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>