<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40834426</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-5049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of cardiovascular nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiovasc Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Impact of Nurse-Led Peer Support Interventions on Psychological Status and Quality of Life After Acute Myocardial Infarction Stent Implantation in China.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JCN.0000000000001247</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patients with acute myocardial infarction (AMI) often experience psychological distress and reduced quality of life after stent implantation. In this study, our aim was to evaluate the effectiveness of a nurse-led peer support intervention on the psychological status and quality of life of patients with AMI post stent implantation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this randomized controlled trial, 200 patients with AMI who underwent stent implantation were randomly assigned to either a nurse-led peer support intervention group (n = 100) or a standard care control group (n = 100). The intervention consisted of weekly 90-minute group sessions facilitated by trained nurses and peer supporters for 12 weeks. Psychological status was assessed using the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale and the Perceived Stress Scale. Quality of life was measured using the Short Form-36 (SF-36) questionnaire. Assessments were conducted at baseline and 12 weeks post intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared with the control group, individuals in the intervention group showed significantly lower anxiety (mean difference, -2.5; 95% confidence interval [CI], -3.2 to -1.8; P &lt; .001) and depression (mean difference, -2.1; 95% CI, -2.8 to -1.4; P &lt; .001) scores at 12 weeks. Perceived stress levels were also significantly reduced in the intervention group (mean difference, -3.7; 95% CI, -4.5 to -2.9; P &lt; .001). Quality of life scores improved significantly across all domains of the Short Form-36 in the intervention group, with the most notable improvements in emotional well-being (mean difference, 10.2; 95% CI, 7.1-13.3; P &lt; .001) and social functioning (mean difference, 9.8; 95% CI, 6.7-12.9; P &lt; .001). Medication adherence and perceived social support also improved significantly in the intervention group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nurse-led peer support interventions significantly improve psychological status and quality of life in patients with AMI after stent implantation. These findings suggest that incorporating such interventions into standard care could enhance postoperative recovery and long-term outcomes for individuals with AMI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Hongmei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Qiong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiovasc Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8703516</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0889-4655</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nurse-led intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peer support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological status</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stent implantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40834426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCN.0000000000001247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005082-990000000-00330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Cardiovascular diseases (CVDs). https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/cardiovascular-diseases-(cvds). Published June 11, 2023. Accessed October 15, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotseva K, De Backer G, De Bacquer D, et al. Lifestyle and impact on cardiovascular risk factor control in coronary patients across 27 countries: results from the European Society of Cardiology ESC-EORP EUROASPIRE V registry. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2019;26(8):824&#x2013;835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaccarino V, Badimon L, Bremner JD, et al. Depression and coronary heart disease: 2018 position paper of the ESC working group on coronary pathophysiology and microcirculation. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(17):1687&#x2013;1696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albus C, Waller C, Fritzsche K, et al. Significance of psychosocial factors in cardiology: update 2018: position paper of the German Cardiac Society. Clin Res Cardiol. 2019;108(11):1175&#x2013;1196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M, Zhu Y, Lv J, et al. Association of anxiety with cardiovascular disease in a Chinese cohort of 0.5 million adults. J Affect Disord. 2022;315:291&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Stillman CM, Ballard RM, et al. Physical activity, cognition, and brain outcomes: a review of the 2018 physical activity guidelines. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(6):1242&#x2013;1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llewellyn-Beardsley J, Rennick-Egglestone S, Bradstreet S, et al. Not the story you want? Assessing the fit of a conceptual framework characterising mental health recovery narratives. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2020;55:295&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X, Li J, Wang B, et al. Diabetes self-management education reduces risk of all-cause mortality in type 2 diabetes patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Endocrine. 2017;55(3):712&#x2013;731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin JW, Skrobik Y, G&#xe9;linas C, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the prevention and management of pain, agitation/sedation, delirium, immobility, and sleep disruption in adult patients in the ICU. Crit Care Med. 2018;46(9):e825&#x2013;e873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hler AK, Tingstr&#xf6;m P, Jaarsma T, Nilsson S. Patient empowerment and general self-efficacy in patients with coronary heart disease: a cross-sectional study. BMC Fam Pract. 2018;19(1):76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashidi A, Kaistha P, Whitehead L, Robinson S. Factors that influence adherence to treatment plans amongst people living with cardiovascular disease: a review of published qualitative research studies. Int J Nurs Stud. 2020;110:103727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santiago de Ara&#xfa;jo Pio C, Chaves GS, Davies P, Taylor RS, Grace SL. Interventions to promote patient utilisation of cardiac rehabilitation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;2(2):CD007131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supervia M, Turk-Adawi K, Lopez-Jimenez F, et al. Nature of cardiac rehabilitation around the globe. EClinicalMedicine. 2019;13:46&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesah E, Turk-Adawi K, Supervia M, et al. Cardiac rehabilitation delivery in low/middle-income countries. Heart. 2019;105(23):1806&#x2013;1812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gary RA, Paul S, Corwin E, et al. Exercise and cognitive training intervention improves self-care, quality of life and functional capacity in persons with heart failure. J Appl Gerontol. 2022;41(2):486&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell MV, Turakhia MP, Harrington RA, King AC, Ashley EA. Mobile health advances in physical activity, fitness, and atrial fibrillation: moving hearts. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;71(23):2691&#x2013;2701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celano CM, Villegas AC, Albanese AM, Gaggin HK, Huffman JC. Depression and anxiety in heart failure: a review. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2018;26(4):175&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chindhy S, Taub PR, Lavie CJ, et al. Current challenges in cardiac rehabilitation: strategies to overcome social factors and attendance barriers. Expert Rev Cardiovasc Ther. 2020;18(11):777&#x2013;789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff N, Sreedhara SK, Wood W, et al. Testing interventions to reduce clinical inertia in the treatment of hypertension: rationale and design of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. Am Heart J. 2024;268:18&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrzykowski &#x141;, Michalski P, Kosobucka A, et al. Medication adherence and its determinants in patients after myocardial infarction. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):12028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia N, Li H. Loneliness, social isolation, and cardiovascular health. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2018;28(9):837&#x2013;851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng SX, Wang W, Shen Q, et al. The effectiveness of preoperative education interventions on improving perioperative outcomes of adult patients undergoing cardiac surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2022;21(6):521&#x2013;536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway-Phillips R, Dagadu H, Motley D, et al. Qualitative evidence for Resilience, Stress, and Ethnicity (RiSE): a program to address race-based stress among Black women at risk for cardiovascular disease. Complement Ther Med. 2020;48:102277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmons-Bell S, Johnson C, Roth G. Prevalence, incidence and survival of heart failure: a systematic review. Heart. 2022;108(17):1351&#x2013;1360.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>