<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40978523</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2399-3529</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2025</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Human reproduction open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hum Reprod Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Levothyroxine supplementation and pregnancy outcomes in women with thyroid disorders: an umbrella review of systematic reviews and meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>hoaf036</StartPage><MedlinePgn>hoaf036</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">hoaf036</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/hropen/hoaf036</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="STUDY QUESTION" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Does levothyroxine (LT4) treatment reduce adverse pregnancy outcomes in pregnant women with thyroid dysfunction?</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY ANSWER" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">LT4 treatment significantly reduces the risks of pregnancy loss, preterm delivery, and gestational hypertension, with no significant impacts on rates of live birth, placental abruption, or gestational diabetes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT IS KNOWN ALREADY" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Multiple meta-analyses have examined the impact of LT4 on pregnancy outcomes, but quantitative confidence assessments are still lacking. Thus, an umbrella review is needed to systematically synthesize and assess the quality of this evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN SIZE DURATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This umbrella review of systematic reviews and meta-analyses used PubMed, Embase, Web of Science, and the Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. Searches included studies published in English or Chinese up to 20 March 2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS/MATERIALS SETTING METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Included studies were systematic reviews or meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials assessing the effects of LT4 on pregnancy outcomes in women with subclinical hypothyroidism (SCH) or thyroid peroxidase antibody (TPOAb) positivity. A set of 24 associations across six pregnancy outcomes were analyzed: pregnancy loss, preterm delivery, live birth, placental abruption, gestational hypertension, and gestational diabetes. Methodological quality was assessed using AMSTAR 1, and evidence quality was graded using GRADE. Sensitivity analyses were conducted to confirm robustness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS AND THE ROLE OF CHANCE" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eleven meta-analyses were included. High-quality evidence showed that LT4 treatment reduced the risks of pregnancy loss (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.43; class III evidence), preterm delivery (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.56; class III evidence), and gestational hypertension (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.63; class IV evidence). Moderate-to-low-quality evidence indicated no significant impact on rates of live birth, placental abruption, or gestational diabetes. Of the 24 associations, 22 were rated as high confidence and two as medium confidence based on AMSTAR 1. Sensitivity analyses confirmed the robustness of the findings, but treatment effects varied according to the study population, treatment timing, and method. For pregnancy loss and preterm delivery outcomes, the risk was significantly reduced only when LT4 treatment was initiated in early pregnancy (pregnancy loss: RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.60, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03; RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.59, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003; preterm labor: RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.58, <i>P&#x2009;</i>&lt;&#x2009;0.0001; RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.46, <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.00001). Additionally, women with TSH levels greater than 4.0&#xa0;mU/l derived greater benefits from LT4 treatment compared to those with TSH levels between 2.5 and 4.0&#xa0;mU/l.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS REASONS FOR CAUTION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Limitations include small sample sizes, potential biases (selection and reporting), and language restrictions to English and Chinese studies, which may affect generalizability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WIDER IMPLICATIONS OF THE FINDINGS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">By integrating high-quality evidence, this study confirms that LT4 can reduce the risk of pregnancy loss and preterm delivery in pregnant women with thyroid dysfunction, supports its clinical application in specific populations, such as SCH patients with positive TPOAb or TSH&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;4.0&#xa0;mU/l, and warns against the risk of overtreatment. The results of this study provide an evidence base for clinical precision intervention. Future studies should address the heterogeneity through standardized large studies, clarify the dose threshold, and evaluate the long-term health effects of LT4 on mothers and infants, to further improve the guidelines and optimize risk stratification management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY FUNDING/COMPETING INTERESTS" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This work was supported by the National Key R&amp;D Program of China (Grant No. 2023YFC2508300, 2023YFC2508303, and 2023YFC2508305), the National Science and Technology Major Project (Grant No. 2024ZD0533403), and the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 82100831, 81570709, and 82470826). All authors declared no competing interests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">CRD42024586105.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of European Society of Human Reproduction and Embryology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism and the Institute of Endocrinology, NHC Key Laboratory of Diagnosis and Treatment of Thyroid Diseases, First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jiashu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5961-7342</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism and the Institute of Endocrinology, NHC Key Laboratory of Diagnosis and Treatment of Thyroid Diseases, First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Shenzhen University Medical School, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Aihua</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Wanyu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine, The First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-8787-0845</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Shengjing Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teng</LastName><ForeName>Weiping</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6445-6192</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism and the Institute of Endocrinology, NHC Key Laboratory of Diagnosis and Treatment of Thyroid Diseases, First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yongze</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8782-3314</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism and the Institute of Endocrinology, NHC Key Laboratory of Diagnosis and Treatment of Thyroid Diseases, First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shan</LastName><ForeName>Zhongyan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2849-2380</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism and the Institute of Endocrinology, NHC Key Laboratory of Diagnosis and Treatment of Thyroid Diseases, First Hospital of China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hum Reprod Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101722764</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2399-3529</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gestational hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">levothyroxine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pregnancy outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subclinical hypothyroidism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyroid autoantibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyroid dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">umbrella review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40978523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12448225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hropen/hoaf036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hoaf036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abalovich M, Amino N, Barbour LA, Cobin RH, Groot LJD, Glinoer D, Mandel SJ, Stagnaro-Green A. &#xa0;Management of thyroid dysfunction during pregnancy and postpartum: an endocrine society clinical practice guideline. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2007;92:s1&#x2013;s47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17948378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alc&#xe1;zar L&#xe1;zaro V, L&#xf3;pez del Val T, Garc&#xed;a Lacalle C, Torres Moreno B, Castillo Carvajal G, Vergara Fern&#xe1;ndez L, Benfdil L, Torre Carrera C, Orizales Lago MC, Ramos Zu&#xf1;iga L. &#xa0;Slightly elevated thyrotropin levels in pregnancy in our clinical practice. Endocrinol Diabetes Nutr (Engl Ed) &#xa0;2019;66:620&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31262691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander EK, Marqusee E, Lawrence J, Jarolim P, Fischer GA, Larsen PR. &#xa0;Timing and magnitude of increases in levothyroxine requirements during pregnancy in women with hypothyroidism. N Engl J Med &#xa0;2004;351:241&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander EK, Pearce EN, Brent GA, Brown RS, Chen H, Dosiou C, Grobman WA, Laurberg P, Lazarus JH, Mandel SJ &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;2017 guidelines of the American Thyroid Association for the diagnosis and management of thyroid disease during pregnancy and the postpartum. Thyroid &#xa0;2017;27:315&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28056690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli A, Wartofsky L, Miccoli P. &#xa0;Editorial: levothyroxine therapy in patients with hypothyroidism. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) &#xa0;2021;12:734895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8329437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34354674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aromataris E, Fernandez R, Godfrey CM, Holly C, Khalil H, Tungpunkom P. &#xa0;Summarizing systematic reviews. Int J Evid Based Healthc &#xa0;2015;13:132&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26360830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai N. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine on the pregnancy out-comes in recurrent abortion patients with thyroid per-oxidase antibody positive. Cap Food Medi &#xa0;2019;26:51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bath SC, Rayman MP. &#xa0;Antenatal thyroid screening and childhood cognitive function. N Engl J Med &#xa0;2012;366:1640&#x2013;1641; author reply 1641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22533585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bein M, Yu OHY, Grandi SM, Frati FYE, Kandil I, Filion KB. &#xa0;Levothyroxine and the risk of adverse pregnancy outcomes in women with subclinical hypothyroidism: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Endocr Disord &#xa0;2021;21:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33639909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey BM, Dashe JS, Wells CE, McIntire DD, Byrd W, Leveno KJ, Cunningham FG. &#xa0;Subclinical hypothyroidism and pregnancy outcomes. Obstet Gynecol &#xa0;2005;105:239&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15684146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey BM, Thom EA, Peaceman AM, Varner MW, Sorokin Y, Hirtz DG, Reddy UM, Wapner RJ, Thorp JM, Saade G &#xa0;et al. ; Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Maternal&#x2013;Fetal Medicine Units Network. Treatment of subclinical hypothyroidism or hypothyroxinemia in pregnancy. N Engl J Med &#xa0;2017;376:815&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28249134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Jiao X-F, Zhang L, Zhang M, Zeng L, Liu D, Li H, Zou K, Wei Q, Zhang L. &#xa0;The impact of levothyroxine therapy on pregnancy and neonatal outcomes in euthyroid pregnant women with thyroid autoimmunity: a systematic review, meta-analysis and trial sequential analysis. Front Pharmacol &#xa0;2023;14:1054935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10018182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36937892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Hu R. &#xa0;Thyroid autoimmunity and miscarriage: a meta-analysis. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) &#xa0;2011;74:513&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21198746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng WL, Liu XR, Zuo Y, Zheng W, Wu SS, Jiang B. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine treatment on pregnancy outcomes in euthyroid women with thyroid autoantibody positive: a meta-analysis. Zhonghua Fu Chan Ke Za Zhi &#xa0;2021;56:58&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33486929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dechartres A, Altman DG, Trinquart L, Boutron I, Ravaud P. &#xa0;Association between analytic strategy and estimates of treatment outcomes in meta-analyses. Jama &#xa0;2014;312:623&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25117131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon-Smith RK, Middleton LJ, Sunner KK, Cheed V, Baker K, Farrell-Carver S, Bender-Atik R, Agrawal R, Bhatia K, Edi-Osagie E &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Levothyroxine in women with thyroid peroxidase antibodies before conception. N Engl J Med &#xa0;2019;380:1316&#x2013;1325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30907987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Girolamo R, Liberati M, Silvi C, D&#x2019;Antonio F. &#xa0;Levothyroxine supplementation in euthyroid pregnant women with positive autoantibodies: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) &#xa0;2022;13:759064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35250850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Z, Liu Y, Maraka S, Abdelouahab N, Huang H-F, Fraser WD, Fan J. &#xa0;Pregnancy and neonatal outcomes with levothyroxine treatment in women with subclinical hypothyroidism based on new diagnostic criteria: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) &#xa0;2021;12:797423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8703220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34956101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J, Zhang Y, Zhang C, Barjaktarovic M, Yang X, Peeters RP, Huang H-F, Korevaar TIM. &#xa0;Persistency of thyroid dysfunction from early to late pregnancy. Thyroid &#xa0;2019;29:1475&#x2013;1484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31347461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gates M, Gates A, Pieper D, Fernandes RM, Tricco AC, Moher D, Brennan SE, Li T, Pollock M, Lunny C &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Reporting guideline for overviews of reviews of healthcare interventions: development of the PRIOR statement. BMJ &#xa0;2022;378:e070849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9361065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35944924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, Kunz R, Vist G, Brozek J, Norris S, Falck-Ytter Y, Glasziou P, DeBeer H &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction&#x2014;GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol &#xa0;2011;64:383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, Kunz R, Falck-Ytter Y, Alonso-Coello P, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ; GRADE Working Group. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ &#xa0;2008;336:924&#x2013;926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. &#xa0;Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ &#xa0;2003;327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Chen Z, Chen B, Li J, Yuan X, Li J, Wang W, Dai T, Chen H, Wang Y &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Dietary sugar consumption and health: umbrella review. BMJ &#xa0;2023;381:e071609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10074550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37019448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA. &#xa0;Integration of evidence from multiple meta-analyses: a primer on umbrella reviews, treatment networks and multiple treatments meta-analyses. CMAJ &#xa0;2009;181:488&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2761440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iravani AT, Saeedi MM, Pakravesh J, Hamidi S, Abbasi M. &#xa0;Thyroid autoimmunity and recurrent spontaneous abortion in Iran: a case-control study. Endocr Pract &#xa0;2008;14:458&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao X-F, Zhang M, Chen J, Wei Q, Zeng L, Liu D, Zhang C, Li H, Zou K, Zhang L &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;The impact of levothyroxine therapy on the pregnancy, neonatal and childhood outcomes of subclinical hypothyroidism during pregnancy: an updated systematic review, meta-analysis and trial sequential analysis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) &#xa0;2022;13:964084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9400061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36034430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahaly GJ, Gottwald-Hostalek U. &#xa0;Use of levothyroxine in the management of hypothyroidism: a historical perspective. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) &#xa0;2022;13:1054983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9666762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36407302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakosta P, Alegakis D, Georgiou V, Roumeliotaki T, Fthenou E, Vassilaki M, Boumpas D, Castanas E, Kogevinas M, Chatzi L. &#xa0;Thyroid dysfunction and autoantibodies in early pregnancy are associated with increased risk of gestational diabetes and adverse birth outcomes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2012;97:4464&#x2013;4472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C-H, Ahn J-W, Kang SP, Kim S-H, Chae H-D, Kang B-M. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine treatment on in vitro fertilization and pregnancy outcome in infertile women with subclinical hypothyroidism undergoing in vitro fertilization/intracytoplasmic sperm injection. Fertil Steril &#xa0;2011;95:1650&#x2013;1654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korevaar TIM, Medici M, Visser TJ, Peeters RP. &#xa0;Thyroid disease in pregnancy: new insights in diagnosis and clinical management. Nat Rev Endocrinol &#xa0;2017;13:610&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28776582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korevaar TIM, Muetzel R, Medici M, Chaker L, Jaddoe VWV, Rijke YB, de Steegers EAP, Visser TJ, White T, Tiemeier H &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Association of maternal thyroid function during early pregnancy with offspring IQ and brain morphology in childhood: a population-based prospective cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol &#xa0;2016;4:35&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26497402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane MM, Gamage E, Du S, Ashtree DN, McGuinness AJ, Gauci S, Baker P, Lawrence M, Rebholz CM, Srour B &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Ultra-processed food exposure and adverse health outcomes: umbrella review of epidemiological meta-analyses. BMJ &#xa0;2024;384:e077310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10899807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau J, Ioannidis JPA, Schmid CH. &#xa0;Quantitative synthesis in systematic reviews. Ann Intern Med &#xa0;1997;127:820&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9382404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau L, Benham JL, Lemieux P, Yamamoto J, Donovan LE. &#xa0;Impact of levothyroxine in women with positive thyroid antibodies on pregnancy outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ Open &#xa0;2021;11:e043751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7907864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33622947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus JH. &#xa0;Thyroid function in pregnancy. Br Med Bull &#xa0;2011;97:137&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21186204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng T, Li X, Zhang H. &#xa0;Levothyroxine treatment for subclinical hypothyroidism improves the rate of live births in pregnant women with recurrent pregnancy loss: a randomized clinical trial. Gynecol Endocrinol &#xa0;2022;38:488&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35426326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Dai J. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine on pregnancy out-comes in patients with TPOAb-positive recurrent spontaneous abortion. Chin J Woman Child Heal Res &#xa0;2018;29:1097&#x2013;1100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Shan Z, Li C, Mao J, Xie X, Wang W, Fan C, Wang H, Zhang H, Han C &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Maternal subclinical hypothyroidism, thyroid autoimmunity, and the risk of miscarriage: a prospective cohort study. Thyroid &#xa0;2014;24:1642&#x2013;1649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maraka S, Ospina NMS, O&#x2019;Keeffe DT, Espinosa De Ycaza AE, Gionfriddo MR, Erwin PJ, Coddington CC, Stan MN, Murad MH, Montori VM. &#xa0;Subclinical hypothyroidism in pregnancy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thyroid &#xa0;2016;26:580&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4827301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26837268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercuri M, Gafni A. &#xa0;The evolution of GRADE (part 3): a framework built on science or faith? &#xa0;J Eval Clin Pract &#xa0;2018;24:1223&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30066429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitrogiannis I, Evangelou E, Efthymiou A, Kanavos T, Birbas E, Makrydimas G, Papatheodorou S. &#xa0;Risk factors for preterm birth: an umbrella review of meta-analyses of observational studies. BMC Med &#xa0;2023;21:494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10720103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38093369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG; PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med &#xa0;2009;6:e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Reyes R, Glinoer D, Oyen H, Van, Vandevijvere S. &#xa0;High prevalence of thyroid disorders in pregnant women in a mildly iodine-deficient country: a population-based study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2013;98:3694&#x2013;3701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23846819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazarpour S, Ramezani Tehrani F, Simbar M, Tohidi M, Alavi Majd H, Azizi F. &#xa0;Effects of levothyroxine treatment on pregnancy outcomes in pregnant women with autoimmune thyroid disease. Eur J Endocrinol &#xa0;2017;176:253&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27879326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazarpour S, Ramezani Tehrani F, Simbar M, Tohidi M, Minooee S, Rahmati M, Azizi F. &#xa0;Effects of levothyroxine on pregnant women with subclinical hypothyroidism, negative for thyroid peroxidase antibodies. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2018;103:926&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro R, Formoso G, Mangieri T, Pezzarossa A, Dazzi D, Hassan H. &#xa0;Levothyroxine treatment in euthyroid pregnant women with autoimmune thyroid disease: effects on obstetrical complications. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2006;91:2587&#x2013;2591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro R, Mangieri T, Coppola L, Presicce G, Casavola EC, Gismondi R, Locorotondo G, Caroli P, Pezzarossa A, Dazzi D &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Levothyroxine treatment in thyroid peroxidase antibody-positive women undergoing assisted reproduction technologies: a prospective study. Hum Reprod &#xa0;2005;20:1529&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15878930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro R, Schwartz A, Stagnaro-Green A. &#xa0;Impact of levothyroxine in miscarriage and preterm delivery rates in first trimester thyroid antibody-positive women with TSH less than 2.5 mIU/L. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2016;101:3685&#x2013;3690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27459527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro R, Stagnaro-Green A. &#xa0;Diagnosis and management of subclinical hypothyroidism in pregnancy. BMJ &#xa0;2014;349:g4929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25288580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuenschwander M, Ballon A, Weber KS, Norat T, Aune D, Schwingshackl L, Schlesinger S. &#xa0;Role of diet in type 2 diabetes incidence: umbrella review of meta-analyses of prospective observational studies. BMJ &#xa0;2019;366:l2368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6607211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31270064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieper D, Antoine S-L, Mathes T, Neugebauer EAM, Eikermann M. &#xa0;Systematic review finds overlapping reviews were not mentioned in every other overview. J Clin Epidemiol &#xa0;2014;67:368&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24581293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pop VJ, Biondi B, Wijnen HA, Kuppens SM, LVader H. &#xa0;Maternal thyroid parameters, body mass index and subsequent weight gain during pregnancy in healthy euthyroid women. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) &#xa0;2013;79:577&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23445086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provinciatto H, Moreira MVB, Neves GR, Freitas LR, De Mitsui HC, Zhang JMF, Araujo J&#xfa;nior E. &#xa0;Levothyroxine for subclinical hypothyroidism during pregnancy: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arch Gynecol Obstet &#xa0;2024;309:2387&#x2013;2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38676741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman AHA, Abbassy HA, Abbassy AAE. &#xa0;Improved in vitro fertilization outcomes after treatment of subclinical hypothyroidism in infertile women. Endocrine Practice &#xa0;2010;16:792&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20350920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao M, Zeng Z, Zhou F, Wang H, Liu J, Wang R, Wen Y, Yang Z, Su C, Su Z &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine supplementation on pregnancy loss and preterm birth in women with subclinical hypothyroidism and thyroid autoimmunity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Reprod Update &#xa0;2019;25:344&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30951172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankoda A, Suzuki H, Imaizumi M, Yoshihara A, Kobayashi S, Katai M, Hamada K, Hidaka Y, Yoshihara A, Nakamura H &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Effects of levothyroxine treatment on fertility and pregnancy outcomes in subclinical hypothyroidism: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Thyroid &#xa0;2024;34:519&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38368537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn SJ. &#xa0;Overstating the evidence&#x2014;double counting in meta-analysis and related problems. BMC Med Res Methodol &#xa0;2009;9:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2653069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19216779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazi MN. &#xa0;Mechanisms of human embryo development: from cell fate to tissue shape and back. Development &#xa0;2020;147:190629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7375473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, Shekelle P, Stewart LA. &#xa0;Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation. BMJ &#xa0;2015;350:g7647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea BJ, Hamel C, Wells GA, Bouter LM, Kristjansson E, Grimshaw J, Henry DA, Boers M. &#xa0;AMSTAR is a reliable and valid measurement tool to assess the methodological quality of systematic reviews. J Clin Epidemiol &#xa0;2009;62:1013&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19230606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan PM, Nankervis A, Araujo J&#xfa;nior E, Silva Costa F, Da. Maternal thyroid disease and preterm birth: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2015;100:4325&#x2013;4331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26383905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara DR, Santos TdS, Carvalho HCd, Lopes LCB, G&#xfc;nther LSA, Aristides SMA, Teixeira JJV, Demarchi IG. &#xa0;Pregnancy complications associated with maternal hypothyroidism: a systematic review. Obstet Gynecol Surv &#xa0;2018;73:219&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29701867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu Z, Fang Q, Ma E. &#xa0;Effects of levothyroxine on pregnancy hormone levels, thyroid function and pregnancy outcome in patients with thyroid peroxidase antibody-negative pregnancy complicated with subclinical hypothyroidism. Eval Anal Drug Use Hosp China &#xa0;2019;19:815&#x2013;817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stagnaro-Green A, Abalovich M, Alexander E, Azizi F, Mestman J, Negro R, Nixon A, Pearce EN, Soldin OP, Sullivan S &#xa0;et al. ; American Thyroid Association Taskforce on Thyroid Disease During Pregnancy and Postpartum. Guidelines of the American Thyroid Association for the diagnosis and management of thyroid disease during pregnancy and postpartum. Thyroid &#xa0;2011;21:1081&#x2013;1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3472679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21787128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stryhn JKG, V&#xe6;ver MS, Hoffmann AL, G&#xe6;de PH. &#xa0;Developmental scores in offspring of women with subclinical hypothyroidism in pregnancy are affected by gender and thyrotropin cutoff. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab &#xa0;2023;36:1079&#x2013;1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37883713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta&#x144;ska K, Gietka-Czernel M, Glinicki P, Kozakowski J. &#xa0;Thyroid autoimmunity and its negative impact on female fertility and maternal pregnancy outcomes. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) &#xa0;2023;13:1049665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9874701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36714589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thangaratinam S, Tan A, Knox E, Kilby MD, Franklyn J, Coomarasamy A. &#xa0;Association between thyroid autoantibodies and miscarriage and preterm birth: meta-analysis of evidence. BMJ &#xa0;2011;342:d2616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3089879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21558126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayakaran R, Adderley NJ, Sainsbury C, Torlinska B, Boelaert K, &#x160;umilo D, Price M, Thomas GN, Toulis KA, Nirantharakumar K. &#xa0;Thyroid replacement therapy, thyroid stimulating hormone concentrations, and long term health outcomes in patients with hypothyroidism: longitudinal study. BMJ &#xa0;2019;366:l4892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6719286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31481394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson W, Russell G, Baragwanath G, Matthews J, Vaidya B, Thompson&#x2010;Coon J. &#xa0;Maternal thyroid hormone insufficiency during pregnancy and risk of neurodevelopmental disorders in offspring: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) &#xa0;2018;88:575&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5888183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29325223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toulis KA, Goulis DG, Venetis CA, Kolibianakis EM, Negro R, Tarlatzis BC, Papadimas I. &#xa0;Risk of spontaneous miscarriage in euthyroid women with thyroid autoimmunity undergoing IVF: a meta-analysis. Eur J Endocrinol &#xa0;2010;162:643&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay U, Vora PA, Patel R, Prajapati B. &#xa0;Levothyroxine sodium&#x2014;thyroid hormone replacement therapy for hypothyroidism: a review of patent literature. Recent Pat Biotechnol &#xa0;2023;17:245&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dijk MM, Vissenberg R, Fliers E, Post J V D, Hoorn M-LPvd, Weerd S D, Kuchenbecker WK, Hoek A, Sikkema JM, Verhoeve HR &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Levothyroxine in euthyroid thyroid peroxidase antibody positive women with recurrent pregnancy loss (T4LIFE trial): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol &#xa0;2022;10:322&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35298917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Gao H, Chi H, Zeng L, Xiao W, Wang Y, Li R, Liu P, Wang C, Tian Q &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine on miscarriage among women with normal thyroid function and thyroid autoimmunity undergoing in vitro fertilization and embryo transfer. Jama &#xa0;2017;318:2190&#x2013;2198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29234808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Xie B, Chen H, Guan H, Li C. &#xa0;Effect of iodine nutrition combined with thyroid hormone replacement therapy for pregnant women with subclinical hypothyroidism and its pregnancy outcomes. Chin J Fam Plan &#xa0;2021;7:020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Chen H. &#xa0;Study on the therapeutic value of levothyroxine tablets for recurrent abortion patients with thyroid peroxidase antibody positive. Our Health &#xa0;2020;6:151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu DY, Jiang HY, Zhang HY, Liu YP. &#xa0;Effect of subclinical hypothyroidism in pregnancy with negative thyroid peroxidase antibody on pregnancy outcome and neonates. Chin Matern Child Health Care &#xa0;2016;31:5344&#x2013;5347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto JM, Metcalfe A, Nerenberg KA, Khurana R, Chin A, Donovan LE. &#xa0;Thyroid function testing and management during and after pregnancy among women without thyroid disease before pregnancy. CMAJ &#xa0;2020;192:E596&#x2013;E602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32575048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Wang R, Zhang W, Yang Y, Wang F. &#xa0;Predicting risk of the subsequent early pregnancy loss in women with recurrent pregnancy loss based on preconception data. BMC Womens Health &#xa0;2024;24:381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11218098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying H, Tang Y-P, Bao Y-R, Su X-J, Cai X, Li Y-H, Wang D-F. &#xa0;Maternal TSH level and TPOAb status in early pregnancy and their relationship to the risk of gestational diabetes mellitus. Endocrine &#xa0;2016;54:742&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M, Long Y, Wang Y, Zhang R, Tao L. &#xa0;Effect of levothyroxine on the pregnancy outcomes in recurrent pregnancy loss women with subclinical hypothyroidism and thyroperoxidase antibody positivity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med &#xa0;2023;36:2233039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JF, Li Y, Cao YM, Liu DL, Ma M, Xu H &#xa0;et al. &#xa0;Effects of levothyroxine sodium on perinatal outcomes in subclinical hypothyroidism patients with negative thyroid peroxidase antibody in early pregnancy. Clin Focus &#xa0;2016;31:293&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Jiang G, Tian X, Zhang X, Zhu T, Chen B, Wang Y, Ma Q. &#xa0;Initiation timing effect of levothyroxine treatment on subclinical hypothyroidism in pregnancy. Gynecol Endocrinol &#xa0;2018;34:845&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29560762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>