<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40704276</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Efficacy and Long-Term Outcomes of Drug-Eluting Stents vs. Bare-Metal Stents in Coronary Artery Disease: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e86617</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e86617</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e86617</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.86617</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronary artery disease (CAD) is a major global cause of morbidity and mortality, driving ongoing improvements in percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI). Drug-eluting stents (DES) have largely replaced bare-metal stents (BMS) due to superior performance in reducing restenosis and the need for repeat revascularization. This systematic review compares the efficacy and long-term safety of DES versus BMS in patients undergoing PCI. A total of 13 studies, including randomized controlled trials and observational studies, were included, covering diverse populations and follow-up periods ranging from 1 to 14 years. Primary outcomes assessed were all-cause mortality, major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE), myocardial infarction (MI), and target lesion revascularization (TLR). DES, particularly second-generation devices, were consistently associated with lower rates of MACE, MI, and TLR compared to BMS. Everolimus-eluting stents (EES) showed the most favorable safety profile regarding stent thrombosis. Secondary outcomes included in-stent restenosis (ISR) and bleeding risks. Notably, the benefits of DES were more pronounced in patients with diabetes and complex coronary anatomy. Some studies suggested gender-based differences favoring DES in women, though subgroup findings were exploratory and not always powered for statistical comparison. A few long-term studies observed a narrowing of the efficacy gap between DES and BMS beyond 10 years, though the clinical relevance of this remains limited. Overall, the findings support the continued use of DES as the preferred option in most PCI settings, with individualized decisions based on lesion complexity, comorbidities, and patient adherence to dual antiplatelet therapy. Continued innovation in stent design and long-term patient monitoring remains essential to optimizing CAD outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Amjad et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amjad</LastName><ForeName>Hina</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nazir Bhatti Memorial Hospital, Abbottabad, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ullah</LastName><ForeName>Asad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Belfast Health and Social Care Trust, Belfast, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shakoor</LastName><ForeName>Mehtab</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine and Surgery, Liaquat National Hospital and Medical College, Karachi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanveer</LastName><ForeName>Faiqa</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine and Surgery, University College of Medicine and Dentistry, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qureshi</LastName><ForeName>Mehak</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, Government Medical College, Srinagar, Srinagar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jahan</LastName><ForeName>Fazeelat</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Shadan Institute of Medical Sciences, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manzoor</LastName><ForeName>Hamna</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Rehman Medical Institute, Peshawar, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoud</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, El-Salam Specialized Hospital, Cairo, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masharifa Ahamed</LastName><ForeName>Fathima</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ras Al Khaimah Medical and Health Sciences University, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halder</LastName><ForeName>Anik</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Dhaka Medical College Hospital, Dhaka, BGD.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dilawar</LastName><ForeName>Rimsha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Fauji Foundation Hospital, Rawalpindi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anthony</LastName><ForeName>Nouman</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Rehman Medical Institue, Peshawar, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bare-metal stents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug-eluting stents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual antiplatelet therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">major adverse cardiovascular events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">restenosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stent thrombosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">target lesion revascularization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40704276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12286641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.86617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risk Factors, 1990-2019: update from the GBD 2019 study. Roth GA, Mensah GA, Johnson CO, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:2982&#x2013;3021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33309175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Gerhardt TE, Kwon E. StatPearls . Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Risk factors for coronary artery disease.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of percutaneous coronary intervention on death and myocardial infarction stratified by stable and unstable coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Chacko L, P Howard J, Rajkumar C, et al. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2020;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7034389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32063040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restenosis of drug-eluting stents: a new classification system based on disease mechanism to guide treatment and state-of-the-art review. Shlofmitz E, Iantorno M, Waksman R. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2019;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31345066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bare metal stents versus drug-eluting stents: where do we stand in 2015? Meraj PM, Jauhar R, Singh A. Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med. 2015;17:393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26154294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-eluting coronary-artery stents. Stefanini GG, Holmes DR Jr. N Engl J Med. 2013;368:254&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23323902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleeding risk, dual antiplatelet therapy cessation, and adverse events after percutaneous coronary intervention: the Paris Registry. Sorrentino S, Sartori S, Baber U, et al. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2020;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32216472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronary in-stent restenosis: JACC state-of-the-art review. Giustino G, Colombo A, Camaj A, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;80:348&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35863852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short- and long-term outcomes with drug-eluting and bare-metal coronary stents: a mixed-treatment comparison analysis of 117 762 patient-years of follow-up from randomized trials. Bangalore S, Kumar S, Fusaro M, et al. Circulation. 2012;125:2873&#x2013;2891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22586281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of drug-eluting stents in the real world: 8-year follow-up. Pellegrini DO, Gomes VO, Lasevitch R, et al. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2014;103:174&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4193064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25098375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration. Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, et al. J Clin Epidemiol. 2009;62:0&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions: Cochrane Book Series. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd; 2008. Assessing risk of bias in included studies; pp. 187&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Stang A. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25:603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20652370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-eluting stents versus bare metal stents in percutaneous coronary interventions (a meta-analysis) Indolfi C, Pavia M, Angelillo IF. Am J Cardiol. 2005;95:1146&#x2013;1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15877984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Updating guidance for reporting systematic reviews: development of the PRISMA 2020 statement. Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;134:103&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-eluting stents versus bare-metal stents in large coronary artery revascularization: systematic review and meta-analysis. Changal KH, Mir T, Khan S, et al. Cardiovasc Revasc Med. 2021;23:42&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-eluting or bare-metal stents for percutaneous coronary intervention: a systematic review and individual patient data meta-analysis of randomised clinical trials. Piccolo R, Bonaa KH, Efthimiou O, et al. Lancet. 2019;393:2503&#x2013;2510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31056295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-eluting stents in large coronary vessels improve both safety and efficacy compared with bare-metal stents in women: a pooled analysis of the BASKET-PROVE I and II trials. Bjerking LH, Hansen KW, S&#xf8;rensen R, et al. Open Heart. 2019;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6546185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31217999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Two-year outcomes after percutaneous coronary intervention with drug-eluting stents or bare-metal stents in elderly patients with coronary artery disease. Lafont A, Sinnaeve PR, Cuisset T, et al. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2021;97:0&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>10-year outcomes from a randomized trial of polymer-free versus durable polymer drug-eluting coronary stents. Kufner S, Ernst M, Cassese S, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:146&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term results after drug-eluting versus bare-metal stent implantation in saphenous vein grafts: randomized controlled trial. Fahrni G, Farah A, Engstr&#xf8;m T, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33032485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>One-year clinical outcomes of drug-eluting stents versus bare-metal stents in large coronary arteries. Singhal R, Prajapati J, Patel I, Patel C, Sahoo S. J Clin Prev Cardiol. 2020;9:56&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug-eluting or bare-metal stents for left anterior descending or left main coronary artery revascularization. Piccolo R, Bonaa KH, Efthimiou O, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8751874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34622669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natural history of coronary stents: 14 year follow-up of drug eluting stents versus bare metal stents. Walse RS, Mohanan Nair KK, Valaparambil A, Sasidharan B, Sivadasapillai H, Thulaseedharan JV. Indian Heart J. 2023;75:457&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10774566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37926420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical outcomes of drug-eluting versus bare-metal in-stent restenosis after the treatment of drug-eluting stent or drug-eluting balloon: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Yang YX, Liu Y, Li CP, Lu PJ, Wang J, Gao J. J Interv Cardiol. 2020;2020:8179849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7336236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32684867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of drug eluting stents vs bare metal stents in patients with atrial fibrillation: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sambola A, Rello P, Soriano T, et al. Thromb Res. 2020;195:128&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32688097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison between bare-metal stents and drug-eluting stents in patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention. Elsayed KR. Int J Med Arts. 2020;2:786&#x2013;792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Very long-term safety and effectiveness of drug-eluting or bare-metal stents for left main coronary disease. Park H, Ahn JM, Kang DY, et al. CJC Open. 2021;3:1199&#x2013;1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8636232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term effect of ultrathin-strut versus thin-strut drug-eluting stents in patients with small vessel coronary artery disease undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention: a subgroup analysis of the BIOSCIENCE randomized trial. Iglesias JF, Heg D, Roffi M, et al. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2019;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31525083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individualized or uniform de-escalation strategies for antiplatelet therapy in acute coronary syndrome: a review of clinical trials with platelet function testing and genetic testing-based protocols. El Abdallaoui OE, Tornyos D, Luk&#xe1;cs R, Szab&#xf3; D, Kom&#xf3;csi A. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:9071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10219318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37240417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrathin bioresorbable polymer sirolimus-eluting stents versus thin durable polymer everolimus-eluting stents. Kandzari DE, Koolen JJ, Doros G, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:3287&#x2013;3297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30257191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten-year clinical outcomes from a trial of three limus-eluting stents with different polymer coatings in patients with coronary artery disease. Kufner S, Joner M, Thannheimer A, et al. Circulation. 2019;139:325&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suboptimal stent deployment is associated with subacute stent thrombosis: optical coherence tomography insights from a multicenter matched study. From the CLI Foundation investigators: the CLI-THRO study. Prati F, Kodama T, Romagnoli E, et al. Am Heart J. 2015;169:249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25641534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence, predictors, and outcomes of DAPT non-compliance in planned vs. ad hoc PCI in chronic coronary syndrome. Malik J, Yousaf H, Abbasi W, Hameed N, Mohsin M, Shahid AW, Fatima M. PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8284673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34270595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nine-year clinical outcomes of drug-eluting stents vs. bare metal stents for large coronary vessel lesions. Yin D, Li J, Yang YJ, et al. J Geriatr Cardiol. 2017;14:35&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5329731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28270840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gender differences in cardiovascular disease: hormonal and biochemical influences. P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez FR, Larrad-Mur L, Kallen A, Chedraui P, Taylor HS. Reprod Sci. 2010;17:511&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20460551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>