<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40948670</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-9358</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of diabetes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Diabetes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Digital health for rural diabetes care: Implementation experience from China and India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107733</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107733</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">107733</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4239/wjd.v16.i8.107733</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetes affects an estimated 828 million people globally, with approximately 44% living in China and India. Rural residents with diabetes in these countries face significant challenges in access to care. Although digital health interventions are increasingly used to reach underserved populations, considerable knowledge gaps exist. This mini-review presents the first comparative analysis of digital health implementations for diabetes care in rural China and India, comprising clinical decision support tools, telemedicine, and mobile health applications. The review examines how their distinct health system structures influence technology adoption and clinical outcomes. China's hierarchical administrative structure facilitates standardized nationwide platforms with consistent protocols, while India's federal system enables diverse localized innovations that accommodate regional diversity. Cluster-randomized trials for digital health tools in rural China show significant improvements in glycemic control. In India, interventions examined in this review were associated with improved health behaviors and medication adherence. Both countries demonstrate that digital interventions leveraging existing social structures and co-created with stakeholders yield better outcomes than standard care approaches. This analysis provides actionable insights for policymakers globally while identifying valuable opportunities for knowledge exchange between these two nations that together are home to nearly half of all people living with diabetes worldwide.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasooly</LastName><ForeName>Alon</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Policy and Systems Management, School of Public Health, Ben-Gurion University, Beersheba 8410501, Israel. rasooly@post.bgu.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beran</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Tropical and Humanitarian Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Geneva and Geneva University Hospitals, Geneva CH-1211, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Peng-Peng</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Chronic and Noncommunicable Disease Control and Prevention, Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing 100050, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joshi</LastName><ForeName>Surabhi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Noncommunicable Diseases, Disability and Rehabilitation, The World Health Organization, Geneva 1211, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Xue-Jun</ForeName><Initials>XJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Jiangxi Medical College, Nanchang University, Nanchang 330006, Jiangxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory of Disease Prevention and Public Health, Nanchang University, Nanchang 330006, Jiangxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tandon</LastName><ForeName>Nikhil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi 110029, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Rui-Tai</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Population Medicine and Public Health, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Diabetes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101547524</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-9358</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">China</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-creation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">India</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rural healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Task-sharing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest related to this publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40948670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12432586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v16.i8.107733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>NCD Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC) Worldwide trends in diabetes prevalence and treatment from 1990 to 2022: a pooled analysis of 1108 population-representative studies with 141 million participants. Lancet. 2024;404:2077&#x2013;2093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7616842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39549716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Diabetes Federation. Diabetes Atlas. 11th ed. Brussels, Belgium: International Diabetes Federation, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flood D, Seiglie JA, Dunn M, Tschida S, Theilmann M, Marcus ME, Brian G, Norov B, Mayige MT, Singh Gurung M, Aryal KK, Labadarios D, Dorobantu M, Silver BK, Bovet P, Adelin Jorgensen JM, Guwatudde D, Houehanou C, Andall-Brereton G, Quesnel-Crooks S, Sturua L, Farzadfar F, Saeedi Moghaddam S, Atun R, Vollmer S, B&#xe4;rnighausen TW, Davies JI, Wexler DJ, Geldsetzer P, Rohloff P, Ram&#xed;rez-Zea M, Heisler M, Manne-Goehler J. The state of diabetes treatment coverage in 55 low-income and middle-income countries: a cross-sectional study of nationally representative, individual-level data in 680 102 adults. Lancet Healthy Longev. 2021;2:e340&#x2013;e351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8865379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35211689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranasinghe P, Jayawardena R, Gamage N, Sivanandam N, Misra A. Prevalence and trends of the diabetes epidemic in urban and rural India: A pooled systematic review and meta-analysis of 1.7 million adults. Ann Epidemiol. 2021;58:128&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33727086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su B, Wang Y, Dong Y, Hu G, Xu Y, Peng X, Wang Q, Zheng X. Trends in Diabetes Mortality in Urban and Rural China, 1987-2019: A Joinpoint Regression Analysis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:777654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8801697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35111135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global strategy on digital health 2020-2025. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maita KC, Maniaci MJ, Haider CR, Avila FR, Torres-Guzman RA, Borna S, Lunde JJ, Coffey JD, Demaerschalk BM, Forte AJ. The Impact of Digital Health Solutions on Bridging the Health Care Gap in Rural Areas: A Scoping Review. Perm J. 2024;28:130&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11404635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39135461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia W, Zhang P, Zhu D, Duolikun N, Li H, Bao Y, Li X ROADMAP Study Group. Evaluation of an mHealth-enabled hierarchical diabetes management intervention in primary care in China (ROADMAP): A cluster randomized trial. PLoS Med. 2021;18:e1003754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8454951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34547030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian M, Ajay VS, Dunzhu D, Hameed SS, Li X, Liu Z, Li C, Chen H, Cho K, Li R, Zhao X, Jindal D, Rawal I, Ali MK, Peterson ED, Ji J, Amarchand R, Krishnan A, Tandon N, Xu LQ, Wu Y, Prabhakaran D, Yan LL. A Cluster-Randomized, Controlled Trial of a Simplified Multifaceted Management Program for Individuals at High Cardiovascular Risk (SimCard Trial) in Rural Tibet, China, and Haryana, India. Circulation. 2015;132:815&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4558306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26187183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfammatter A, Spring B, Saligram N, Dav&#xe9; R, Gowda A, Blais L, Arora M, Ranjani H, Ganda O, Hedeker D, Reddy S, Ramalingam S. mHealth Intervention to Improve Diabetes Risk Behaviors in India: A Prospective, Parallel Group Cohort Study. J Med Internet Res. 2016;18:e207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4992169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27496271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinman NJ, Shah A, Shah S, Phatak S, Viswanathan V. Improved Medication Adherence and Frequency of Blood Glucose Self-Testing Using an m-Health Platform Versus Usual Care in a Multisite Randomized Clinical Trial Among People with Type 2 Diabetes in India. Telemed J E Health. 2017;23:733&#x2013;740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28328396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Tao X, Ma Y, Zhang Y, Ma X, Song H, Liu Y, Patel A, Jan S, Peiris D. Improving the management of type 2 diabetes in China using a multifaceted digital health intervention in primary health care: the SMARTDiabetes cluster randomised controlled trial. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2024;49:101130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11269311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39056088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabor&#xe9; SS, Ngangue P, Soubeiga D, Barro A, Pilabr&#xe9; AH, Bationo N, Pafadnam Y, Drabo KM, Hien H, Savadogo GBL. Barriers and facilitators for the sustainability of digital health interventions in low and middle-income countries: A systematic review. Front Digit Health. 2022;4:1014375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9742266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36518563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Olmen J, Erwin E, Garc&#xed;a-Ulloa AC, Meessen B, Miranda JJ, Bobrow K, Iwelunmore J, Nwaozuru U, Obiezu Umeh C, Smith C, Harding C, Kumar P, Gonzales C, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez S, Yeates K. Implementation barriers for mHealth for non-communicable diseases management in low and middle income countries: a scoping review and field-based views from implementers. Wellcome Open Res. 2020;5:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32399497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au A. Digitalization in China: who&#x2019;s left behind? Infor Commun Soc. 2024;27:1247&#x2013;1265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Zhang G, Jiao Y, Wang Y, Wang P. "Digital Dividend" or "Digital Divide": What Role Does the Internet Play in the Health Inequalities among Chinese Residents? Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:15162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9690004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36429878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Observer Research Foundation.  Exploring India's Digital Divide. 2022. [cited 6 May 2025]. Available from: https://www.orfonline.org/expert-speak/exploring-indias-digital-divide .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, Dong J, Pan W, Yu Y. Associations between digital literacy, health literacy, and digital health behaviors among rural residents: evidence from Zhejiang, China. Int J Equity Health. 2024;23:68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11003150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38594723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q, Yang H, Chen W, Sun Q, Liu X. People's Republic of China health system review. In: Mills A, Tangcharoensathien V, editors. Health Systems in Transition. Manila, Philippines: World Health Organization, Regional Office for the Western Pacific, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakthivel S, Karan A, Srivastava S, Bhan N, Mukhopadhyay I. India health system review. Mahal AS, editor. New Delhi: World Health Organization, Regional Office for South-East Asia on behalf of the Asia Pacific Observatory on Health Systems and Policies, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Lu J, Hu S, Cheng KK, De Maeseneer J, Meng Q, Mossialos E, Xu DR, Yip W, Zhang H, Krumholz HM, Jiang L, Hu S. The primary health-care system in China. Lancet. 2017;390:2584&#x2013;2594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29231837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakovljevic M, Chang H, Pan J, Guo C, Hui J, Hu H, Grujic D, Li Z, Shi L. Successes and challenges of China's health care reform: a four-decade perspective spanning 1985-2023. Cost Eff Resour Alloc. 2023;21:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10469830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37649062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin J, Lin C, Zhang Y, Zhang L. The status and challenges of primary health care in China. Chin Gen Pract J. 2024;1:182&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapoor S. Digital Health Ecosystem in India. D Y Patil J Health Sci. 2022;10:202&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>India's Ministry of Health and Family Welfare.  Update on Prevention and control of Non-Communicable Diseases (NCDs). 2023. [cited 26 March 2025]. Available from: https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleaseIframePage.aspx?PRID=1945739 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raina SK, Babu BV, Basappa YC, Hazarika CR, Jebasingh FK, Masoodi SR, Thomas N, Kerketta AS, Menon NK. Development of Protocol for the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) task force study to strengthen the implementation of National Programme for Prevention and Control of Non-Communicable Diseases (NP-NCD) in tribal population. J Family Med Prim Care. 2024;13:4083&#x2013;4089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11504817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39464930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang F, Yang X, Peng W, Zhen S, Cao W, Li Q, Xiao Z, Gong M, Wang Y, Gu D. Applications of digital health approaches for cardiometabolic diseases prevention and management in the Western Pacific region. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2024;43:100817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10920052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38456090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakaran D, Jha D, Ajay VS, Roy A, Perel P. Response by Prabhakaran et al to Letter Regarding Article, "Effectiveness of an mHealth-Based Electronic Decision Support System for Integrated Management of Chronic Conditions in Primary Care: The mWellcare Cluster-Randomized Controlled Trial". Circulation. 2019;139:e1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31180750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahul A, Chintha S, Anish TS, Prajitha KC, Indu PS. Effectiveness of a Non-pharmacological Intervention to Control Diabetes Mellitus in a Primary Care Setting in Kerala: A Cluster-Randomized Controlled Trial. Front Public Health. 2021;9:747065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8636158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34869163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan V, Deepa M, Pradeepa R, Prathiba V, Datta M, Sethuraman R, Rakesh H, Sucharita Y, Webster P, Allender S, Kapur A, Anjana RM. Prevention of diabetes in rural India with a telemedicine intervention. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2012;6:1355&#x2013;1364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3570875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan V, Prathiba V, Pradeepa R. Tele-diabetology to Screen for Diabetes and Associated Complications in Rural India: The Chunampet Rural Diabetes Prevention Project Model. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2014;8:256&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24876575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jindal D, Sharma H, Gupta Y, Ajay VS, Roy A, Sharma R, Ali M, Jarhyan P, Gupta P, Srinivasapura Venkateshmurthy N, Ali MK, Narayan KMV, Prabhakaran D, Weber MB, Mohan S, Patel SA, Tandon N. Improving care for hypertension and diabetes in india by addition of clinical decision support system and task shifting in the national NCD program: I-TREC model of care. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22:688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin X, Wang Z, Yang J, Li J, Han S, Feng W, Liu Q, Li N, Zhang L, Ke J, Wei X, Zhang J, Sarrafzadegan N, Shao R. Improvement of Care Cascade for Hypertension and Diabetes in Rural China: Protocol for an Implementation Study. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2024;26:1466&#x2013;1478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11654860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39494843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong S, Lu H, Peoples N, Duman EK, Najarro A, Ni Z, Gong E, Yin R, Ostbye T, Palileo-Villanueva LM, Doma R, Kafle S, Tian M, Yan LL. Digital health interventions for non-communicable disease management in primary health care in low-and middle-income countries. NPJ Digit Med. 2023;6:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9889958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36725977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moschonis G, Siopis G, Jung J, Eweka E, Willems R, Kwasnicka D, Asare BY, Kodithuwakku V, Verhaeghe N, Vedanthan R, Annemans L, Oldenburg B, Manios Y DigiCare4You Consortium. Effectiveness, reach, uptake, and feasibility of digital health interventions for adults with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Lancet Digit Health. 2023;5:e125&#x2013;e143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  First-ever global coverage targets for diabetes adopted at the 75th World Health Assembly. May 28, 2022. [cited 16 June 2025]. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/first-ever-global-coverage-targets-for-diabetes-adopted-at-the-75-th-world-health-assembly .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thankappan KR, Sathish T, Tapp RJ, Shaw JE, Lotfaliany M, Wolfe R, Absetz P, Mathews E, Aziz Z, Williams ED, Fisher EB, Zimmet PZ, Mahal A, Balachandran S, D'Esposito F, Sajeev P, Thomas E, Oldenburg B. A peer-support lifestyle intervention for preventing type 2 diabetes in India: A cluster-randomized controlled trial of the Kerala Diabetes Prevention Program. PLoS Med. 2018;15:e1002575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5991386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29874236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjekum A, Blasimme A, Vayena E. Elements of Trust in Digital Health Systems: Scoping Review. J Med Internet Res. 2018;20:e11254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd R, Palagyi A, Jan S, Abdel-All M, Nambiar D, Madhira P, Balane C, Tian M, Joshi R, Abimbola S, Peiris D. Organisation of primary health care systems in low- and middle-income countries: review of evidence on what works and why in the Asia-Pacific region. BMJ Glob Health. 2019;4:e001487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6703302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31478026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong S, Jiang W, Wang Y, Wang G, Zhang X, Hu C, Bao M, Li F, Yang J, Hou H, Peng N, Wang Q, Jiang R, Liu T, Wang J, Ma Y, Ye P, Mao L, Peiris D, Tian M. Co-designing interventions to strengthen the primary health care system for the management of hypertension and type 2 diabetes in China. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2024;49:101131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11269299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39056090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G, Gong M, Wu Y, Liu L, Shi B, Zeng Z. Advancing digital health in China: Aligning challenges, opportunities, and solutions with the Global Initiative on Digital Health (GIDH) Health Care Sci. 2024;3:365&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11520242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39479272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Initiative on Digital Health. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>State Council of the People's Republic of China.  [Outline of the 14th Five-Year Plan for National Economic and Social Development of the People's Republic of China and the Long-Term Objectives for 2035]. March 13, 2021. [cited 17 Jun 2025]. Available from: https://www.gov.cn/xinwen/2021-03/13/content_5592681.htm .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  Global Health Observatory. [cited 12 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://www.who.int/data/gho .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank Group.  World Development Indicators. [cited 8 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://databank.worldbank.org/source/world-development-indicators .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statista  India: number of internet users by region 2023. [cited 12 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://www.statista.com/statistics/751060/number-of-internet-users-by-region-india/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statista  China: official internet penetration rate 2005-2024. [cited 12 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://www.statista.com/statistics/236963/penetration-rate-of-internet-users-in-china/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>China's Office of the Central Cyberspace Affairs Commission.  [Key Points for Digital Rural Development in 2024]. [cited 12 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://www.cac.gov.cn/2024-05/15/c_1717449026412502.htm .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank.  South Asia&#x2019;s Digital Economy: An Opportunity to Build Back Better, Digitally (English). Washington, D.C.: World Bank Group. April 5, 2022. [cited 12 Mar 2025]. Available from http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/099230004062228270 .</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>