<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40783721</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2261</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cardiovascular disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Therapeutic inertia in statin therapy for secondary prevention after percutaneous coronary intervention: a nationwide population-based cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>595</StartPage><MedlinePgn>595</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">595</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12872-025-05081-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Therapeutic inertia is defined as the failure to provide guideline-directed therapy and is a barrier to achieving optimal clinical outcomes. We aimed to evaluate therapeutic inertia in statin therapy after percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) and its association with patient characteristics and physician&#x2019;s prescribing practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We analyzed the medical claims data on patients undergoing PCI using National Health Insurance Service in Republic of Korea. The primary outcome of interest was therapeutic inertia, defined as not providing high-intensity statin (HIS) therapy within 30 days after discharge for PCI. To identify statin use in identical clinical setting, we restricted study duration to between 2013 American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association cholesterol guideline and publications of RACING (Randomized Comparison of Efficacy and Safety of Lipid-lowering with Statin Monotherapy Versus Statin&#x2013;ezetimibe Combination for High-risk Cardiovascular Disease) and LODESTAR (Low-Density Lipoprotein Cholesterol-Targeting Statin Therapy Versus Intensity-Based Statin Therapy in Patients With Coronary Artery Disease) trials that demonstrated non-inferiority of alternative statin strategies compared with HIS therapy in atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. We also assessed patient characteristics affecting HIS prescription, statin switching before and after PCI among previous statin users, and impact of previous statin regimen on prescribing of HIS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of 204,708 participants (mean age 66.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.3 years, 30.8% female, 56.6% previous statin users, 43.4% previous statin nonusers), therapeutic inertia was identified in 64.1%, and HIS prescription rate was higher in previous statin nonusers (42.0%) than in previous statin users (31.1%). There were few differences in patient characteristics as positive (male and acute coronary syndrome as indication for PCI) and negative (increase of age, comorbidities, and cardiovascular medications) predictors of HIS prescription between previous statin users and nonusers. Because 79.1% of previous HIS users and 23.8% of previous non-HIS users received HIS following PCI, previous HIS users were more likely to be prescribed HIS as compared to previous statin nonusers (odds ratio, 5.42; 95% confidence intervals, 4.44&#x2013;6.61) and previous non-HIS users (odds ratio, 12.30; 95% confidence intervals, 9.95&#x2013;15.19).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Suboptimal HIS prescription following PCI was substantially affected by patient characteristics and the practice of repetitive prescribing of previous statin without guideline-directed titration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12872-025-05081-0.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Young-Hoon</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Cardio-Cerebrovascular Center, Konyang University Hospital, 158, Gwanjeodong-Ro, Seo-Gu, Daejeon, 35365, Republic of Korea. sdurzel@hanmail.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Jee-Young</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research Institute, Konyang University Medical Center, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Yong-Kyun</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Cardio-Cerebrovascular Center, Konyang University Hospital, 158, Gwanjeodong-Ro, Seo-Gu, Daejeon, 35365, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ki-Hong</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Cardio-Cerebrovascular Center, Konyang University Hospital, 158, Gwanjeodong-Ro, Seo-Gu, Daejeon, 35365, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Taek-Geun</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Chungbuk National University Hospital, Cheongju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bae</LastName><ForeName>Jang-Ho</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Cardio-Cerebrovascular Center, Konyang University Hospital, 158, Gwanjeodong-Ro, Seo-Gu, Daejeon, 35365, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968539</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2261</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Secondary prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Statin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapeutic inertia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board of Konyang University Hospital (2020-04-013) and requirement for written informed consents was waived because this study used anonymized and deidentified data. The study followed the STROBE (Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology) reporting guideline and was performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40783721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12335056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-025-05081-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12872-025-05081-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Grundy SM, Stone NJ, Bailey AL, Beam C, Birtcher KK, Blumenthal RS, et al. AHA/ACC/AACVPR/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/ADA/AGS/APhA/ASPC/NLA/PCNA Guideline on the Management of Blood Cholesterol: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2019;139(25):e1082&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7403606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mach F, Baigent C, Catapano AL, Koskinas KC, Casula M, Badimon L, et al. 2019 ESC/EAS guidelines for the management of dyslipidaemias: lipid modification to reduce cardiovascular risk. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(1):111&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee EJ, Kim HC, Kim JH, Lee EY, Kim BJ, Kim EM, et al. 2018 guidelines for the management of dyslipidemia in Korea. Korean J Intern Med. 2019;34(5):1171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6718745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31466435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone NJ, Robinson JG, Lichtenstein AH, Bairey Merz CN, Blum CB, Eckel RH, et al. 2013 ACC/AHA guideline on the treatment of blood cholesterol to reduce atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk in adults: a report of the American college of cardiology/american heart association task force on practice guidelines. Circulation. 2014;129(25 Suppl 2):S1&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24222016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez F, Lin S, Maron DJ, Knowles JW, Virani SS, Heidenreich PA. Use of high-intensity Statins for patients with atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in the veterans affairs health system: practice impact of the new cholesterol guidelines. Am Heart J. 2016;182:97&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27914506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez F, Maron DJ, Knowles JW, Virani SS, Lin S, Heidenreich PA. Association between intensity of statin therapy and mortality in patients with atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. JAMA Cardiol. 2017;2(1):47&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27829091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien EC, Wu J, Schulte PJ, Christian A, Laskey W, Bhatt DL, et al. Statin use, intensity, and 3-year clinical outcomes among older patients with coronary artery disease. Am Heart J. 2016;173:27&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenson RS, Farkouh ME, Mefford M, Bittner V, Brown TM, Taylor B, et al. Trends in use of High-Intensity Statin therapy after myocardial infarction, 2011 to 2014. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;69(22):2696&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28571633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray KK, Molemans B, Schoonen WM, Giovas P, Bray S, Kiru G, et al. EU-Wide Cross-Sectional observational study of Lipid-Modifying therapy use in secondary and primary care: the DA VINCI study. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2021;28(11):1279&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33580789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin Abdulhak AA, Vaughan-Sarrzin M, Kaboli P, Horwitz PA, Mosher H, Sigurdsson G, et al. Temporal Trends of High-Intensity Statin Therapy Among Veterans Treated With Percutaneous Coronary Intervention. J Am Heart Assoc. 2018;7(5)::e007370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29503265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AJ, Haynes K, Shambhu S, Eapen Z, Cziraky MJ, Nanna MG, et al. High-Intensity Statin use among patients with atherosclerosis in the U.S. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(18):1802&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9344279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35512860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedeney P, Claessen BE, Baber U, Camaj A, Sorrentino S, Aquino M, et al. Temporal trends in Statin prescriptions and residual cholesterol risk in patients with stable coronary artery disease undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention. Am J Cardiol. 2019;123(11):1788&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musich S, Wang SS, Schwebke K, Slindee L, Waters E, Yeh CS. Underutilization of statin therapy for secondary prevention of cardiovascular disease among older adults. Popul Health Manag. 2019;22(1):74&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6386076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29893617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroes ES, Thompson PD, Corsini A, Vladutiu GD, Raal FJ, Ray KK, et al. Statin-associated muscle symptoms: impact on Statin therapy-European atherosclerosis society consensus panel statement on assessment, aetiology and management. Eur Heart J. 2015;36(17):1012&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4416140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byty&#xe7;i I, Penson PE, Mikhailidis DP, Wong ND, Hernandez AV, Sahebkar A, et al. Prevalence of Statin intolerance: a meta-analysis. Eur Heart J. 2022;43(34):3213&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9757867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35169843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colantonio LD, Huang L, Monda KL, Bittner V, Serban MC, Taylor B, et al. Adherence to high-intensity statins following a myocardial infarction hospitalization among medicare beneficiaries. JAMA Cardiol. 2017;2(8):890&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5815081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28423147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serban MC, Colantonio LD, Manthripragada AD, Monda KL, Bittner VA, Banach M, et al. Statin intolerance and risk of coronary heart events and All-Cause mortality following myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;69(11):1386&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28302290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed ST, Akeroyd JM, Mahtta D, Street R, Slagle J, Navar AM, et al. Shared decisions: A qualitative study on clinician and patient perspectives on Statin therapy and Statin-Associated side effects. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9(22):e017915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33170055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon DL, Sharma G, Sandesara PB, Yang E, Braun LT, Mensah GA, et al. Therapeutic inertia in cardiovascular disease prevention: time to move the bar. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;74(13):1728&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31558257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dormuth CR, Filion KB, Paterson JM, James MT, Teare GF, Raymond CB, et al. Higher potency statins and the risk of new diabetes: multicentre, observational study of administrative databases. BMJ. 2014;348:g3244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4038449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24874977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virani SS, Akeroyd JM, Ahmed ST, Krittanawong C, Martin LA, Slagle J, et al. The use of structured data elements to identify ASCVD patients with statin-associated side effects: insights from the department of veterans affairs. J Clin Lipidol. 2019;13(5):797&#x2013;e803791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8393880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31501043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Gomes MB, Pocock S, Shestakova MV, Pintat S, Fenici P, et al. Therapeutic inertia in the treatment of hyperglycaemia in patients with type 2 diabetes: A systematic review. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2018;20(2):427&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5813232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell RE, Zaccardi F, Beebe C, Chen XM, Crawford A, Cuddeback J, et al. Strategies for overcoming therapeutic inertia in type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2021;23(9):2137&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow CK, Gupta R. Blood pressure control: a challenge to global health systems. Lancet. 2019;394(10199):613&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi EK. Cardiovascular research using the Korean National health information database. Korean Circ J. 2020;50(9):754&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BK, Hong SJ, Lee YJ, Hong SJ, Yun KH, Hong BK, et al. Long-term efficacy and safety of moderate-intensity Statin with Ezetimibe combination therapy versus high-intensity Statin monotherapy in patients with atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease (RACING): a randomised, open-label, non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2022;400(10349):380&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35863366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SJ, Lee YJ, Lee SJ, Hong BK, Kang WC, Lee JY, et al. Treat-to-target or high-intensity statin in patients with coronary artery disease: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2023;329(13):1078&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9989958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36877807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okonofua EC, Simpson KN, Jesri A, Rehman SU, Durkalski VL, Egan BM. Therapeutic inertia is an impediment to achieving the healthy people 2010 blood pressure control goals. Hypertension. 2006;47(3):345&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew BH, Mohd-Yusof BN, Lai PSM, Khunti K. Overcoming therapeutic inertia as the achilles&#x2019; heel for improving suboptimal diabetes care: an integrative review. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul). 2023;38(1):34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36792353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo P, Basile C, Galasso G, Bellino M, D&#x2019;Elia D, Patti G, et al. Strike early-strike strong lipid-lowering strategy with proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 inhibitors in acute coronary syndrome patients: real-world evidence from the AT-TARGET-IT registry. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2024;31(15):1806&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38788773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo P, Marzano F, Crisci M, Marcucci R, Bruzzese D, Maloberti A, et al. Real-World Efficacy and Safety of Inclisiran: A Single-Country, Multicenter, Observational Study (CHOLINET Registry). J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025;85(5):536&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39665700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>