<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39138906</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-277X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human nutrition and dietetics : the official journal of the British Dietetic Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Nutr Diet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Patients' experiences of dietary changes during a structured dietary intervention for irritable bowel syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1336</StartPage><EndPage>1348</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1336-1348</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jhn.13349</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Diet plays an important role in management of gastrointestinal (GI) symptoms in patients with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). Restrictive diets have gained popularity as treatment for IBS, but no studies have examined the patients' experiences of implementing such diets. Thus, the present study aimed to explore the experience of patients with IBS undergoing a structured dietary intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Using inductive content analysis, semi-structured interviews were conducted in 19 patients with IBS, who were recruited from a randomised controlled trial evaluating two different restrictive diets for 4 weeks: a diet low in total carbohydrates; and a diet low in fermentable oligo-, di- and monosaccharides and polyols (i.e., FODMAP) combined with traditional IBS dietary advice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Three main themes developed from the qualitative analysis and together they describe the dietary intervention as supportive, as well as the dietary changes as challenging and contributing to reflection. Patients found the dietary support effective in both initiating and adhering to their dietary changes. Despite the support, the implementation of the diet was perceived as challenging when it interfered with other important aspects of their lives. However, going through the dietary change process, the patients began to reflect on their eating behaviours, which enabled individual dietary adjustments. The adjustments that patients maintained were not only a result of alleviation of GI symptoms, but also based on personal preferences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with IBS undergoing restrictive diets appear to benefit from structured support. However, considering the individual patient's life situation and personal preferences, individualised dietary options should be encouraged to achieve long-term dietary changes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Dietetic Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weznaver</LastName><ForeName>Cecilia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-2844-6474</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nybacka</LastName><ForeName>Sanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9299-1929</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simren</LastName><ForeName>Magnus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Functional GI and Motility Disorders, University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T&#xf6;rnblom</LastName><ForeName>Hans</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jakobsson</LastName><ForeName>Sofie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5223-6363</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and care Sciences, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>St&#xf6;rsrud</LastName><ForeName>Stine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1601-846X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>939090, 931291, 839182</GrantID><Agency>The Health &amp;amp; Medical Care Committee of the Region V&#xe4;stra G&#xf6;taland</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2018-02566</GrantID><Agency>Swedish Research Council</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>771191, 932656, 722331</GrantID><Agency>Agreement concerning research and education of doctors</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1606-01, 1703-01</GrantID><Agency>The Wilhelm and Martina Lundgren Science Foundation, Skandia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1511-01</GrantID><Agency>Dietary Science foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2016-00136</GrantID><Agency>Nanna Swartz Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>The funders had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the&#xa0;manuscript, or in the decision to publish the results</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Nutr Diet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904840</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0952-3871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004040">Dietary Carbohydrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009005">Monosaccharides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050528" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet, Carbohydrate-Restricted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005247" MajorTopicYN="N">Feeding Behavior</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004040" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Carbohydrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010349" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Compliance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009005" MajorTopicYN="N">Monosaccharides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005285" MajorTopicYN="N">Fermentation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">experiences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structured dietary changes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39138906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.13349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Mearin F, Chang L, Chey WD, Lembo AJ, Simren M, et al. Bowel disorders. Gastroenterology. 2016;150(6):1393&#x2013;407.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperber AD, Bangdiwala SI, Drossman DA, Ghoshal UC, Simren M, Tack J, et al. Worldwide prevalence and burden of functional gastrointestinal disorders, results of Rome Foundation Global Study. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(1):99&#x2013;114.e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Sperber AD, Corsetti M, Camilleri M. Irritable bowel syndrome. Lancet. 2020;396(10263):1675&#x2013;1688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Forman D, Bailey AG, Axon ATR, Moayyedi P. Irritable bowel syndrome: a 10&#x2010;yr natural history of symptoms and factors that influence consultation behavior. Am J Gastroenterol. 2008;103(5):1229&#x2013;1239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gralnek IM, Hays RD, Kilbourne A, Naliboff B, Mayer EA. The impact of irritable bowel syndrome on health&#x2010;related quality of life. Gastroenterology. 2000;119(3):654&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tornkvist NT, Aziz I, Whitehead WE, Sperber AD, Palsson OS, Hreinsson JP, et al. Health care utilization of individuals with Rome IV irritable bowel syndrome in the general population. United European Gastroenterol J. 2021;9(10):1178&#x2013;1188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes PA, Fraher MH, Quigley EM. Irritable bowel syndrome: the role of food in pathogenesis and management. Gastroenterol Hepatol (N Y). 2014;10(3):164&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hn L, St&#xf6;rsrud S, T&#xf6;rnblom H, Bengtsson U, Simr&#xe9;n M. Self&#x2010;reported food&#x2010;related gastrointestinal symptoms in IBS are common and associated with more severe symptoms and reduced quality of life. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013;108(5):634&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chey WD, Hashash JG, Manning L, Chang L. AGA clinical practice update on the role of diet in irritable bowel syndrome: expert review. Gastroenterology. 2022;162(6):1737&#x2013;45.e5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel NV. Let food be thy medicine: diet and supplements in irritable bowel syndrome. Clin Exp Gastroenterol. 2021;14:377&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarrett M, Visser R, Heitkemper M. Diet triggers symptoms in women with irritable bowel syndrome: the patient's perspective. Gastroenterol Nurs. 2001;24(5):246&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamieson AE, Fletcher PC, Schneider MA. Seeking control through the determination of diet: a qualitative investigation of women with irritable bowel syndrome and inflammatory bowel disease. Clin Nurse Spec. 2007;21(3):152&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpert A, Dalton CB, Palsson O, Morris C, Hu Y, Bangdiwala S, et al. What patients know about irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) and what they would like to know. National survey on patient educational needs in IBS and development and validation of the patient educational needs questionnaire (PEQ). Am J Gastroenterol. 2007;102(9):1972&#x2013;1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott N, Aziz I, Rej A, Surendran Sanders D. How patients with IBS use low FODMAP dietary information provided by general practitioners and gastroenterologists: a qualitative study. Nutrients. 2019;11(6):1313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hn L, St&#xf6;rsrud S, Liljebo T, Collin L, Lindfors P, T&#xf6;rnblom H, et al. Diet low in FODMAPs reduces symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome as well as traditional dietary advice: a randomized controlled trial. Gastroenterology. 2015;149(6):1399&#x2013;407.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halmos EP, Power VA, Shepherd SJ, Gibson PR, Muir JG. A diet low in FODMAPs reduces symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome. Gastroenterology. 2014;146(1):67&#x2013;75.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionne J, Ford AC, Yuan Y, Chey WD, Lacy BE, Saito YA, et al. A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis evaluating the efficacy of a gluten&#x2010;free diet and a low FODMAPs diet in treating symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome. Am J Gastroenterol. 2018;113(9):1290&#x2013;1300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie YA, Bowyer RK, Leach H, Gulia P, Horobin J, O'Sullivan NA, et al. British dietetic association systematic review and evidence&#x2010;based practice guidelines for the dietary management of irritable bowel syndrome in adults (2016 update). J Hum Nutr Diet. 2016;29(5):549&#x2013;575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Exellence. Irritable Bowel Syndrome in Adults: Diagnosis and Management, Guidance and Guidelines. London, UK: NICE; 2017. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg61/chapter/1-Recommendations#more-information</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao SS, Yu S, Fedewa A. Systematic review: dietary fibre and FODMAP&#x2010;restricted diet in the management of constipation and irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2015;41(12):1256&#x2013;1270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh A, Eslick EM, Eslick GD. Does a diet low in FODMAPs reduce symptoms associated with functional gastrointestinal disorders? A comprehensive systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Eur J Nutr. 2016;55(3):897&#x2013;906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altobelli E, Del Negro V, Angeletti P, Latella G. Low&#x2010;FODMAP diet improves irritable bowel syndrome symptoms: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Nutrients. 2017;9(9):940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varj&#xfa; P, Farkas N, Hegyi P, Garami A, Szab&#xf3; I, Ill&#xe9;s A, et al Low fermentable oligosaccharides, disaccharides, monosaccharides and polyols (FODMAP) diet improves symptoms in adults suffering from irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) compared to standard IBS diet: a meta&#x2010;analysis of clinical studies. PLoS One. 2017;12(8):e0182942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann D, Klose P, Lauche R, Dobos G, Langhorst J, Cramer H. Low fermentable, oligo&#x2010;, di&#x2010;, mono&#x2010;saccharides and polyol diet in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Nutrition. 2018;45:24&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson PR, Shepherd SJ. Evidence&#x2010;based dietary management of functional gastrointestinal symptoms: The FODMAP approach. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2010;25(2):252&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black CJ, Staudacher HM, Ford AC. Efficacy of a low FODMAP diet in irritable bowel syndrome: systematic review and network meta&#x2010;analysis. Gut. 2022;71(6):1117&#x2013;1126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher HM, Lomer MCE, Farquharson FM, Louis P, Fava F, Franciosi E, et al. A diet low in FODMAPs reduces symptoms in patients with irritable bowel syndrome and a probiotic restores bifidobacterium species: a randomized controlled trial. Gastroenterology. 2017;153(4):936&#x2013;947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halmos EP, Christophersen CT, Bird AR, Shepherd SJ, Gibson PR, Muir JG. Diets that differ in their FODMAP content alter the colonic luminal microenvironment. Gut. 2015;64(1):93&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari A, Hosadurg D, Martin L, Zarate&#x2010;Lopez N, Passananti V, Emmanuel A. Adherence with a low&#x2010;FODMAP diet in irritable bowel syndrome: are eating disorders the missing link? Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;31(2):178&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswaran SL, Chey WD, Han&#x2010;Markey T, Ball S, Jackson K. A randomized controlled trial comparing the low FODMAP diet vs. modified NICE guidelines in US adults with IBS&#x2010;D. Am J Gastroenterol. 2016;111(12):1824&#x2013;1832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuck C, Barrett J. Re&#x2010;challenging FODMAPs: the low FODMAP diet phase two. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32(S1):11&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClernon FJ, Yancy WS, Eberstein JA, Atkins RC, Westman EC. The effects of a low&#x2010;carbohydrate ketogenic diet and a low&#x2010;fat diet on mood, hunger, and other self&#x2010;reported symptoms. Obesity. 2007;15(1):182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin GL, Dalton CB, Hu Y, Morris CB, Hankins J, Weinland SR, et al. A very low&#x2010;carbohydrate diet improves symptoms and quality of life in diarrhea&#x2010;predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;7(6):706&#x2013;8.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilholm C, Larsson E, Sonestedt E, Roth B, Ohlsson B. Assessment of a 4&#x2010;week starch&#x2010;and sucrose&#x2010;reduced diet and its effects on gastrointestinal symptoms and inflammatory parameters among patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Nutrients. 2021;13(2):416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoor N, Vinknes KJ, Veier&#xf8;d MB, Retterst&#xf8;l K. Effects of low&#x2010;carbohydrate diets v. low&#x2010;fat diets on body weight and cardiovascular risk factors: a meta&#x2010;analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Nutr. 2016;115(3):466&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoor N, Vinknes KJ, Veier&#xf8;d MB, Retterst&#xf8;l K. Low&#x2010;carbohydrate diets increase LDL&#x2010;cholesterol, and thereby indicate increased risk of CVD. Br J Nutr. 2016;115(12):2264&#x2013;2266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperber AD, Bangdiwala SI, Drossman DA, Ghoshal UC, Simren M, Tack J, et al. Worldwide prevalence and burden of functional gastrointestinal disorders, results of Rome Foundation Global Study. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(1):99&#x2013;114.e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Keeffe M, Lomer MCE. Who should deliver the low FODMAP diet and what educational methods are optimal: a review: Low FODMAP diet education. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32:23&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelan K, Martin LD, Staudacher HM, Lomer MCE. The low FODMAP diet in the management of irritable bowel syndrome: an evidence&#x2010;based review of FODMAP restriction, reintroduction and personalisation in clinical practice. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2018;31(2):239&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett JS. How to institute the low&#x2010;FODMAP diet. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32(S1):8&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Roest RH, Dobbs BR, Chapman BA, Batman B, O'Brien LA, Leeper JA, et al. The low FODMAP diet improves gastrointestinal symptoms in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a prospective study. Int J Clin Pract. 2013;67(9):895&#x2013;903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher HM, Lomer MCE, Anderson JL, Irving PM, Whelan K. Impact of a diet low in fermentable carbohydrates on gastrointestinal symptoms, stool output and faecal pH in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a randomised controlled trial. Proc Nutr Soc. 2011;70(OCE5):E293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao CK, Gibson PR, Shepherd SJ. Design of clinical trials evaluating dietary interventions in patients with functional gastrointestinal disorders. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013;108(5):748&#x2013;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halmos EP, Gibson PR. Controversies and reality of the FODMAP diet for patients with irritable bowel syndrome. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;34(7):1134&#x2013;1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsson Ung E, Ringstrom G, Sj&#xf6;vall H, Simr&#xe9;n M. How patients with long&#x2010;term experience of living with irritable bowel syndrome manage illness in daily life: a qualitative study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2013;25(12):1478&#x2013;1483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf6;rkman I, Dellenborg L, Ringstr&#xf6;m G, Simr&#xe9;n M, Jakobsson Ung E. The gendered impact of irritable bowel syndrome: a qualitative study of patients' experiences. J Adv Nurs. 2014;70(6):1334&#x2013;1343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringstrom G, Sjovall H, Simr&#xe9;n M, Ung EJ. The importance of a person&#x2010;centered approach in diagnostic workups of patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a qualitative study. Gastroenterol Nurs. 2013;36(6):443&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rej A, Sanders DS, Shaw CC, Buckle R, Trott N, Agrawal A, et al. Efficacy and acceptability of dietary therapies in non&#x2010;constipated irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized trial of traditional dietary advice, the Low FODMAP diet, and the gluten&#x2010;free diet. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;20(12):2876&#x2013;87.e15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis CY, Morris J, Whorwell PJ. The irritable bowel severity scoring system: a simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 1997;11(2):395&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybacka S, T&#xf6;rnblom H, Simren M, St&#xf6;rsrud S. The role of carbohydrates in irritable bowel syndrome: protocol for a randomized controlled trial comparing three different treatment options. JMIR Res Protoc. 2022;11(1):e31413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybacka S, T&#xf6;rnblom H, Josefsson A, Hreinsson JP, B&#xf6;hn L, Fr&#xe4;ndemark &#xc5;, et al. A low FODMAP diet plus traditional dietary advice versus a low&#x2010;carbohydrate diet versus pharmacological treatment in irritable bowel syndrome (CARIBS): a single&#x2010;centre, single&#x2010;blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2024;9(6):507&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elo S, Kyng&#xe4;s H. The qualitative content analysis process. J Adv Nurs. 2008;62(1):107&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministers NCo. Nordic Nutritional Recommendations 2012. Copenhagen: Nordisk Ministerr&#xe5;d; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuck C, Barrett J. Re&#x2010;challenging FODMAPs: the low FODMAP diet phase two. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;32:11&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher PC, Jamieson AE, Schneider MA, Harry RJ. &#x2018;I know this is bad for me, but&#x2026;&#x2019;: a qualitative investigation of women with irritable bowel syndrome and inflammatory bowel disease: part II. Clin Nurse Spec. 2008;22(4):184&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xe4;ndemark &#xc5;, Jakobsson Ung E, T&#xf6;rnblom H, Simr&#xe9;n M, Jakobsson S. Fatigue: a distressing symptom for patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Neurogastroenterol Motility. 2017;29(1):12898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krippendorff K. Content analysis: an introduction to its methodology. Beverly Hills, Calif: Sage; 1980.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>