<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40985958</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1078-6791</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Alternative therapies in health and medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Altern Ther Health Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evidence-Based Clinical Effectiveness of Kundalini Yoga: Systematic Review of RCTs Across Multiple Health Conditions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">AT11722</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Kundalini Yoga (KY) integrates breathwork, meditation, dynamic movement, and chanting, and has gained recognition as a therapeutic intervention. Despite promising results from individual randomized controlled trials (RCTs), to our knowledge, no systematic review has exclusively synthesized RCT evidence on KY across health domains.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To critically assess the clinical effectiveness and safety of KY interventions across diverse cognitive, psychological, emotional, sleep-related, and physical health outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PRISMA-guided systematic review of RCTs evaluating KY was conducted from January 2015 to December 2024. Databases included MEDLINE (PubMed), Scopus, CENTRAL (Cochrane Library), Embase, PsycINFO, and CINAHL. Risk of bias was independently assessed using the Joanna Briggs Institute Critical Appraisal Checklist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Studies were conducted worldwide, across multiple sites.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Approximately 1370 participants ranging from healthy adults to those diagnosed with conditions such as Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI), Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD), Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder (OCD), Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD), insomnia, chronic pain, and post-treatment Lyme disease syndrome. No serious adverse events were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">KY protocols (pranayama, asana/kriya, meditation, chanting) delivered in person, online, or hybrid formats; duration 6 weeks-12 months (most 8-12 weeks) with practice from once weekly to daily.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pre-specified validated measures assessed cognitive function, psychological symptoms (e.g., anxiety, depression), sleep quality, emotional regulation, and physical health outcomes (e.g., hippocampal metrics, absenteeism, blood pressure).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This systematic review included 15 studies, among which 13 demonstrated a low risk of bias. The findings suggest that KY significantly improves memory, executive functioning, and hippocampal structure, reduces symptoms of anxiety, PTSD, OCD, and depression, enhances sleep quality and emotional regulation, and modestly improves fatigue, blood pressure, and functional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">KY appears safe and shows benefits for a wide range of cognitive, psychological, and physical health conditions. However, larger, standardized RCTs with active comparators, biomarkers, and longer follow-up are needed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEYWORDS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Kundalini Yoga, randomized controlled trials, cognitive function, mental health, sleep, PTSD, hypertension, complementary therapy, mind-body intervention.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Sharmistha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD Scholar; Department of Social and Behavioral Health, School of Public Health. University of Nevada, Las Vegas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biswas</LastName><ForeName>Ashis Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health. University of Nevada, Las Vegas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Manoj</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Kirk Kerkorian School of Medicine at UNLV, University of Nevada, Las Vegas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Altern Ther Health Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9502013</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-6791</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40985958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AT11722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>