<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37436844</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1140</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>279</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ondansetron for Low Anterior Resection Syndrome (LARS): A Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Cross-Over, Randomized Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>196</StartPage><EndPage>202</EndPage><MedlinePgn>196-202</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SLA.0000000000005995</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of the study was to examine the efficacity and safety of ondansetron, a serotonin receptor antagonist, to treat patients with low anterior resection syndrome (LARS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">LARS after rectal resection is common and debilitating. Current management strategies include behavioral and dietary modifications, physiotherapy, antidiarrheal drugs, enemas, and neuromodulation, but the results are not always satisfactory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a randomized, multicentric, double-blinded, placebo-controlled, and cross-over study. Patients with LARS (LARS score &gt;20) no longer than 2 years after rectal resection were randomized to receive either 4 weeks of ondansetron followed by 4 weeks of placebo (O-P group) or 4 weeks of placebo followed by 4 weeks of ondansetron (P-O group). The primary endpoint was LARS severity measured using the LARS score; secondary endpoints were incontinence (Vaizey score) and irritable bowel syndrome quality of life (IBS-QoL questionnaire). Patients' scores and questionnaires were completed at baseline and after each 4-week treatment period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 46 randomized patients, 38 were included in the analysis. From baseline to the end of the first period, in the O-P group, the mean (SD) LARS score decreased by 25% [from 36.6 (5.6) to 27.3 (11.5)] and the proportion of patients with major LARS (score &gt;30) went from 15/17 (88%) to 7/17 (41%), ( P =0.001). In the P-O group, the mean (SD) LARS score decreased by 12% [from 37 (4.8) to 32.6 (9.1)], and the proportion of major LARS went from 19/21 (90%) to 16/21 (76%). After crossover, LARS scores deteriorated again in the O-P group receiving placebo, but further improved in the P-O group receiving ondansetron. Mean Vaizey scores and IBS QoL scores followed a similar pattern.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Ondansetron is a safe and simple treatment that appears to improve both symptoms and QoL in LARS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Popeskou</LastName><ForeName>Sotirios Georgios</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, Hospital of Lugano (EOC), Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roesel</LastName><ForeName>Raffaello</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, Hospital of Lugano (EOC), Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faes</LastName><ForeName>Seraina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, University Hospital of Lausanne (CHUV), Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanoni</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, Hospital of Lugano (EOC), Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galafassi</LastName><ForeName>Jacopo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, Hospital of Lugano (EOC), Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>di Tor Vajana</LastName><ForeName>Antonjacopo Ferrario</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Swiss Surgical Practice, Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piotet</LastName><ForeName>Laure-Meline</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, University Hospital of Lausanne (CHUV), Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christoforidis</LastName><ForeName>Dimitri</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, Hospital of Lugano (EOC), Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Visceral Surgery, University Hospital of Lausanne (CHUV), Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372354</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-4932</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>4AF302ESOS</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017294">Ondansetron</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017294" MajorTopicYN="N">Ondansetron</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094123" MajorTopicYN="N">Low Anterior Resection Syndrome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012004" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rectal Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011183" MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative Complications</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37436844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000005995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000658-202402000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>van Gijn W, Marijnen CA, Nagtegaal ID, et al. Preoperative radiotherapy combined with total mesorectal excision for resectable rectal cancer: 12-year follow-up of the multicentre, randomised controlled TME trial. Lancet Oncol. 2011;12:575&#x2013;582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant CL, Lunniss PJ, Knowles CH, et al. Anterior resection syndrome. Lancet Oncol. 2012;13:e403&#x2013;e408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croese AD, Lonie JM, Trollope AF, et al. A meta-analysis of the prevalence of low anterior resection syndrome and systematic review of risk factors. Int J Surg. 2018;56:234&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pucciani F. A review on functional results of sphincter-saving surgery for rectal cancer: the anterior resection syndrome. Updates Surg. 2013;65:257&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoerske C, Weber K, Goehl J, et al. Long-term outcomes and quality of life after rectal carcinoma surgery. Br J Surg. 2010;97:1295&#x2013;1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters KCMJ, van de Velde CJH, Leer JWH, et al. Late side effects of short-course preoperative radiotherapy combined with total mesorectal excision for rectal cancer: increased bowel dysfunction in irradiated patients&#x2014;a Dutch colorectal cancer group study. J Clin Oncol. 2005;23:6199&#x2013;6206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son DN, Choi DJ, Woo SU, et al. Relationship between diversion colitis and quality of life in rectal cancer. World J Gastroenterol. 2013;19:542&#x2013;549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bregendahl S, Emmertsen KJ, Lous J, et al. Bowel dysfunction after low anterior resection with and without neoadjuvant therapy for rectal cancer: a population-based cross-sectional study. Colorectal Dis. 2013;15:1130&#x2013;1139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmertsen KJ, Laurberg S. Low anterior resection syndrome score: development and validation of a symptom-based scoring system for bowel dysfunction after low anterior resection for rectal cancer. Ann Surg. 2012;255:922&#x2013;928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koda K, Saito N, Seike K, et al. Denervation of the neorectum as a potential cause of defecatory disorder following low anterior resection for rectal cancer. Dis Colon Rectum. 2005;48:210&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee WY, Takahashi T, Pappas T, et al. Surgical autonomic denervation results in altered colonic motility: an explanation for low anterior resection syndrome? Surgery. 2008;143:778&#x2013;783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xfc;rst A, Burghofer K, Hutzel L, et al. Neorectal reservoir is not the functional principle of the colonic J-pouch: the volume of a short colonic J-pouch does not differ from a straight coloanal anastomosis. Dis Colon Rectum. 2002;45:660&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iizuka I, Koda K, Seike K, et al. Defecatory malfunction caused by motility disorder of the neorectum after anterior resection for rectal cancer. Am J Surg. 2004;188:176&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershon MD. Review article: serotonin receptors and transporters&#x2014;roles in normal and abnormal gastrointestinal motility. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2004;20(suppl 7):3&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing F, Zhang J. Metabolic kinetics of 5-hydroxytryptamine and the research targets of functional gastrointestinal disorders. Dig Dis Sci. 2014;59:2642&#x2013;2648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cremonini F, Delgado-Aros S, Camilleri M. Efficacy of alosetron in irritable bowel syndrome: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2003;15:79&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson W, Lockhart S, Whorwell PJ, et al. Altered 5-hydroxytryptamine signaling in patients with constipation- and diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Gastroenterology. 2006;130:34&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garsed K, Chernova J, Hastings M, et al. A randomised trial of ondansetron for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhoea. Gut. 2014;63:1617&#x2013;1625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tack J, Broekaert D, Fischler B, et al. A controlled crossover study of the selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor citalopram in irritable bowel syndrome. Gut. 2006;55:1095&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitashima F, Itagaki R, Sezai A, et al. Serotonin (5-HT3) receptor antagonists for the reduction of symptoms of low anterior resection syndrome. Clin Exp Gastroenterol. 2014;7:47&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryoo SB, Park JW, Lee DW, et al. Anterior resection syndrome: a randomized clinical trial of a 5-HT3 receptor antagonist (ramosetron) in male patients with rectal cancer. Br J Surg. 2021;108:644&#x2013;651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juul T, Ahlberg M, Biondo S, et al. International validation of the low anterior resection syndrome score. Ann Surg. 2014;259:728&#x2013;734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaizey CJ, Carapeti E, Cahill JA, et al. Prospective comparison of faecal incontinence grading systems. Gut. 1999;44:77&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrae DA, Patrick DL, Drossman DA, et al. Evaluation of the irritable bowel syndrome quality of life (IBS-QOL) questionnaire in diarrheal-predominant irritable bowel syndrome patients. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2013;11:208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International conference on harmonization of technical requirements for registration of pharmaceuticals for human use. ICH Harmonized Tripartite - Guideline for Good Clinical Practice E6(R1)1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keane C, Fearnhead NS, Bordeianou LG, et al. International consensus definition of low anterior resection syndrome. Dis Colon Rectum. 2020;63:274&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Cho SY, Yoo KY, et al. Population pharmacokinetics of ramosetron. J Pharmacokinet Pharmacodyn. 2016;43:73&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinello FG, Jim&#xe9;nez LM, Talavera E, et al. Percutaneous tibial nerve stimulation in patients with severe low anterior resection syndrome: randomized clinical trial. Br J Surg. 2021;108:380&#x2013;387.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>