<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40444524</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-4801</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pediatric gastroenterology and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ESPGHAN/NASPGHAN guidelines for treatment of irritable bowel syndrome and functional abdominal pain-not otherwise specified in children aged 4-18 years.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>442</StartPage><EndPage>471</EndPage><MedlinePgn>442-471</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jpn3.70070</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Abdominal pain related disorders of gut-brain interaction (AP-DGBIs) such as irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) and functional abdominal pain-not otherwise specified (FAP) are common conditions in children, significantly impacting quality of life. This treatment guideline for IBS and FAP in children of 4-18 years is a collaborative effort of the European and North American Societies for Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition (ESPGHAN and NASPGHAN). We aim to comprehensively review the current evidence on treatment options and offer evidence-based recommendations with utility across all treatment settings worldwide, as well as to provide methodological directions for future research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The guideline development followed the "Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation" (GRADE) approach, which is in accordance with the GRADE handbook and supported by the World Health Organization. The Guideline Development Group (GDG) comprised clinical experts, representing ESPGHAN, NASPGHAN, and Cochrane. Individual members have put forward a final consensus list of treatment options, which were then translated into "patient, intervention, comparison, outcome" (PICO) format options. Prospective agreement on decision thresholds for efficacy and safety outcomes was reached through a Delphi process among the GDG to support GRADEing of the literature. Consensus voting was used to finalize recommendations, and a treatment algorithm was developed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Systematic literature searches for this output identified 86 original randomized controlled trials assessing treatment of IBS and FAP. Consensus was reached for 25 GRADEd recommendations. Ten best practice statements were formulated, and guidance for future research methodology was proposed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This guideline represents the first collaborative output of ESPGHAN and NASPGHAN on treatment options for AP-DGBIs. Systematic review of the evidence has exposed major evidence gaps for the treatment of these disorders and incentivizes large pediatric trials, particularly on treatment options for which, to date, no evidence exists.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Journal of Pediatric Gastroenterology and Nutrition published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of European Society for Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Nutrition and North American Society for Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Groen</LastName><ForeName>Jip</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7465-7549</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, Pediatric Gastroenterology, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam Gastroenterology Endocrinology Metabolism, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam Reproduction and Development research institute, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Morris</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chogle</LastName><ForeName>Ashish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Orange County, Orange, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benninga</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, Pediatric Gastroenterology, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borlack</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Children's Hospital at Montefiore, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borrelli</LastName><ForeName>Osvaldo</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Great Ormond Street Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darbari</LastName><ForeName>Anil</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's National Hospital, George Washington University School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Washington, District of Columbia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dolinsek</LastName><ForeName>Jernej</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Centre Maribor, Maribor, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khlevner</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Columbia University Vagelos College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Lorenzo</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Person</LastName><ForeName>Hannibal</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Seattle Children's Hospital, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanghavi</LastName><ForeName>Rinarani</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Snyder</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thapar</LastName><ForeName>Nikhil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Children's Hospital, School of Medicine, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vlieger</LastName><ForeName>Arine</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St. Antonius Hospital, Nieuwegein, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinopoulou</LastName><ForeName>Vasiliki</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Central Lancashire, Preston, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabbers</LastName><ForeName>Merit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, Pediatric Gastroenterology, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saps</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Miami, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>NASPGHAN</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>ESPGHAN</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017065">Practice Guideline</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8211545</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-2116</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015746" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abdominal Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005762" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastroenterology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Reviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disorders of gut brain interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional abdominal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut&#x2010;brain psychotherapies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Regulations for conflict of interest followed the Cochrane handbook as well as the GRADE body. These implied that not only the receipt of financial contributions of institutions with links to assessed treatment options implied a conflict, but academic involvement in research on a specific treatment option without commercial funding as well. Marc Alexander Benninga indicated conflicts of interest for Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT), Yoga, Hypnotherapy, and laxatives, due to involvement in studies assessing these therapies. Marc Alexander Benninga also indicated consulting services for Norgine, Coloplast, Wellspect, Allergan, Mallinckrodt, United Pharmaceuticals, Danone, FrieslandCampina, and HIPP. Marc Alexander Benninga also served as speaker for Abbott and Menarini. Ashish Chogle indicated a conflict of interest for neurostimulation, due to involvement in studies assessing these therapies. Julie Khlevner indicated a conflict of interest for laxatives, due to involvement in studies assessing these therapies. Julie Khlevner also indicated consulting services for Abbvie Inc. Carlo Di Lorenzo indicated conflicts of interest for neurostimulation, amitriptyline, linaclotide, and prucalopride, due to involvement in studies assessing these therapies. Miguel Saps indicated conflicts of interest for amitriptyline and linaclotide, due to involvement in studies assessing these therapies. Miguel Saps also indicated consulting services for Abbvie Inc., IQVIA, and Focus Medical Communications. Nikhil Thapar indicated conflicts of interest for probiotics, due to receiving honoraria from both Biogaia and Nutricia for roles in the advisory board and in moderating a key opinion leaders meeting on the addition of pre&#x2010;/probiotics in infant formula, respectively. Arine Vlieger indicated a conflict of interest for Hypnotherapy, due to involvement in studies assessing these therapies. Arine Vlieger also indicated an unpaid position as Chair of the Dutch Society for Hypnosis in Children. The remaining authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40444524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12314588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jpn3.70070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Korterink JJ, Diederen K, Benninga MA, Tabbers MM. Epidemiology of pediatric functional abdominal pain disorders: a meta&#x2010;analysis. PLoS One. 2015;10(5):e0126982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4439136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25992621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef NN, Atienza K, Langseder AL, Strauss RS. Chronic abdominal pain and depressive symptoms: analysis of the national longitudinal study of adolescent health. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2008;6(3):329&#x2010;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18258491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoekman DR, Rutten JMTM, Vlieger AM, Benninga MA, Dijkgraaf MGW. Annual costs of care for pediatric irritable bowel syndrome, functional abdominal pain, and functional abdominal pain syndrome. J Pediatr. 2015;167(5):1103&#x2010;1108.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26329806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis ML, Palsson OS, Whitehead WE, van Tilburg MAL. Prevalence of functional gastrointestinal disorders in children and adolescents. J Pediatr. 2016;177:39&#x2010;43.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27156185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assa A, Ish&#x2010;Tov A, Rinawi F, Shamir R. School attendance in children with functional abdominal pain and inflammatory bowel diseases. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2015;61(5):553&#x2010;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25950089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhroove G, Chogle A, Saps M. A million&#x2010;dollar work&#x2010;up for abdominal pain: is it worth it? J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2010;51(5):579&#x2010;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20706149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyams JS, Di Lorenzo C, Saps M, et al. Functional disorders: children and adolescents. Gastroenterology. 2016:150(6):1456&#x2010;1468.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutten JMTM, Benninga MA, Vlieger AM. IBS and FAPS in children: a comparison of psychological and clinical characteristics. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2014;59(4):493&#x2010;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24897168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bruijn CM, Rexwinkel R, Gordon M, Sinopoulou V, Benninga MA, Tabbers MM. Dietary interventions for functional abdominal pain disorders in children: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;16(4):359&#x2010;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35311425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon M, Sinopoulou V, Tabbers M, et al. Psychosocial interventions for the treatment of functional abdominal pain disorders in children: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. JAMA Pediatr. 2022;176(6):560&#x2010;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rexwinkel R, de Bruijn CMA, Gordon M, Benninga MA, Tabbers MM. Pharmacologic treatment in functional abdominal pain disorders in children: a systematic review. Pediatrics. 2021;147(6):e2020022421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34045320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace C, Gordon M, Sinopoulou V, Akobeng AK. Probiotics for management of functional abdominal pain disorders in children. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;2(2):CD012849. 10.1002/14651858.CD012849.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD012849.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9945052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36799531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapar N, Benninga MA, Crowell MD, et al. Paediatric functional abdominal pain disorders. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6(1):89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33154368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabbers MM, DiLorenzo C, Berger MY, et al. Evaluation and treatment of functional constipation in infants and children: evidence&#x2010;based recommendations from ESPGHAN and NASPGHAN. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2014;58(2):258&#x2010;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24345831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HBJ, Guyatt G, Oxman A, eds, GRADE Handbook for Grading Quality of Evidence and Strength of Recommendations. The GRADE Working Group; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon M, Benninga MA, Borlack R, et al. ESPGHAN and NASPGHAN 2023 protocol for paediatric FAPD treatment guidelines (standard operating procedure). BMJ Paediatr Open. 2023;7(1):e002166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10749037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38128947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon M, Darie A&#x2010;M, Sinopoulou V, et al. BSG 2024 IBD guidelines protocol (standard operating procedures). BMJ Open Gastroenterol. 2023;10(1):e001067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36764690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeevenhooven J, Rexwinkel R, Van Berge Henegouwen VWA, et al. A core outcome set for clinical trials in pediatric functional abdominal pain disorders. J Pediatr. 2020;221:115&#x2010;122.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32312551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasa P, Jain R, Juneja D. Delphi methodology in healthcare research: how to decide its appropriateness. World J Methodol. 2021;11(4):116&#x2010;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8299905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34322364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgano GP, Mbuagbaw L, Santesso N, et al. Defining decision thresholds for judgments on health benefits and harms using the grading of recommendations assessment, development and evaluation (GRADE) evidence to decision (EtD) frameworks: a protocol for a randomised methodological study (GRADE&#x2010;THRESHOLD). BMJ Open. 2022;12(3):053246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8915269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35273045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaban N, Sinopoulou V, Vuyyuru S, Moran G, Gordon M. DOP02 developing explicit thresholds for outcomes to inform (GRADE) evidence to decision frameworks for inflammatory bowel disease guidelines. J Crohn's Colitis. 2024;18(supplment_1):i73&#x2010;i74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinopoulou V, Gordon M, Moran GW, et al. Prepublication abstract&#x2010;only reports compared with full&#x2010;text manuscripts for randomised controlled trials in inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review. BMJ Open Gastroenterol. 2024;11(1):e001334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10921483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38453251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon MKJ, Sinopoulou V. Quality of reporting of inflammatory bowel disease trials: a systematic review. BMJ Open Gastro. 2024. In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11033348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38631808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist G, et al. GRADE guidelines: 4. Rating the quality of evidence&#x2014;study limitations (risk of bias). J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):407&#x2010;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21247734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso&#x2010;Coello P, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Moberg J, et al. GRADE Evidence to Decision (EtD) frameworks: a systematic and transparent approach to making well informed healthcare choices. 1: introduction. BMJ. 2016;353:i2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27353417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlieger AM, Menko&#x2013;Frankenhuis C, Wolfkamp SCS, Tromp E, Benninga MA. Hypnotherapy for children with functional abdominal pain or irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Gastroenterology. 2007;133(5):1430&#x2010;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17919634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulewitsch MD, M&#xfc;ller J, Hautzinger M, Schlarb AA. Brief hypnotherapeutic&#x2010;behavioral intervention for functional abdominal pain and irritable bowel syndrome in childhood: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Pediatr. 2013;172(8):1043&#x2010;1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23568514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulewitsch MD, Schlarb AA. Comparison of gut&#x2010;directed hypnotherapy and unspecific hypnotherapy as self&#x2010;help format in children and adolescents with functional abdominal pain or irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized pilot study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;29(12):1351&#x2010;1360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29023318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutten JMTM, Vlieger AM, Frankenhuis C, et al. Home&#x2010;based hypnotherapy self&#x2010;exercises vs individual hypnotherapy with a therapist for treatment of pediatric irritable bowel syndrome, functional abdominal pain, or functional abdominal pain syndrome: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Pediatr. 2017;171(5):470&#x2010;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28346581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pas R, Rheel E, Van Oosterwijck S, et al. Pain neuroscience education for children with functional abdominal pain disorders: a randomized comparative pilot study. J Clin Med. 2020;9(6):1797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weydert JA, Shapiro DE, Acra SA, Monheim CJ, Chambers AS, Ball TM. Evaluation of guided imagery as treatment for recurrent abdominal pain in children: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Pediatr. 2006;6:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1660537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17090333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef NN, Van Tilburg MA, Matta EN, Langseder A, Whitehead WE. 1007 feasibility and efficacy of pilot study investigating a school nurse administered guided imagery program for childhood functional abdominal pain. Gastroenterology. 2009;136(5, supplment 1):A&#x2010;156&#x2010;A&#x2010;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Tilburg MAL, Chitkara DK, Palsson OS, et al. Audio&#x2010;recorded guided imagery treatment reduces functional abdominal pain in children: a pilot study. Pediatrics. 2009;124(5):e890&#x2010;e897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfv&#xe9;n G, Lindstrom A. A new method for the treatment of recurrent abdominal pain of prolonged negative stress origin. Acta Paediatr (Stockholm). 2007;96(1):76&#x2010;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17187609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnert M, Ol&#xe9;n O, Lalouni M, et al. Internet&#x2010;delivered exposure&#x2010;based cognitive&#x2010;behavioral therapy for adolescents with functional abdominal pain or functional dyspepsia: a feasibility study. Behav Ther. 2019;50(1):177&#x2010;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30661558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham NR, Kalomiris A, Peugh J, et al. Cognitive behavior therapy tailored to anxiety symptoms improves pediatric functional abdominal pain outcomes: a randomized clinical trial. J Pediatr. 2021;230:62&#x2010;70.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33130153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte MA, Penna FJ, Andrade EMG, Cancela CSP, Neto JCA, Barbosa TF. Treatment of nonorganic recurrent abdominal pain: cognitive&#x2010;behavioral family intervention. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2006;43(1):59&#x2010;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16819378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gro&#xdf; M, Warschburger P. Evaluation of a cognitive&#x2010;behavioral pain management program for children with chronic abdominal pain: a randomized controlled study. Int J Behav Med. 2013;20(3):434&#x2010;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys PA, Gevirtz RN. Treatment of recurrent abdominal pain: components analysis of four treatment protocols. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2000;31(1):47&#x2010;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalouni M, Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Bonnert M, et al. Clinical and cost effectiveness of online cognitive behavioral therapy in children with functional abdominal pain disorders. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;17(11):2236&#x2010;2244.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30502501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy RL, Langer SL, Walker LS, et al. Cognitive&#x2010;behavioral therapy for children with functional abdominal pain and their parents decreases pain and other symptoms. Am J Gastroenterol. 2010;105(4):946&#x2010;956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20216531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto R, Boixad&#xf3;s M, Ruiz G, et al Effects and experiences of families following a web&#x2010;based psychosocial intervention for children with functional abdominal pain and their parents: a mixed&#x2010;methods pilot randomized controlled trial. J Pain Res. 2019;12:3395&#x2010;3412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6997197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32099447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robins PM, Smith SM, Glutting JJ, Bishop CT. A randomized controlled trial of a cognitive&#x2010;behavioral family intervention for pediatric recurrent abdominal pain. J Pediatr Psychol. 2005;30(5):397&#x2010;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15944167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders MR, Rebgetz M, Morrison M, et al. Cognitive&#x2010;behavioral treatment of recurrent nonspecific abdominal pain in children: an analysis of generalization, maintenance, and side effects. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1989;57(2):294&#x2010;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2708618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders MR, Shepherd RW, Cleghorn G, Woolford H. The treatment of recurrent abdominal pain in children: a controlled comparison of cognitive&#x2010;behavioral family intervention and standard pediatric care. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1994;62(2):306&#x2010;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8201068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Veek SMC, Derkx BHF, Benninga MA, Boer F, de Haan E. Cognitive behavior therapy for pediatric functional abdominal pain: a randomized controlled trial. Pediatrics. 2013;132(5):e1163&#x2010;e1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24127467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker LS, Stone AL, Han GT, et al. Internet&#x2010;delivered cognitive behavioral therapy for youth with functional abdominal pain: a randomized clinical trial testing differential efficacy by patient subgroup. Pain. 2021;162(12):2945&#x2010;2955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8602868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34793406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallander JL, Madan&#x2010;Swain A, Klapow J, Saeed S. A randomised controlled trial of written self&#x2010;disclosure for functional recurrent abdominal pain in youth. Psychol Health. 2011;26(4):433&#x2010;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2911499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20419562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warschburger P, Calvano C, Becker S, et al. Do children with functional abdominal pain benefit more from a pain&#x2010;specific cognitive&#x2010;behavioral intervention than from an unspecific attention control intervention? Results of a randomized controlled trial. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116(6):1322&#x2010;1335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassom MC, Schurman JV, Friesen CA, Rapoff MA. A pilot study of &#x201c;Gutstrong&#x201d; for adolescents with functional gastrointestinal disorders. Clin Pract Pediatr Psychol. 2013;1(3):201&#x2010;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks CL, von Baeyer CL, McGrath PJ. Online psychological treatment for pediatric recurrent pain: a randomized evaluation. J Pediatr Psychol. 2006;31(7):724&#x2010;736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16093516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy RL, Langer SL, van Tilburg MAL, et al. Brief telephone&#x2010;delivered cognitive behavioral therapy targeted to parents of children with functional abdominal pain: a randomized controlled trial. Pain. 2017;158(4):618&#x2010;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5370191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28301859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sator&#x2010;Katzenschlager SM, Michalek&#x2010;Sauberer A. P&#x2010;Stim&#x2122; auricular electroacupuncture stimulation device for pain relief. Expert Rev Med Devices. 2007;4(1):23&#x2010;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17187468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed HE, Craig WF, White PF, Huber P. Percutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (PENS): a complementary therapy for the management of pain secondary to bony metastasis. Clin J Pain. 1998;14(4):320&#x2010;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9874011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Bonifacio C, Yang JC, Ercius P, Gleeson B. Effect of environmental sulfur on the structure of alumina scales formed on Ni&#x2010;base alloys. Acta Mater. 2015;97:41&#x2010;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folan&#x2010;curran J, Hickey K, Monkhouse WS. Innervation of the rat external auditory meatus: a retrograde tracing study. Somatosens Mot Res. 1994;11(1):65&#x2010;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8017145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras RJ, Beckstead RM, Norgren R. The central projections of the trigeminal, facial, glossopharyngeal and vagus nerves: an autoradiographic study in the rat. J Auton Nerv Syst. 1982;6(3):303&#x2010;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7169500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacic K, Hainsworth K, Sood M, et al. Neurostimulation for abdominal pain&#x2010;related functional gastrointestinal disorders in adolescents: a randomised, double&#x2010;blind, sham&#x2010;controlled trial. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;2(10):727&#x2010;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28826627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasaelap A, Sood MR, Li BUK, et al. Efficacy of auricular neurostimulation in adolescents with irritable bowel syndrome in a randomized, double&#x2010;blind trial. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;18(9):1987&#x2010;1994.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31622740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamphorst K, Vlieger AM, Oosterloo BC, Garssen J, van Elburg RM. Neonatal antibiotics and food allergy are associated with FGIDs at 4&#x2010;6 years of age. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2022;74(6):770&#x2010;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35588166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uusij&#xe4;rvi A, Bergstr&#xf6;m A, Simr&#xe9;n M, et al. Use of antibiotics in infancy and childhood and risk of recurrent abdominal pain&#x2014;a Swedish birth cohort study. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2014;26(6):841&#x2010;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24708246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x15f;t&#xfc;rk A, Artan R, Y&#x131;lmaz A. Efficacy of synbiotic, probiotic, and prebiotic treatments for irritable bowel syndrome in children: a randomized controlled trial. Turk J Gastroenterol. 2016;27(5):439&#x2010;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27782892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Eftekhari K, Vahedi Z, Kamali Aghdam M, Noemi Diaz D. A randomized double&#x2010;blind placebo&#x2010;controlled trial of <i>Lactobacillus reuteri</i> for chronic functional abdominal pain in children. Iran J Ped. 2015;25(6):e2616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26635937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Francavilla R, Miniello V, Magist&#xe0; AM, et al. A randomized controlled trial of <i>Lactobacillus</i> GG in children with functional abdominal pain. Pediatrics. 2010;126(6):e1445&#x2010;e1452.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21078735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gawro&#x144;ska A, Dziechciarz P, Horvath A, Szajewska H. A randomized double&#x2010;blind placebo&#x2010;controlled trial of <i>Lactobacillus</i> GG for abdominal pain disorders in children. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;25(2):177&#x2010;184.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannetti E, Maglione M, Alessandrella A, et al. A mixture of 3 bifidobacteria decreases abdominal pain and improves the quality of life in children with irritable bowel syndrome: a multicenter, randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled, crossover trial. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2017;51(1):e5&#x2010;e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guandalini S, Magazz&#xf9; G, Chiaro A, et al. VSL#3 improves symptoms in children with irritable bowel syndrome: a multicenter, randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled, double&#x2010;blind, crossover study. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2010;51(1):24&#x2010;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20453678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Jadre&#x161;in O, Hojsak I, Mi&#x161;ak Z, et al. 
<i>Lactobacillus reuteri</i> DSM 17938 in the treatment of functional abdominal pain in children: RCT study. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2017;64(6):925&#x2010;929.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27906800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Jadre&#x161;in O, Sila S, Trivi&#x107; I, Mi&#x161;ak Z, Kola&#x10d;ek S, Hojsak I. 
<i>Lactobacillus reuteri</i> DSM 17938 is effective in the treatment of functional abdominal pain in children: results of the double&#x2010;blind randomized study. Clin Nutr. 2020;39(12):3645&#x2010;3651.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari SS, Hashemi SM, Sadeghi B, Almasi&#x2010;Hashiani A. Ability of polymicrobial probiotic and mono&#x2010;strain probiotic to reduce functional abdominal pain in children: a randomized clinical trial. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2022;65(12):589&#x2010;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9742761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36457200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Maragkoudaki M, Chouliaras G, Orel R, Horvath A, Szajewska H, Papadopoulou A. 
<i>Lactobacillus reuteri</i> DSM 17938 and a placebo both significantly reduced symptoms in children with functional abdominal pain. Acta Paediatr (Stockholm). 2017;106(11):1857&#x2010;1862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28712129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani P, Ghouran&#x2010;Orimi A, Motamed F, Moradzadeh A. Evaluating the effects of probiotics in pediatrics with recurrent abdominal pain. Clin Exp Pediatr. 2020;63(12):485&#x2010;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7738771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32718147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Romano C, Ferrau' V, Cavataio F, et al. 
<i>Lactobacillus reuteri</i> in children with functional abdominal pain (FAP). J Paediatr Child Health. 2014;50(10):E68&#x2010;E71.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20626584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sabbi T. PP223&#x2010;MON the use of <i>Lactobacillus</i> GG in children with functional abdominal pain: a double&#x2010;blind randomized control trial. Clin Nutr Suppl. 2011;6:198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
V&#xe1;zquez&#x2010;Frias R, Consuelo&#x2010;S&#xe1;nchez A, Acosta&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Bueno CP, et al. Efficacy and safety of the adjuvant use of probiotic <i>Bacillus clausii</i> strains in pediatric irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled study. Pediatric Drugs. 2023;25(1):115&#x2010;126.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9666949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36380186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Weizman Z, Abu&#x2010;Abed J, Binsztok M. 
<i>Lactobacillus reuteri</i> DSM 17938 for the management of functional abdominal pain in childhood: a randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. J Pediatr. 2016;174:160&#x2010;164.e1.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27156182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Asgarshirazi M, Shariat M, Dalili H. Comparison of the effects of pH&#x2010;dependent peppermint oil and synbiotic lactol (<i>Bacillus coagulans</i> + fructooligosaccharides) on childhood functional abdominal pain: a randomized placebo&#x2010;controlled study. Iran Red Crescent Med J. 2015;17(4):e23844.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4443394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26023339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bausserman M, Michail S. The use of <i>Lactobacillus</i> GG in irritable bowel syndrome in children: a double&#x2010;blind randomized control trial. J Pediatr. 2005;147(2):197&#x2010;201.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16126049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholizadeh A, Mehrabani S, Esmaeili Dooki M, Haji Ahmadi M. Effect of a synbiotic on functional abdominal pain in childhood. Caspian J Intern Med. 2021;12(2):194&#x2010;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8111801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kianifar H, Jafari SA, Kiani M, et al. Probiotic for irritable bowel syndrome in pediatric patients: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Electron Physician. 2015;7(5):1255&#x2010;1260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4590561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26435825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otuzbir A, Ozkan TB, Ozgur T, Sahin U, Altay D, Budak F, et al. Efficiency and immunologic effects of synbiotics in children with functional abdominal pain. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2016;62:426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Saneian H, Pourmoghaddas Z, Roohafza H, Gholamrezaei A. Synbiotic containing <i>Bacillus coagulans</i> and fructo&#x2010;oligosaccharides for functional abdominal pain in children. Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench. 2015;8(1):56&#x2010;65.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4285933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25584177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sudha MR, Jayanthi N, Aasin M, Dhanashri RD, Anirudh T. Efficacy of <i>Bacillus coagulans</i> unique IS2 in treatment of irritable bowel syndrome in children: a double blind, randomised placebo controlled study. Benef Microbes. 2018;9(4):563&#x2010;572.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Nieuwboer M, Brummer RJ, Guarner F, Morelli L, Cabana M, Claassen E. Safety of probiotics and synbiotics in children under 18 years of age. Benef Microbes. 2015;6(5):615&#x2010;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25809217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline RM, Kline JJ, Di Palma J, Barbero GJ. Enteric&#x2010;coated, pH&#x2010;dependent peppermint oil capsules for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome in children. J Pediatr. 2001;138(1):125&#x2010;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingrosso MR, Ianiro G, Nee J, et al. Systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis: efficacy of peppermint oil in irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;56(6):932&#x2010;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35942669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannister K, Dickenson AH. What do monoamines do in pain modulation? Curr Opin Support Palliat Care. 2016;10(2):143&#x2010;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5604728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27043287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bushnell MC, &#x10c;eko M, Low LA. Cognitive and emotional control of pain and its disruption in chronic pain. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14(7):502&#x2010;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23719569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer EA, Labus JS, Tillisch K, Cole SW, Baldi P. Towards a systems view of IBS. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2015;12(10):592&#x2010;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5001844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26303675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Oudenhove L, Crowell MD, Drossman DA, et al Biopsychosocial aspects of functional gastrointestinal disorders. Gastroenterology. 2016:150(6):1355&#x2010;1367.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8809487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahar RJ, Collins BS, Steinmetz B, Ament ME. Double&#x2010;blind placebo&#x2010;controlled trial of amitriptyline for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome in adolescents. J Pediatr. 2008;152(5):685&#x2010;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18410774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saps M, Youssef N, Miranda A, et al. Multicenter, randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial of amitriptyline in children with functional gastrointestinal disorders. Gastroenterology. 2009;137(4):1261&#x2010;1269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2827243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19596010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seetharaman J, Poddar U, Yachha SK, Srivastava A, Sen Sarma M. Efficacy of amitriptyline in pediatric functional abdominal pain disorders: a randomized placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;37(4):685&#x2010;691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34935191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Lacy BE, Harris LA, Quigley EMM, Moayyedi P. Effect of antidepressants and psychological therapies in irritable bowel syndrome: an updated systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2019;114(1):21&#x2010;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30177784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puoti MG, Assa A, Benninga M, et al. Drugs in focus: domperidone. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2023;77(2):e13&#x2010;e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37159421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karunanayake A, Rajindrajith S, Silva HA, Gunawardena S, Devanarayana NM. Autonomic functions and gastric motility in children with functional abdominal pain disorders. World J Gastroenterol. 2019;25(1):95&#x2010;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6328964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30643361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karunanayake A, Devanarayana NM, de Silva A, Gunawardena S, Rajindrajith S. Randomized controlled clinical trial on value of domperidone in functional abdominal pain in children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2018;66(5):725&#x2010;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29112086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavakoli Haghighiand N, Mehrabani S, Esmaeili Dooki M, et al. Effect of domperidone on children with functional abdominal pain: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Shiraz E&#x2010;Med J. 2023;24(2):e128504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milo R. Use of the peripheral dopamine antagonist, domperidone, in the management of gastro&#x2010;intestinal symptoms in patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Curr Med Res Opin. 1980;6(9):577&#x2010;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6996928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junqueira DR, Bennett D, Huh SY, Fahrbach K, Neupane B, Betts M. Risk of adverse events associated with domperidone and metoclopramide in gastroparesis: systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Drugs R&amp;D. 2023;23(1):1&#x2010;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36749528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez L, Diaz J, Nurko S. Safety and efficacy of cyproheptadine for treating dyspeptic symptoms in children. J Pediatr. 2013;163(1):261&#x2010;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3661691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23419589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghian M, Farahmand F, Fallahi GH, Abbasi A. Cyproheptadine for the treatment of functional abdominal pain in childhood: a double&#x2010;blinded randomized placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Minerva Pediatr. 2008;60(6):1367&#x2010;1374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18971897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojsak I, Benninga MA, Hauser B, et al. Benefits of dietary fibre for children in health and disease. Arch Dis Child. 2022;107(11):973&#x2010;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9606532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35277379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill SK, Rossi M, Bajka B, Whelan K. Dietary fibre in gastrointestinal health and disease. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;18(2):101&#x2010;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland I, Gibson G, Heinken A, et al. Gut microbiota functions: metabolism of nutrients and other food components. Eur J Nutr. 2018;57(1):1&#x2010;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5847071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28393285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman W. The use of dietary fiber in the management of simple, childhood, idiopathic, recurrent, abdominal pain. Results in a prospective, double&#x2010;blind, randomized, controlled trial. Am J Dis Child. 1985;139(12):1216&#x2010;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2998181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath A. Glucomannan for abdominal pain&#x2010;related functional gastrointestinal disorders in children: a randomized trial. World J Gastroenterol. 2013;19(20):3062&#x2010;3068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3662945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23716985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon J, Thapa BR, Kumari R, Puttaiah Kadyada S, Rana S, Lal SB. Efficacy of oral psyllium in pediatric irritable bowel syndrome: a double&#x2010;blind randomized control trial. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2023;76(1):14&#x2010;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36136861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano C. Partially hydrolyzed guar gum in pediatric functional abdominal pain. World J Gastroenterol. 2013;19(2):235&#x2010;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3547554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23345946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shulman RJ, Hollister EB, Cain K, et al. Psyllium fiber reduces abdominal pain in children with irritable bowel syndrome in a randomized, double&#x2010;blind trial. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15(5):712&#x2010;719.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5064811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27080737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tack J, Van Den Elzen B, Tytgat G, et al. A placebo&#x2010;controlled trial of the 5&#x2010;HT1A agonist R&#x2010;137696 on symptoms, visceral hypersensitivity and on impaired accommodation in functional dyspepsia. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2009;21(6):619&#x2010;626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19220756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkman HP, Yates KP, Sarosiek I, et al. Buspirone for early satiety and symptoms of gastroparesis: a multi&#x2010;centre, randomised, placebo&#x2010;controlled, double&#x2010;masked trial (BESST). Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2023;57(11):1272&#x2010;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10202558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badihian N, Yaghini O, Badihian S, Shahsanai A, Saneian H. Comparison of the efficacy of buspirone and placebo in childhood functional abdominal pain: a randomized clinical trial. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115(5):756&#x2010;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32221160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Den Hertog A, Van den Akker J. Modification of &#x3b1;1&#x2010;receptor&#x2010;operated channels by mebeverine in smooth muscle cells of guinea&#x2010;pig taenia caeci. Eur J Pharmacol. 1987;138(3):367&#x2010;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2442008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenslade FC, Newquist KL, Krider KM, Chasin M, Scott CK. Heterogeneity of biochemical actions among vasodilators. J Pharm Sci. 1982;71(1):94&#x2010;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6276530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patai Z, Guttman A, Mikus EG. Potential L&#x2010;type voltage&#x2010;operated calcium channel blocking effect of drotaverine on functional models. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2016;359(3):442&#x2010;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27738091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourmoghaddas Z, Saneian H, Roohafza H, Gholamrezaei A. Mebeverine for pediatric functional abdominal pain: a randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. BioMed Res Int. 2014;2014:191026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4095832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25089264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narang M, Shah D, Akhtar H. Efficacy and safety of drotaverine hydrochloride in children with recurrent abdominal pain: a randomized placebo controlled trial. Indian Pediatr. 2015;52(10):847&#x2010;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26499007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darvish&#x2010;Damavandi M. A systematic review of efficacy and tolerability of mebeverine in irritable bowel syndrome. World J Gastroenterol. 2010;16(5):547&#x2010;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2816265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20128021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grondin JA, Khan WI. Emerging roles of gut serotonin in regulation of immune response, microbiota composition and intestinal inflammation. J Can Assoc Gastroenterol. 2023;7(1):88&#x2010;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10836984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38314177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roohafza H, Pourmoghaddas Z, Saneian H, Gholamrezaei A. Citalopram for pediatric functional abdominal pain: a randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2014;26(11):1642&#x2010;1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25244442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruepert L, Quartero AO, de Wit NJ, et al Bulking agents, antispasmodics and antidepressants for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;2011(8):Cd003460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8745618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21833945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans S, Lung KC, Seidman LC, Sternlieb B, Zeltzer LK, Tsao JCI. Iyengar yoga for adolescents and young adults with irritable bowel syndrome. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2014;59(2):244&#x2010;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4146428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25025601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gstr&#xf6;m S, Philipson A, Ekstav L, et al. Dance and yoga reduced functional abdominal pain in young girls: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Pain. 2022;26(2):336&#x2010;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34529293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korterink JJ, Ockeloen LE, Hilbink M, Benninga MA, Deckers&#x2010;Kocken JM. Yoga therapy for abdominal pain&#x2010;related functional gastrointestinal disorders in children: a randomized controlled trial. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2016;63(5):481&#x2010;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27050045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuttner L, Chambers CT, Hardial J, Israel DM, Jacobson K, Evans K. A randomized trial of yoga for adolescents with irritable bowel syndrome. Pain Res Manag. 2006;11(4):217&#x2010;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2673138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17149454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue H, Shao S. Effect of acupuncture combined with Astragalus injection on peripheral blood inflammatory factors in children with diarrhea&#x2010;predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Eur J Inflamm. 2019;17:2058739219853689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
IngoC
. <i>Auswirkungen Osteopathischer Behandlung bei Kindern mit funktionellen Bauchschmerzen: Eine klinische Studie mit 32 Kindern und Jugendlichen im Alter von 6 bis 18 Jahren, in Osteopathie Schule</i>. Dissertation. Dresden International University; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boradyn KM, Przyby&#x142;owicz KE, Jarocka&#x2010;Cyrta E. Low FODMAP diet is not effective in children with functional abdominal pain: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Nutr Metab. 2020;76(5):334&#x2010;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33075788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumpitazi BP, Cope JL, Hollister EB, et al. Randomised clinical trial: gut microbiome biomarkers are associated with clinical response to a low FODMAP diet in children with the irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2015;42(4):418&#x2010;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4514898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26104013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumpitazi BP, McMeans AR, Vaughan A, et al. Fructans exacerbate symptoms in a subset of children with irritable bowel syndrome. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;16(2):219&#x2010;225.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5794652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth S, Klodt C, Wintermeyer P, et al. Positive or negative fructose breath test results do not predict response to fructose restricted diet in children with recurrent abdominal pain: results from a prospective randomized trial. Klin Padiatr. 2014;226(5):268&#x2010;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrouk R, Herdes RE, Karpinski AC, Hyman PE. Serum&#x2010;derived bovine immunoglobulin for children with diarrhea&#x2010;predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Pediatr Health Med Ther. 2018;9:129&#x2010;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6207257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30498390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins BS, Lin HC. Double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled antibiotic treatment study of small intestinal bacterial overgrowth in children with chronic abdominal pain. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2011;52(4):382&#x2010;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21240023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Heyland K, Friedt M, Buehr P, Braegger CP. No advantage for antibiotic treatment over placebo in <i>Blastocystis hominis</i>&#x2010;positive children with recurrent abdominal pain. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2012;54(5):677&#x2010;679.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut GS, Be&#x15f;er &#xd6;F, Ergin&#xf6;z E, Kutlu T, &#xc7;oku&#x11f;ra&#x15f; F&#xc7;, Erkan T. The incidence of irritable bowel syndrome in children using the Rome III criteria and the effect of trimebutine treatment. J Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2013;19(1):90&#x2010;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3548133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23350053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dipasquale V, Palermo L, Barbalace A, Tumminello G, Romano C. Randomised controlled trial of melatonin for paediatric functional abdominal pain disorders. J Paediatr Child Health. 2023;59(3):458&#x2010;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36624990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Amrousy D, Hassan S, El Ashry H, Yousef M, Hodeib H. Vitamin D supplementation in adolescents with irritable bowel syndrome: is it useful? A randomized controlled trial. Saudi J Gastroenterol. 2018;24(2):109&#x2010;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5900470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29637918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francavilla R, Cristofori F, Verzillo L, et al. Randomized double&#x2010;blind placebo&#x2010;controlled crossover trial for the diagnosis of non&#x2010;celiac gluten sensitivity in children. Am J Gastroenterol. 2018;113(3):421&#x2010;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29380821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe4;vo B, Stenstam M, Nielsen A&#x2010;L. Loperamide in treatment of irritable bowel syndrome&#x2014;a double&#x2010;blind placebo controlled study. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1987;22(sup130):77&#x2010;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3306903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovdenak N. Loperamide treatment of the irritable bowel syndrome. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1987;22(sup130):81&#x2010;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3306904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M, Vijayvargiya P. The role of bile acids in chronic diarrhea. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115(10):1596&#x2010;1603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7541465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayvargiya P, Camilleri M, Carlson P, et al. Effects of colesevelam on bowel symptoms, biomarkers, and colonic mucosal gene expression in patients with bile acid diarrhea in a randomized trial. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;18(13):2962&#x2010;2970.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7442687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32088296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoekman DR, Zeevenhooven J, van Etten&#x2010;Jamaludin FS, et al. The placebo response in pediatric abdominal pain&#x2010;related functional gastrointestinal disorders: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Pediatr. 2017;182:155&#x2010;163.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster Forum &#x2013; Living Guidelines. Accessed March 26, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>