<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40951542</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1756-2856</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in neurological disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Neurol Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>GLP-1 receptor agonists in Parkinson's disease progression: a meta-analysis with trial sequential analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17562864251372747</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17562864251372747</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17562864251372747</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17562864251372747</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists (GLP-1 RAs) have emerged as potential neuroprotective agents for Parkinson's disease (PD). However, evidence regarding their efficacy remains inconclusive.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To assess the therapeutic effects and safety profile of GLP-1 RAs in patients with mild-to-moderate PD. We aim to conduct an updated systematic review to evaluate the effects of GLP-1 RAs in patients with mild-to-moderate PD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) with trial sequential analysis (TSA) and Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluations certainty assessment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PubMed, Embase, and the Cochrane Library were searched through April 14, 2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of RCTs with TSA comparing GLP-1 RAs to placebo in patients with mild-to-moderate PD. The primary outcome was change in the Movement Disorder Society-unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale (MDS-UPDRS) scores.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Five RCTs involving a total of 708 nondiabetic patients with mild-to-moderate PD were included. GLP-1 RAs significantly attenuated motor symptom progression, as evidenced by a mean difference in MDS-UPDRS Part III (off medication) of -2.06 (95% confidence interval (CI): -4.09; -0.03; <i>I</i> <sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;56%), with conclusive evidence supported by TSA. No statistically significant improvements were observed in other MDS-UPDRS domains, levodopa equivalent daily dose reduction, or functional scales (Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-39, Non-Motor Symptoms Scale for Parkinson's Disease, UDysRS). A nonsignificant trend toward increased serious adverse events or treatment discontinuation was observed (odds ratio&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.52; 95% CI: 0.66; 3.50), with low heterogeneity. TSA for secondary outcomes indicated that additional trials are required.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">GLP-1 RAs may provide a modest benefit in slowing motor progression in PD. However, their effects on nonmotor symptoms, medication use, and long-term safety remain uncertain due to the limited number of available trials. Further large-scale, long-duration trials are warranted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">INPLASY2024110119.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsai</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Wen</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1484-8016</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Chi-Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Hsien</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Chi-Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jheng-Yan</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chuang</LastName><ForeName>Min-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jui-Yi</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Nutrition, Chia Nan University of Pharmacy and Science, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care Medicine, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hung</LastName><ForeName>Kuo Chuan</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Chi Mei Medical Center, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Meng-Tsang</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Chi Mei Medical Center, No. 901, Zhonghua Road, Yongkang District, Tainan City 710, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ther Adv Neurol Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101480242</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-2856</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Can diabetes drugs help slow Parkinson&#x2019;s disease? Parkinson&#x2019;s disease is a brain disorder that worsens over time, causing problems with movement, balance, and daily functioning. Current treatments can reduce symptoms, but they do not slow the progression of the disease. Recently, drugs originally designed for diabetes&#x2014;called GLP-1 receptor agonists&#x2014;have shown promise in protecting brain cells. In this study, we analyzed data from five clinical trials involving 708 people with early to moderate Parkinson&#x2019;s disease who did not have diabetes. We compared patients who received GLP-1 drugs with those who received a placebo. Our results showed that people taking GLP-1 drugs had slightly slower worsening of movement symptoms. However, the effect on other symptoms and medication needs was unclear. There were also some concerns about side effects, especially with higher doses. These findings suggest that GLP-1 drugs may offer a new way to help manage Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Larger, long-term studies are needed to confirm these benefits and better understand safety risks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2025.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GLP-1 RAs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroprotection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40951542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12426393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17562864251372747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_17562864251372747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tanner CM, Ostrem JL. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. N Engl J Med 2024; 391: 442&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39083773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahn S, Oakes D, Shoulson I, et al. Levodopa and the progression of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. N Engl J Med 2004; 351: 2498&#x2013;2508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15590952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabresi P, Di Filippo M, Ghiglieri V, et al. Levodopa-induced dyskinesias in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: filling the bench-to-bedside gap. Lancet Neurol 2010; 9: 1106&#x2013;1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20880751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo-Moreno T, Garc&#xed;a-Morales V, Suleiman-Martos S, et al. Current treatments and new, tentative therapies for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Pharmaceutics 2023; 15: 770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10051786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36986631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nauck MA, Quast DR, Wefers J, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists in the treatment of type 2 diabetes&#x2014;state-of-the-art. Mol Metab 2021; 46: 101102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8085572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33068776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang V, Tseng KY, Kuo TT, et al. Attenuating mitochondrial dysfunction and morphological disruption with PT320 delays dopamine degeneration in MitoPark mice. J Biomed Sci 2024; 31: 38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11022395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38627765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv R, Zhao Y, Wang X, et al. GLP-1 analogue liraglutide attenuates CIH-induced cognitive deficits by inhibiting oxidative stress, neuroinflammation, and apoptosis via the Nrf2/HO-1 and MAPK/NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathways. Int Immunopharmacol 2024; 142: 113222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39321702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopp KO, Li Y, Glotfelty EJ, et al. Incretin-based multi-agonist peptides are neuroprotective and anti-inflammatory in cellular models of neurodegeneration. Biomolecules 2024; 14: 872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11275108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39062586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athauda D, Foltynie T. The glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP) receptor as a therapeutic target in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: mechanisms of action. Drug Discov Today 2016; 21: 802&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Zheng J, Li S, et al. GLP-1 improves the neuronal supportive ability of astrocytes in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease by regulating mitochondrial dysfunction via the cAMP/PKA pathway. Biochem Pharmacol 2021; 188: 114578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33895160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aviles-Olmos I, Dickson J, Kefalopoulou Z, et al. Exenatide and the treatment of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Clin Invest 2013; 123: 2730&#x2013;2736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3668846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athauda D, Maclagan K, Skene SS, et al. Exenatide once weekly versus placebo in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet (London, England) 2017; 390: 1664&#x2013;1675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28781108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGarry A, Rosanbalm S, Leinonen M, et al. Safety, tolerability, and efficacy of NLY01 in early untreated Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol 2024; 23: 37&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38101901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meissner WG, Remy P, Giordana C, et al. Trial of lixisenatide in early parkinson&#x2019;s disease. N Engl J Med 2024; 390: 1176&#x2013;1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38598572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
jRCT J. Phase 2 study of oral semaglutide tablet for patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Trial registry record. https://trialsearchwhoint/Trial2aspx?TrialID=JPRN-jRCT2051230090 (2023, accessed 4 September 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagliati M, Hogg E, Tan E, et al. A phase II, randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial of liraglutide in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Parkinson&#x2019;s Dis 2016; 6: 218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulvaney CA, Duarte GS, Handley J, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020; 7: Cd012990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Albuquerque MB, Nunes LEDB, De Oliveira Maldonado JV, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: an updated meta-analysis. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2025; 130: 107220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39642803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021; 372: n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019; 366: l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balduzzi S, R&#xfc;cker G, Schwarzer G. How to perform a meta-analysis with R: a practical tutorial. Evid Based Ment Health 2019; 22: 153&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10231495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31563865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JPT, Altman DG, et al. Chapter 10: Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. (eds) Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 63 (updated February 2022). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2022, pp.241&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Higgins JPT, Sterne JAC. Assessing risk of bias due to missing results in a synthesis. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. (eds) Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2nd ed. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2019, pp.349&#x2013;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetterslev J, Thorlund K, Brok J, et al. Trial sequential analysis may establish when firm evidence is reached in cumulative meta-analysis. J Clin Epidemiol 2008; 61: 64&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao S-C, Kuo L-T, Huang Y-T, et al. Using grading of recommendations assessment, development, and evaluation (GRADE) to rate the certainty of evidence of study outcomes from systematic reviews: a quick tutorial. Dermatol Sin 2023; 41: 3&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brignardello-Petersen R, Guyatt GH, Mustafa RA, et al. GRADE guidelines 33: addressing imprecision in a network meta-analysis. J Clin Epidemiol 2021; 139: 49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34293434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijiaratnam N, Girges C, Auld G, et al. Exenatide once a week versus placebo as a potential disease-modifying treatment for people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in the UK: a phase 3, multicentre, double-blind, parallel-group, randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet 2025; 405: 627&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39919773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aviles-Olmos I, Dickson J, Kefalopoulou Z, et al. Motor and cognitive advantages persist 12 months after exenatide exposure in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Parkinsons Dis 2014; 4: 337&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athauda D, Budnik N, Chowdhury K, et al. The effect of exenatide on specific non-motor symptoms in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease&#x2014;a post-hoc analysis. Eur J Neurol 2018; 25: 309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29843254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athauda D, Gulyani S, Karnati HK, et al. Utility of neuronal-derived exosomes to examine molecular mechanisms that affect motor function in patients with Parkinson disease: a secondary analysis of the exenatide-PD trial. JAMA Neurol 2019; 76: 420&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6459135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30640362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sango K, Takaku S, Tsukamoto M, et al. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists as potential myelination-inducible and anti-demyelinating remedies. Front Cell Dev Biol 2022; 10: 950623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9298969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti G, Gomes Moreira D, Richner M, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists in neurodegeneration: neurovascular unit in the spotlight. Cells 2022; 11: 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9265397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35805109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahiya S, Tisch S, Greenfield J. The effect of GLP-1 receptor agonists in pre-clinical rodent models of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Park Relat Disord 2022; 6: 100133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8804263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie D, Shen Q, Zhou J, et al. Non-motor symptoms are associated with REM sleep behavior disorder in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurol Sci 2021; 42: 47&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33025325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Chen J, Wang L, et al. Association between different GLP-1 receptor agonists and gastrointestinal adverse reactions: a real-world disproportionality study based on FDA adverse event reporting system database. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2022; 13: 1043789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9770009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36568085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng SL, Roddick AJ, Aghar-Jaffar R, et al. Association between use of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors, glucagon-like peptide 1 agonists, and dipeptidyl peptidase 4 inhibitors with all-cause mortality in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA 2018; 319: 1580&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5933330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29677303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams J, Mari Z, Pontone G, et al. Natural history of UPDRS motor scores in an observational Parkinson&#x2019;s disease cohort (S22.004). Neurology 2012; 78: S22.004-S022.004.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>