<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39875940</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-administered active versus sham acupressure for diarrhea predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a nurse-led randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-024-02594-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome (IBS-D) significantly impacts patients' quality of life, with existing treatments offering limited relief. Self-administered acupressure presents a potential non-invasive, cost-effective treatment option that could alleviate symptoms and enhance health outcomes in these patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This randomized controlled trial aimed to evaluate the effect of active acupressure compared to sham acupressure on primary and secondary outcomes among IBS-D patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study included 63 patients with IBS-D, recruited from Alexandria Main University Hospital, Egypt. Participants were randomized into either an active acupressure group or a sham acupressure group. Both groups underwent two days of training, followed by four weeks of intervention. The active group applied pressure to specific therapeutic acupoints, while the sham group used non-therapeutic points. Outcomes were assessed at baseline, week 2, and week 4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The active acupressure group showed a significant reduction in symptom severity, improved stool consistency, and frequency, and greater adequate symptom relief by week 4 compared to the sham group. Psychological outcomes, including anxiety and depression, also improved significantly in the active group. Additionally, the active group reported reduced use of rescue medications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Active acupressure is an effective nursing intervention for alleviating symptoms of IBS-D, particularly when applied consistently over time. It improves both physical and psychological outcomes, offering a valuable non-pharmacological treatment option.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nurses can integrate self-administered acupressure into IBS-D care plans, teaching patients this technique to manage symptoms independently, thus enhancing their quality of life (QOL) and reducing reliance on conventional medications. This intervention aligns with holistic nursing care and offers a cost-effective, patient-friendly solution for managing IBS-D.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study was prospectively registered as a randomized controlled trial in https://clinicaltrials.gov/ Registration Date: January 7, 2023, Registration Number: NCT05702255.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asal</LastName><ForeName>Maha Gamal Ramadan</ForeName><Initials>MGR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9348-8898</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Surgical Nursing Department, Faculty of Nursing, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Sayed</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed Abdelwahab Ibrahim</ForeName><Initials>AAI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9124-0808</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Administration Department, Faculty of Nursing, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt. ahmed-abdelwahab@alexu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsenany</LastName><ForeName>Samira Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-2811-0458</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Department, Faculty of Nursing, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramzy</LastName><ForeName>Zahraa Hassan</ForeName><Initials>ZH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Surgical Nursing Department, Faculty of Nursing, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dawood</LastName><ForeName>Rasha Fathy Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>RFA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2727-0794</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Surgical Nursing Department, Faculty of Nursing, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05702255</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Active acupressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diarrhea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nurse led Trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing Care.</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sham acupressure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Before initiating the study, the Research Ethics Committee, Faculty of Nursing, Alexandria University, Egypt (IRB00013620, SN:2022-9-55) authorized the study protocol on September 13, 2022. It was registered on Clinicaltrials.gov under the registration number NCT05702255 on January 7, 2023. Following an explanation of the study&#x2019;s purpose, each study participant signed informed consent. Participants&#x2019; data was kept confidential, and the study participants&#x2019; privacy was respected. Participants were informed that their participation was completely optional and that they might opt out of the study at any time without any harmful consequences. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39875940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11776273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-024-02594-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-024-02594-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Colomier E, Algera J, Melchior C. Pharmacological therapies and their clinical targets in irritable bowel syndrome with Diarrhea. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canavan C, West J, Card T. Review article: the economic impact of the irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2014;40:1023&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25199904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucak S, Chang L, Halpert A, Harris LA. Current and emergent pharmacologic treatments for irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea: evidence-based treatment in practice. Th Adv Gastroenterol. 2017;10:253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5298476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28203283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Mearin F, Chang L, Chey WD, Lembo AJ, Simren M, et al. Bowel disorders. Gastroenterology. 2016;150:1393&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enck P, Aziz Q, Barbara G, Farmer AD, Fukudo S, Mayer EA, et al. Irritable bowel syndrome. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2016;2:1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5001845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27159638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surdea-Blaga T, B&#x1ce;ban A, Dumitrascu DL. Psychosocial determinants of irritable bowel syndrome. World J Gastroenterol. 2012;18:616&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3281218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22363132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xe4;ndemark &#xc5;, T&#xf6;rnblom H, Jakobsson S, Simr&#xe9;n M. Work Productivity and Activity Impairment in Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS): a multifaceted problem. Am J Gastroenterol. 2018;113:1540&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30254230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodoory VC, Cho |, Ng E, Christopher |, Black J, Ford AC. Impact of Rome IV irritable bowel syndrome on work and activities of daily living. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;56:844&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9543519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassar GE, Youssef GJ, Knowles S, Moulding R, Austin DW. Health-related quality of life in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. Gastroenterol Nurs. 2020;43:E102&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32487960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Staller K, Barshop K, Dai E, Newman J, Yoon S, et al. Patients with irritable bowel syndrome-diarrhea have lower disease-specific quality of life than irritable bowel syndrome-constipation. World J Gastroenterol. 2015;21:8103&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4499353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26185382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE. Diagnosis and treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Int J Gen Med. 2016;9:7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4755466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26929659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farndale R, Roberts L. Long-term impact of irritable bowel syndrome: a qualitative study. Prim Health Care Res Dev. 2011;12:52&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21426615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetto S, Fagoonee S, Battaglia E, Grassini M, Saracco GM, Pellicano R. Recent advances in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Pol Arch Intern Med. 2021;131:709&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algera J, Colomier E, Simr&#xe9;n M. The Dietary Management of Patients with Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Narrative Review of the Existing and Emerging Evidence. Nutrients 2019, Vol 11, Page 2162. 2019;11:2162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31505870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Gru, fang Xie X. Peng C. Treatment of irritable bowel syndrome by Chinese Medicine: a review. Chin J Integr Med. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34546535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Zhang T, Cao Z, Tao Z, Wan T, Yao M, et al. Effects and mechanisms of acupuncture on Diarrhea-Predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review. Front Neurosci. 2022;16:1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9334728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35911986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz S, Chaitow L, Hymel GM. Focused Massage Application. Clinical massage in the Healthcare setting. Elsevier; 2008. pp. 314&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos LC, Machado JP, Monteiro FJ, Greten HJ. Understanding traditional Chinese medicine therapeutics: an overview of the basics and clinical applications. Healthcare. 2021;9:257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8000828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J-G, Kotha P, Chen Y-H. Understandings of acupuncture application and mechanisms. Am J Transl Res. 2022;14:1469&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8991130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inangil D, Inangil G. The effect of acupressure (GB30) on intramuscular injection pain and satisfaction: Single&#x2013;blind, randomised controlled study. J Clin Nurs. 2020;29:1094&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31891437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restawan IG, Sjattar EL, Irwan AM. Effectiveness of acupressure therapy in lowering blood pressure in patients with hypertension: a systematic review. Clin Epidemiol Glob Health. 2023;21:101292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, He T, Xu Q, Li Z, Liu Y, Li F, et al. Acupuncture and regulation of gastrointestinal function. World J Gastroenterology: WJG. 2015;21:8304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4507100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26217082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manheimer E, Wieland LS, Cheng K, Li SM, Shen X, Berman BM, et al. Acupuncture for irritable bowel syndrome: systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2012;107:835&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3671917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22488079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris LA, Heitkemper MM. Practical considerations for recognizing and managing severe irritable bowel syndrome. Gastroenterol Nurs. 2012;35:12&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22306725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung WF, Yu BY-MM, Chung K-FF, Zhang Z-JJ, Lao L, Ho FY-YY et al. Self-administered acupressure for insomnia disorder: a randomized controlled trial. Phytomedicine. 2022;99 September 2021:153993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35193046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S-M, Chen W-L, Tai C-J, Hsieh S-H, Lin C-K, Chen P-Y, et al. Effects of Self-Administered acupressure on fatigue following traumatic Brain Injury: a Randomized Controlled Trial. J Head Trauma Rehabilitation. 2023;38:E404&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang YY, Park H. Effects of auricular acupressure on the quality of sleep and anxiety in patients undergoing cardiac surgery: a single-blind, randomized controlled trial. Appl Nurs Res. 2020;53:151269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32451010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafabadi MM, Ghafari S, Nazari F, Valiani M. The effect of acupressure on quality of life among female nurses with chronic back pain. Appl Nurs Res. 2020;51:151175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31831270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maa S, Tsou T, Wang K, Wang C, Lin H, Huang Y. Self-administered acupressure reduces the symptoms that limit daily activities in bronchiectasis patients: pilot study findings. J Clin Nurs. 2007;16:794&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17402962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zick SM, Sen A, Wyatt GK, Murphy SL, Arnedt JT, Harris RE. Investigation of 2 types of self-administered acupressure for Persistent Cancer-related fatigue in breast Cancer survivors. JAMA Oncol. 2016;2:1470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27388752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung W-F, Chen S-C, Cheung DST, Wong CK-H, Chong TC, Ho YS, et al. Self-administered acupressure for probable knee osteoarthritis in Middle-aged and older adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7:e245830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11031685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38639940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo D, Ma S, Zhao Y, Dong J, Guo B, Li X. Self-administered acupressure and exercise for patients with osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2022;36:350&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34658285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Park H. Effects of auricular acupressure on pain and disability in adults with chronic neck pain. Appl Nurs Res. 2019;45:12&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30683245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Lenon GB, Li M, Yang AWH. Feasibility of self-administered acupressure for allergic rhinitis: a pilot randomized controlled trial and lessons learnt for future studies. Acupunct Med. 2022;40:142&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovliaei Bidgoli M, Tagharrobi Z, Sharifi K, Sooki Z, Momen-Heravi M, Zare Joshaghani F, et al. The effect of ear acupressure on occupational cognitive failure in nurses after the COVID-19 crisis: a randomized controlled clinical trial. BMC Nurs. 2024;23:457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11225119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaafari H, Houghton L, West R, Shuweihdi F, Nikolova S, Ford A, et al. O67 differences in dietary intake patterns contribute to variations in the worldwide prevalence and severity of irritable bowel syndrome. Oral presentations. BMJ Publishing Group Ltd and British Society of Gastroenterology; 2024. pp. A42&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal UC, Mustafa U, Goenka MK. Managing irritable bowel syndrome: balancing diet and pharmacotherapy. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2024;9:488&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho FF, Sun H, Zheng H, Wong DCN, Gao Y-Y, Mao C, et al. Association of healthy lifestyle behaviours with incident irritable bowel syndrome: a large population-based prospective cohort study. Gut. 2024;73:922&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38378250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams EA, Stimpson J, Wang D, Plummer S, Garaiova I, Barker ME, et al. Clinical trial: a multistrain probiotic preparation significantly reduces symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome in a double-blind placebo&#x2010;controlled study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2009;29:97&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18785988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen J-H, Ye Y-M, Zhu K-X, Li S-S. Acupuncture for diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized control study. World J Acupunct - Moxibustion. 2022;32:123&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Research Randomizer. https://www.randomizer.org/. Accessed 11 Sep 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui KKS, Nixon EE, Vangel MG, Liu J, Marina O, Napadow V, et al. Characterization of the deqi response in acupuncture. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2007;7:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2200650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17973984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Yang L, Su S, Piao MY, Li BL, Liang LX et al. The Diagnosis Performance of the TCM Syndromes of Irritable Bowel Syndrome by Gastroenterologists Based on Modified Simple Criteria Compared to TCM Practitioners: A Prospective, Multicenter Preliminary Study. Evidence-based Complementary and Alternative Medicine. 2020;2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32695213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joos S, Brinkhaus B, Maluche C, Maupai N, Kohnen R, Kraehmer N, et al. Acupuncture and moxibustion in the treatment of active Crohn&#x2019;s disease: a randomized controlled study. Digestion. 2004;69:131&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15114043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis CY, Morris J, Whorwell PJ. The irritable bowel severity scoring system: a simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 1997;11:395&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9146781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangel AW, Hahn BA, Heath AT, Northcutt AR, Kong S, Dukes GE, et al. Adequate relief as an endpoint in clinical trials in irritable bowel syndrome. J Int Med Res. 1998;26:76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9602985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinozaki M, Kanazawa M, Kano M, Endo Y, Nakaya N, Hongo M, et al. Effect of autogenic training on general improvement in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Appl Psychophysiol Biofeedback. 2010;35:189&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19997775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyra A, Hillil&#xe4; M, Huttunen T, M&#xe4;nnikk&#xf6; S, Taalikka M, Tennil&#xe4; J, et al. Irritable bowel syndrome symptom severity improves equally with probiotic and placebo. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22:10631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5192275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28082816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake MR, Raker JM, Whelan K. Validity and reliability of the Bristol Stool Form Scale in healthy adults and patients with diarrhoea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2016;44:693&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27492648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The Hospital anxiety and Depression Scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983;67:361&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6880820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brekelmans ACM, Ramnarain D, Pouwels S. Bereavement Support Programs in the Intensive Care Unit: a systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2022;64:e149&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terkawi A, Tsang S, Alkahtani G, Al-Mousa S, Al Musaed S, Alzoraigi U, et al. Development and validation of arabic version of the hospital anxiety and Depression Scale. Saudi J Anaesth. 2017;11:S11&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5463562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28616000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wal A, Debnath B, Verma N, Bhattacharya S, Shivajirao Solunke R, Masih Uzzaman Khan M, et al. Role of Herbal Medicine, Acupressure and acupuncture in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Acupuncture and moxibustion - recent advances, New perspectives, and applications [Working Title]. IntechOpen; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing L-Y, Qu L-X, Chen H, Gao S. [Clinical observation on acupressure at Jiaji points for irritable bowel syndrome]. Zhongguo Zhen Jiu. 2013;33:739&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24195220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Lu M, Zheng Y, Ma J, Ma X, Wang Y, et al. Quality of evidence supporting the role of acupuncture for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Pain Res Manag. 2021;2021:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8694972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34956431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang J, Zhang C, Guo Y, Zhao M, Zhang M et al. The efficacy and neural mechanism of acupuncture therapy in the treatment of visceral hypersensitivity in irritable bowel syndrome. Front Neurosci. 2023;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10507180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37732301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei L, Geng H, Guo J, Yang G, Wang L, Shen R et al. Effect of Acupuncture in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Mayo Clin Proc. 2020;95:1671&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Xing X, Wu J, Zhang H, Yun Y, Qin Z, et al. Acupuncture for adults with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome or functional diarrhea: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. Neural Plast. 2020;2020:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7705439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33299403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Rao K, Zhan K, Shen M, Zheng H, Qin S et al. Clinical evidence of acupuncture and moxibustion for irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Public Health. 2022;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9801330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes A, Jackson S, Walter C, Quraishi S, Jacyna M, Pitcher M. Acupuncture for irritable bowel syndrome: a blinded placebo-controlled trial. World J Gastroenterol. 2005;11:4040&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4502100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15996029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe C, Aiken A, Day AG, Depew W, Vanner SJ. Sham acupuncture is as efficacious as true acupuncture for the treatment of IBS: a randomized placebo controlled trial. Neurogastroenterology Motil. 2017;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T. Acupuncture for functional gastrointestinal disorders. J Gastroenterol. 2006;41:408&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16799881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Zheng H, Wang X, Wang X, Shi Y, Xie C, et al. Efficacy of acupuncture in refractory irritable bowel syndrome patients: a randomized controlled trial. Front Med. 2024. 10.1007/s11684-024-1073-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38958923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Ma Y, Ye S, Shu Z. Acupuncture for diarrhoea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a Network Meta-Analysis. Evidence-Based Complement Altern Med. 2018;2018:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5994265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29977312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan-Mohammadi F, Jafari H, Bagheri-Nesami M, Moosazadeh M, Kamali M, Esmaeili-Ahangarkelai N, et al. Effects of acupressure on intestinal function in patients with coronary artery bypass graft surgery: a randomized clinical trial. Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench. 2023;16:282&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10520391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37767324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go GY, Park H. Effects of Auricular Acupressure on Women with irritable bowel syndrome. Gastroenterol Nurs. 2020;43:E24&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong C, Han M, Zhang C, Zhao Z, Fang F, Zhang Z et al. Auricular point acupressure improved nausea, vomiting, diarrhea and nutritional status in gastric cancer patients receiving oral S-1 therapy. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabra N, Nadkarni A. Prevalence of depression and anxiety in irritable bowel syndrome: a clinic based study from India. Indian J Psychiatry. 2013;55:77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3574461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23439939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chitkara DK, van Tilburg MAL, Blois-Martin N, Whitehead WE. Early life risk factors that contribute to irritable bowel syndrome in adults: a systematic review. Official J Am Coll Gastroenterol | ACG. 2008;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3856200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18177446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EJ, Frazier SK. The efficacy of Acupressure for Symptom Management: a systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2011;42:589&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3154967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21531533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Shi X, Lv J, Zhang J, Huo Y, Zuo G et al. Acupuncture and related therapies for the anxiety and depression in irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea (IBS-D): a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9816906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36620677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani M, Sharma L, Advani U, Kumar S. Acupressure as an Adjunct to Pharmacological Treatment for Depression, anxiety, and stress in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. 2020;13:129&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Li Y, Liu D, Zou Y, Wang H, Pan L. Clinical rules of acupoint selection for cancer pain opioid-induced constipation based on journal literature data mining: a systematic review. Heliyon. 2024;10:e26170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10909647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38439874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au DWH, Tsang HWH, Ling PPM, Leung CHT, Ip PK, Cheung WM. Effects of Acupressure on anxiety: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. Acupunct Med. 2015;33:353&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26002571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monson E, Arney D, Benham B, Bird R, Elias E, Linden K, et al. Beyond pills: Acupressure Impact on Self-Rated Pain and anxiety scores. J Altern Complement Med. 2019;25:517&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6533784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30932686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mr&#xf3;z M, Czub M, Brytek-Matera A. Heart Rate Variability&#x2014;An Index of the efficacy of complementary therapies in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2022;14:3447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9416471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36014953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>