<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41024970</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1949-8462</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coronary computed tomography angiography <i>vs</i> stress testing for stable angina evaluation: Diagnostic and prognostic superiority.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>110061</StartPage><MedlinePgn>110061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4330/wjc.v17.i9.110061</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Stable angina pectoris, a clinical manifestation of coronary artery disease (CAD), is commonly evaluated using non-invasive diagnostic tools. Traditionally, stress testing modalities such as exercise electrocardiography (ECG), myocardial perfusion imaging (MPI), and stress echocardiography have been the first-line strategies. However, coronary computed tomography angiography (CCTA), an anatomic imaging modality, is increasingly used for its ability to directly visualize coronary artery stenoses and plaque burden. Despite growing adoption, the comparative effectiveness of CCTA and stress testing in terms of diagnostic accuracy, prognostic value, and clinical outcomes in stable angina remains an area of active debate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the diagnostic and prognostic performance of CCTA with various forms of stress testing in adult patients presenting with suspected or confirmed stable angina.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive literature search was performed across PubMed, EMBASE, Scopus, and the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials in accordance with the PRISMA guidelines. Only randomized controlled trials (RCT) published in English within the last 15 years were included. Studies involving adult patients (&#x2265; 18 years) with stable angina or low-risk chest pain were selected. The intervention was CCTA, and the comparators included ECG, MPI, and stress echocardiography. Data were extracted using a standardized process, and study quality was assessed using the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2.0 tool. Due to heterogeneity in outcome measures and modalities, narrative synthesis was employed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Five high-quality RCTs encompassing a total of 5551 patients were included. CCTA demonstrated superior diagnostic accuracy and prognostic capability across multiple studies. It was more effective in predicting major adverse cardiac events, including myocardial infarction and cardiac death, and was associated with fewer unnecessary invasive coronary angiographies and better event-free survival. Studies also reported improved revascularization rates in patients evaluated with CCTA, particularly within tiered diagnostic protocols. Stress testing, while useful, showed limitations in sensitivity and downstream clinical decision-making.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">CCTA offers a diagnostically superior and clinically impactful strategy for the initial evaluation of patients with stable angina, especially those with intermediate pretest probability of CAD. Compared to conventional stress testing, it enhances risk stratification, reduces unnecessary procedures, and may improve long-term outcomes. These findings support its broader integration into diagnostic pathways for stable angina.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gundareddy</LastName><ForeName>Vinay</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nathan Kline Institute for Psychiatric Research, Orangeburg, NY 10962, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singla</LastName><ForeName>Shivam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Tidal Health Peninsula Regional, Salisbury, NC 21801, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mounika</LastName><ForeName>Jupalle</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Kurnool Medical College, Kurnool 518002, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owona</LastName><ForeName>Okello</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ministry of Health, Lusaka 10101, Zambia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singla</LastName><ForeName>Bhavna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Erie County Medical Center, Buffalo, NY 14215, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Taranpreet</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Mahatma Gandhi Mission Medical College and Hospital, Navi Mumbai 410209, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anwar</LastName><ForeName>Sidra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Shaikh Zayed Hospital, Lahore 54600, Punjab, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramachandran</LastName><ForeName>Vignesh</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Melmaruvathur Adhiparasakthi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research, Melmaruvathur 603319, Tamil N&#x101;du, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ullah</LastName><ForeName>Hikmat</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Allama Iqbal Medical College, Lahore 54550, Punjab, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazari</LastName><ForeName>Shabbir</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Kabul Medical University, Kabul 100306, Afghanistan. shabbirmazari826@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101537090</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary computed tomography angiography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnostic accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Event-free survival</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardial perfusion imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-invasive cardiac imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Revascularization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stable angina</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress testing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41024970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12476583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4330/wjc.v17.i9.110061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>