<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40821221</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of Landiolol in the Treatment of Tachycardia in Patients With Sepsis and Septic Shock: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e88004</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e88004</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e88004</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.88004</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Landiolol is being investigated for its potential to manage septic shock (SS) and sepsis-related tachyarrhythmias (TA).&#x202f;We performed a systematic review and meta-analysis of three randomized controlled trials (RCTs) involving 473 patients with sepsis or SS, including those with TA, comparing landiolol to standard therapy-controlled (STC) groups.&#x202f;Standard therapy consisted of usual sepsis care &#xb1; placebo but excluded &#x3b2;-blockers in the control arms.&#x202f;MEDLINE, Embase, and Cochrane databases were searched for trial data extracted from published reports up to November 2024, excluding non-English reports. Quality assessment was performed per Cochrane recommendations. Risk ratios (RRs) and mean differences (MDs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were pooled across trials to evaluate the outcomes. The primary endpoints included heart rate (HR) at 96 hours, chosen because all three trials consistently recorded HR at this time point, allowing for uniform comparison despite additional time points being reported, and 28-day mortality.&#x202f;Secondary outcomes included atrial fibrillation (AF), hypotension, changes in Sequential Organ Failure Assessment score, and norepinephrine dose.&#x202f;Of the three RCTs, 473 patients were included, with an intervention-to-control arm ratio of approximately 1:1. A lower HR (MD: -6.36; 95% CI: -9.25, -3.47; p &lt; 0.0001; I&#xb2; = 0%) was observed in the landiolol group compared to the STC. Hypotension (RR: 3.62, 95% CI: 1.37, 9.58; p = 0.010; I&#xb2; = 5%) was significantly increased in patients who received landiolol when compared to STC, and 28-day mortality&#x202f;showed no significant difference between the groups&#x202f;(RR: 1.07; 95% CI: 0.72, 1.58; p = 0.74; I&#xb2; = 44%), as did AF (RR: 0.63; 95% CI: 0.25, 1.59; p = 0.33; I&#xb2; = 8%). Landiolol, a highly selective ultrashort-acting &#x3b2;1-blocker with distinct pharmacokinetic properties from esmolol, reduces HR in patients with sepsis-related TA without significantly affecting 28-day mortality. However, careful monitoring for hypotension is advised, given the absolute risk increase of 8.4% observed in treated patients. However, results should be interpreted cautiously as only three small trials underpin these results. To our knowledge, this is the first MA to focus exclusively on landiolol in this setting, offering drug-specific insights for critical care management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Paneer Selvam et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paneer Selvam</LastName><ForeName>Shivraj</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Cardiff University, Cardiff, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gamarra-Valverde</LastName><ForeName>Norma Nicole</ForeName><Initials>NN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia, Lima, PER.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripoli</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samaniego</LastName><ForeName>Miguel A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Universidad Aut&#xf3;noma Metropolitana, Mexico City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giorgi</LastName><ForeName>Juliana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Hospital Sirio-Libanes, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta-blocker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">landiolol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sepsis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">septic shock</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tachyarrhythmia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40821221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12352523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.88004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The association between tachycardia and mortality in septic shock patients according to serum lactate level: a nationwide multicenter cohort study. Na SJ, Oh DK, Park S, et al. J Korean Med Sci. 2023;38:313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10578996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37846786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Developing a new definition and assessing new clinical criteria for septic shock: for the Third International Consensus Definitions for Sepsis and Septic Shock (Sepsis-3) Shankar-Hari M, Phillips GS, Levy ML, et al. JAMA. 2016;315:775&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4910392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landiolol for heart rate control in patients with septic shock and persistent tachycardia. A multicenter randomized clinical trial (Landi-SEP) Rehberg S, Frank S, &#x10c;ern&#xfd; V, et al. Intensive Care Med. 2024;50:1622&#x2013;1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11447033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39297945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landiolol and organ failure in patients with septic shock: the stress-L randomized clinical trial. Whitehouse T, Hossain A, Perkins GD, et al. JAMA. 2023;330:1641&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10600724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37877587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of landiolol, an ultra-short-acting &#x3b2;1-selective antagonist, for treatment of sepsis-related tachyarrhythmia (J-Land 3S): a multicentre, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Kakihana Y, Nishida O, Taniguchi T, et al. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:863&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32243865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Third International Consensus Definitions for Sepsis and Septic Shock (Sepsis-3) Singer M, Deutschman CS, Seymour CW, et al. JAMA. 2016;315:801&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4968574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanisms of sepsis-induced cardiac dysfunction. Rudiger A, Singer M. Crit Care Med. 2007;35:1599&#x2013;1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17452940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of heart rate control with esmolol on hemodynamic and clinical outcomes in patients with septic shock: a randomized clinical trial. Morelli A, Ertmer C, Westphal M, et al. JAMA. 2013;310:1683&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landiolol has a less potent negative inotropic effect than esmolol in isolated rabbit hearts. Ikeshita K, Nishikawa K, Toriyama S, Yamashita T, Tani Y, Yamada T, Asada A. J Anesth. 2008;22:361&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landiolol: a review of its use in intraoperative and postoperative tachyarrhythmias. Plosker GL. Drugs. 2013;73:959&#x2013;977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23760735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surviving sepsis campaign: International Guidelines for Management of Sepsis and Septic Shock 2021. Evans L, Rhodes A, Alhazzani W, et al. Crit Care Med. 2021;49:1063&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34605781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Sterne JA. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions, Second Edition. Hoboken (NJ): Wiley; 2019. Assessing risk of bias in a randomized trial; pp. 205&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Review Manager (RevMan) 2020. https://revman.cochrane.org/info https://revman.cochrane.org/info</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of the &#x3b2;-adrenergic receptor antagonists landiolol and esmolol: receptor selectivity, partial agonism, and pharmacochaperoning actions. Nasrollahi-Shirazi S, Sucic S, Yang Q, Freissmuth M, Nanoff C. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2016;359:73&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27451411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of esmolol in septic shock patients with tachycardia: a randomized clinical trial. Liu H, Ding XF, Zhang SG, et al. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2019;99:1317&#x2013;1322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31091579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemodynamic and anti-inflammatory effects of early esmolol use in hyperkinetic septic shock: a pilot study. Levy B, Fritz C, Piona C, et al. Crit Care. 2021;25:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7791811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The efficacy and safety of esmolol for septic shock: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Huang P, Zheng X, Liu Z, Fang X. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:682232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8204042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of esmolol in sepsis: a meta-analysis based on randomized controlled trials. Wei Y, Bo F, Wang J, et al. BMC Anesthesiol. 2024;24:326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11391746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39266951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benefits of esmolol in adults with sepsis and septic shock: an updated meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Zhang J, Chen C, Liu Y, Yang Y, Yang X, Yang J. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022;101:29820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35801730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of ultrashort-acting &#x3b2;-blockers on mortality in patients with sepsis with persistent tachycardia despite initial resuscitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Hasegawa D, Sato R, Prasitlumkum N, Nishida K, Takahashi K, Yatabe T, Nishida O. Chest. 2021;159:2289&#x2013;2300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33434497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of beta blockers and mortality in adults with septic shock: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trial. V&#xe1;squez-Tirado GA, Quispe-Casta&#xf1;eda CV, Meregildo-Rodr&#xed;guez ED, et al. Front Med (Lausanne) 2024;11:1448573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11458450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39380732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortality in septic patients treated with short-acting betablockers: a comprehensive meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Alexandru MG, Niewald P, Kr&#xfc;ger S, et al. Crit Care. 2024;28:392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11603935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39605034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consensus on circulatory shock and hemodynamic monitoring. Task force of the European Society of Intensive Care Medicine. Cecconi M, De Backer D, Antonelli M, et al. Intensive Care Med. 2014;40:1795&#x2013;1815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4239778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25392034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>