<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40903851</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1463-1326</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetes, obesity &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetes Obes Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Early insulin degludec with continuous intravenous insulin infusion in the management of diabetic ketoacidosis: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/dom.70101</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the effectiveness and safety of early combination therapy with insulin degludec and intravenous insulin infusion (IVII) compared with IVII alone in diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This prospective, open-label, randomised controlled trial included 80 adults (&#x2265;18&#x2009;years) with DKA. Participants were randomised to either the intervention group, which received early subcutaneous (SC) insulin degludec (0.3&#x2009;units/kg SC within 3&#x2009;h of diagnosis) plus standard IVII, or the control group, which received standard IVII alone. The primary outcome was time to DKA resolution. Secondary outcomes included rebound hyperglycaemia, rebound DKA, hypoglycaemia, hypokalaemia, length of hospital stay (LOS), and in-hospital mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty patients were enrolled; 67.5% of participants had type 2 diabetes. Baseline characteristics were comparable between groups. DKA resolution was significantly faster in the early degludec group by 3.25&#x2009;h (7.75&#x2009;h, IQR 6.00-9.00&#x2009;h vs. 11.00&#x2009;h, IQR 6.25-15.00; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.039). At 72&#x2009;h after transition to SC insulin, mean capillary blood glucose (CBG) was significantly lower with early degludec (213.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;25.8&#x2009;mg/dL vs. 240.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;42.0&#x2009;mg/dL; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.012). Rates of rebound hyperglycaemia at 12&#x2009;h after bridging, mean CBG levels at 12, 24, and 48&#x2009;h among those with rebound hyperglycaemia, as well as rates of rebound DKA, hypoglycaemia, hypokalaemia, LOS, and in-hospital mortality, were not significantly different between groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Early administration of SC insulin degludec in combination with IVII accelerated DKA resolution and improved blood glucose levels at 72&#x2009;h in patients with rebound hyperglycaemia after discontinuation of IVII, without increasing the risk of hypoglycaemia or hypokalaemia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Diabetes, Obesity and Metabolism published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thammakosol</LastName><ForeName>Kitti</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chakri Naruebodindra Medical Institute, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Samut Prakan, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jantarapootirat</LastName><ForeName>Methus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chakri Naruebodindra Medical Institute, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Samut Prakan, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Traiwanatham</LastName><ForeName>Sirinapa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chakri Naruebodindra Medical Institute, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Samut Prakan, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sriphrapradang</LastName><ForeName>Chutintorn</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8294-8601</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RF66046</GrantID><Agency>Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Thailand.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetes Obes Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883645</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1462-8902</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">basal insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetic ketoacidosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoglycaemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypokalaemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long&#x2010;acting insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rebound hyperglycaemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40903851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.70101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Umpierrez GE, Davis GM, ElSayed NA, et al. Hyperglycemic crises in adults with diabetes: a consensus report. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(8):1257&#x2010;1275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umpierrez G, Korytkowski M. Diabetic emergencies: ketoacidosis, hyperglycaemic hyperosmolar state and hypoglycaemia. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2016;12(4):222&#x2010;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhatariya KK, Joint British Diabetes Societies for Inpatient Care. The management of diabetic ketoacidosis in adults: an updated guideline from the Joint British Diabetes Society for Inpatient Care. Diabet Med. 2022;39(6):e14788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong VW, Juhaeri J, Mayer&#x2010;Davis EJ. Trends in hospital admission for diabetic ketoacidosis in adults with type 1 and type 2 diabetes in England, 1998&#x2013;2013: a retrospective cohort study. Diabetes Care. 2018;41(9):1870&#x2010;1877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoit SR. Trends in diabetic ketoacidosis hospitalizations and in&#x2010;hospital mortality: United States, 2000&#x2013;2014. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018;67(12):362&#x2010;365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitabchi AE, Umpierrez GE, Miles JM, Fisher JN. Hyperglycemic crises in adult patients with diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2009;32(7):1335&#x2010;1343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thammakosol K, Sriphrapradang C. Effectiveness and safety of early insulin glargine administration in combination with continuous intravenous insulin infusion in the management of diabetic ketoacidosis: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2023;25(3):815&#x2010;822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade&#x2010;Castellanos CA, Colunga&#x2010;Lozano LE. Systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis: subcutaneous insulin glargine coadministration for diabetic ketoacidosis. Gac Med Mex. 2016;152(6):761&#x2010;769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsia E, Seggelke S, Gibbs J, et al. Subcutaneous administration of glargine to diabetic patients receiving insulin infusion prevents rebound hyperglycemia. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012;97(9):3132&#x2010;3137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse R, Woo V. Flexibly timed once&#x2010;daily dosing with degludec: a new ultra&#x2010;long&#x2010;acting basal insulin. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2013;15(12):1077&#x2010;1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birkeland KI, Home PD, Wendisch U, et al. Insulin degludec in type 1 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial of a new&#x2010;generation ultra&#x2010;long&#x2010;acting insulin compared with insulin glargine. Diabetes Care. 2011;34(3):661&#x2010;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane W, Bailey TS, Gerety G, et al. Effect of insulin degludec vs insulin glargine U100 on hypoglycemia in patients with type 1 diabetes: the SWITCH 1 randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2017;318(1):33&#x2010;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinman B, Philis&#x2010;Tsimikas A, Cariou B, et al. Insulin degludec versus insulin glargine in insulin&#x2010;naive patients with type 2 diabetes: a 1&#x2010;year, randomized, treat&#x2010;to&#x2010;target trial (BEGIN once long). Diabetes Care. 2012;35(12):2464&#x2010;2471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneghini LF, Miranda&#x2010;Palma B. Insulin degludec: a novel ultra&#x2010;long&#x2010;acting basal insulin for use in type 1 and 2 diabetes. Expert Rev Endocrinol Metab. 2012;7(1):9&#x2010;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu C, Hollander P, Miranda&#x2010;Palma B, et al. Efficacy and safety of insulin degludec in a flexible dosing regimen vs insulin glargine in patients with type 1 diabetes (BEGIN: Flex T1): a 26&#x2010;week randomized, treat&#x2010;to&#x2010;target trial with a 26&#x2010;week extension. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;98(3):1154&#x2010;1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galindo RJ, Pasquel FJ, Vellanki P, et al. Degludec hospital trial: a randomized controlled trial comparing insulin degludec U100 and glargine U100 for the inpatient management of patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2022;24(1):42&#x2010;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houshyar J, Bahrami A, Aliasgarzadeh A. Effectiveness of insulin glargine on recovery of patients with diabetic ketoacidosis: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Diagn Res. 2015;9(5):OC01&#x2010;OC04.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doshi P, Potter AJ, De Los Santos D, Banuelos R, Darger BF, Chathampally Y. Prospective randomized trial of insulin glargine in acute management of diabetic ketoacidosis in the emergency department: a pilot study. Acad Emerg Med. 2015;22(6):657&#x2010;662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, et al. 6. Glycemic targets: standards of care in diabetes&#x2014;2023. Diabetes Care. 2023;46(suppl 1):S97&#x2010;S110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck RW, Bergenstal RM, Riddlesworth TD, Kollman C. The association of biochemical hypoglycemia with the subsequent risk of a severe hypoglycemic event: analysis of the DCCT data set. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2019;21(1):1&#x2010;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhatariya K, Nunney I, Higgins K, Sampson M, Iceton G. National survey of the management of diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) in the UK in 2014. Diabet Med. 2016;33(2):252&#x2010;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman JE, Kramer AA, McNair DS, Malila FM. Acute physiology and chronic health evaluation (APACHE) IV: hospital mortality assessment for today's critically ill patients. Crit Care Med. 2006;34(5):1297&#x2010;1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nally LM, Sherr JL, Tichy E, et al. Impact of school&#x2010;supervised ultra&#x2010;long&#x2010;acting basal insulin injections on ketosis in youth with T1D and elevated haemoglobin A1c: a pilot study. Diabet Med. 2023;40(10):e15123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thalange N, Deeb L, Klingensmith G, et al. The rate of hyperglycemia and ketosis with insulin degludec&#x2010;based treatment compared with insulin detemir in pediatric patients with type 1 diabetes: an analysis of data from two randomized trials. Pediatr Diabetes. 2019;20(3):314&#x2010;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo V, Berard L, Roscoe R. Understanding the clinical profile of insulin degludec, the latest basal insulin approved for use in Canada: a narrative review. Diabetes Ther. 2020;11:2539&#x2010;2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heise T, Meneghini LF. Insulin stacking versus therapeutic accumulation: understanding the differences. Endocr Pract. 2014;20(1):75&#x2010;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stathi D, Dhatariya KK, Mustafa OG. Management of diabetes&#x2010;related hyperglycaemic emergencies in advanced chronic kidney disease: review of the literature and recommendations. Diabet Med. 2025;42(2):e15405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer IH, Khunti K, Sadusky T, et al. Diabetes management in chronic kidney disease: a consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and kidney disease: improving global outcomes (KDIGO). Diabetes Care. 2022;45(12):3075&#x2010;3090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berard L, MacNeill G. Insulin degludec, a long&#x2010;acting once&#x2010;daily basal analogue for type 1 and type 2 diabetes mellitus. Can J Diabetes. 2015;39(1):4&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo VC. A review of the clinical efficacy and safety of insulin degludec and glargine 300&#x2009;U/mL in the treatment of diabetes mellitus. Clin Ther. 2017;39(8):S12&#x2010;S33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association professional practice committee. 16. Diabetes Care in the Hospital: standards of care in diabetes&#x2014;2024. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(Suppl 1):S295&#x2010;S306.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>