<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40531488</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2380-6591</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Finerenone According to Frailty in Heart Failure: A Prespecified Analysis of the FINEARTS-HF Randomized Clinical Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>829</StartPage><EndPage>840</EndPage><MedlinePgn>829-840</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamacardio.2025.1775</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients with frailty are often perceived to have a less favorable benefit-risk profile for novel therapies and therefore may be less likely to receive these.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To examine the efficacy and safety of finerenone, compared with placebo, according to frailty status in patients with heart failure (HF) and mildly reduced ejection fraction (HFmrEF) or with HF and preserved ejection fraction (HFpEF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This was a prespecified secondary analysis of a phase 3 randomized clinical trial, the Finerenone Trial to Investigate Efficacy and Safety Superior to Placebo in Patients With Heart Failure (FINEARTS-HF), conducted across 653 sites in 37 countries. Patients with HF with New York Heart Association functional class II through IV, a left ventricular ejection fraction of 40% or higher, evidence of structural heart disease, and elevated natriuretic peptide levels were randomized between September 2020 and January 2023. Data analysis was conducted from October 1 to November 30, 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Addition of once-daily finerenone or placebo to usual therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The primary outcome was a composite of cardiovascular death and total worsening HF events. Frailty was measured using the Rockwood cumulative deficit approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Of the 6001 patients randomized in FINEARTS-HF, a frailty index (FI) was calculable in 5952 patients (mean [SD] age, 72.0 [9.6] years; 3241 [54.4%] male). In total, 1588 patients (26.7%) had class I frailty (FI &#x2264;0.210 [not frail]), 2141 (36.0%) had class II frailty (FI 0.211-0.310 [more frail]), and 2223 (37.3%) had class III frailty (FI &#x2265;0.311 [most frail]). Compared with patients with class I frailty, those with class II and III frailty had a higher risk of the primary outcome (unadjusted rate ratio [RR], 1.88 [95% CI, 1.54-2.28] for class II and 3.86 [95% CI, 3.22-4.64] for class III). The effect of finerenone on the primary outcome did not vary significantly by frailty class (class I: RR, 1.07 [95% CI, 0.77-1.49]; class II: RR, 0.66 [95% CI, 0.52-0.83]; class III: RR, 0.91 [95% CI, 0.76-1.07]; P for interaction&#x2009;=&#x2009;.77). Frailty class did not modify the effects of finerenone on the components of the primary outcome, all-cause death, or improvement in the Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire total symptom score. The effects of finerenone, compared with placebo, on experiencing hypotension, elevated creatinine level, hyperkalemia, or hypokalemia did not differ by frailty class.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In FINEARTS-HF, finerenone reduced the risk of total worsening HF events and cardiovascular death, and it improved symptoms; these effects were not modified by frailty status. In addition, the effects of finerenone on experiencing hypotension, elevated creatinine level, hyperkalemia, or hypokalemia did not differ by frailty status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT04435626.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Butt</LastName><ForeName>Jawad H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jhund</LastName><ForeName>Pardeep S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henderson</LastName><ForeName>Alasdair D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Claggett</LastName><ForeName>Brian L</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiang</LastName><ForeName>Chern-En</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Clinical Research Center and Division of Cardiology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Linssen</LastName><ForeName>Gerard C M</ForeName><Initials>GCM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Hospital Group Twente, Almelo, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saldarriaga</LastName><ForeName>Clara I</ForeName><Initials>CI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro Cardiovascular Colombiano, Cl&#xed;nica Santa Mar&#xed;a, Medellin, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saraiva</LastName><ForeName>Jose F K</ForeName><Initials>JFK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Instituto de Pesquisa Cl&#xed;nica de Campinas, Campinas, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kawaguchi Cardiovascular and Respiratory Hospital, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schou</LastName><ForeName>Morten</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Herlev-Gentofte University Hospital, Hellerup, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>von Lewinski</LastName><ForeName>Dirk</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Cardiology, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lay-Flurrie</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer, Research and Development, Pharmaceuticals, Reading, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scalise</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer, Cardiology and Nephrology Clinical Development, Bayer Hispania, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rohwedder</LastName><ForeName>Katja</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayer, Global Medical Affairs, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Akshay S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lam</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn S P</ForeName><Initials>CSP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart Centre Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Duke-National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Senni</LastName><ForeName>Michele</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Milano-Bicocca ASST Papa Giovanni XXIII Hospital, Bergamo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Sanjiv J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zannad</LastName><ForeName>Faiez</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Lorraine, Inserm Clinical Investigation Centre, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pitt</LastName><ForeName>Bertram</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaduganathan</LastName><ForeName>Muthiah</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Scott D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McMurray</LastName><ForeName>John J V</ForeName><Initials>JJV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04435626</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101676033</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C576501">finerenone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000451">Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009287">Naphthyridines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Failure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073496" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frailty</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013318" MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke Volume</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000451" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009287" MajorTopicYN="Y">Naphthyridines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Butt reported advisory board honoraria from AstraZeneca and Bayer, consultant honoraria from Novartis and AstraZeneca, and travel grants from AstraZeneca outside the submitted work. Dr Jhund reported speakers&#x2019; fees from AstraZeneca, Novartis, Alkem Metabolics, ProAdWise Communications, and Sun Pharmaceuticals, advisory board fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Novartis, research funding from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Analog Devices Inc, and Roche Diagnostics, remuneration to the University of Glasgow from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Novartis, and Novo Nordisk, and serving as director of GCTP Ltd outside the submitted work. Dr Henderson reported travel and consultant fees from Bayer outside the submitted work. Dr Claggett reported personal fees for consulting from Alnylam, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardior, Cardurion, Corvia, Cytokinetics, CVRx, Eli Lilly and Co, Intellia, and Rocket and serving on a data safety monitoring board for Novo Nordisk outside the submitted work. Dr Chiang reported honoraria from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly and Co, MSD, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, and Sanofi outside the submitted work. Dr Saldarriaga reported grants from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and serving as an advisor for Bayer, Merck, and Novo Nordisk, as a principal investigator for AstraZeneca, Bayer, Merck, Novartis, and Novo Nordisk, and as a speaker for Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly and Co, Pfizer, Sanofi, and Servier outside the submitted work. Dr Saraiva reported grants from the Instituto de Pesquisa Clinica de Campinas during the conduct of the study; and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, and Servier outside the submitted work. Dr Sato reported honoraria from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and honoraria from Abiomed, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Novartis, Ono, Otsuka, Pfizer, Roche Japan, Taisho, Terumo, and Tsumura and serving as a national leader for Bayer outside the submitted work. Dr Schou reported personal fees from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and lecture fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, and Novo Nordisk, personal fees from Alleviant, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Edwards Lifesciences, Janssen, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, and Rivus, and a grant from Bayer outside the submitted work. Dr von Lewinski reported trial funding from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and honoraria from Bayer outside the submitted work. Mr Lay-Flurrie reported employment by Bayer during the conduct of the study. Dr Scalise reported employment by Bayer during the conduct of the study. Dr Rohwedder reported employment by Bayer during the conduct of the study. Dr Desai reported institutional grants and consulting fees from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and grants from Abbott, Alnylam, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Novartis, and Pfizer and consulting fees from Abbott, Alnylam, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Biofourmis, Boston Scientific, Endotronix, GlaxoSmithKline, Medpace, Medtronic, Merck, New Amsterdam, Novartis, Parexel, Porter Health, Regeneron, River 2 Renal, Roche, scPharmaceuticals, Veristat, Verily, and Zydus outside the submitted work. Dr Lam reported grants from the National Medical Research Council of Singapore, NovoNordisk, and Roche, and serving as a consultant or on the advisory board, steering committee, or executive committee for Alleviant Medical, Allysta Pharma, Alnylam, AnaCardio, Applied Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Biopeutics, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, Bristol Myers Squibb, CardioRenal, Corteria, CPC Clinical Research, Cytokinetics, Eli Lilly and Co, Impulse Dynamics, Ionis, Intellia Therapeutics, Janssen, Medscape/WebMD, Merck, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Prosciento, Quidel Corp, Radcliffe Group Ltd, Recardio, ReCor Medical, Roche, Sanofi, Siemens Healthcare Diagnostics, and Us2.ai, being a cofounder and nonexecutive director of Us2.ai, having a patent pending for PCT/SG2016/050217, and having US patent 10,702,247 issued outside the submitted work. Dr Senni reported personal fees from Novartis, Bayer, Merck, MSD, Abbott, NovoNordisk, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cardurion, Amgen, and Vifor outside the submitted work. Dr Shah reported consulting fees from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and grants from the National Institutes of Health, American Heart Association, AstraZeneca, Corvia, and Pfizer and consulting fees from Abbott, Alleviant, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Aria CV, Axon Therapies, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cyclerion, Cytokinetics, Edwards Lifesciences, Eidos, Imara, Eli Lilly and Co, Impulse Dynamics, Intellia, Ionis, Merck, MyoKardia, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, Prothena, Regeneron, Rivus, Sardocor, Shifamed, Tenax, Tenaya, and Ultromics outside the submitted work. Dr Zannad reported personal fees from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and serving on steering committees, data and safety monitoring boards, or advisory boards for Applied Therapeutics, Bayer, Biopeutics, Boehringer Ingelheim, CellProthera, Cereno, Corteria, CVRx, Merck, Owkin, and Ribocure, having equity in Cereno and CVCT, receiving personal fees from 89Bio, Abbott, Acceleron, Applied Therapeutics, Bayer, Betagenon, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cambrian, Cardior, CellProthera, Cereno, CEVA, CVRx, Inventiva, KBP, Lupin, Opalia Recordati, Merck, Northsea, NovoNordisk, Owkin, Otsuka, Roche, Us2.ai, and Viatris, having stock options at CardioRenal, Eshmoun, and G3, and being a founder of CVCT outside the submitted work. Dr Pitt reported consultant fees from AnaCardio, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Brainstorm Medical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cereno, G3 Pharmaceuticals, KBP Biosciences, Lexicon, Prointel, Sarfez Pharmaceuticals, scPharmaceuticals, SeaStar Medical, SQinnovations, and Vifor, having stock or stock options with Brainstorm Medical, KBP Biosciences, Prointel, Sarfez Pharmaceuticals, SeaStar Medical, SQinnovations, and Vifor, having US patent 9931412 issued, and having US patent 63/045,783 pending outside the submitted work. Dr Vaduganathan reported grants from American Regent, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Baxter Healthcare, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Cytokinetics, Fresenius Medical Care, Idorsia, Lexicon, Merck, Milestone Pharmaceuticals, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pharmacosmos, Relypsa, Roche, Sanofi, and Tricog Health and serving on advisory boards or as a speaker for Amgen, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Galmed, Novartis, Bayer, Occlutech, and Impulse Dynamics, and participating on clinical trial committees for studies sponsored by AstraZeneca, Galmed, Novartis, Bayer, Occlutech, and Impulse Dynamics outside the submitted work. Dr Solomon reported grants from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and grants from Alexion, Alnylam, Applied Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bellerophon, Bayer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boston Scientific, Cytokinetics, Edgewise, Eidos/BridgeBio, Eli Lilly and Co, Gossamer, GSK, Ionis, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, National Institutes of Health, Novartis, NovoNordisk, Respicardia, Sanofi Pasteur, Tenaya, Theracos, and Us2.ai and personal fees from Abbott, Action, Akros, Alexion, Alnylam, American Regent, Amgen, AnaCardio, Arena, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardiac Dimensions, Cardior, Cardurion, CellProthera, Corvia, Cytokinetics, Daiichi Sankyo, Dinaqor, Eli Lilly and Co, GSK, Intellia, Janssen, Lexicon, Merck, Moderna, Myokardia, Novartis, Roche, Quantum Genomics, Sanofi Pasteur, Sarepta, Tenaya, Theracos, Tremeau, and Valo outside the submitted work. Dr McMurray reported grants from Bayer during the conduct of the study; and grants from Alynylam, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, British Heart Foundation, Cardurion, Catalyze Group, Cytokinetics, GSK, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, Novartis, Roche, and SQ Innovations to Glasgow University, personal fees from Abbot, Alkem Metabolics, Alynylam, Amgen, AnaCardio, Armgo, AstraZeneca, At the Limits, Bayer, Berlin Cures, Biohaven, Blue Ocean Scientific Solutions, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Canadian Medical and Surgical Knowledge, Cardurion, Centrix Healthcare, Chugai, Cytokinetics, DalCor, Emcure, Eris Lifesciences, European Academy of CME, Global Clinical Trial Partners, Hikma, Hilton Pharmaceuticals, Imagica Health, iMedic, Intas, Ionis, J.B. Chemicals &amp; Pharmaceuticals, Lupin, MCI India, Medscape/Heart.Org, Micro Labs, Novartis, ProAdWise Communications, Protherics, Radcliffe Cardiology, Regeneron, River BioMedics, River 2 Renal, Sun Pharma, The Corpus, Translational Medicine Academy, Translation Research Group, and WCG Clinical Services, and serving as director for Global Clinical Trial Partners outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40531488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12177723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2025.1775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2835441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Woods NF, LaCroix AZ, Gray SL, et al. ; Women&#x2019;s Health Initiative . Frailty: emergence and consequences in women aged 65 and older in the Women&#x2019;s Health Initiative Observational Study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53(8):1321-1330. doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53405.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53405.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16078957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan H, Kalogeropoulos AP, Georgiopoulou VV, et al. Frailty and risk for heart failure in older adults: the Health, Aging, and Body Composition Study. Am Heart J. 2013;166(5):887-894. doi: 10.1016/j.ahj.2013.07.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2013.07.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3844525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24176445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denfeld QE, Winters-Stone K, Mudd JO, Gelow JM, Kurdi S, Lee CS. The prevalence of frailty in heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2017;236:283-289. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2017.01.153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2017.01.153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5392144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28215466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bielecka-Dabrowa A, Ebner N, Dos Santos MR, Ishida J, Hasenfuss G, von Haehling S. Cachexia, muscle wasting, and frailty in cardiovascular disease. Eur J Heart Fail. 2020;22(12):2314-2326. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32949422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale C, Jankowska E, Hill L, et al. Heart Failure Association/European Society of Cardiology position paper on frailty in patients with heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2019;21(11):1299-1305. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.1611</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.1611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31646718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH, Rockwood K. Frailty in older adults. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(6):538-548. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra2301292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra2301292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11634188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39115063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewan P, Jackson A, Jhund PS, et al. The prevalence and importance of frailty in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction&#x2014;an analysis of PARADIGM-HF and ATMOSPHERE. Eur J Heart Fail. 2020;22(11):2123-2133. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.1832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.1832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders NA, Supiano MA, Lewis EF, et al. The frailty syndrome and outcomes in the TOPCAT trial. Eur J Heart Fail. 2018;20(11):1570-1577. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.1308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.1308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30225878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yuan M, Gong M, Tse G, Li G, Liu T. Frailty and clinical outcomes in heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2018;19(11):1003-1008.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.jamda.2018.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2018.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottle A, Kim D, Hayhoe B, et al. Frailty and co-morbidity predict first hospitalisation after heart failure diagnosis in primary care: population-based observational study in England. Age Ageing. 2019;48(3):347-354. doi: 10.1093/ageing/afy194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afy194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30624588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vid&#xe1;n MT, Blaya-Novakova V, S&#xe1;nchez E, Ortiz J, Serra-Rexach JA, Bueno H. Prevalence and prognostic impact of frailty and its components in non-dependent elderly patients with heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2016;18(7):869-875. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27072307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt JH, Dewan P, Merkely B, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin according to frailty in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: a post hoc analysis of the DAPA-HF trial. Ann Intern Med. 2022;175(6):820-830. doi: 10.7326/M21-4776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M21-4776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35467935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt JH, Jhund PS, Belohl&#xe1;vek J, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin according to frailty in patients with heart failure: a prespecified analysis of the DELIVER trial. Circulation. 2022;146(16):1210-1224. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.061754</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.061754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9815819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36029465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt JH, Dewan P, Jhund PS, et al. Sacubitril/valsartan and frailty in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;80(12):1130-1143. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2022.06.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2022.06.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36050227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coats AJS, Butler J, Tsutsui H, et al. Efficacy of empagliflozin in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction according to frailty status in EMPEROR-Preserved. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2024;15(1):412-424. doi: 10.1002/jcsm.13393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38158636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene SJ, Butler J, Albert NM, et al. Medical therapy for heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: the CHAMP-HF registry. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72(4):351-366. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.04.070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2018.04.070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30025570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner-La Rocca HP, Linssen GC, Smeele FJ, et al. ; CHECK-HF Investigators . Contemporary drug treatment of chronic heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: the CHECK-HF registry. JACC Heart Fail. 2019;7(1):13-21. doi: 10.1016/j.jchf.2018.10.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchf.2018.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veenis JF, Brunner-La Rocca HP, Linssen GCM, et al. ; CHECK-HF Investigators . Age differences in contemporary treatment of patients with chronic heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2019;26(13):1399-1407. doi: 10.1177/2047487319835042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487319835042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30866680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtin D, Dukelow T, James K, O&#x2019;Donnell D, O&#x2019;Mahony D, Gallagher P. Deprescribing in multi-morbid older people with polypharmacy: agreement between STOPPFrail explicit criteria and gold standard deprescribing using 100 standardized clinical cases. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2019;75(3):427-432. doi: 10.1007/s00228-018-2598-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-018-2598-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner A, Braunstein ED, Umadat G, Ahsan H, Lin J, Palma EC. Utility of the Modified Frailty Index to predict cardiac resynchronization therapy outcomes and response. Am J Cardiol. 2020;125(7):1077-1082. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.12.049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.12.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31992439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubala M, Gu&#xe9;don-Moreau L, Anselme F, et al. Utility of frailty assessment for elderly patients undergoing cardiac resynchronization therapy. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2017;3(13):1523-1533. doi: 10.1016/j.jacep.2017.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacep.2017.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29759834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulignano G, Del Sindaco D, Di Lenarda A, et al. Usefulness of frailty profile for targeting older heart failure patients in disease management programs: a cost-effectiveness, pilot study. J Cardiovasc Med (Hagerstown). 2010;11(10):739-747. doi: 10.2459/JCM.0b013e328339d981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2459/JCM.0b013e328339d981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20736784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey A, Segar MW, Singh S, et al. Frailty status modifies the efficacy of exercise training among patients with chronic heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: an analysis from the HF-ACTION trial. Circulation. 2022;146(2):80-90. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.059983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.059983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10273304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35616018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, McMurray JJV, Vaduganathan M, et al. ; FINEARTS-HF Committees and Investigators . Finerenone in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(16):1475-1485. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2407107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2407107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39225278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, Ostrominski JW, Vaduganathan M, et al. Baseline characteristics of patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: the FINEARTS-HF trial. Eur J Heart Fail. 2024;26(6):1334-1346. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.3266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.3266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38733212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Lam CSP, et al. Finerenone in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: rationale and design of the FINEARTS-HF trial. Eur J Heart Fail. 2024;26(6):1324-1333. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.3253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.3253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38742248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitnitski AB, Mogilner AJ, Rockwood K. Accumulation of deficits as a proxy measure of aging. ScientificWorldJournal. 2001;1:323-336. doi: 10.1100/tsw.2001.58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1100/tsw.2001.58</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6084020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12806071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rockwood K, Mitnitski A. Frailty in relation to the accumulation of deficits. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2007;62(7):722-727. doi: 10.1093/gerona/62.7.722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/62.7.722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17634318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searle SD, Mitnitski A, Gahbauer EA, Gill TM, Rockwood K. A standard procedure for creating a frailty index. BMC Geriatr. 2008;8:24. doi: 10.1186/1471-2318-8-24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2318-8-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2573877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18826625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theou O, Brothers TD, Mitnitski A, Rockwood K. Operationalization of frailty using eight commonly used scales and comparison of their ability to predict all-cause mortality. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2013;61(9):1537-1551. doi: 10.1111/jgs.12420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.12420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24028357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blodgett JM, Theou O, Howlett SE, Rockwood K. A frailty index from common clinical and laboratory tests predicts increased risk of death across the life course. Geroscience. 2017;39(4):447-455. doi: 10.1007/s11357-017-9993-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-017-9993-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5636769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28866737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blodgett J, Theou O, Kirkland S, Andreou P, Rockwood K. Frailty in NHANES: comparing the frailty index and phenotype. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2015;60(3):464-470. doi: 10.1016/j.archger.2015.01.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2015.01.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25697060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin DY, Wei LJ, Yang I, Ying Z. Semiparametric regression for the mean and rate functions of recurrent events. J R Stat Soc Series B Stat Methodol. 2000;62(4):711-730. doi: 10.1111/1467-9868.00259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-9868.00259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajewski NM, Williamson JD, Applegate WB, et al. ; SPRINT Study Research Group . Characterizing frailty status in the Systolic Blood Pressure Intervention Trial. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2016;71(5):649-655. doi: 10.1093/gerona/glv228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glv228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5007741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26755682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warwick J, Falaschetti E, Rockwood K, et al. No evidence that frailty modifies the positive impact of antihypertensive treatment in very elderly people: an investigation of the impact of frailty upon treatment effect in the Hypertension in the Very Elderly Trial (HYVET) study, a double-blind, placebo-controlled study of antihypertensives in people with hypertension aged 80 and over. BMC Med. 2015;13(1):78. doi: 10.1186/s12916-015-0328-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-015-0328-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25880068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoogendijk EO, Theou O, Rockwood K, Onwuteaka-Philipsen BD, Deeg DJH, Huisman M. Development and validation of a frailty index in the Longitudinal Aging Study Amsterdam. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2017;29(5):927-933. doi: 10.1007/s40520-016-0689-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-016-0689-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5589777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27896796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong JJ, Mitnitski A, Launer LJ, White LR, Rockwood K. Frailty in the Honolulu-Asia Aging Study: deficit accumulation in a male cohort followed to 90% mortality. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2015;70(1):125-131. doi: 10.1093/gerona/glu089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glu089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24973228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan J, Espinoza S, Ernst ME, et al. Validation of a deficit-accumulation frailty index in the Aspirin in Reducing Events in the Elderly study and its predictive capacity for disability-free survival. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2022;77(1):19-26. doi: 10.1093/gerona/glab225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glab225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8751791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34338761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams DM, Jylh&#xe4;v&#xe4; J, Pedersen NL, H&#xe4;gg S. A frailty index for UK Biobank participants. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2019;74(4):582-587. doi: 10.1093/gerona/gly094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gly094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29924297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al. ; ESC Scientific Document Group . 2021 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2021;42(36):3599-3726. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehab368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehab368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34447992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, McMurray JJV, Claggett B, et al. ; DELIVER Trial Committees and Investigators . Dapagliflozin in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med. 2022;387(12):1089-1098. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2206286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2206286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36027570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, et al. ; EMPEROR-Preserved Trial Investigators . Empagliflozin in heart failure with a preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(16):1451-1461. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2107038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2107038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, McMurray JJV, Anand IS, et al. ; PARAGON-HF Investigators and Committees . Angiotensin-neprilysin inhibition in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med. 2019;381(17):1609-1620. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1908655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1908655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31475794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, et al. ; ACC/AHA Joint Committee Members . 2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2022;145(18):e895-e1032. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dent E, Martin FC, Bergman H, Woo J, Romero-Ortuno R, Walston JD. Management of frailty: opportunities, challenges, and future directions. Lancet. 2019;394(10206):1376-1386. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31785-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31785-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31609229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>