<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40933935</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>29</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology, pathophysiology, and interventions for postpartum depression: Systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>110948</StartPage><MedlinePgn>110948</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">110948</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v13.i29.110948</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Postpartum depression (PPD) is a prevalent and debilitating psychiatric disorder affecting maternal mental health, infant development, and family well-being. Despite increasing global awareness, significant disparities remain in screening, diagnosis, and treatment, particularly in low-resource and culturally diverse settings. The complex interplay of biological and psychosocial determinants complicates conventional intervention models. Integrating epidemiological patterns, pathophysiological mechanisms, and sociocultural factors will inform more effective and equitable strategies for PPD screening, prevention, and treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesize current evidence on risk factors, underlying mechanisms, and interventions for postpartum depression and outline directions toward equitable care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A narrative review was conducted following PRISMA 2020 guidelines. Peer-reviewed studies published from January 2010 to May 2025 were systematically searched in PubMed, Web of Science, EMBASE, and PsycINFO. Inclusion criteria comprised studies addressing PPD epidemiology, risk stratification, biological mechanisms, and intervention strategies. After screening and full-text review, 84 studies were included. Study designs primarily involved cohort studies, randomized controlled trials, and meta-analyses. Extracted data were categorized thematically and assessed for methodological quality and generalizability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">PPD arises from multifactorial interactions involving hormonal dysregulation, neurochemical changes, psychosocial stressors, and cultural influences. Primary risk factors include personal or family history of depression, antenatal anxiety, low maternal self-efficacy, and inadequate social support. Evidence-based interventions encompass Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale-based screening, cognitive behavioral therapy, interpersonal psychotherapy, psychoeducation, and pharmacological treatments such as brexanolone and zuranolone. Culturally adapted, community-integrated models-including stepped-care approaches and task-shifting-improve feasibility and scalability, particularly in underserved populations. Emerging evidence highlights inflammatory biomarkers (<i>e.g.</i>, interleukin-6 and C-reactive protein), AI-assisted screening tools, and family-inclusive strategies as promising for enhanced detection and outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Effective PPD management requires integrative, culturally sensitive approaches, prioritizing scalable, personalized non-pharmacological interventions to reduce disparities and enhance maternal mental health equity across diverse populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Qing-Qing</ForeName><Initials>QQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Birth Defects and Related Diseases of Women and Children (Sichuan University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu 610041, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Meng-Yi</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Birth Defects and Related Diseases of Women and Children (Sichuan University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu 610041, Sichuan Province, China. 18583986082@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-based intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Global health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maternal mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroendocrine mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postpartum depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk stratification</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All authors declare no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40933935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12417937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v13.i29.110948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Liang HF, Chen J, Li ZB, Han YS, Chen JX, Li JC. Postpartum Depression: Current Status and Possible Identification Using Biomarkers. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:620371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal I, Mehendale AM, Malhotra R. Risk Factors of Postpartum Depression. Cureus. 2022;14:e30898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9711915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36465774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saharoy R, Potdukhe A, Wanjari M, Taksande AB. Postpartum Depression and Maternal Care: Exploring the Complex Effects on Mothers and Infants. Cureus. 2023;15:e41381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10400812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37546054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee-van den Berg AI, Boere-Boonekamp MM, Groothuis-Oudshoorn CGM, Reijneveld SA. Postpartum depression and anxiety: a community-based study on risk factors before, during and after pregnancy. J Affect Disord. 2021;286:158&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puyan&#xe9; M, Subir&#xe0; S, Torres A, Roca A, Garcia-Esteve L, Gelabert E. Personality traits as a risk factor for postpartum depression: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2022;298:577&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominiak M, Antosik-Wojcinska AZ, Baron M, Mierzejewski P, Swiecicki L. Recommendations for the prevention and treatment of postpartum depression. Ginekol Pol. 2021;92:153&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Nasr RS, Altharwi K, Derbah MS, Gharibo SO, Fallatah SA, Alotaibi SG, Almutairi KA, Asdaq SMB. Prevalence and predictors of postpartum depression in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia: A cross sectional study. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0228666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7010279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32040495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryawanshi O 4th, Pajai S. A Comprehensive Review on Postpartum Depression. Cureus. 2022;14:e32745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9851410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36686097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mwita M, Dewey D, Konje ET, Patten S. Non-pharmacological interventions for perinatal depression and anxiety among adolescent mothers: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2025;379:168&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40081580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alba BM. CE: Postpartum Depression: A Nurse's Guide. Am J Nurs. 2021;121:32&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34117132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann CS, Hoegholt NF, Vuust P, Kringelbach M, Jespersen KV. The effect of music on pregnancy-related insomnia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Midwifery. 2025;142:104294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39826401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaldon C, Solmi M, Correll CU, Barbui C, Schoretsanitis G. Risk factors of postpartum depression and depressive symptoms: umbrella review of current evidence from systematic reviews and meta-analyses of observational studies. Br J Psychiatry. 2022;221:591&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35081993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacher Kjeldsen MM, Bricca A, Liu X, Frokjaer VG, Madsen KB, Munk-Olsen T. Family History of Psychiatric Disorders as a Risk Factor for Maternal Postpartum Depression: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2022;79:1004&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9386615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35976654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning J, Deng J, Li S, Lu C, Zeng P. Meta-analysis of association between caesarean section and postpartum depression risk. Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1361604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11006970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38606408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould JF, Gibson RA, Green TJ, Makrides M. A Systematic Review of Vitamin D during Pregnancy and Postnatally and Symptoms of Depression in the Antenatal and Postpartum Period from Randomized Controlled Trials and Observational Studies. Nutrients. 2022;14:2300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9183028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35684101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng Y, Liu W, Yu Z, Zhang H, Li Y, Zhao W. Socioeconomic factors and sex effects of postpartum maternal depression on offspring internalizing symptoms: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Med. 2025;23:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11804016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39915783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelke A, Chakole S. A Review on Risk Factors of Postpartum Depression in India and Its Management. Cureus. 2022;14:e29150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9573019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36258936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meltzer-Brody S, Kanes SJ. Allopregnanolone in postpartum depression: Role in pathophysiology and treatment. Neurobiol Stress. 2020;12:100212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32435663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, He L, Li Z, Ding R, Han X, Chen B, Cao G, Ye JH, Li T, Fu R. Bridging Neurobiological Insights and Clinical Biomarkers in Postpartum Depression: A Narrative Review. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:8835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11354679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39201521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf6;tsch MK, Ehlert U. Allopregnanolone and mood in the peripartum: a longitudinal assessment in healthy women. Front Behav Neurosci. 2024;18:1499416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11617183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39640510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deligiannidis KM, Meltzer-Brody S, Gunduz-Bruce H, Doherty J, Jonas J, Li S, Sankoh AJ, Silber C, Campbell AD, Werneburg B, Kanes SJ, Lasser R. Effect of Zuranolone vs Placebo in Postpartum Depression: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78:951&#x2013;959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8246337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34190962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batt MM, Duffy KA, Novick AM, Metcalf CA, Epperson CN. Is Postpartum Depression Different From Depression Occurring Outside of the Perinatal Period? A Review of the Evidence. Focus (Am Psychiatr Publ) 2020;18:106&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7587887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33162848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombage RL, Holden S, Lamport DJ, Barfoot KL. The effects of flavonoid supplementation on the mental health of postpartum parents. Front Glob Womens Health. 2024;5:1345353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38577523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang P, Li GH, Rao YB, Cheng C, He WL, Wang JJ, Li XY, Lu YR. Serum Cytokines as Biomarkers for Comorbid Anxiety in Postpartum Depression: A Machine Learning Approach. Psychiat Clin Psych. 2025;1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12371739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40824102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman ME, Reichenberg A, Savitz DA, Cnattingius S, Lichtenstein P, Hultman CM, Larsson H, Sandin S. The risk factors for postpartum depression: A population-based study. Depress Anxiety. 2017;34:178&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5462547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Sun L, Chen Q, Jiao C, Wang Y, Li H, Xie J, Zhu F, Wang J, Zhang W, Xie L, Wu H, Zuo Z, Chen X. Gut microbiota dysbiosis contributes to depression-like behaviors via hippocampal NLRP3-mediated neuroinflammation in a postpartum depression mouse model. Brain Behav Immun. 2024;119:220&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38599497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Q, Wang S, Tian X, Liu W, Gao P. Fecal microbiota transplantation confirmed that 919 Syrup reduced the ratio of erucamide to 5-AVAB in hippocampus to alleviate postpartum depression by regulating gut microbes. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1203015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10244653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37292211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accortt E, Mirocha J, Zhang D, Kilpatrick SJ, Libermann T, Karumanchi SA. Perinatal mood and anxiety disorders: biomarker discovery using plasma proteomics. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2023;229:166.e1&#x2013;166.e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36649818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnakenberg P, Hahn L, Stickel S, Stickeler E, Habel U, Eickhoff SB, Chechko N, Dukart J. Examining early structural and functional brain alterations in postpartum depression through multimodal neuroimaging. Sci Rep. 2021;11:13551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34193913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn MG, Nam E. Scaling Up Maternal Mental Health Care: Evaluating Community-Based Interventions in Ethiopia: A Systematic Review. Korean J Health Promot. 2025;25:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubel J. Grandmothers - a neglected family resource for saving newborn lives. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e003808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7887373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33589417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay RP, Chowdhury R, Aslyeh Salehi, Sarkar K, Singh SK, Sinha B, Pawar A, Rajalakshmi AK, Kumar A. Postpartum depression in India: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bull World Health Organ. 2017;95:706&#x2013;717C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5689195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29147043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen LT, Minh Giang L, Nguyen DB, Nguyen TT, Lin C. Unraveling reproductive and maternal health challenges of women living with HIV/AIDS in Vietnam: a qualitative study. Reprod Health. 2024;21:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10929216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38468301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan SH, Shorey S. Effectiveness of psychosocial interventions on the psychological outcomes of parents with preterm infants: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pediatr Nurs. 2024;74:23&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37988885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakina R, Khan SE, Chaudhry AG. Stigma of postpartum depression: The role of lady health workers in health care-A qualitative study. Health Care Women Int. 2022;43:1095&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34520333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng CY, Chou YH, Chang CH, Liou SR. Trends of Perinatal Stress, Anxiety, and Depression and Their Prediction on Postpartum Depression. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:9307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8431252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Q, Long Q, De Silva V, Gunarathna N, Jayathilaka U, Dabrera T, Lynn H, &#xd8;stbye T. Prevalence and risk factors for postpartum depression in Sri Lanka: A population-based study. Asian J Psychiatr. 2020;47:101855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31733601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AW, Reid C, Skeffington P, Marriott R. A systematic review of EPDS cultural suitability with Indigenous mothers: a global perspective. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2021;24:353&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8116293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Seon Q, Gomez Cardona L, Karia M, Velupillai G, Noel V, Linnaranta O. Safe and valid? A systematic review of the psychometric properties of culturally adapted depression scales for use among Indigenous populations. Glob Ment Health (Camb) 2023;10:e60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37854390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali GC, Ryan G, De Silva MJ. Validated Screening Tools for Common Mental Disorders in Low and Middle Income Countries: A Systematic Review. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0156939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4911088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27310297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fellmeth G, Harrison S, Opondo C, Nair M, Kurinczuk JJ, Alderdice F. Validated screening tools to identify common mental disorders in perinatal and postpartum women in India: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Psychiatry. 2021;21:200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33879130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heer K, Mahmoud L, Abdelmeguid H, Selvan K, Malvankar-Mehta MS. Prevalence, Risk Factors, and Interventions of Postpartum Depression in Refugees and Asylum-Seeking Women: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 2024;89:11&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10871679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38219724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skoog M, Hallstr&#xf6;m IK, Vilhelmsson A. Health care professionals' experiences of screening immigrant mothers for postpartum depression-a qualitative systematic review. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0271318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9282607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35834550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow R, Huang E, Li A, Li S, Fu SY, Son JS, Foster WG. Appraisal of systematic reviews on interventions for postpartum depression: systematic review. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2021;21:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33407226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JA, Ohan JL, Gibson LY, Prescott SL, Finlay-Jones AL. Understanding Engagement in Digital Mental Health and Well-being Programs for Women in the Perinatal Period: Systematic Review Without Meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2022;24:e36620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9399849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35943773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iturralde E, Hsiao CA, Nkemere L, Kubo A, Sterling SA, Flanagan T, Avalos LA. Engagement in perinatal depression treatment: a qualitative study of barriers across and within racial/ethnic groups. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2021;21:512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8284181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34271852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinty EE, Alegria M, Beidas RS, Braithwaite J, Kola L, Leslie DL, Moise N, Mueller B, Pincus HA, Shidhaye R, Simon K, Singer SJ, Stuart EA, Eisenberg MD. The Lancet Psychiatry Commission: transforming mental health implementation research. Lancet Psychiatry. 2024;11:368&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38552663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naslund JA, Aschbrenner KA, Araya R, Marsch LA, Un&#xfc;tzer J, Patel V, Bartels SJ. Digital technology for treating and preventing mental disorders in low-income and middle-income countries: a narrative review of the literature. Lancet Psychiatry. 2017;4:486&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5523650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28433615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Lawrence K, Schoenthaler AM, Mann D. A framework for digital health equity. NPJ Digit Med. 2022;5:119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9387425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35982146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torous J, Lipschitz J, Ng M, Firth J. Dropout rates in clinical trials of smartphone apps for depressive symptoms: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2020;263:413&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31969272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthes E. Mental health: There's an app for that. Nature. 2016;532:20&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27078548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Kang X, Dong X, Zeng Z, Zou Q, Su M, Zhang K, Liu G, Yu G. Effect of transcranial direct current stimulation on postpartum depression: A study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Front Psychol. 2023;14:990162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9976935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36874857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment and Management of Mental Health Conditions During Pregnancy and Postpartum: ACOG Clinical Practice Guideline No. 5. Obstet Gynecol. 2023;141:1262&#x2013;1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37486661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meltzer-Brody S, Colquhoun H, Riesenberg R, Epperson CN, Deligiannidis KM, Rubinow DR, Li H, Sankoh AJ, Clemson C, Schacterle A, Jonas J, Kanes S. Brexanolone injection in post-partum depression: two multicentre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trials. Lancet. 2018;392:1058&#x2013;1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30177236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Laplante DP, Paquin V, Lafortune S, Elgbeili G, King S. Effectiveness of cognitive behavioral therapy for perinatal maternal depression, anxiety and stress: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Psychol Rev. 2022;92:102129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan J, Luo W, Zhang H, Wang Y, Lu H, Wang C, Li C, Fu L, Hu Y, Li Y, Shen M. The Effects of Online Cognitive Behavioral Therapy on Postpartum Depression: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Healthcare (Basel) 2025;13:696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11989130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40217993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai FW, Gao LL. Effect of couple-based interpersonal psychotherapy on postpartum depressive symptoms: A randomised controlled trial. Asian J Psychiatr. 2022;78:103274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang HK, Bisht B, Kaur M, Alexis O, Worsley A, John D. Effectiveness of interpersonal psychotherapy in comparison to other psychological and pharmacological interventions for reducing depressive symptoms in women diagnosed with postpartum depression in low- and middle-income countries: A systematic review. Campbell Syst Rev. 2024;20:e1399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11032640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38645302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasujja R, Birungi P, Bhamidipati K, Assefa F, Kim HY, Peterson KM, Kohrt BA, Bershteyn A. Six-Week Problem Area-Concordant vs 8-Week Problem Area-Discordant Group Interpersonal Psychotherapy: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2025;8:e255242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12004200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40238099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-G&#xf3;mez C, Moreno-Peral P, Bell&#xf3;n JA, Conejo-Cer&#xf3;n S, Campos-Paino H, G&#xf3;mez-G&#xf3;mez I, Rigabert A, Ben&#xed;tez I, Motrico E. Effectiveness of psychological interventions in preventing postpartum depression in non-depressed women: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Psychol Med. 2022;52:1001&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35257650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Liu R, Wang X, Yang J. Effectiveness of aerobic exercise in the prevention and treatment of postpartum depression: Meta-analysis and network meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2023;18:e0287650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38019729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport MH, McCurdy AP, Mottola MF, Skow RJ, Meah VL, Poitras VJ, Jaramillo Garcia A, Gray CE, Barrowman N, Riske L, Sobierajski F, James M, Nagpal T, Marchand AA, Nuspl M, Slater LG, Barakat R, Adamo KB, Davies GA, Ruchat SM. Impact of prenatal exercise on both prenatal and postnatal anxiety and depressive symptoms: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:1376&#x2013;1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30337464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Zhou B, Kan J, Liu G, Zhang S, Si L, Zhang X, Yang X, Ma J, Cheng J, Liu X, Yang Y. Corrigendum: Gut microbiota: Linking nutrition and perinatal depression. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2022;12:1053553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9695397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36439221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szajna A, Tekkalaki B, Nandagaon V, Udapi G, Sogalad M, Dandagi S, Kole U, Patil S, Raddi S, Short V, Kelly PJ. Feasibility and acceptability of a community health worker administered behavioral activation intervention for postpartum depression: a single arm pilot study from India. Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1284674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11089130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38742133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boran P, D&#xf6;nmez M, Bar&#x131;&#x15f; E, Us MC, Alta&#x15f; ZM, Nisar A, Atif N, Sikander S, H&#x131;d&#x131;ro&#x11f;lu S, Save D, Rahman A. Delivering the Thinking Healthy Programme as a universal group intervention integrated into routine antenatal care: a randomized-controlled pilot study. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9816542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36604685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumpf U, Palm U, Eder J, Ezim H, Stadler M, Burkhardt G, Dechantsreiter E, Padberg F. TDCS at home for depressive disorders: an updated systematic review and lessons learned from a prematurely terminated randomized controlled pilot study. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2023;273:1403&#x2013;1420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10185954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37191697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Q, Shi L, Zhu L, Jiao N, Chong YS, Chan SW, Chan YH, Luo N, Wang W, He H. Cost-effectiveness of Web-Based and Home-Based Postnatal Psychoeducational Interventions for First-time Mothers: Economic Evaluation Alongside Randomized Controlled Trial. J Med Internet Res. 2022;24:e25821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8956997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35275078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  Improving early childhood development: WHO guideline. Geneva: WHO. (2022). Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/97892400020986 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACOG Committee Opinion No. 757: Screening for Perinatal Depression. Obstet Gynecol. 2018;132:e208&#x2013;e212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30629567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE)  (2014, updated 2020). Antenatal and postnatal mental health: clinical management and service guidance (CG192). Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg192 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31990493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Preventive Services Task Force, Curry SJ, Krist AH, Owens DK, Barry MJ, Caughey AB, Davidson KW, Doubeni CA, Epling JW Jr, Grossman DC, Kemper AR, Kubik M, Landefeld CS, Mangione CM, Silverstein M, Simon MA, Tseng CW, Wong JB. Interventions to Prevent Perinatal Depression: US Preventive Services Task Force Recommendation Statement. JAMA. 2019;321:580&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang E, Colquhoun H, LeBlanc JC, Riva JJ, Moore A, Traversy G, Wilson B, Grad R Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care. Recommendation on instrument-based screening for depression during pregnancy and the postpartum period. CMAJ. 2022;194:E981&#x2013;E989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9328462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35878894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhi GS, Bell E, Bassett D, Boyce P, Bryant R, Hazell P, Hopwood M, Lyndon B, Mulder R, Porter R, Singh AB, Murray G. The 2020 Royal Australian and New Zealand College of Psychiatrists clinical practice guidelines for mood disorders. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2021;55:7&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33353391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Verde M, Luciano M, Fordellone M, Sampogna G, Lettieri D, Palma M, Torella D, Marrapodi MM, Di Vincenzo M, Torella M. Postpartum Depression and Inflammatory Biomarkers of Neutrophil-Lymphocyte Ratio, Platelet-Lymphocyte Ratio, and Monocyte-Lymphocyte Ratio: A Prospective Observational Study. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 2024;89:140&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38346412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coecke S, Panzarella G, Firth J, Sarris J, Buckman JE, Toczyski P, van Rijn E, Qu&#xe9;tel CR, Kephalopoulos S, Vignes M, Kourti N, Bobach C, Pladunova S, Solmi M, van Kamp I, Ronchi F, Pevere M, Gallo S, De Bernardi F, Sachana M, Laureys S, Torres F, Palacios Sanchez L, Cairney S, Kaihsiang Y, Charveriat C, Pang C, Vernetti C, Baggio M, Kovacic M, Di Gioia R, Munoz A, Puertas-Gallardo A, Takki M, Petrillo M, Gallo A, Alcaro S, Gawlik BM, Tavazzi S, Lombardi I, Hupont-Torres I, Romeo P, Schade S, Barreda Angeles M, Bakogianni I, Maragkoudakis P, Ceresa M, Querci M, Caldeira S, Wiesenthal T.  Decoding depression: Exploring the environome across life course. Securing mental health systems: Preparedness, innovation, and policy for global resilience, Publications Office of the European Union. 2025. Available from: https://publications.jrc.ec.europa.eu/repository/handle/JRC139918 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le SM, Quang HT.  Digital Journey in Primary Health Care - Empowering Patients with Noncommunicable Diseases in Vietnam (English). Health; Nutrition; and Population (HNP) Discussion Paper Washington, DC: World Bank Group. Available from: http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/099017103132412996 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dachew B, Ayano G, Duko B, Lawrence B, Betts K, Alati R. Paternal Depression and Risk of Depression Among Offspring: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e2329159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10433087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37585203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno A, Celebre L, Mento C, Rizzo A, Silvestri MC, De Stefano R, Zoccali RA, Muscatello MRA. When Fathers Begin to Falter: A Comprehensive Review on Paternal Perinatal Depression. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:1139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32053929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Li YL, Qiu D, Xiao SY. Factors Influencing Paternal Postpartum Depression: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Affect Disord. 2021;293:51&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad K, Gerloff C, Kohl SH, Mehler DMA, Mehlem L, Volbert EL, Komorek M, Henn AT, Boecker M, Weiss E, Reindl V. Interpersonal neural synchrony and mental disorders: unlocking potential pathways for clinical interventions. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1286130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10962391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38529267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne JL, Maguire J. Pathophysiological mechanisms implicated in postpartum depression. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2019;52:165&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30552910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kargbo RB. Neurosteroids and Postpartum Depression: The Mechanism, Efficacy, and Approval of Brexanolone and Zurzuvae. ACS Med Chem Lett. 2023;14:1326&#x2013;1328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10577692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37849543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagher RK, Bruckheim HE, Colpe LJ, Edwards E, White DB. Perinatal Depression: Challenges and Opportunities. J Womens Health (Larchmt) 2021;30:154&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7891219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33156730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf6;rvang RD, Vrettou M, Bujanda Cundin X, Del Prete E, R&#xfc;egg J, Lager S, di Bernardo D, Comasco E, Skalkidou A. Differentially expressed transcripts associated with depressive symptoms during pregnancy and postpartum. Mol Psychiatry. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40473930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>