<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40907851</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-1913</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>258</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Phase 1b Randomized Clinical Trial of AZD5642 and Dapagliflozin in Patients With Heart Failure and Moderate Renal Impairment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>49</StartPage><EndPage>53</EndPage><MedlinePgn>49-53</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.amjcard.2025.08.046</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-9149(25)00510-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>AZD5462 is the first oral selective relaxin/insulin-like family peptide receptor 1 agonist in clinical development. The aim of this mechanistic study is to investigate the renal effects of AZD5462 when administered on top of the sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor dapagliflozin in participants with heart failure and moderate renal impairment. AURORA is a phase 1b, placebo-controlled, double-blind, 2-centre study of AZD5462 on top of dapagliflozin as standard of care in 2 arms. Approximately 40 participants with heart failure with ejection fraction &#x2264;50% and moderate renal impairment (estimated glomerular filtration rate of 30-60 mL/min/1.73 m<sup>2</sup>, inclusive) will be randomized 1:1 to AZD5462 or placebo tablets for a treatment period of 4 weeks. All participants will be standardized to 10 mg dapagliflozin prior to AZD5462 administration, and dapagliflozin as standard of care will continue until the end of the follow-up period. The objectives of the study are to evaluate the renal and haemodynamic effects of AZD5462 compared with placebo on top of dapagliflozin on natriuresis, albuminuria, haematocrit, fluid balance, cardiorenal biomarkers, and systemic hemodynamics. The safety and tolerability of AZD5462 will be further evaluated compared with placebo on top of dapagliflozin. AURORA is a phase 1b pharmacodynamic, pharmacokinetic, and safety study of AZD5462 on top of dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure and renal impairment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quintana-Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Macarena Paz</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Clinical Development, Cardiovascular, Renal and Metabolism, BioPharmaceuticals R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Connolly</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Clinical Development, Cardiovascular, Renal and Metabolism, BioPharmaceuticals R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greasley</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Clinical Development, Cardiovascular, Renal and Metabolism, BioPharmaceuticals R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Melanie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biometrics, Cardiovascular, Renal and Metabolism, BioPharmaceuticals R&amp;D, AstraZeneca Mississauga, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadaat</LastName><ForeName>Masood</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Clinical Development, Cardiovascular, Renal and Metabolism, BioPharmaceuticals R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Gaithersburg, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svedlund</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ribocure Pharmaceuticals, Gothenburg, Sweden; Suzhou Ribo Life Science Co., Kunshan City, Jiangsu, China; Department of Clinical Physiology, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Gothenburg, Sweden; Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenmeier</LastName><ForeName>Jaya Birgitte</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Clinical Development, Cardiovascular, Renal and Metabolism, BioPharmaceuticals R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Gothenburg, Sweden. Electronic address: jayabirgitte.rosenmeier@astrazeneca.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0207277</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9149</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Macarena P. Quintana-Hayashi reports a relationship with AstraZeneca that includes: employment and equity or stocks. Kathleen Connolly reports a relationship with AstraZeneca that includes: employment and equity or stocks. Peter Greasley reports a relationship with AstraZeneca that includes: employment and equity or stocks. Masood Saddat reports a relationship with AstraZeneca that includes: employment and equity or stocks. Sara Svedlund reports a relationship with Ribocure Pharmaceuticals AB that includes: employment. Jaya Birgitte Rosenmeier reports a relationship with AstraZeneca that includes: employment and equity or stocks. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40907851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2025.08.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9149(25)00510-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>