<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40840822</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6744</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>291</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American heart journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am Heart J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>DAPAgliflozin for renal protection in heart transplant recipients. Rationale and design of the randomized controlled DAPARHT trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>128</StartPage><EndPage>135</EndPage><MedlinePgn>128-135</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ahj.2025.08.010</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-8703(25)00300-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Heart transplantation is the preferred treatment for selected patients with end stage heart failure. Kidney function often declines after heart transplantation. Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) slow the decline in eGFR in different populations. However, the effect of SGLT2i on kidney function in heart transplant recipients is unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Dapagliflozin for Renal protection in Heart Transplant recipients (DAPARHT) trial is an investigator initiated, double blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial designed to assess dapagliflozin's effect on kidney function in heart transplant recipients. Adults heart transplanted at least one year prior to randomization are eligible. Exclusion criteria include an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;25 mL/min/1.73 m<sup>2</sup>, diabetes type I, and contraindication to study medication. Four hundred and thirty patients will be randomized 1:1 to receive 12 months blinded treatment with dapagliflozin 10 mg o.d. or placebo, followed by 24-months open-label treatment. The primary endpoint is the chronic slope of the eGFR from two weeks to 12 months after starting randomized treatment. The open-label phase evaluates dapagliflozin's long-term effects on kidney function, clinical outcomes, safety, and tolerability. Enrolment began in June 2022. As of December 18, 2024, 300 patients were enrolled. The mean baseline creatinine was 104 &#xb1; 28 &#xb5;mol/L with corresponding eGFR of 66 &#xb1; 22 mL/min/1.73 m<sup>2</sup>. Estimated last patient visit is in September, 2028.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The DAPARHT trial will test whether dapagliflozin improves eGFR slope compared to placebo during one year of follow-up, providing the first randomized evidence of the efficacy of SGLT2i in heart transplant recipients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Dapagliflozin for Renal protection in Heart Transplant recipients (DAPARHT), NCT05321706, clinicaltrials.gov.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holmen</LastName><ForeName>Stine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway; Department of Medicine, Innlandet Hospital Trust, Hamar, Norway; Institute of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Oslo, Norway. Electronic address: b19808@ous-hf.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manintveld</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Cardiovascular Institute, Erasmus Medical Center, Rotterdam, the Netherlands; Erasmus MC Transplant Institute, Erasmus University Medical Center Rotterdam, Rotterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damman</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University of Groningen, University Medical Center Groningen, Groningen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Oscar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital and Department of Clinical Sciences Lund, Cardiology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf6;fman</LastName><ForeName>Ida Haugen</ForeName><Initials>IH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine Solna, Karolinska Institutet, Department of Cardiology, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szymanski</LastName><ForeName>Mariusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center Utrecht, Department of Cardiology, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ravnestad</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe5;vard</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway; Institute of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gude</LastName><ForeName>Einar</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bj&#xf8;rkelund</LastName><ForeName>Elisabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andreassen</LastName><ForeName>Arne K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gullestad</LastName><ForeName>Lars</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway; Institute of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Broch</LastName><ForeName>Kaspar</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Oslo University Hospital, Oslo, Norway; Institute of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05321706</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am Heart J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370465</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-8703</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest S. Holmen conflicts of interest: none declared. O. Manintveld reports speaker engagement or advisory board fees from AstraZeneca, Abbott, Boehringer Ingelheim, Daiichi Sankyo, Novartis, Novo Nordisk and Siemens. K. Damman reports speaker and consultancy fees to his employer from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Abbott, FIRE1 and Echosense. O. Braun has received speaker fees from, and has served on advisory boards for AstraZeneca, Abbott, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Orion Pharma, Novartis and Pfizer. I. H. L&#xf6;fman has received speaker fees from AstraZeneca and Orion Pharma. M. Szymanski reports speaker fees to his employer from AstraZeneca. H. Ravnestad reports speaker fees from Bayer, and consulting fees from Nordic InfuCare and Merck Sharp and Dohme. E. Gude reports speaker fee or advisory board fees from Novartis and Pfizer. E. Bj&#xf8;rkelund conflicts of interest: none declared. A. Andreassen conflicts of interest: none declared. L. Gullestad has received speaker fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim and Novartis. K. Broch has received speaker fees from, and has served on advisory boards for, Abbott, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, and Pharmacosmos.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40840822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2025.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-8703(25)00300-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>