<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40937036</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2434-0790</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Circulation reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Circ Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Early Invasive Strategy in Non-ST-Elevation Acute Coronary Syndrome With Congestive Heart Failure&#x3000;- A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>697</StartPage><EndPage>704</EndPage><MedlinePgn>697-704</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1253/circrep.CR-25-0104</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Congestive heart failure (CHF) is associated with worse clinical outcomes in patients with non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome (NSTE-ACS); however, the optimal timing of invasive intervention in NSTE-ACS with CHF remains unclear. In this study, we assessed the impact of early vs. delayed invasive strategies on mortality and cardiac events by synthesizing a systematic review of randomized controlled trials of patients with NSTE-ACS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We searched MEDLINE, CENTRAL, and the Web of Science for randomized controlled trials comparing early and delayed invasive strategies in patients with NSTE-ACS and CHF, published before February 2023. Observational studies were excluded. The primary endpoint was a composite of all-cause mortality and myocardial infarction at 2 years. Two eligible studies, including 310 participants, were identified. The primary endpoint occurred in 40 (24.5%) of 163 patients in the early invasive strategy group, compared with 39 (26.5%) of 147 patients in the delayed invasive strategy group, and the effect of an early invasive strategy on the primary outcome was uncertain (risk ratio 0.95 [95% confidence interval 0.66-1.37]). The certainty of the evidence was rated very low.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The effects of an early invasive strategy in patients with NSTE-ACS and CHF remains uncertain, with no clear reduction in composite outcome of mortality and myocardial infarction at 2 years compared with delayed intervention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, THE JAPANESE CIRCULATION SOCIETY.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Kiyotaka</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine Sendai Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taniguchi</LastName><ForeName>Takuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Otsu City Hospital Shiga Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kojima</LastName><ForeName>Sunao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Sakurajyuji Yatsushiro Rehabilitation Hospital Kumamoto Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arai</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine Sendai Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aoyama</LastName><ForeName>Rie</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Heart and Vascular Institute, Funabashi Municipal Medical Center Chiba Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tateishi</LastName><ForeName>Kazuya</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Chiba University Hospital Chiba Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minami</LastName><ForeName>Yuichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tokyo Women's Medical University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokose</LastName><ForeName>Masashi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Generalist Medicine, Dokkyo Medical University Tochigi Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Akihito</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine Nagoya Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuo</LastName><ForeName>Kunihiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Fukuoka Tokushukai Hospital Fukuoka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Junichi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tokyo Women's Medical University Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mano</LastName><ForeName>Toshiaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Center, Kansai Rosai Hospital Hyogo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Intensive Care, Nippon Medical School Hospital Tokyo Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakayama</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Kumamoto University Hospital Kumamoto Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanada</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency, Disaster and General Medicine, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine Aomori Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hashiba</LastName><ForeName>Katsutaka</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Yokosuka General Medical Center Kanagawa Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakashima</LastName><ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Kumamoto University Hospital Kumamoto Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kondo</LastName><ForeName>Toru</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine Nagoya Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noguchi</LastName><ForeName>Teruo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center Osaka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsujimoto</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scientific Research WorkS Peer Support Group (SRWS-PSG) Osaka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oku Medical Clinic Osaka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matoba</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Kyushu University Faculty of Medical Sciences Fukuoka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Funazaki</LastName><ForeName>Toshikazu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Kawaguchi Cupola Rehabilitation Hospital Saitama Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahara</LastName><ForeName>Yoshio</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center Osaka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nonogi</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Science, University of Shizuoka Shizuoka Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kikuchi</LastName><ForeName>Migaku</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Critical Care Center, Dokkyo Medical University Tochigi Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Japan Resuscitation Council (JRC) Emergency Cardiovascular Care (ECC) Acute Coronary Syndrome (ACS) Task Force and the Guideline Editorial Committee on behalf of the Japanese Circulation Society (JCS) Emergency and Critical Care Committee</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Circ Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101746642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2434-0790</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Congestive heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Early invasive strategy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>T. Matoba is a member of the Editorial Team for Circulation Reports and received research grants from Amgen. T. Mano received research grants from Abbott Medical Japan. The other authors declare no conflicts of interest with regard to this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40937036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12421134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circrep.CR-25-0104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Fox KA, Clayton TC, Damman P, Pocock SJ, de Winter RJ, Tijssen JG, et al.. 
Long-term outcome of a routine versus selective invasive strategy in patients with non-ST-segment elevation acute coronary syndrome a meta-analysis of individual patient data.
<i>J Am Coll Cardiol</i>
2010; 55: 2435&#x2013;2445.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20359842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Fanning JP, Nyong J, Scott IA, Aroney CN, Walters DL.. 
Routine invasive strategies versus selective invasive strategies for unstable angina and non-ST elevation myocardial infarction in the stent era.
<i>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</i>
2016; 2016: CD004815.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8568369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kotanidis CP, Mills GB, Bendz B, Berg ES, Hildick-Smith D, Hirlekar G, et al.. 
Invasive vs. conservative management of older patients with non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome: Individual patient data meta-analysis. <i>Eur Heart J</i>
2024; 45: 2052&#x2013;2062.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11177715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38596853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Byrne RA, Rossello X, Coughlan JJ, Barbato E, Berry C, Chieffo A, et al.. 
2023 ESC guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes.
<i>Eur Heart J</i>
2023; 44: 3720&#x2013;3826.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37622654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Amsterdam EA, Wenger NK, Brindis RG, Casey DE Jr, Ganiats TG, Holmes DR Jr, et al.. 
2014 AHA/ACC guideline for the management of patients with non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndromes: Executive summary: A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. <i>Circulation</i>
2014; 130: 2354&#x2013;2394.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kimura K, Kimura T, Ishihara M, Nakagawa Y, Nakao K, Miyauchi K, et al.. 
JCS 2018 guideline on diagnosis and treatment of acute coronary syndrome.
<i>Circ J</i>
2019; 83: 1085&#x2013;1196.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Navarese EP, Gurbel PA, Andreotti F, Tantry U, Jeong YH, Kozinski M, et al.. 
Optimal timing of coronary invasive strategy in non-ST-segment elevation acute coronary syndromes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Ann Intern Med</i>
2013; 158: 261&#x2013;270.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23420234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Jobs A, Mehta SR, Montalescot G, Vicaut E, Van&#x2019;t Hof AWJ, Badings EA, et al.. 
Optimal timing of an invasive strategy in patients with non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome: A meta-analysis of randomised trials. <i>Lancet</i>
2017; 390: 737&#x2013;746.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28778541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kite TA, Kurmani SA, Bountziouka V, Cooper NJ, Lock ST, Gale CP, et al.. 
Timing of invasive strategy in non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. <i>Eur Heart J</i>
2022; 43: 3148&#x2013;3161.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9433309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35514079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kofoed KF, Kelb&#xe6;k H, Hansen PR, Torp-Pedersen C, H&#xf8;fsten D, Kl&#xf8;vgaard L, et al.. 
Early versus standard care invasive examination and treatment of patients with non-ST-segment elevation acute coronary syndrome.
<i>Circulation</i>
2018; 138: 2741&#x2013;2750.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30565996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ozaki Y, Tobe A, Onuma Y, Kobayashi Y, Amano T, Muramatsu T, et al.. 
CVIT expert consensus document on primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) for acute coronary syndromes (ACS) in 2024.
<i>Cardiovasc Interv Ther</i>
2024; 39: 335&#x2013;375.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39302533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kikuchi M, Tahara Y, Yamaguchi J, Nakashima T, Nomura O, Tanaka A, et al.. 
Executive summary: Acute coronary syndrome in the Japan Resuscitation Council guidelines for resuscitation 2020. <i>Circ J</i>
2023; 87: 866&#x2013;878.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37081690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Steg PG, Dabbous OH, Feldman LJ, Cohen-Solal A, Aumont MC, L&#xf3;pez-Send&#xf3;n J, et al.. 
Determinants and prognostic impact of heart failure complicating acute coronary syndromes: Observations from the Global Registry of Acute Coronary Events (GRACE). <i>Circulation</i>
2004; 109: 494&#x2013;499.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14744970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bahit MC, Lopes RD, Clare RM, Newby LK, Pieper KS, Van de Werf F, et al.. 
Heart failure complicating non-ST-segment elevation acute coronary syndrome: Timing, predictors, and clinical outcomes. <i>JACC Heart Fail</i>
2013; 1: 223&#x2013;229.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24621874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kueh SH, Devlin G, Lee M, Doughty RN, Kerr AJ.. 
Management and long-term outcome of acute coronary syndrome patients presenting with heart failure in a contemporary New Zealand cohort (ANZACS-QI 4).
<i>Heart, Lung Circ</i>
2016; 25: 837&#x2013;846.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27132622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Alsheikh-Ali AA, Al-Mallah MH, Al-Mahmeed W, Albustani N, Al Suwaidi J, Sulaiman K, et al.. 
Heart failure in patients hospitalized with acute coronary syndromes: Observations from the Gulf Registry of Acute Coronary Events (Gulf RACE). <i>Eur J Heart Fail</i>
2009; 11: 1135&#x2013;1142.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19889691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wu AH, Parsons L, Every NR, Bates ER.. 
Hospital outcomes in patients presenting with congestive heart failure complicating acute myocardial infarction: A report from the Second National Registry of Myocardial Infarction (NRMI-2). <i>J Am Coll Cardiol</i>
2002; 40: 1389&#x2013;1394.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12392826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Adams KF Jr, Fonarow GC, Emerman CL, LeJemtel TH, Costanzo MR, Abraham WT, et al.. 
Characteristics and outcomes of patients hospitalized for heart failure in the United States: Rationale, design, and preliminary observations from the first 100,000 cases in the Acute Decompensated Heart Failure National Registry (ADHERE). <i>Am Heart J</i>
2005; 149: 209&#x2013;216.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15846257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sulo G, Sulo E, J&#xf8;rgensen T, Linnenberg A, Prescott E, Tell GS, et al.. 
Ischemic heart failure as a complication of incident acute myocardial infarction: Timing and time trends: A national analysis including 78,814 Danish patients during 2000&#x2013;2009. <i>Scand J Public Health</i>
2020; 48: 294&#x2013;302.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30813840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Fox KA, Eagle KA, Gore JM, Steg PG, Anderson FA.. 
The Global Registry of Acute Coronary Events, 1999 to 2009--GRACE.
<i>Heart</i>
2010; 96: 1095&#x2013;1101.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20511625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al.. 
PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: Updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. <i>BMJ</i>
2021; 372: n160.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Ioannidis JP, et al.. 
The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: Explanation and elaboration. <i>J Clin Epidemiol</i>
2009; 62: e1&#x2013;e34.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Cristo-Ropero MJ, Garcia-Rubira JC, Rivera-Rabanal FJ, Seoane-Garc&#xed;a T, Madrona-Jim&#xe9;nez L, Izquierdo-Bajo &#xc1;, et al.. 
N-terminal pro-B-type natriuretic peptide and pulmonary echography are predictors of acute heart failure needing early mechanical ventilation in acute coronary syndrome.
<i>Coron Artery Dis</i>
2024; 35: 556&#x2013;563.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38828510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hollenberg SM, Stevenson LW, Ahmad T, Bozkurt B, Butler J, Davis LL, et al.. 
2024 ACC expert consensus decision pathway on clinical assessment, management, and trajectory of patients hospitalized with heart failure focused update: A report of the American College of Cardiology Solution Set Oversight Committee. <i>J Am Coll Cardiol</i>
2024; 84: 1241&#x2013;1267.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39127954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al.. 
RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. <i>BMJ</i>
2019; 366: l4898.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Atkins D, Eccles M, Flottorp S, Guyatt GH, Henry D, Hill S, et al.; The GRADE Working Group.. 
Systems for grading the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations I: Critical appraisal of existing approaches The GRADE Working Group. <i>BMC Health Serv Res</i>
2004; 4: 38.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15615589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Tugwell P, Knottnerus A.. 
GRADE guidelines: A new series of articles in the Journal of Clinical Epidemiology. <i>J Clin Epidemiol</i>
2011; 64: 380&#x2013;382.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21185693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Huedo-Medina TB, S&#xe1;nchez-Meca J, Mar&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez F, Botella J.. 
Assessing heterogeneity in meta-analysis: Q statistic or I2 index? <i>Psychol Methods</i>
2006; 11: 193&#x2013;206.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16784338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Butt JH, Kofoed KF, Kelb&#xe6;k H, Hansen PR, Torp-Pedersen C, H&#xf8;fsten D, et al.. 
Importance of risk assessment in timing of invasive coronary evaluation and treatment of patients with non-ST-segment-elevation acute coronary syndrome: Insights from the VERDICT trial. <i>J Am Heart Assoc</i>
2021; 10: e022333.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8649124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34585591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Badings EA, Remkes WS, The SH, Dambrink JE, Tjeerdsma G, Rasoul S, et al.. 
Two-year outcome after early or late intervention in non-ST elevation acute coronary syndrome.
<i>Open Heart</i>
2017; 4: e000538.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Noma S, Kato K, Otsuka T, Nakao YM, Aoyama R, Nakayama A, et al.. 
Sex differences in cardiovascular disease-related hospitalization and mortality in Japan: Analysis of health records from a nationwide claim-based database, the Japanese Registry of All Cardiac and Vascular Disease (JROAD). <i>Circ J</i>
2024; 88: 1332&#x2013;1342.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38839304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kawamoto T, Otsuki H, Arashi H, Jujo K, Oka T, Mori F, et al.. 
Adverse clinical events after percutaneous coronary intervention in very elderly patients with acute coronary syndrome.
<i>Cardiovasc Interv Ther</i>
2024; 39: 438&#x2013;447.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38839727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Takeji Y, Morimoto T, Shiomi H, Kato ET, Imada K, Yoshikawa Y, et al.. 
Sex differences in clinical outcomes after percutaneous coronary intervention.
<i>Circ J</i>
2023; 87: 277&#x2013;286.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36351607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ninomiya R, Koeda Y, Nasu T, Ishida M, Yoshizawa R, Ishikawa Y, et al.. 
Effect of patient&#x2019;s symptom interpretation on in-hospital mortality in acute coronary syndrome.
<i>Circ J</i>
2024; 88: 1225&#x2013;1234.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38880608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Vaur L, Danchin N, Gen&#xe8;s N, Dubroca I, Etienne S, Ferri&#xe8;res J, et al.. 
Epidemiology of myocardial infarction in France: Therapeutic and prognostic implications of heart failure during the acute phase. <i>Am Heart J</i>
1999; 137: 49&#x2013;58.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9878936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Steg PG, Kerner A, Van de Werf F, L&#xf3;pez-Send&#xf3;n J, Gore JM, Fitzgerald G, et al.. 
Impact of in-hospital revascularization on survival in patients with non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome and congestive heart failure.
<i>Circulation</i>
2008; 118: 1163&#x2013;1171.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18725494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Shen L, Xian Y, Chen AY, Thomas L, Roe MT, Peterson ED, et al.. 
Effect of intervention timing on one-year mortality in elderly non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction patients.
<i>Coron Artery Dis</i>
2021; 32: 138&#x2013;144.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kim MC, Jeong MH, Sim DS, Hong YJ, Kim JH, Ahn Y, et al.. 
Optimal timing of percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction complicated by acute decompensated heart failure (from the Korea Acute Myocardial Infarction Registry-National Institutes of Health [KAMIR-NIH]).
<i>Am J Cardiol</i>
2018; 121: 1285&#x2013;1292.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29680172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Yoshida R, Ishii H, Morishima I, Tanaka A, Morita Y, Takagi K, et al.. 
Early versus delayed invasive strategy in patients with non-ST-elevation acute coronary syndrome and concomitant congestive heart failure.
<i>J Cardiol</i>
2019; 74: 320&#x2013;327.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.. International Clinical Trials Registry Platform. https://trialsearch.who.int/Trial2.aspx?TrialID=KCT0006035 (accessed May, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Cordero A, Mart&#xed;nez Rey-Ra&#xf1;al E, Moreno MJ, Escribano D, Moreno-Arribas J, Quintanilla MA, et al.. 
Predictive value of Pro-BNP for heart failure readmission after an acute coronary syndrome.
<i>J Clin Med</i>
2021; 10: 1653.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33924437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bhatia MS, Sharda SC, Attri R, Pannu AK, Dahiya N.. 
Correlation of mortality with Pro-BNP and precipitating factors of acute heart failure in patients presenting to a medical emergency of tertiary care hospital: An observational study from north India. <i>Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci</i>
2022; 26: 6459&#x2013;6468.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>