<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40895968</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Renal Effects of Continuous Infusion Versus Intermittent Bolus Dosing of IV Loop Diuretics in Acute Decompensated Heart Failure: A Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e88953</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e88953</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e88953</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.88953</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>IV loop diuretics remain the cornerstone of treatment for acute decompensated heart failure (ADHF). Although previous meta-analyses have compared continuous infusion and intermittent bolus dosing of IV loop diuretics, their respective renal effects remain unclear. Given the prognostic significance of worsening renal function (WRF) or acute kidney injury in ADHF, evaluating the renal safety of different diuretic regimens is essential. We conducted a systematic search of the PubMed database and performed a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) comparing both diuretic strategies. The primary outcome was WRF, while secondary outcomes included increases in serum creatinine (sCr), sCr levels at discharge, discharge blood urea nitrogen (BUN) levels, and length of hospitalization. A post hoc trial sequential analysis (TSA) was also conducted to assess the adequacy of the current pooled evidence. A total of 11 RCTs were included. There was no statistically significant difference in the incidence of WRF between continuous infusion and intermittent bolus dosing (RR 1.12; 95% CI, 0.86 to 1.48; I&#xb2; = 0.00%). Similarly, no significant differences were found in secondary outcomes: increase in sCr (mean difference (MD) 0.24 mg/dL; 95% CI, -0.17 to 0.66 mg/dL; I&#xb2; = 98.7%), sCr at discharge (MD 0.33 mg/dL; 95% CI, -0.13 to 0.80 mg/dL; I&#xb2; = 69.6%), discharge BUN levels (MD 6.57 mg/dL; 95% CI, -7.93 to 21.80 mg/dL; I&#xb2; = 78.7%), and length of hospitalization (MD -0.50 days; 95% CI, -2.75 to 1.76 days; I&#xb2; = 93.0%). The post hoc TSA revealed that the current evidence base is underpowered and inconclusive. Limited heterogeneity (I&#xb2; = 0%) was observed among studies reporting WRF, indicating consistency in this primary outcome. However, the high I&#xb2; values and wide CIs in the secondary outcomes reflect imprecise effect estimates, thereby limiting the clinical certainty of these findings. The TSA calculated a required information size of 3,342 participants, whereas the accrued information size in this meta-analysis was only 693 participants. This discrepancy underscores the potential for a type II error and reinforces the conclusion that current evidence remains insufficient to draw definitive conclusions. Overall, continuous infusion of loop diuretics does not appear to provide a significant renal advantage over intermittent bolus administration. The substantial evidence gap highlights the need for larger, high-quality RCTs powered to detect clinically meaningful renal outcomes. This study represents the first meta-analysis to prioritize renal endpoints and incorporate TSA in comparing these two diuretic strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Kugasenanchettiar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kugasenanchettiar</LastName><ForeName>Abbeykeith</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Internal Medicine, Ealing Hospital, Southall, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasanthan</LastName><ForeName>Kowshijan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Internal Medicine, George Eliot Hospital, Nuneaton, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saha</LastName><ForeName>Arkaprabha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Internal Medicine, East Surrey Hospital, Redhill, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lakra</LastName><ForeName>Oltiana</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, London North West University Healthcare NHS Trust, Harrow, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute decompensated heart failure (adhf)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">continuous infusion loop diuretic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decompensated heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diuretic therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure hospitalization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40895968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12392021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.88953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Temporal trends in hospitalization for acute decompensated heart failure in the United States, 1998-2011. Agarwal SK, Wruck L, Quibrera M, et al. Am J Epidemiol. 2016;183:462&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26895710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34447992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, et al. Circulation. 2022;145:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35379503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diuretic treatment in heart failure. Ellison DH, Felker GM. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:1964&#x2013;1975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5811193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29141174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The physiologic basis of diuretic synergism: its role in treating diuretic resistance. Ellison DH. Ann Intern Med. 1991;114:886&#x2013;894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2014951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role and mechanism of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system in the onset and development of cardiorenal syndrome. Ma K, Gao W, Xu H, Liang W, Ma G. J Renin Angiotensin Aldosterone Syst. 2022;2022:3239057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35111237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characterization of alpha-adrenoceptors on isolated rabbit renal arterioles. Edwards RM, Trizna W. Am J Physiol. 1988;254:0&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2830789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Society of Nephrology&#x2019;s 0by25 initiative for acute kidney injury (zero preventable deaths by 2025): a human rights case for nephrology. Mehta RL, Cerd&#xe1; J, Burdmann EA, et al. The Lancet. 2015;27:2616&#x2013;2643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25777661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Readmission and mortality after hospitalization with acute kidney injury. Schulman IH, Chan K, Der JS, et al. Am J Kidney Dis. 2023;82:63&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10293057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37115159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worsening renal function and mortality in heart failure: causality or confounding? Testani JM, Brisco-Bacik MA. Circ Heart Fail. 2017;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5382499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28209768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worsening renal function and prognosis in heart failure: systematic review and meta-analysis. Damman K, Navis G, Voors AA, et al. J Card Fail. 2007;13:599&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17923350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diuretic therapy and resistance in congestive heart failure. Ellison DH. Cardiology. 2001;96:132&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11805380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous infusion versus bolus injection of loop diuretics in congestive heart failure. Salvador DR, Rey NR, Ramos GC, Punzalan FE. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2005;2005:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16034890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous infusion versus bolus injection of loop diuretics for patients with congestive heart failure: a meta-analysis. Karedath J, Asif A, Tentu N, et al. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10005852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36909062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous infusion vs. intermittent bolus injection of furosemide in acute decompensated heart failure: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Ng KT, Yap JL. Anaesthesia. 2018;73:238&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28940440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diuretic treatment in high-risk acute decompensation of advanced chronic heart failure-bolus intermittent vs. continuous infusion of furosemide: a randomized controlled trial. Frea S, Pidello S, Volpe A, et al. Clin Res Cardiol. 2020;109:417&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31256261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of bolus dose furosemide versus continuous infusion in patients with acute decompensated left ventricular failure and atrial fibrillation. Khan B, Shuja D, Saqib BU, et al. Clin Cardiol. 2024;47:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11573718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39558518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. Cochrane; 2024. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. BMJ. 2009;339:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Section 2: AKI definition. Kidney Int Suppl (2011) 2012;2:19&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4089595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25018918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loop diuretic strategies in patients with acute decompensated heart failure: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Wu MY, Chang NC, Su CL, et al. J Crit Care. 2014;29:2&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24331943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous versus intermittent administration of furosemide in acute decompensated heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Kuriyama A, Urushidani S. Heart Fail Rev. 2019;24:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advanced heart failure: parenteral diuretics for breathlessness and peripheral oedema - systematic review. Hughes A, Oluyase AO, Below N, Bajwah S. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2024;14:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36585222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. BMJ. 2019;366:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous versus bolus dosing of furosemide for patients hospitalized for heart failure. Allen LA, Turer AT, Dewald T, Stough WG, Cotter G, O'Connor CM. Am J Cardiol. 2010;105:1794&#x2013;1797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20538132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diuretic strategies in patients with acute decompensated heart failure. Felker GM, Lee KL, Bull DA, et al. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:797&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21366472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A study on continuous infusion versus intermittent bolus dosing of furosemide in hospitalized heart failure patients. Jaya Shree D, Daniel CJ, Marsh C, et al. RJPT. 2021;26:2814&#x2013;2818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical effects and safety of different strategies for administering intravenous diuretics in acutely decompensated heart failure: a randomised clinical trial. Llorens P, Mir&#xf3; &#xd2;, Herrero P, et al. Emerg Med J. 2014;31:706&#x2013;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23793945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous versus bolus intermittent loop diuretic infusion in acutely decompensated heart failure: a prospective randomized trial. Palazzuoli A, Pellegrini M, Ruocco G, et al. Crit Care. 2014;18:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4227080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24974232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous infusion of furosemide versus intermittent boluses in acute decompensated heart failure: effect on thoracic fluid content. Ragab D, Taema KM, Farouk W, Saad M. Egypt Heart J. 2018;70:65&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6112354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30166884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A prospective, randomized study to evaluate the efficacy of various diuretic strategies in acute decompensated heart failure. Shah RA, Subban V, Lakshmanan A, et al. Indian Heart J. 2014;66:309&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4121756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24973836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of three diuretic treatment strategies for patients with acute decompensated heart failure. Yayla &#xc7;, Akyel A, Canpolat U, et al. Herz. 2015;40:1115&#x2013;1120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26135463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Continuous versus intermittent use of furosemide in patients with heart failure and moderate chronic renal dysfunction. Zheng Z, Jiang X, Chen J, He D, Xie X, Lu Y. ESC Heart Fail. 2021;8:2070&#x2013;2078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8120396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33689236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, et al. BMJ. 2011;343:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trial sequential analysis may establish when firm evidence is reached in cumulative meta-analysis. Wetterslev J, Thorlund K, Brok J, Gluud C. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61:64&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A multiple testing procedure for clinical trials. O'Brien PC, Fleming TR. Biometrics. 1979;35:549&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">497341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group sequential methods in the design and analysis of clinical trials. Pocock SJ. Biometrika. 1977;64:191&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute tolerance to furosemide diuresis in humans. Pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic modeling. Hammarlund MM, Odlind B, Paalzow LK. https://jpet.aspetjournals.org/article/S0022-3565(25)21252-6/abstract. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1985;233:447&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3999028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of heart failure patient with CKD. Banerjee D, Rosano G, Herzog CA. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;16:1131&#x2013;1139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8425606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33495289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>