<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40992983</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-0210</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Primary care diabetes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Prim Care Diabetes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intervention fidelity and behaviour change mechanisms in a health promotion intervention for women following gestational diabetes mellitus: Secondary analysis of the Face-it RCT.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1751-9918(25)00188-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.pcd.2025.09.003</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We evaluated the fidelity of the Face-it intervention and its impact on behaviour change mechanisms among women with recent gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this randomised controlled trial, 277 women were allocated to usual care or an intervention comprising three home visits, digital platform health coaching and cross-sectoral communication to support health behaviour change during the first year after delivery. Behaviour change mechanisms included social support, motivation, self-efficacy, risk perception and health literacy. High fidelity was defined as completing three home visits and &#x2265;&#x202f;9 coaching contacts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Within the intervention group, 86.4 % completed &#x2265;&#x202f;2 home visits, 88.6&#x202f;% registered digitally with a median (IQR) of 10.0 (3.0-20.0) contacts. At one-year after delivery, the high-fidelity group (n&#x202f;=&#x202f;73; 39.7&#x202f;%) had higher odds of perceiving moderate/high diabetes risk (OR 2.42; 95&#x202f;% CI 1.06-5.51) and higher health literacy (adjusted difference 0.20; 95&#x202f;% CI 0.04-0.35), whereas no difference was found for social support, motivation and self-efficacy compared with usual care. No difference was observed between the low fidelity and the usual care group in behaviour change mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The Face-it intervention achieved acceptable fidelity. High fidelity appears essential for improving risk perception, health literacy and supporting behaviour change mechanisms among women with recent GDM.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Husted Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Nanna</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark. Electronic address: naje@ph.au.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dahl-Petersen</LastName><ForeName>Inger Katrine</ForeName><Initials>IK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prevention, Health Promotion and Community Care, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Herlev, Denmark. Electronic address: inger.katrine.dahl-petersen.01@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nielsen</LastName><ForeName>Karoline Kragelund</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Prevention, Health Promotion and Community Care, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Herlev, Denmark. Electronic address: karoline.kragelund.nielsen@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Dorte M&#xf8;ller</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Odense, Odense, Denmark; Department of Gynaecology and Obstetrics, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark; Department of Clinical Research, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark. Electronic address: dorte.moeller.jensen@rsyd.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damm</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Pregnant Women with Diabetes, Department of Gynaecology Fertility and Obstetrics, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark; Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark. Electronic address: pdamm@dadlnet.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ovesen</LastName><ForeName>Per</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus, Aarhus, Denmark; Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark; Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark. Electronic address: per.ovesen@clin.au.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathiesen</LastName><ForeName>Elisabeth R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark; Center for Pregnant Women with Diabetes, Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Copenhagen University Hospital-Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark. Electronic address: elisabeth.reinhardt.mathiesen@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kampmann</LastName><ForeName>Ulla</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus, Aarhus, Denmark; Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark. Electronic address: ulla.kampmann@clin.au.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vinter</LastName><ForeName>Christina Anne</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Odense, Odense, Denmark; Department of Gynaecology and Obstetrics, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark; Department of Clinical Research, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark. Electronic address: christina.vinter@rsyd.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Reilly</LastName><ForeName>Sharleen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Agriculture and Food Sciences, University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland. Electronic address: Sharleen.oreilly@ucd.ie.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maindal</LastName><ForeName>Helle Terkildsen</ForeName><Initials>HT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark; Department of Prevention, Health Promotion and Community Care, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Herlev, Denmark. Electronic address: htm@ph.au.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Face-it Study Group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Prim Care Diabetes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101463825</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1878-0210</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behaviour Change Mechanisms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fidelity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gestational Diabetes Mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Promotion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interests KKN, IKDP and HTM were full-time or part-time employees at Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen. DMJ and CAV are employed at Steno Diabetes Center Odense. NHJ is affiliated to Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus and PO and UK are employed at Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus. The Steno Diabetes Centers are regional public hospitals and research institutions, which are partly funded by grants from the Novo Nordisk Foundation. PD has participated in clinical studies on the use of insulin in pregnant women with preexisting diabetes in collaboration with Novo Nordisk, but no personal honorarium was involved. ERM has contracts with Novo Nordisk for the Expect trial and the Evolve trial investigating newer insulin analogs and insulin pump treatment in pregnant women with diabetes, has received fees from Novo Nordisk for lectures, has received financial support from Novo Nordisk for travelling to one international scientific meeting in the field of diabetes, and is participating on an advisory board for Novo Nordisk. NHJ has received funding from the Danish Diabetes Foundation for a research stay abroad. SOR declares no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40992983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcd.2025.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1751-9918(25)00188-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>