<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">40904246</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-698X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Median arcuate ligament syndrome: challenges, comorbidities, and controversies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>447</StartPage><EndPage>451</EndPage><MedlinePgn>447-451</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MOP.0000000000001503</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Median arcuate ligament syndrome (MALS) is understood to be a condition where compression of the celiac artery by the median arcuate ligament (MAL) may lead to symptoms of postprandial or exercise-induced abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, oral aversion, and weight loss. This review summarizes recent literature on pediatric MALS while highlighting the challenges, comorbidities, and controversies encountered in this condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The pathophysiologic mechanism by which MALS leads to pain is currently unknown. Several overlapping conditions are described in MALS, including mental health comorbidities to autonomic disorders such as orthostatic intolerance, POTS, or Ehlers-Danlos syndrome. Comorbid gastrointestinal conditions may include gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), and gastroparesis. This overlap makes it difficult to distinguish the cause of broad symptoms patients may experience. MALS remains a complex and controversial topic with particular challenges in consensus diagnostic criteria, normative values in children, symptom definition or correlation, patient selection, predictive outcomes, or long-term follow-up data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with MALS deserve a comprehensive multidisciplinary team to address their health. There is also a desperate need for collaborative research including randomized control trials in adults and a multicenter patient registry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mostamand</LastName><ForeName>Shikib</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition, Stanford University School of Medicine and Stanford Children's Health, Palo Alto, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9000850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-8703</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074742" MajorTopicYN="Y">Median Arcuate Ligament Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Orthostatic Intolerance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004535" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015746" MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009325" MajorTopicYN="N">Nausea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014839" MajorTopicYN="N">Vomiting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003967" MajorTopicYN="N">Diarrhea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">celiac artery compression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric abdominal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric median arcuate ligament syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40904246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOP.0000000000001503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00008480-202510000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>King S, Chambers CT, Huguet A, et al. The epidemiology of chronic pain in children and adolescents revisited: a systematic review. Pain 2011; 152:2729&#x2013;2738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers CT, Dol J, Tutelman PR, et al. The prevalence of chronic pain in children and adolescents: a systematic review update and meta-analysis. Pain 2024; 165:2215&#x2013;2234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harjola P-T, Lahtiharju A. Celiac axis syndrome: abdominal angina caused by external compression of the celiac artery. Am J Surg 1968; 115:864&#x2013;869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EN, Lamb K, Relles D, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome-review of this rare disease. JAMA Surg 2016; 151:471&#x2013;477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter SR, Bernstein EF. The anatomic basis for respiratory variation in median arcuate ligament compression of the celiac artery. Surgery 1973; 73:381&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terlouw LG, Moelker A, Abrahamsen J, et al. European guidelines on chronic mesenteric ischaemia&#x2013;joint United European Gastroenterology, European Association for Gastroenterology, Endoscopy and Nutrition, European Society of Gastrointestinal and Abdominal Radiology, Netherlands Association of Hepatogastroenterologists, Hellenic Society of Gastroenterology, Cardiovascular and Interventional Radiological Society of Europe, and Dutch Mesenteric Ischemia Study group clinical guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of patients with chronic mesenteric ischaemia. United Eur Gastroenterol J 2020; 8:371&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak GZ, Speaker C, Anderson K, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome in the pediatric population. J Pediatr Surg 2013; 48:2261&#x2013;2270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelly CL, Mak GZ. Median arcuate ligament syndrome&#x2013;current state of management. Semin Pediatr Surg 2021; 30:151129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber H, Loizides A, Peer S, Gruber I. Ultrasound of the median arcuate ligament syndrome: a new approach to diagnosis. Med Ultrason 2012; 14:5&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Hayek KM, Titus J, Bui A, et al. Laparoscopic median arcuate ligament release: are we improving symptoms? J Am Coll Surg 2013; 216:272&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultan S, Hynes N, Elsafty N, Tawfick W. Eight years experience in the management of median arcuate ligament syndrome by decompression, celiac ganglion sympathectomy, and selective revascularization. Vasc Endovasc Surg 2013; 47:614&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts B, Pevsner R, Alkhoury F. Robotic approach for median arcuate ligament release in pediatrics. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A 2020; 30:92&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall R, Langridge B, Onida S, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome. J Vasc Surg 2020; 71:2170&#x2013;2176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moak JP, Ramwell C, Fabian R, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome with orthostatic intolerance: intermediate-term outcomes following surgical intervention. J Pediatr 2021; 231:141&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower KS, McCarthy CC, Vyasa P, et al. Celiac plexus block: a diagnostic tool for neurogenic median arcuate ligament syndrome. Pain Pract 2025; 25:e13403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shnayder-Adams MM, Masotti M, Sanogo ML. Clinical outcomes after median arcuate ligament release in patients responsive to celiac plexus block. J Vasc Interv Radiol 2024; 35:558&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak GZ, Lucchetti AR, Drossos T, et al. Pediatric chronic abdominal pain and median arcuate ligament syndrome: a review and psychosocial comparison. Pediatr Ann 2016; 45:e257&#x2013;e264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeCicco J, Raja F, Ganesan S, El-Hayek K. First description of a histopathologic grading system and relationship to outcomes after robotic median arcuate ligament release with celiac ganglionectomy and lymphadenectomy. Surgery 2024; 175:822&#x2013;832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeCicco J, Raja F, Ganesan S, et al. Pediatric outcomes after robotic median arcuate ligament release, celiac ganglionectomy, and lymphadenectomy. J Pediatr Surg 2024; 59:161664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakavand B, Burns RC, Centner A, Casas-Melley A. Median arcuate ligament syndrome in children: a single-center experience. Cureus 2024; 16:e57184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiles-Shields C, Osos S, Heilbrun A, et al. Targeting coping to improve surgical outcomes in pediatric patients with median arcuate ligament syndrome: feasibility study. Front Psychol 2021; 12:695435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiles-Shields C, Skelly CL, Mak GZ, et al. Psychological factors and outcomes in the surgical treatment of pediatric patients with median arcuate ligament syndrome. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2018; 66:866&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelly CL, Stiles-Shields C, Mak GZ, et al. The impact of psychiatric comorbidities on patient-reported surgical outcomes in adults treated for the median arcuate ligament syndrome. J Vasc Surg 2018; 68:1414&#x2013;1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JE, Kang M, Jeong OS, Rhee PL. A median arcuate ligament syndrome could be re-termed as a nutcracker celiac ganglion abdominal pain syndrome. J Neurogastroenterol Motil 2023; 29:200&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholbach T. Celiac artery compression syndrome in children, adolescents, and young adults: clinical and color duplex sonographic features in a series of 59 cases. J Ultrasound Med 2006; 25:299&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park CM, Chung JW, Kim HB, et al. Celiac axis stenosis: incidence and etiologies in asymptomatic individuals. Korean J Radiol 2001; 2:8&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskan O, Kaya E, Gungoren FZ, Erol C. Compression of the celiac artery by the median arcuate ligament: multidetector computed tomography findings and characteristics. Can Assoc Radiol J 2015; 66:272&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petnys A, Puech-Le&#xe3;o P, Zerati AE, et al. Prevalence of signs of celiac axis compression by the median arcuate ligament on computed tomography angiography in asymptomatic patients. J Vasc Surg 2018; 68:1782&#x2013;1787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazan V, Qu W, Al-Natour M, et al. Celiac artery compression syndrome: a radiological finding without clinical symptoms? Vascular 2013; 21:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner HH, Kemprud E. A clinicoanatomical study of the arcuate ligament of the diaphragm. Arch Surg 1971; 103:600&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metz FM, Blauw JT, Brusse-Keizer M, et al. Systematic review of the efficacy of treatment for median arcuate ligament syndrome. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2022; 64:720&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce DD, Antiel RM, Oderich G, et al. Pediatric median arcuate ligament syndrome: surgical outcomes and quality of life. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A 2014; 24:104&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnasamy K, Sanghavi R. Median arcuate ligament syndrome: the past and the future. Gastroenterol Clin North Am 2025; 54:589&#x2013;595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen J, Gordon M, Chogle A, et al. ESPGHAN/NASPGHAN guidelines for treatment of irritable bowel syndrome and functional abdominal pain-not otherwise specified in children aged 4-18&#x200a;years. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2025; 81:442&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>