<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40901093</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2049-0801</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of medicine and surgery (2012)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med Surg (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative efficacy of sodium-glucose transporter 2 inhibitors on lipid profiles in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD): a comprehensive Bayesian network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6008</StartPage><EndPage>6022</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6008-6022</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MS9.0000000000003658</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is a global health concern associated with dyslipidemia, obesity, and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM), necessitating effective therapeutic strategies. Sodium-glucose transporter 2 (SGLT-2) inhibitors have shown promise in improving metabolic parameters, but their comparative efficacy in NAFLD remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We systematically searched PubMed, Cochrane Library, Scopus, and Embase for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) up to 31 December 2024, involving NAFLD patients treated with SGLT-2 inhibitors versus placebo or standard treatments. Outcomes included changes in low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C), high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C), total cholesterol, triglycerides, BMI, and HbA1c. A Bayesian NMA was performed using a random-effects model, with mean differences (MD) and 95% credible intervals (CrI) reported. Treatments were ranked using Surface Under the Cumulative Ranking Curve (SUCRA) scores.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We evaluated and compared the efficacy of SGLT-2 inhibitors in improving lipid profiles (LDL-C, HDL-C, total cholesterol, and triglycerides), BMI, and HbA1c in patients with NAFLD. Eleven RCTs involving 805 patients were included. Empagliflozin achieved the greatest LDL-C reduction (MD:&#xa0;-8.07 mg/dL, 95% CrI:&#xa0;-25.92 to 1.41; SUCRA: 95.38%), total cholesterol reduction (MD:&#xa0;-15.08 mg/dL, 95% CrI: -58.87 to 5.38; SUCRA: 94.32%), and HbA1c reduction (MD:&#xa0;-0.69%, 95% CrI:&#xa0;-1.52 to -0.06; SUCRA: 81.84%). Ipragliflozin non-significantly increased HDL-C (MD: 2.28 mg/dL, 95% CrI:&#xa0;-1.21 to 4.83; SUCRA: 85.11%) and significantly reduced triglyceride (MD:&#xa0;-22.39 mg/dL, 95% CrI:&#xa0;-39.25 to -7.27; SUCRA: 82.26%). Dapagliflozin resulted in significant BMI reduction (MD: -1.23 kg/m<sup>2</sup>, 95% CrI: -2.11 to -0.41; SUCRA: 73.28%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Empagliflozin and ipragliflozin demonstrated superior efficacy in improving lipid profiles, while dapagliflozin was most effective for BMI reduction in NAFLD patients. These findings align with their cardiovascular and metabolic benefits, offering a multifaceted approach to a complex disease. Further research is needed to confirm long-term effects and optimize treatment strategies for diverse NAFLD populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalil</LastName><ForeName>Ibrahim</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8995-1058</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dhaka Medical College and Hospital, BD, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hossain</LastName><ForeName>Md Imran</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-3949-9388</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Dhaka University, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akter</LastName><ForeName>Mahmuda</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Dhaka University, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Badri</LastName><ForeName>Sajjad Ghanim</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, University of Baghdad, Baghdad, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Med Surg (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101616869</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2049-0801</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bayesian network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NAFLD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SGLT-2 inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipid profiles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic parameters</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40901093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12401347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MS9.0000000000003658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AMSU-D-25-01067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Younossi ZM, Koenig AB, Abdelatif D, et al. Global epidemiology of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease-Meta-analytic assessment of prevalence, incidence, and outcomes. Hepatology 2016;64:73&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26707365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalasani N, Younossi Z, Lavine JE, et al. The diagnosis and management of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: practice guidance from the American association for the study of liver diseases. Hepatology 2018;67:328&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estes C, Razavi H, Loomba R, et al. Modeling the epidemic of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease demonstrates an exponential increase in burden of disease. Hepatology 2018;67:123&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5767767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28802062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eslam M, Sanyal AJ, George J. International Consensus Panel. MAFLD: a consensus-driven proposed nomenclature for metabolic associated fatty liver disease. Gastroenterology 2020;158:1999&#x2013;2014.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32044314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilg H, Moschen AR, Roden M. NAFLD and diabetes mellitus. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2017;14:32&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27729660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsiki N, Mikhailidis DP, Mantzoros CS. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and dyslipidemia: an update. Metabolism 2016;65:1109&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27237577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Targher G, Byrne CD, Tilg H. NAFLD and increased risk of cardiovascular disease: clinical associations, pathophysiological mechanisms and pharmacological implications. Gut 2020;69:1691&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazlehurst JM, Woods C, Marjot T, et al. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and diabetes. Metabolism 2016;65:1096&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4943559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26856933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilar-Gomez E, Martinez-Perez Y, Calzadilla-Bertot L, et al. Weight loss through lifestyle modification significantly reduces features of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Gastroenterology 2015;149:367&#x2013;e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25865049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassailly G, Caiazzo R, Buob D, et al. Bariatric surgery reduces features of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis in morbidly obese patients. Gastroenterology 2015;149:379&#x2013;e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25917783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumida Y, Yoneda M. Current and future pharmacological therapies for NAFLD/NASH. J Gastroenterol 2018;53:362&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5847174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29247356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinman B, Wanner C, Lachin JM, et al. EMPA-REG OUTCOME Investigators. Empagliflozin, cardiovascular outcomes, and mortality in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2015;373:2117&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heerspink HJ, Perkins BA, Fitchett DH, et al. Sodium glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in the treatment of diabetes mellitus: cardiovascular and kidney effects, potential mechanisms, and clinical applications. Circulation 2016;134:752&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27470878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheen AJ. Sodium-glucose cotransporter type 2 inhibitors for the treatment of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nat Rev Endocrinol 2020;16:556&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32855502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajaj HS, Brown RE, Bhullar L, et al. SGLT2 inhibitors and incretin agents: associations with alanine aminotransferase activity in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Metab 2018;44:493&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30149145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komiya C, Tsuchiya K, Shiba K, et al. Ipragliflozin improves hepatic steatosis in obese mice and liver dysfunction in type 2 diabetic patients irrespective of body weight reduction. PloS One 2016;11:e0151511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26977813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahl S, Gancheva S, Stra&#xdf;burger K, et al. Empagliflozin effectively lowers liver fat content in well-controlled type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, phase 4, placebo-controlled trial. Diabetes Care 2020;43:298&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31540903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Li J, Xi W, et al. Dapagliflozin for nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2022;185:109791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neal B, Perkovic V, Mahaffey KW, et al. CANVAS Program Collaborative Group. Canagliflozin and cardiovascular and renal events in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2017;377:644&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28605608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohki T, Isogawa A, Toda N, et al. Effectiveness of ipragliflozin, a sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitor, as a second-line treatment for non-alcoholic fatty liver disease patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus who do not respond to incretin-based therapies including glucagon-like peptide-1 analogs and dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors. Clin Drug Investig 2016;36:313&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26914659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt DL, Szarek M, Steg PG, et al. SOLOIST-WHF Trial Investigators. Sotagliflozin in patients with diabetes and recent worsening heart failure. N Engl J Med 2021;384:117&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terra SG, Focht K, Davies M, et al. Phase III, efficacy and safety study of ertugliflozin monotherapy in people with type 2 diabetes mellitus inadequately controlled with diet and exercise alone. Diabetes Obes Metab 2017;19:721&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28116776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani A, Byrne CD, Scorletti E, et al. Efficacy and safety of anti-hyperglycaemic drugs in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease with or without diabetes: an updated systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Metab 2020;46:427&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuchay MS, Krishan S, Mishra SK, et al. Effect of Empagliflozin on Liver Fat in Patients with type 2 diabetes and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial (E-LIFT Trial). Diabetes Care 2018;41:1801&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito D, Shimizu S, Inoue K, et al. Comparison of ipragliflozin and pioglitazone effects on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized, 24-week, open-label, active-controlled trial. Diabetes Care 2017;40:1364&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28751548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Hou Y, Xin W, et al. The efficacy of sodium-glucose transporter 2 inhibitors in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pharmacol Res 2025;213:107647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39929274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G, Higgins JP, Ades AE, et al. Evaluation of networks of randomized trials. Stat Methods Med Res 2008;17:279&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17925316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Caldwell DM, et al. Checking consistency in mixed treatment comparison meta-analysis. Stat Med 2010;29:932&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20213715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monami M, Nardini C, Mannucci E. Efficacy and safety of sodium glucose co-transport-2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Diabetes Obes Metab 2014;16:457&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24320621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XL, Zhu QQ, Chen YH, et al. Cardiovascular safety, long-term noncardiovascular safety, and efficacy of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systemic review and meta-analysis with trial sequential Analysis. J Am Heart Assoc 2018;7:e007165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5850151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29353233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med 2015;162:777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Clarke M, Dooley G, et al. The nuts and bolts of PROSPERO: an international prospective register of systematic reviews. Syst Rev 2012;1:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3348673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22587842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea BJ, Reeves BC, Wells G, et al. AMSTAR 2: a critical appraisal tool for systematic reviews that include randomised or non-randomised studies of healthcare interventions, or both. BMJ 2017;358:j4008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, and Deeks JJ. Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. In. Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, eds. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2019:143-176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre C, Glanville J, Briscoe S, et al. Searching for and selecting studies. In. Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, eds. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2019:67-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramer WM, Milic J, Mast F. Reviewing retrieved references for inclusion in systematic reviews using EndNote. J Med Library Assoc 2017;105:84&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5234463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28096751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Puhan MA, Vedula SS, et al. Ad Hoc Network Meta-analysis Methods Meeting Working Group. Network meta-analysis-highly attractive but more methodological research is needed. BMC Med 2011;9:79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21707969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al. Cochrane Bias Methods Group, &amp; Cochrane Statistical Methods Group. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2024. https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;liveau A, Boyne DJ, Slater J, et al. BUGSnet: an R package to facilitate the conduct and reporting of Bayesian network Meta-analyses. BMC Med Res Methodol 2019;19:196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S, Sutton AJ, Ades AE, et al. Evidence synthesis for decision making 2: a generalized linear modeling framework for pairwise and network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Med Decis Making: Int J Soc Med Decis Making 2013;33:607&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A, Carlin JB, Stern HS, et al. Bayesian Data Analysis. 3rd ed. 2-6 Boundary Row, London, SE1 8HN: Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks SP, Gelman A. General methods for monitoring convergence of iterative simulations. J Comput Graph Stat 1998;7:434&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Valkenhoef G, Kuiper J.
gemtc: Network Meta-Analysis Using Bayesian Methods. R package version 1.0-1; 2021. https://cran.r-project.org/package=gemtc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G, Ades AE, Ioannidis JP. Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol 2011;64:163&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Sutton AJ, et al. Evidence synthesis for decision making 1: introduction. Med Decis Making: Int J Soc Med Decis Making 2013;33:597&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23804506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegelhalter DJ, Best NG, Carlin BP, et al. Bayesian measures of model complexity and fit. J R Stat Soc Ser B Stat Method 2002;64:583&#x2013;639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaimani A, Caldwell DM, Li T, et al. Undertaking network meta-analyses. In. Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, eds. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2019:285-320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Sterne JAC, Savovic J, et al. A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomized trials. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2016;10:29&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phrueksotsai S, Pinyopornpanish K, Euathrongchit J, et al. The effects of dapagliflozin on hepatic and visceral fat in type 2 diabetes patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021;36:2952&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34129252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehrehgosha H, Sohrabi MR, Ismail-Beigi F, et al. Empagliflozin improves liver steatosis and fibrosis in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Diabetes Ther 2021;12:843&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri H, Malek M, Ismail-Beigi F, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on liver steatosis and fibrosis in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease without diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Adv Ther 2020;37:4697&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi H, Kessoku T, Kawanaka M, et al. Ipragliflozin improves the hepatic outcomes of patients with diabetes with NAFLD. Hepatol Commun 2022;6:120&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8710792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34558835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aso Y, Sagara M, Niitani T, et al. Serum high-molecular-weight adiponectin and response to dapagliflozin in patients with type 2 diabetes and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. J Investig Med 2021;69:1324&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34016738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han E, Lee YH, Lee BW, et al. Ipragliflozin additively ameliorates non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in patients with type 2 diabetes controlled with metformin and pioglitazone: a 24-week randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med 2020;9:259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31963648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson JW, Lundkvist P, Jansson PA, et al. Effects of dapagliflozin and n-3 carboxylic acids on non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in people with type 2 diabetes: a double-blind randomised placebo-controlled study. Diabetologia 2018;61:1923&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29971527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhini SH, Wahsh EA, Elberry AA, et al. The impact of an SGLT2 inhibitor versus ursodeoxycholic acid on liver steatosis in diabetic patients. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 2022;15:1516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9786599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36558967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M, Zhang H, Wang W, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin on liver and pancreatic fat in patients with type 2 diabetes and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. J Diabetes Complications 2023;37:108610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37722211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain M, Babar MZM, Tariq S, et al. Therapeutic outcome of dapagliflozin on various parameters in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) patients. Int J Diabetes Dev Ctries 2022;42:290&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>