<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40900863</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2222-0682</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of methodology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Methodol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety and efficacy of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists in individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus fasting during Ramadan: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>105478</StartPage><MedlinePgn>105478</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">105478</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5662/wjm.v15.i4.105478</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Data on the use of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists (GLP-1RAs) in individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) during Ramadan fasting is limited. No meta-analysis has summarized the safety and effectiveness of GLP-1RAs in these situations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the safety and efficacy of GLP-1RA in patients with T2DM fasting during Ramadan.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Electronic databases were systematically searched for relevant studies that featured GLP-1RA in the intervention arm and other glucose-lowering medications in the control arm. The primary outcome was adverse events (AEs) during Ramadan for both groups; other outcomes included changes in glycemic and anthropometric measures during the peri-Ramadan period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Four studies [three randomized-controlled trials with low risk of bias (RoB) and one prospective observational study with serious RoB] involving 754 subjects were analyzed. GLP-1RA group achieved greater glycated hemoglobin reduction than the non-GLP-1RA group [mean difference (MD): -0.31%, 95%CI: -0.61 to -0.01, <i>P</i> = 0.04, <i>I</i> <sup>2</sup> = 77%] with a lower risk of documented symptomatic hypoglycemia (risk ratio = 0.38, 95%CI: 0.16 to 0.88, <i>P</i> = 0.02). Any AEs, serious AEs, or AEs that led to treatment discontinuation were comparable between the two groups. The GLP-1RA group experienced greater weight loss compared to the non-GLP-1RA group (MD: -2.0 kg, 95%CI: -3.37 to -0.63, <i>P</i> = 0.004, <i>I</i> <sup>2</sup> = 95%). There were comparable changes in blood pressure and lipid profile between the two groups. GLP-1RA users experienced higher risks of gastrointestinal AEs, nausea, and vomiting; however, the risks of heartburn, abdominal pain, and diarrhea were similar in both groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Limited evidence suggests that GLP-1RAs are safe for T2DM management during Ramadan, offering modest benefits in blood sugar control and weight loss. Large multicenter trials are needed to confirm their safety and efficacy in at-risk populations, improving clinical practice decision-making.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamrul-Hasan</LastName><ForeName>Abul Bashar Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>ABM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Mymensingh Medical College, Mymensingh 2200, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pappachan</LastName><ForeName>Joseph M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester M156BH, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Kasturba Medical College, Manipal and Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal 576104, Karnataka, India. drpappachan@yahoo.co.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashraf</LastName><ForeName>Hamid</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rajiv Gandhi Centre for Diabetes and Endocrinology, Aligarh Muslim University, Aligarh 202002, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagendra</LastName><ForeName>Lakshmi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, JSS Medical College, JSS Academy of Higher Education and Research, Mysore, 570004, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dutta</LastName><ForeName>Deep</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, CEDAR Superspeciality Healthcare, New Delhi 110075, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuchay</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Shafi</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Diabetes, Medanta-The Medicity Hospital, Gurugram 122001, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaikh</LastName><ForeName>Shehla</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Sir H.N. Reliance Foundation Hospital and Research Centre, Mumbai 400004, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Methodol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101628739</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2222-0682</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ramadan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Religious fasting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: There are no conflicts in interest among authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40900863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12400322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5662/wjm.v15.i4.105478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ochani RK, Shaikh A, Batra S, Pikale G, Surani S. Diabetes among Muslims during Ramadan: A narrative review. World J Clin Cases. 2023;11:6031&#x2013;6039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10507567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37731557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanein MM, Hanif W, Malek R, Jabbar A. Changes in fasting patterns during Ramadan, and associated clinical outcomes in adults with type 2 diabetes: A narrative review of epidemiological studies over the last 20 years. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2021;172:108584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33307133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanein M, Hussein Z, Shaltout I, Wan Seman WJ, Tong CV, Mohd Noor N, Buyukbese MA, El Tony L, Shaker GM, Alamoudi RM, Hafidh K, Fariduddin M, Batais MA, Shaikh S, Malek PR, Alabbood M, Sahay R, Alshenqete AM, Yakoob Ahmedani M. The DAR 2020 Global survey: Ramadan fasting during COVID 19 pandemic and the impact of older age on fasting among adults with Type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2021;173:108674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33493579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratama SA, Kurniawan R, Chiu HY, Kuo HJ, Ekpor E, Kung PJ, Al Baqi S, Hasan F, Romadlon DS. Glycemic fluctuations, fatigue, and sleep disturbances in type 2 diabetes during ramadan fasting: A cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2025;20:e0312356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11882071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40043024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baynouna Alketbi L, Afandi B, Nagelkerke N, Abdubaqi H, Al Nuaimi RA, Al Saedi MR, Al Blooshi FI, Al Blooshi NS, AlAryani AM, Al Marzooqi NM, Al Khouri AA, Al Mansoori SA, Hassanein M. Validation of the IDF-DAR risk assessment tool for Ramadan fasting in patients with diabetes in primary care. Front Clin Diabetes Healthc. 2025;6:1426120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11968361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40190383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee. Summary of Revisions: Standards of Care in Diabetes-2025. Diabetes Care. 2025;48:S6&#x2013;S13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11635056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39651984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold SV, Tang F, Cooper A, Chen H, Gomes MB, Rathmann W, Shimomura I, Vora J, Watada H, Khunti K, Kosiborod M. Global use of SGLT2 inhibitors and GLP-1 receptor agonists in type 2 diabetes. Results from DISCOVER. BMC Endocr Disord. 2022;22:111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9040320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35473607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanein M, Afandi B, Yakoob Ahmedani M, Mohammad Alamoudi R, Alawadi F, Bajaj HS, Basit A, Bennakhi A, El Sayed AA, Hamdy O, Hanif W, Jabbar A, Kleinebreil L, Lessan N, Shaltout I, Mohamad Wan Bebakar W, Abdelgadir E, Abdo S, Al Ozairi E, Al Saleh Y, Alarouj M, Ali T, Ali Almadani A, Helmy Assaad-Khalil S, Bashier AMK, Arifi Beshyah S, Buyukbese MA, Ahmad Chowdhury T, Norou Diop S, Samir Elbarbary N, Elhadd TA, Eliana F, Ezzat Faris M, Hafidh K, Hussein Z, Iraqi H, Kaplan W, Khan TS, Khunti K, Maher S, Malek R, Malik RA, Mohamed M, Sayed Kamel Mohamed M, Ahmed Mohamed N, Pathan S, Rashid F, Sahay RK, Taha Salih B, Sandid MA, Shaikh S, Slim I, Tayeb K, Mohd Yusof BN, Binte Zainudin S. Diabetes and Ramadan: Practical guidelines 2021. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2022;185:109185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35016991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.5. United Kingdom: Cochrane, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, Stewart LA, Thomas J, Tricco AC, Welch VA, Whiting P, Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Review Manager (RevMan) [Computer program]  Version 7.2.0. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2024. Available from: https://revman.cochrane.org .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Sterne JAC. Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in a randomized trial. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.4. United Kingdom: Cochrane, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Hern&#xe1;n MA, McAleenan A, Reeves BC, Higgins JPT. Chapter 25: Assessing risk of bias in a non-randomized study. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.5. United Kingdom: Cochrane, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness LA, Higgins JPT. Risk-of-bias VISualization (robvis): An R package and Shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Res Synth Methods. 2021;12:55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Hippel PT. The heterogeneity statistic I(2) can be biased in small meta-analyses. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2015;15:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25880989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azar ST, Echtay A, Wan Bebakar WM, Al Araj S, Berrah A, Omar M, Mutha A, Torn&#xf8;e K, Kaltoft MS, Shehadeh N. Efficacy and safety of liraglutide compared to sulphonylurea during Ramadan in patients with type 2 diabetes (LIRA-Ramadan): a randomized trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2016;18:1025&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5095865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27376711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanein MM, Sahay R, Hafidh K, Djaballah K, Li H, Azar S, Shehadeh N, Hanif W. Safety of lixisenatide versus sulfonylurea added to basal insulin treatment in people with type 2 diabetes mellitus who elect to fast during Ramadan (LixiRam): An international, randomized, open-label trial. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2019;150:331&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30772385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathan MF, Akter N, Selim S, Amin MF, Afsana F, Saifuddin M, Kamrul-hasan ABM, Mustari M, Chakraborty AK, Hossain RMM. Safety and Efficacy of Semaglutide Use in Diabetes during Ramadan Fasting: A Real-world Experience from Bangladesh. Bangladesh J Endocr Metab. 2024;3:26&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady EM, Davies MJ, Gray LJ, Saeed MA, Smith D, Hanif W, Khunti K. A randomized controlled trial comparing the GLP-1 receptor agonist liraglutide to a sulphonylurea as add on to metformin in patients with established type 2 diabetes during Ramadan: the Treat 4 Ramadan Trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2014;16:527&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanein M, Malek R, Al Sifri S, Sahay RK, Buyukbese MA, Djaballah K, Melas-Melt L, Shaltout I. Safety and Effectiveness of Concomitant iGlarLixi and SGLT-2i Use in People with T2D During Ramadan Fasting: A SoliRam Study Sub-analysis. Diabetes Ther. 2024;15:2309&#x2013;2322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11467161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39249672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahay R, Hafidh K, Djaballah K, Coudert M, Azar S, Shehadeh N, Hanif W, Hassanein M. Safety of lixisenatide plus basal insulin treatment regimen in Indian people with type 2 diabetes mellitus during Ramadan fast: A post hoc analysis of the LixiRam randomized trial. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2020;163:108148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debray TPA, Moons KGM, Riley RD. Detecting small-study effects and funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analysis of survival data: A comparison of new and existing tests. Res Synth Methods. 2018;9:41&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5873397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Z, Sun W, Wang H, Chang R, Wang J, Song C, Zhang S, Ni Q, An X. Comparison of the effectiveness and safety of GLP-1 receptor agonists for type 2 diabetes mellitus patients with overweight/obesity: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2025;222:111999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39828025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao H, Zhang A, Li D, Wu Y, Wang CZ, Wan JY, Yuan CS. Comparative effectiveness of GLP-1 receptor agonists on glycaemic control, body weight, and lipid profile for type 2 diabetes: systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2024;384:e076410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10823535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38286487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhezi OS, Alahmed AA, Alfayez OM, Alzuman OA, Almutairi AR, Almohammed OA. Comparative effectiveness of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists for the management of obesity in adults without diabetes: A network meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Obes Rev. 2023;24:e13543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36579723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlou V, Cienfuegos S, Lin S, Ezpeleta M, Ready K, Corapi S, Wu J, Lopez J, Gabel K, Tussing-Humphreys L, Oddo VM, Alexandria SJ, Sanchez J, Unterman T, Chow LS, Vidmar AP, Varady KA. Effect of Time-Restricted Eating on Weight Loss in Adults With Type 2 Diabetes: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e2339337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10611992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37889487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HY, Eso AA, Cook N, O'Neill HM, Albarqouni L. Meal Timing and Anthropometric and Metabolic Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7:e2442163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11530941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39485353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moiz A, Filion KB, Toutounchi H, Tsoukas MA, Yu OHY, Peters TM, Eisenberg MJ. Efficacy and Safety of Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists for Weight Loss Among Adults Without Diabetes : A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials. Ann Intern Med. 2025;178:199&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39761578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu BD, Udemba SC, Liang K, Tarabichi Y, Hill H, Fass R, Song G. Shorter-acting glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists are associated with increased development of gastro-oesophageal reflux disease and its complications in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a population-level retrospective matched cohort study. Gut. 2024;73:246&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37739778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austreg&#xe9;silo de Athayde De Hollanda Morais B, Martins Priz&#xe3;o V, de Moura de Souza M, Ximenes Mendes B, Rodrigues Defante ML, Cosendey Martins O, Rodrigues AM. The efficacy and safety of GLP-1 agonists in PCOS women living with obesity in promoting weight loss and hormonal regulation: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Diabetes Complications. 2024;38:108834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal J, Wu HX, Hu N, Zhou YH, Li L, Xiao F, Wang T, Jiang HL, Xu SN, Huang BL, Zhou HD. Effect of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists on body weight in adults with obesity without diabetes mellitus-a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Obes Rev. 2022;23:e13435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamarullah W, Pranata R, Wiramihardja S, Tiksnadi BB. Role of Incretin Mimetics in Cardiovascular Outcomes and Other Classical Cardiovascular Risk Factors beyond Obesity and Diabetes Mellitus in Nondiabetic Adults with Obesity: a Meta-analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2025;25:203&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39616304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong HJ, Toh KZX, Teo YH, Teo YN, Chan MY, Yeo LLL, Eng PC, Tan BYQ, Zhou X, Yang Q, Dalakoti M, Sia CH. Effects of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists on blood pressure in overweight or obese patients: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Hypertens. 2025;43:290&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39445607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae Y, Kwon SH, Nam JH, Kang E, Im J, Kim HJ, Lee EK. Lipid profile changes induced by glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2024;17:721&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38832475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari HUH, Qazi SU, Sajid F, Altaf Z, Ghazanfar S, Naveed N, Ashfaq AS, Siddiqui AH, Iqbal H, Qazi S. Efficacy and Safety of Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists on Body Weight and Cardiometabolic Parameters in Individuals With Obesity and Without Diabetes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Endocr Pract. 2024;30:160&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38029929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>