<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39830577</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Probiotics in the Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e75954</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e75954</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e75954</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.75954</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) significantly impacts quality of life. Probiotics offer relief by modulating gut microbiota, but variability in outcomes necessitates a systematic evaluation of their efficacy. This study aims to evaluate the efficacy of probiotics in improving symptoms of IBS through a systematic review and meta-analysis. A comprehensive search of PubMed and Google Scholar identified studies published between 2014 and 2018. Inclusion criteria focused on randomized controlled trials evaluating probiotics in adult IBS patients diagnosed using standardized criteria. Statistical analysis utilized random effects models to account for heterogeneity, with subgroup analysis performed for IBS subtypes. This review included 23 studies involving 3,288 participants. Probiotics significantly reduced abdominal pain (mean difference = -1.66, 95% CI = -2.39 to -0.93, p &lt; 0.0001) and bloating (mean difference =&#xa0;-2.13, 95% CI = -3.96 to -0.30, p = 0.0224). Improvement in stool habits was significant (mean difference = -1.52, 95% CI = -2.15 to -0.88, p &lt; 0.0001), particularly in diarrhea-predominant IBS. Quality of life improved significantly, with a mean increase of 8.77 points (95% CI = 0.91 to 16.64, p = 0.028). Adverse events were mild and infrequent. However, heterogeneity was high (I&#xb2; &gt; 90%), reflecting variability in study protocols. Probiotics are effective in reducing IBS symptoms and improving quality of life, mainly in diarrhea-predominant IBS. More research should be conducted that focuses on standardized, long-term trials to refine treatment strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Almabruk et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almabruk</LastName><ForeName>Bandar A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, King Salman Hospital, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bajafar</LastName><ForeName>Ali A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, King Abdullah Medical Complex, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Care Medicine, SEHA Salma Rehabilitation Hospital, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Zahrani</LastName><ForeName>Saleh A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, King Saud Bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albishi</LastName><ForeName>Naif M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing, Imam Abdulrahman Bin Faisal University, Dammam, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aljarwan</LastName><ForeName>Rafeef</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, King Saud Bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aljaser</LastName><ForeName>Rola A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Batterjee Medical College, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alghamdi</LastName><ForeName>Lama I</ForeName><Initials>LI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Batterjee Medical College, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almutairi</LastName><ForeName>Turki S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Surgery, Taif University, Taif, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsolami</LastName><ForeName>Almas S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Applied Medical Sciences, King Saud Bin Abdulaziz University for Health Sciences, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alghamdi</LastName><ForeName>Joud K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, King Abdulaziz University Hospital, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abdominal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastrointestinal microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">probiotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39830577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11741147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.75954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The irritable bowel syndrome (IBS): understanding its types, prevalence, and treatment options. Porwal A, Bhagwat G, Sawarkar J, Kamble P. World J Adv Res Rev. 2024;22:720&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Work-related problems and the psychosocial characteristics of individuals with irritable bowel syndrome: an updated literature review. Sugaya N. Biopsychosoc Med. 2024;18:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11094939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38750514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Li C, Ying Y, Zheng Y, Li X, Lan L. https://www.jpublichealth.org/articles/1034.html Epidemiol Public Health. 2024;2:1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multi-omics analysis of gut microbiota and host transcriptomics reveal dysregulated immune response and metabolism in young adults with irritable bowel syndrome. Chen J, Zhao T, Li H, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:3514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10970623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38542485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gut dysbiosis in irritable bowel syndrome: a narrative review on correlation with disease subtypes and novel therapeutic implications. Napolitano M, Fasulo E, Ungaro F, Massimino L, Sinagra E, Danese S, Mandarino FV. Microorganisms. 2023;11:2369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37894027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unveiling the therapeutic potential of modern probiotics in addressing neurodegenerative disorders: a comprehensive exploration, review and future perspectives on intervention strategies. Sharma H, Pathak R, Biswas D. Curr Psychiatry Res Rev. 2024;20:1&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probiotics: shaping the gut immunological responses. Filidou E, Kandilogiannakis L, Shrewsbury A, Kolios G, Kotzampassi K. World J Gastroenterol. 2024;30:2096&#x2013;2108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11045475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38681982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the efficacy of probiotics as treatment in irritable bowel syndrome. Ruiz-S&#xe1;nchez C, Escudero-L&#xf3;pez B, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Pach&#xf3;n MS. Endocrinol Diabetes Nutr (Engl Ed) 2024;71:19&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38331656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of probiotics in irritable bowel syndrome: systematic review and meta-analysis. Goodoory VC, Khasawneh M, Black CJ, Quigley EM, Moayyedi P, Ford AC. Gastroenterology. 2023;165:1206&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37541528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of probiotics, prebiotics and synbiotics in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trials. Zhang WX, Shi LB, Zhou MS, Wu J, Shi HY. J Med Microbiol. 2023;72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37772692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcome-specific efficacy of different probiotic strains and mixtures in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Xie P, Luo M, Deng X, Fan J, Xiong L. Nutrients. 2023;15:3856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10490209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37686889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. BMJ. 2021;372:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cytokine and clinical response to Saccharomyces boulardii therapy in diarrhea-dominant irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized trial. Abbas Z, Yakoob J, Jafri W, et al. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;26:630&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24722560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized clinical trial of Saccharomyces cerevisiae versus placebo in the irritable bowel syndrome. Pineton de Chambrun G, Neut C, Chau A, Cazaubiel M, Pelerin F, Justen P, Desreumaux P. Dig Liver Dis. 2015;47:119&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25488056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of probiotic administration immediately and 1 month after colonoscopy in diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome patients. Khodadoostan M, Shavakhi A, Sherafat Z, Shavakhi A. Adv Biomed Res. 2018;7:94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6036777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30050882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of Lactobacillus gasseri BNR17 on irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-finding trial. Kim JY, Park YJ, Lee HJ, Park MY, Kwon O. Food Sci Biotechnol. 2018;27:853&#x2013;857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6049675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30263811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic effects, tolerability and safety of a multi-strain probiotic in Iranian adults with irritable bowel syndrome and bloating. Jafari E, Vahedi H, Merat S, Momtahen S, Riahi A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24979556/ Arch Iran Med. 2014;17:466&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>I.31, a new combination of probiotics, improves irritable bowel syndrome-related quality of life. Lorenzo-Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga V, Llop E, Su&#xe1;rez C, Alvarez B, Abreu L, Espadaler J, Serra J. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:8709&#x2013;8716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4093724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25024629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized clinical trial on the effect of a multispecies probiotic on visceroperception in hypersensitive IBS patients. Ludidi S, Jonkers DM, Koning CJ, et al. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2014;26:705&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24588932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehealth: low FODMAP diet vs Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG in irritable bowel syndrome. Pedersen N, Andersen NN, V&#xe9;gh Z, et al. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:16215&#x2013;16226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4239510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25473176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of multi-strain probiotic compound on symptoms and quality-of-life in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Shavakhi A, Minakari M, Farzamnia S, et al. Adv Biomed Res. 2014;3:140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4139977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25161987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomised clinical trial: a liquid multi-strain probiotic vs. placebo in the irritable bowel syndrome--a 12 week double-blind study. Sisson G, Ayis S, Sherwood RA, Bjarnason I. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2014;40:51&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24815298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized clinical trial: effect of Lactobacillus plantarum 299 v on symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome. Stevenson C, Blaauw R, Fredericks E, Visser J, Roux S. Nutrition. 2014;30:1151&#x2013;1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25194614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of multispecies probiotics on irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Yoon JS, Sohn W, Lee OY, et al. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;29:52&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23829297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of probiotic Escherichia coli Nissle 1917 in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a double blind placebo-controlled randomized trial. Faghihi AH, Agah S, Masoudi M, Ghafoori SM, Eshraghi A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26586385/ Acta Med Indones. 2015;47:201&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26586385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of administering a multi-species probiotic mixture on the changes in fecal microbiota and symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Yoon H, Park YS, Lee DH, Seo JG, Shin CM, Kim N. J Clin Biochem Nutr. 2015;57:129&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4566021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26388670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irritable bowel syndrome symptom severity improves equally with probiotic and placebo. Lyra A, Hillil&#xe4; M, Huttunen T, et al. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22:10631&#x2013;10642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5192275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28082816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacillus coagulans MTCC 5856 supplementation in the management of diarrhea predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a double blind randomized placebo controlled pilot clinical study. Majeed M, Nagabhushanam K, Natarajan S, et al. Nutr J. 2016;15:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4769834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26922379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial: the efficacy of multispecies probiotic supplementation in alleviating symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome associated with constipation. Mezzasalma V, Manfrini E, Ferri E, et al. Biomed Res Int. 2016;2016:4740907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4993960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27595104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized double blind placebo-controlled trial of Saccharomyces cerevisiae CNCM I-3856 in irritable bowel syndrome: improvement in abdominal pain and bloating in those with predominant constipation. Spiller R, P&#xe9;lerin F, Cayzeele Decherf A, Maudet C, Housez B, Cazaubiel M, J&#xfc;sten P. United European Gastroenterol J. 2016;4:353&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4924426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27403301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of Lactobacillus casei Shirota for patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Thijssen AY, Clemens CH, Vankerckhoven V, Goossens H, Jonkers DM, Masclee AA. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;28:8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26469356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A double-blind, placebo-controlled study to assess the effect of a probiotic mixture on symptoms and inflammatory markers in women with diarrhea-predominant IBS. Hod K, Sperber AD, Ron Y, et al. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2017;29:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28271623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial of a multi-strain probiotic formulation (Bio-Kult&#xae;) in the management of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Ishaque SM, Khosruzzaman SM, Ahmed DS, Sah MP. BMC Gastroenterol. 2018;18:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5970461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29801486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lactobacillus acidophilus CL1285, Lactobacillus casei LBC80R and Lactobacillus rhamnosus CLR2 improve quality-of-life and IBS symptoms: a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled study. Preston K, Krumian R, Hattner J, de Montigny D, Stewart M, Gaddam S. Benef Microbes. 2018;9:697&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29888656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of Clostridium butyricum on symptoms and fecal microbiota in diarrhea-dominant irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Sun YY, Li M, Li YY, et al. Sci Rep. 2018;8:2964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5813237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29445178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methods of determining irritable bowel syndrome and efficiency of probiotics in treatment: a review. Ahlawat GM, Singh PK. Curr Ther Res Clin Exp. 2023;99:100721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10665699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38021264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Features of the effect of a probiotic, containing Lactobacillus and Bifidobacterium on the intestinal microbiota and clinical symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome. (Article in Russian) Khalaidzheva KN, Nikitina NV, Astrashkova OV, Drozdov VN, Melkonyan GG, Shikh EV. https://ter-arkhiv.ru/0040-3660/article/view/630936 Terapevticheskii Arkhiv. 2024;96:356&#x2013;363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probiotics in irritable bowel syndrome: a review of their therapeutic role. Satish Kumar L, Pugalenthi LS, Ahmad M, Reddy S, Barkhane Z, Elmadi J. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9116469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness and safety of probiotics for patients with constipation-predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 10 randomized controlled trials. Shang X, E FF, Guo KL, et al. Nutrients. 2022;14:2482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9231226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35745212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating the efficacy of probiotics in IBS treatment using a systematic review of clinical trials and multi-criteria decision analysis. Ceccherini C, Daniotti S, Bearzi C, Re I. Nutrients. 2022;14:2689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35807868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative efficacy and safety of probiotics for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis protocol. Yang M, Yu Y, Lei PG, Yuan J. BMJ Open. 2019;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choosing an appropriate probiotic product for your patient: an evidence-based practical guide. Sniffen JC, McFarland LV, Evans CT, Goldstein EJ. PLoS One. 2018;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain-specificity and disease-specificity of probiotic efficacy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. McFarland LV, Evans CT, Goldstein EJ. Front Med (Lausanne) 2018;5:124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5949321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29868585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Barrueta T. Molecular Mechanisms of Functional Food. New York, NY: Wiley; 2022. Psychobiotics, a special type of probiotics, and their potential molecular mechanisms to ameliorate symptoms of stress and anxiety; pp. 28&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of probiotics in treating psychiatric and neurological disorders. Fatima SM, Khan A, Asghar B. J Pak Med Assoc. 2024;74:202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38219197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of probiotics in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Li B, Liang L, Deng H, Guo J, Shu H, Zhang L. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>