<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40979655</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2160-200X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of cardiovascular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Cardiovasc Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of Azelnidipine-Telmisartan vs. Amlodipine-Telmisartan: a prospective randomized trial in Indian hypertensive patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>212</StartPage><EndPage>222</EndPage><MedlinePgn>212-222</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/UUWU8819</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The present study aimed to assess the efficacy and safety of a fixed-dose combination (FDC) of Azelnidipine 16 mg and Telmisartan 40 mg compared to FDC of Amlodipine 5 mg and Telmisartan 40 mg in Indian essential hypertensive patients with a special focus on the impact on micro-albuminuria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This prospective, randomized, open-label 12-week study enrolled 225 patients with treatment-naive stage II hypertensive patients or hypertensive patients not controlled on Telmisartan 40 mg monotherapy. The eligible participants were randomized to receive either FDC of Azelnidipine-Telmisartan (Test group; n=115) or FDC of Amlodipine-Telmisartan (Reference group; n=110). Efficacy was assessed via changes in systolic and diastolic blood pressure (SBP/DBP), pulse rate (PR), and urinary albumin-to-creatinine ratio (UACR), a marker of microalbuminuria. Safety parameters were evaluated by documenting the adverse effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both groups showed significant reductions in SBP and DBP from baseline, with no statistical difference among the groups. However, the test group expressed a more favorable effect on pulse rate, displaying a significant reduction compared to the reference group. Additionally, the occurrence of pedal edema was significantly lower in the test group vs. the reference group (1.7% vs. 9.1%). Changes in UACR were nominal and comparable in both groups, indicating limited renoprotective effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Collectively, the study confirms that FDC of Azelnidipine-Telmisartan is as effective as the commonly used FDC of Amlodipine-Telmisartan combination for management of hypertension, with additional safety benefits related to heart rate and edema. These findings support the clinical utility of Azelnidipine in hypertensive patients with concerns associated with tachycardia or pedal edema.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJCD Copyright &#xa9; 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bafna</LastName><ForeName>Akshay</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Head Department of Cardiology, Chhatrapati Pramilatai Raje (CPR) Hospital Kolhapur, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Cardiovasc Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101569582</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2160-200X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amlodipine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Azelnidipine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Telmisartan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcium channel blocker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microalbuminuria</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40979655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12444413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/UUWU8819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO. Hypertension. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/hypertension.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Heart Federation. Hypertension | what we do. https://world-heart-federation.org/what-we-do/hypertension/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills KT, Bundy JD, Kelly TN, Reed JE, Kearney PM, Reynolds K, Chen J, He J. Global disparities of hypertension prevalence and control: a systematic analysis of population-based studies from 90 countries. Circulation. 2016;134:441&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4979614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chobanian AV, Bakris GL, Black HR, Cushman WC, Green LA, Izzo JL Jr, Jones DW, Materson BJ, Oparil S, Wright JT Jr, Roccella EJ Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure. National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; National High Blood Pressure Education Program Coordinating Committee. Seventh report of the joint national committee on prevention, detection, evaluation, and treatment of high blood pressure. Hypertension. 2003;42:1206&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14656957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones KE, Hayden SL, Meyer HR, Sandoz JL, Arata WH, Dufrene K, Ballaera C, Lopez Torres Y, Griffin P, Kaye AM, Shekoohi S, Kaye AD. The evolving role of calcium channel blockers in hypertension management: pharmacological and clinical considerations. Curr Issues Mol Biol. 2024;46:6315&#x2013;6327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11275245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39057019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen BL, Zhang YZ, Luo JQ, Zhang W. Clinical use of azelnidipine in the treatment of hypertension in Chinese patients. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2015;11:309&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4348133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25750535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogensen CE, Neldam S, Tikkanen I, Oren S, Viskoper R, Watts RW, Cooper ME. Randomised controlled trial of dual blockade of renin-angiotensin system in patients with hypertension, microalbuminuria, and non-insulin dependent diabetes: the candesartan and lisinopril microalbuminuria (CALM) study. BMJ. 2000;321:1440&#x2013;1444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11110735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshii H, Mita T, Sato J, Kodama Y, Choi JB, Komiya K, Matsumoto K, Kanno R, Kawasumi M, Koyano H, Hirose T, Onuma T, Kawamori R, Watada H. Comparison of effects of azelnidipine and trichlormethiazide in combination with olmesartan on blood pressure and metabolic parameters in hypertensive type 2 diabetic patients. J Diabetes Investig. 2011;2:490&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4014909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24843534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuriyama S, Tomonari H, Tokudome G, Horiguchi M, Hayashi H, Kobayashi H, Ishikawa M, Hosoya T. Antiproteinuric effects of combined antihypertensive therapies in patients with overt type 2 diabetic nephropathy. Hypertens Res. 2002;25:849&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12484508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stangier J, Su C, Roth W. Pharmacokinetics of orally and intravenously administered telmisartan in healthy young and elderly volunteers and in hypertensive patients. J Int Med Res. 2000;28:149&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11014323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takai S, Kirimura K, Jin D, Muramatsu M, Yoshikawa K, Mino Y, Miyazaki M. Significance of angiotensin II receptor blocker lipophilicities and their protective effect against vascular remodeling. Hypertens Res. 2005;28:593&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16335888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang AL, Iadecola C, Wang G. New generations of dihydropyridines for treatment of hypertension. J Geriatr Cardiol. 2017;14:67&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5329735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28270844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamagishi T. Efficacy of azelnidipine on home blood pressure and pulse rate in patients with essential hypertension: comparison with amlodipine. Hypertens Res. 2006;29:767&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17283863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abernethy DR. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of amlodipine. Cardiology. 1992;80(Suppl 1):31&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1534713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura T, Inoue T, Fujiwara N, Kawagoe Y, Sugaya T, Ueda Y, Koide H, Node K. Additional renoprotective effects of azelnidipine combined with angiotensin receptor blockers in patients with diabetic nephropathy. Clin Nephrol. 2008;70:385&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19000538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kario K, Sato Y, Shirayama M, Takahashi M, Shiosakai K, Hiramatsu K, Komiya M, Shimada K. Inhibitory effects of azelnidipine tablets on morning hypertension. Drugs R D. 2013;13:63&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3627026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23512719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahrens K, Bramlage P. Importance of a fixed combination of telmisartan and amlodipine for the treatment of hypertension. Drugs Today (Barc) 2010;46:339&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20517535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neldam S, Edwards C, Lang M, Jones R TEAMSTA-5 and TEAMSTA-10 Investigators. Long-term tolerability and efficacy of single-pill combinations of Telmisartan 40-80 mg plus Amlodipine 5 or 10 mg in patients whose blood pressure was not initially controlled by Amlodipine 5-10 mg: open-label, long-term follow-ups of the TEAMSTA-5 and TEAMSTA-10 studies. Curr Ther Res Clin Exp. 2012;73:65&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3954024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24653513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalal J, Guha S, Reddy YVC, Ponde CK, Shrivastava S, Badani R, Joshi S, Pande A, Kumar V, Bhalla N, Pradhan A, Mahilmaran A, Kumar N, Manoj S, Sashikant T, Mukhopadhyay M, Tiwaskar M. Telmisartan plus Amlodipine as the preferred initial combination in newly diagnosed Indian patients with hypertension: an expert consensus statements. J Assoc Physicians India. 2023;71:56&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38736055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie M, Tang T, Liang H. Efficacy of single-pill combination in uncontrolled essential hypertension: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Clin Cardiol. 2023;46:886&#x2013;898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10436803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai PB, Patel K, Patel CN, Chaudhary PK. The role of Azelnidipine and Telmisartan in managing stage-II hypertension: a comprehensive review. International Journal of Innovative Science and Research Technology. 2025:1394&#x2013;1396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daikuhara H, Kikuchi F, Ishida T. The combination of OLmesartan and a CAlcium channel blocker (azelnidipine) or candesartan and a calcium channel blocker (amlodipine) in type 2 diabetic hypertensive patients: the OLCA study. Diab Vasc Dis Res. 2012;9:280&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22718810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuramoto K, Ichikawa S, Hirai A, Kanada S, Nakachi T, Ogihara T. Azelnidipine and amlodipine: a comparison of their pharmacokinetics and effects on ambulatory blood pressure. Hypertens Res. 2003;26:201&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal D, Maji S, Maiti R. Efficacy and safety of Azelnidipine as an Antihypertensive compared to Amlodipine: a systematic review and meta-analysis. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev. 2023;30:401&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37768510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogensen CE. Systemic blood pressure and glomerular leakage with particular reference to diabetes and hypertension. J Intern Med. 1994;235:297&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8151262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodicio JL, Campo C, Ruilope LM. Microalbuminuria in essential hypertension. Kidney Int Suppl. 1998;54:S51&#x2013;S54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9839284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram CVS. Therapeutic usefulness of a novel calcium channel blocker Azelnidipine in the treatment of hypertension: a narrative review. Cardiol Ther. 2022;11:473&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9652186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukadinovi&#x107; D, Scholz SS, Messerli FH, Weber MA, Williams B, B&#xf6;hm M, Mahfoud F. Peripheral edema and headache associated with amlodipine treatment: a meta-analysis of randomized, placebo-controlled trials. J Hypertens. 2019;37:2093&#x2013;2103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31107359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>