<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40763842</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-2990</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of the medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of testosterone deficiency and therapy on the cardiometabolic syndrome in men.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-9629(25)01138-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.amjms.2025.08.004</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Testosterone (T) is a metabolic, sexual, and vascular hormone that has an important metabolic function in many tissues and organs and plays a key role in maintaining human physiology and health. A deficiency of T has detrimental effects on men's health and negatively impacts quality of life. T regulates differentiation, growth and function of muscle tissue and inhibits differentiation into adipocytes and fat accumulation; therefore, it regulates body composition. Thus, T deficiency (TD) may contribute to development of adiposity and metabolic syndrome (MetS). It should be noted that over the past 80 years, only 4 randomized clinical trials with a duration of three years or longer were reported. Hence, understanding the effects of long-term T therapy (TTh) on amelioration of MetS and its components would be attained mostly from observational and registry studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive review of the current literature utilizing the NCBI library and PubMed were utilized using the key words "metabolic syndrome; testosterone deficiency; testosterone therapy". Relevant articles were retrieved and a summary of the potential relationship between TD and TTh and MetS were synthesized.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The contemporary findings in the medical literature strongly suggest that TD is a predictor of onset of MetS and TTh ameliorates MetS components. Long-term data from several registry studies on the impact of TTh on MetS in men with TD demonstrated unequivocally that long-term TTh (up to 11 years) resulted in reductions in waist circumference (WC), fasting blood glucose, triglycerides (TGs), systolic and diastolic blood pressure and increased high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL). In summary, long-term TTh in men with TD: 1) produces substantial and sustained weight loss; 2) prevents the progression from prediabetes to type 2 diabetes; 3) may result in remission of type 2 diabetes; 4) reduces fasting blood glucose; and 5) reduces cardiovascular events and mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this narrative review, we summarize the available contemporary literature on the potential relationship between TD and development of MetS and discuss the findings of long-term TTh on amelioration of MetS components in men.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saad</LastName><ForeName>Farid</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Expert and Consultant, Hamburg, Germany, and Research Department, Gulf Medical University, Ajman, United Arab Emirates. Electronic address: farid.saad.hamburg@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Traish</LastName><ForeName>Abdulmaged M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emeritus Professor of Biochemistry, Emeritus Professor of Urology, Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, MA 02118, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370506</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9629</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypogonadism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-term treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone and Type 2 Diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone and cardiovascular risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest F Saad is an occasional consultant to Gruenenthal GmbH, Aachen, Germany, manufacturer and distributor of a testosterone product, and Adon Health, a German Men&#x2019;s Health company. A Traish has no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40763842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjms.2025.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9629(25)01138-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>