<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39560589</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>103</Volume><Issue>46</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of acupuncture treatment for diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with comorbid anxiety and depression: A meta-analysis and systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e40207</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e40207</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e40207</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000040207</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Presently, a diverse range of Western medical interventions are accessible for the management of irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea (IBS-D) concomitant with comorbid anxiety and depression. However, the concomitant adverse effects have also surfaced, exerting strain on healthcare resources and the socio-economic structure. In recent times, the benefits of acupuncture in the management of IBS-D with coexisting anxiety and depression have become progressively evident. Nevertheless, a paucity of evidence-based medicine exists to substantiate the utilization of acupuncture for the treatment of IBS-D with anxiety and depression. The objective of this study is to examine the effectiveness of acupuncture as an intervention for IBS-D with comorbid anxiety and depression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We searched 7 databases, including the Chinese Journal Full-text Database, Wanfang Academic Journals Full-text Database, VIP Chinese Scientific Journals Full-text Database, China Biomedical Literature Database, PubMed, Embase, and Cochrane Library, for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) related to acupuncture treatment for IBS with anxiety and depression, published from database inception to August 1, 2023. RevMan 5.4 and Stata 17.0 software were used for meta-analysis of relevant outcome measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study included a total of 16 RCTs, involving 1305 IBS-D patients (691 in the experimental group and 614 in the control group). The meta-analysis results showed that compared to oral medication, acupuncture therapy improved HAMD scores (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.88, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[0.68, 1.07], P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001), HAMA scores (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;2.32, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[1.70, 2.93], P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001), self-rating anxiety scale scores (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;11.67, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[10.85, 12.49], P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001), SDS scores (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;9.84, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[8.52, 11.16], P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001), IBS-SSS scores (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;37.48, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[12.17, 62.78], P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.004), overall response rate (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;1.27, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[1.20, 1.35], P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001), and relapse rate (MD&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.27, 95% CI&#x2005;=&#x2005;[0.16, 0.47], P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001) in patients with IBS-D comorbid with anxiety and depression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Acupuncture treatment has a definite and beneficial effect on IBS-D patients with comorbid anxiety and depression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0447-090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Acupuncture and Massage, Shandong University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Hongwei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhengwen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Haiyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015670" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acupuncture Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003967" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diarrhea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="Y">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39560589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11576010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000040207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202411150-00083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tang HY, Jiang AJ, Wang XY, et al. . Uncovering the pathophysiology of irritable bowel syndrome by exploring the gut-brain axis: a narrative review. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8350700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34430628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Sperber AD, Corsetti M, Camilleri M. Irritable bowel syndrome. Lancet. 2020;396:1675&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D, Wang C. research progress on the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome using integrated traditional Chinese and Western medicine. Int J Tradit Chin Med. 2019;10:1150&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drossman DA, Hasler WL. Rome IV-functional GI disorders: disorders of gut-brain interaction. Gastroenterology. 2016;150:1257&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27147121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell CA, Kemppinen A, Allgar V, et al. . Double-blinded randomised placebo controlled trial of enterosgel (polymethylsiloxane polyhydrate) for the treatment of IBS with diarrhoea (IBS-D). Gut. 2022;71:2430&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9664110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomier E, Algera J, Melchior C. Pharmacological therapies and their clinical targets in irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea. Front Pharmacol. 2021;11:629026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarar ZI, Farooq U, Zafar Y, et al. . Burden of anxiety and depression among hospitalized patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a nationwide analysis. Ir J Med Sci. 2023;192:2159&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36593438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamani M, Alizadeh-Tabari S, Zamani V. Systematic review with meta-analysis: the prevalence of anxiety and depression in patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2019;50:132&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31157418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher HM, Black CJ, Teasdale SB, Mikocka-Walus A, Keefer L. Irritable bowel syndrome and mental health comorbidity &#x2013; approach to multidisciplinary management. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;20:582&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37268741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz MNM, Kumar J, Muhammad Nawawi KN, Raja Ali RA, Mokhtar NM. Irritable bowel syndrome, depression, and neurodegeneration: a bidirectional communication from gut to brain. Nutrients. 2021;13:3061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34578939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JY, Zhu XJ, Peng Y, et al. . Effects of moxibustion on behaviors and tryptophan metabolism-related products in mice with irritable bowel syndrome. J Acupunct Tuina Sci. 2023;21:91&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosi A, Banfi D, Bistoletti M, Giaroni C, Baj A. Tryptophan metabolites along the microbiota-gut-brain axis: an interkingdom communication system influencing the gut in health and disease. Int J Tryptophan Res. 2020;13:1178646920928984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32577079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nee J, Lembo A. Review Article: Current and future treatment approaches for IBS with diarrhoea (IBS-D) and IBS mixed pattern (IBS-M). Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2021;54(Suppl 1):S63&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34927757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE. Review article: an analysis of safety profiles of treatments for diarrhoea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2018;48:817&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30194692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M, Boeckxstaens G. Dietary and pharmacological treatment of abdominal pain in IBS. Gut. 2017;66:966&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28232472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billings W, Mathur K, Craven HJ, Xu H, Shin A. Potential benefit with complementary and alternative medicine in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19:1538&#x2013;53.e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32961342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang Y, Xing JJ, Li J, Zeng BY, Liang FR. History of acupuncture research. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2013;111:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Shi H, Cao S, et al. . Revealing the magic of acupuncture based on biological mechanisms: a literature review. Biosci Trends. 2022;16:73&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35153276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Singh P, Kumar A. Targeted therapy of irritable bowel syndrome with anti-inflammatory cytokines. Clin J Gastroenterol. 2022;15:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8858303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim B, Manheimer E, Lao L, et al. . Acupuncture for treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2006:CD005111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17054239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manheimer E, Wieland LS, Cheng K, et al. . Acupuncture for irritable bowel syndrome: systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2012;107:835&#x2013;47; quiz 848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3671917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22488079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGrath S, Zhao X, Steele R, Thombs BD, Benedetti A; DEPRESsion Screening Data (DEPRESSD) Collaboration. Estimating the sample mean and standard deviation from commonly reported quantiles in meta-analysis. Stat Methods Med Res. 2020;29:2520&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hozo SP, Djulbegovic B, Hozo I. Estimating themean and variance from the median, range, and the size of asample. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2005;5:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1097734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15840177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Zou R, Zhang Y, et al. . Mechanism analysis of acupuncture&#x2019;s effect on mental and psychological influence in patients with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome based on central regulation of the HPA axis. Chongqing Med. 2022;51:2362&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Jin H, Yan X. Clinical study on the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with spleen-tonifying and mind-regulating warm acupuncture. Shaanxi J Tradit Chin Med. 2023;44:245&#x2013;249+254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu L, L&#xfc; D. Effects of tonifying spleen and regulating liver acupuncture on neurotensin, anxiety, and depression in patients with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. J Mod Integr Tradit Chin West Med. 2020;29:1074&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X, Chen W, Zhong Y, et al. . Clinical observation of acupuncture-regulating mind decoction combined with Shenling Baizhu powder in the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with spleen deficiency and damp accumulation. J Guangzhou Univ Chin Med. 2022;39:1573&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y. Clinical Observation of the Therapeutic Effect of Acupuncture Combined with Separating Ginger Moxibustion in Treating Diarrhea-predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome with Liver Depression and Spleen Deficiency. Hubei University of Chinese Medicine; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Wang W, Gao S, et al. . Clinical study on the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with acupuncture combined with Tongxie Xiaoyao formula. Hebei J Tradit Chin Med. 2022;44:754&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Zhou Y, Zhang M, et al. . Clinical observation of the therapeutic effect of acupuncture combined with salt-separating moxibustion in treating diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with spleen deficiency. Shanghai J Acupunct Moxibustion. 2021;40:400&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Zou R, Zhang L, et al. . Clinical study on the influence of acupuncture on the mental and psychological status of patients with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with liver depression and spleen deficiency. Hubei J Tradit Chin Med. 2020;42:51&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G. Clinical observation of acupuncture treatment for diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Shanghai J Acupunct Moxibustion. 2018;37:187&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X, Li X. Clinical observation of the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome with combined acupuncture and herbal medicine. Henan Tradit Chin Med. 2023;43:454&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhao R, Lv S, et al. . Clinical study on the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome (spleen and stomach weakness pattern) with traditional Chinese medicine combined with umbilical moxibustion. Chin J Emerg Med. 2022;31:2107&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Y. Clinical Observation of the Treatment of Diarrhea-predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome with Separating Medicine Cake Moxibustion. Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Zeng Z, Jiang Q, et al. . Clinical study on the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome with modified Xiaoyao powder combined with acupuncture. World Sci Technol Mod Tradit Chin Med. 2014;16:1331&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen X, Yin X, et al. . Comparative study on the efficacy of electroacupuncture combined with probiotics and dailexin in the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Chin J Integr Tradit West Med. 2012;32:594&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22679715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han B, Feng L. Effect of drug acupuncture combination on cytokines in patients with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome and anxiety status. J Ration Drug Clin Pract. 2013;6:121&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng GJ. Acupuncture treatment for depressive symptom in diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized controlled study. J Acupunct Tuina Sci. 2019;17:422&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desiderio S, Vermeiren S, Van Campenhout C, et al. . Prdm12 directs nociceptive sensory neuron development by regulating the expression of the NGF receptor TrkA. Cell Rep. 2019;26:3522&#x2013;36.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30917309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Tian A, Xiang X, et al. . Study on the therapeutic effect and mechanism of electroacupuncture on irritable bowel syndrome and depressive mood in rats. J Clin Acupunct Moxibustion. 2023;39:71&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubbers T, Luyer MD, de Haan JJ, Hadfoune M, Buurman WA, Greve JWM. Lipid-rich enteral nutrition reduces postoperative ileus in rats via activation of cholecystokinin-receptors. Ann Surg. 2009;249:481&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Asadi S, Weng Z, Sismanopoulos N, Theoharides TC. Stimulated human mast cells secrete mitochondrial components that have autocrine and paracrine inflammatory actions. PLoS One. 2012;7:e49767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3524249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23284625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y, Wang K, Jiang H, et al. . Mechanism study of electroacupuncture regulating mast cell activation and restoring intestinal barrier in rats with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Acupunct Res. 2023;48:281&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>