<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40844282</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Colchicine as an Adjunct Therapy Postablation for Atrial Fibrillation: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001029</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Atrial fibrillation (AF) recurrence following catheter ablation remains a significant clinical challenge, often attributed to postprocedural inflammation. Colchicine, an anti-inflammatory agent, has emerged as a potential therapeutic strategy to reduce recurrence. This meta-analysis evaluates the efficacy and safety of colchicine in preventing AF recurrence after ablation. A comprehensive literature search was conducted across PubMed, Embase, Scopus, and Cochrane databases through March 2025. Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and observational studies assessing colchicine versus control in postablation AF patients were included. The primary outcome was AF recurrence; secondary outcomes included pericarditis, hospitalizations, gastrointestinal side effects, and composite clinical events. Data were pooled using a random-effects model, and subgroup and sensitivity analyses were conducted. A total of 8 studies (N = 3784 patients) were included. Colchicine significantly reduced AF recurrence [risk ratio (RR) = 0.75; 95% confidence interval (CI): 0.57-0.98; P = 0.04; I &#xb2; = 55%]. The effect was more pronounced in RCTs (RR = 0.60; 95% CI: 0.45-0.80; P = 0.0004; I &#xb2; = 0%). Colchicine was associated with an increased risk of gastrointestinal side effects (RR = 2.34; 95% CI: 1.21-4.55; P = 0.01; I &#xb2; = 75%) but had no significant effect on pericarditis (RR = 0.62; 95% CI: 0.23-1.70; P = 0.36), hospitalizations, or composite outcomes. Colchicine appears to reduce AF recurrence following catheter ablation, particularly in rigorously conducted RCTs. While gastrointestinal intolerance is a notable concern, colchicine may offer a valuable adjunctive strategy to improve ablation outcomes. Larger, well-powered trials are warranted to confirm these findings and define optimal dosing strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ain</LastName><ForeName>QuraTul</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Cardiology, Shifa College of Medicine, Shifa Tameer e Millat University, Islamabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Irshad</LastName><ForeName>Tahira</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Usman</LastName><ForeName>Mahnoor</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Haris</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Shaikh Zayed Hospital, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Sheraz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naeem</LastName><ForeName>Silla</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sajjad</LastName><ForeName>Laiba</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Dow University of Health Sciences, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Irshad</LastName><ForeName>Aiman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Farooq Hospital, Westwood, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Mushood</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Rawalpindi Medical University, Rawalpindi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Usman</ForeName><Initials>MU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Irshad</LastName><ForeName>Nishat</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Allama Iqbal Medical College, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naveed</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Dow University of Health Sciences, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salim</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Shifa International Hospital, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Faizan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Jersey Shore University Medical Center, Neptune, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chigurupati</LastName><ForeName>Himaja Dutt</ForeName><Initials>HD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, East Carolina University, Greenville, NC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neppala</LastName><ForeName>Sivaram</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, UT Health Science Center, San Antonio, TX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-inflammatory therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac electrophysiology and arrhythmias</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catheter ablation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colchicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40844282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Zhang N, Korantzopoulos P, et al. Efficacy and safety of colchicine for atrial fibrillation prevention: an updated meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Cardiol. 2024;406:132068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joglar JA, Chung MK, Armbruster AL, et al.; Peer Review Committee Members. 2023 ACC/AHA/ACCP/HRS guideline for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2024;149:e1&#x2013;e156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer DL, Mark DB, Robb RA, et al.; CABANA Investigators. Effect of catheter ablation vs antiarrhythmic drug therapy on mortality, stroke, bleeding, and cardiac arrest among patients with atrial fibrillation: the CABANA randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2019;321:1261&#x2013;1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deftereos SG, Vrachatis DA, Angelidis C, et al. The role of colchicine in treating postoperative and post-catheter ablation atrial fibrillation. Clin Ther. 2019;41:21&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter B, Gwechenberger M, Socas A, et al. Markers of oxidative stress after ablation of atrial fibrillation are associated with inflammation, delivered radiofrequency energy and early recurrence of atrial fibrillation. Clin Res Cardiol. 2012;101:217&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim HS, Schultz C, Dang J, et al. Time course of inflammation, myocardial injury, and prothrombotic response after radiofrequency catheter ablation for atrial fibrillation. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2014;7:83&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slobodnick A, Shah B, Krasnokutsky S, et al. Update on colchicine, 2017. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2018;57(suppl_1):i4&#x2013;i11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imazio M, Brucato A, Trinchero R, et al. Colchicine for pericarditis: hype or hope? Eur Heart J. 2009;30:532&#x2013;539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Chen Y, Mao M, et al. A meta-analysis of colchicine in prevention of atrial fibrillation following cardiothoracic surgery or cardiac intervention. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2022;17:224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Beard CW, Khosla J, et al. Safety and efficacy of colchicine for the prevention of post-operative atrial fibrillation in patients undergoing cardiac surgery: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Europace. 2023;25:euad169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sadawi M, Aslam F, Henriques MD, et al. Effect of low dose colchicine on long term recurrence after atrial fibrillation ablation. Int J Cardiol. 2025;423:132972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiswal V, Deb N, Hanif M, et al. Efficacy of colchicine for prevention of stroke and adverse cardiovascular events: A Meta-analysis of 16 randomized controlled trials. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2025;25:83&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain H, Odat RM, Dey D, et al. Colchicine prevents post-ablation atrial fibrillation recurrence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cardiol Rev. 2024. doi:10.1097/CRD.0000000000000769</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashmi TM, Ahmed M, Haider A, et al. Once-weekly semaglutide versus once-daily liraglutide for weight loss in adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Transl Sci. 2025;18:e70127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheraz M, Asif N, Khan A, et al. Tenecteplase versus alteplase in patients with acute ischemic stroke: an updated meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2025;34:108300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ifzaal M, Bughio SA, Rizvi SAFA, et al. Efficacy and safety of tenecteplase administration in extended time window for acute ischemic stroke: an updated meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2025;34:108338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burhan M, Noor S, Ahmed M, et al. Role of renin-angiotensin system inhibitors after transcatheter aortic valve replacement: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Ther. 2025;32:e382&#x2013;e385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed H, Fahad M, Sharif S, et al. Intravenous versus intraosseous vascular access in out-of-hospital cardiac arrest: a meta-analysis. Cardiol Rev. 2025. doi: 10.1097/CRD.0000000000000966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali MA, Ali MF, Sabir A, et al. Percutaneous mitral valve repair versus surgery in patients with mitral regurgitation: a meta-analysis. Cardiol Rev. 2025. doi: 10.1097/CRD.0000000000000965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed AS, Miller J, Foreman J, et al. Prophylactic colchicine after radiofrequency ablation of atrial fibrillation: the PAPERS study. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2023;9(7 Pt 2):1060&#x2013;1066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benz AP, Amit G, Connolly SJ, et al.; IMPROVE-PVI Investigators. Colchicine to prevent atrial fibrillation recurrence after catheter ablation: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2024;17:e01238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deftereos S, Giannopoulos G, Efremidis M, et al. Colchicine for prevention of atrial fibrillation recurrence after pulmonary vein isolation: mid-term efficacy and effect on quality of life. Heart Rhythm. 2014;11:620&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanty S, Mohanty P, Kessler D, . Impact of colchicine monotherapy on the risk of acute pericarditis following atrial fibrillation ablation. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2023;9:1051&#x2013;1059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deftereos S, Giannopoulos G, Kossyvakis C, et al. Colchicine for prevention of early atrial fibrillation recurrence after pulmonary vein isolation: a randomized controlled study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2012;60:1790&#x2013;1796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal AM, Li KY, Gautam S. Colchicine usage for prevention of post atrial fibrillation ablation pericarditis in patients undergoing high-power short-duration ablation. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2023;34:1370&#x2013;1376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KB, Eickman SD, Truong T, . Colchicine for the prevention of recurrent arrhythmia after catheter ablation of atrial fibrillation: results of a single-center, retrospective study. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2023;23:709&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo LW, Chen SA. Cardiac remodeling after atrial fibrillation ablation. J Atr Fibrillation. 2013;6:877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshpande S, Sawatari H, Rangan K, et al. Pericardial tamponade in coronary interventions: morbidity and mortality. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2024;104:707&#x2013;713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issac TT, Dokainish H, Lakkis NM. Role of inflammation in initiation and perpetuation of atrial fibrillation: a systematic review of the published data. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;50:2021&#x2013;2028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porc&#xf9; E. Microtubule depolymerizing compounds as novel potential antivascular agents in cancer therapy. 2014. Available from: https://www.research.unipd.it/handle/11577/3423703 . Accessed July 2, 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imazio M, Brucato A, Cemin R, et al.; ICAP Investigators. A randomized trial of colchicine for acute pericarditis. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:1522&#x2013;1528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman SL. From randomized controlled trials to observational studies. Am J Med. 2009;122:114&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed M, Nadeem ZA, Ahsan A, et al. Intravascular ultrasound-guided versus angiography-guided percutaneous coronary intervention: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression of randomized control trials. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2025;105:68&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed M, Hashmi TM, Shafiq A, et al. Early intervention versus conservative management for asymptomatic severe aortic stenosis: an updated meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cardiol Rev. 2025. doi:10.1097/CRD.0000000000000910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imazio M, Brucato A, Belli R, et al. Colchicine for the prevention of pericarditis: what we know and what we do not know in 2014 - systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cardiovasc Med (Hagerstown). 2014;15:840&#x2013;846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deftereos SG, Giannopoulos G, Vrachatis DA, et al.; GRECCO-19 investigators. Effect of colchicine vs standard care on cardiac and inflammatory biomarkers and clinical outcomes in patients hospitalized with coronavirus disease 2019: the GRECCO-19 randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2013136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kommu S, Arepally S. The effect of colchicine on atrial fibrillation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2023;15:e35120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roddy E, Clarkson K, Blagojevic-Bucknall M, et al. Open-label randomised pragmatic trial (CONTACT) comparing naproxen and low-dose colchicine for the treatment of gout flares in primary care. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79:276&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed M, Fatima E, Shafiq A, et al. Continuation versus discontinuation of renin-angiotensin aldosterone system inhibitors before non-cardiac surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Anesth. 2024;99:111679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basit J, Ahmed M, Burhan M, et al. Meta-analysis on comparison of fasting versus no fasting before cardiac catheterization. Cardiol Rev. 2025. doi: 10.1097/CRD.0000000000000930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider MP, Hua TA, B&#xf6;hm M, et al. Prevention of atrial fibrillation by renin-angiotensin system inhibition a meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;55:2299&#x2013;2307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashmi TM, Ashraf H, Burhan M, et al. Effects of dexmedetomidine on acute kidney injury and perioperative outcomes in aortic vascular surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Semin Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2025. doi:10.1177/10892532251346645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10892532251346645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>