<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41005596</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-1913</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Amiodarone after Catheter Ablation According to Left Atrial Structure and Function: The AMIO-CAT Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-9149(25)00570-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.amjcard.2025.09.017</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Catheter ablation (CA) is commonly used to obtain rhythm control in patients with atrial fibrillation (AF), yet AF recurrence is frequent. In this study, we hypothesized that measures of left atrial (LA) structure and function modified the treatment effect of amiodarone to prevent AF recurrence, which has otherwise not proven beneficial. This was a post-hoc analysis of the double-blinded AMIO-CAT trial. Patients undergoing CA were randomized to short-term amiodarone treatment or placebo. All patients underwent echocardiography to assess LA volumes and strain. The primary endpoint was AF recurrence at 6-months. Secondary endpoints were cardioversion and AF-related hospitalization during follow-up. Of 212 patients, 108 were randomized to amiodarone and 104 to placebo. 206 patients were eligible for analyses of the primary endpoint, of whom 90 (44%) developed AF recurrence. No measure of LA size or function significantly modified the effect of amiodarone for preventing AF recurrence (p for interaction&gt;0.05 for all measures). However, abnormal LA strain (&lt;22.7%) significantly modified the treatment effect for the secondary outcomes of cardioversions (p for interaction=0.013) and AF-related hospitalization (p for interaction=0.014). In patients with abnormal LA strain, amiodarone significantly reduced the risk of cardioversions (OR 0.35 (0.15-0.80), p=0.013) and AF-related hospitalization (OR 0.31 (0.14-0.73), p=0.007) compared to placebo. In conclusion, LA measures did not modify the treatment effect of amiodarone vs. placebo for preventing AF recurrence at 6 months in patients undergoing CA. However, in patients with abnormal LA strain, amiodarone may reduce cardioversions and AF-related hospitalizations as compared to placebo. Clinical trial registration: Clinicaltrials.gov unique identifier: NCT00826826.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olsen</LastName><ForeName>Flemming Javier</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Herlev and Gentofte, Hellerup, Denmark; Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark. Electronic address: flemming.j.olsen@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darkner</LastName><ForeName>Stine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Zealand University Hospital, Roskilde, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pehrson</LastName><ForeName>Steen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johannessen</LastName><ForeName>Arne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Herlev and Gentofte, Hellerup, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hansen</LastName><ForeName>Jim</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Herlev and Gentofte, Hellerup, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svendsen</LastName><ForeName>Jesper Hastrup</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark; Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biering-S&#xf8;rensen</LastName><ForeName>Tor</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Herlev and Gentofte, Hellerup, Denmark; Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark; Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark; Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark; Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT00826826</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0207277</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9149</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amiodarone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">left atrium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trial</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: JHS: reports to be a member of Vital Beats and Medtronic advisory boards and to have received speaker honoraria and research grants from Medtronic outside this work. TBS: has received research grants from Pfizer, Sanofi Pasteur, GSK, Novo Nordisk, AstraZeneca, Boston Scientific and GE Healthcare, consulting fees from Novo Nordisk, IQVIA, Parexel, Amgen, CSL Seqirus, GSK and Sanofi Pasteur, and lecture fees from Bayer, Novartis, Sanofi Pasteur, GE healthcare and GSK. The remaining authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41005596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2025.09.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9149(25)00570-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>