<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40884738</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8237</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation on the Symptoms and Brain Imaging in Patients with Fibromyalgia Syndrome: A Randomized Controlled Pilot Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40122-025-00770-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) of the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC) has been shown to reduce the symptoms of patients with fibromyalgia syndrome (FMS). We tested whether rTMS of the left DLPFC can reduce the main symptoms in FMS and whether TMS induces changes in brain functional and structural connectivity, cortical gray matter volume, and the metabolites/neurotransmitters GABA and combined glutamate/glutamine (Glx).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-seven women diagnosed with FMS according to the 2010 ACR criteria were included in a randomized controlled trial. They received either ten sessions of active or sham 10-Hz stimulation over 2&#xa0;weeks embedded in a longitudinal neuroimaging setup, including one pre-treatment (T1), one post-treatment (T2), and one follow-up (T3) 3&#xa0;T MRI scan. Pain and pain catastrophizing, depression, daily life/quality of life, and anxiety were assessed using standard questionnaires.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Linear mixed-model analysis of clinical data showed a significant main effect of the main factor time but did not reveal group differences or group-time interactions, indicating a large placebo effect with symptom reduction in both groups. Fractional anisotropy (FA) values of the pontine crossing tract, the sagittal stratum, and the right cingulum in the active rTMS group increased between pre-TMS and the follow-up time points. Subgroup analysis of responders of the treatment group revealed higher functional connectivity between the left DLPFC and the right cerebellum. We did not find evidence for changes in the treatment group in the gray matter of the left DLPFC and for the concentrations of GABA and Glx, but a trend towards decreasing Glx levels for the factor time in all patients could be detected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">While these results may be due to small sample size and short treatment duration, the findings of increased FA after active rTMS and higher functional connectivity between DLPFC and cerebellum in responders should be further explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Auswirkungen der nicht-invasiven Neuromodulation auf das Gehirn bei Fibromyalgiepatienten.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DRKS-ID" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">DRKS00019051.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ackermann</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany. ackermann_l@ukw.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroradiology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany. ackermann_l@ukw.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oto-Rhino-Laryngology, Head and Neck Surgery, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, W&#xfc;rzburg, Haus B2, Germany. ackermann_l@ukw.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeller</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Odorfer</LastName><ForeName>Thorsten</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Homola</LastName><ForeName>Gy&#xf6;rgy A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroradiology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kampf</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroradiology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Mirko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroradiology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Aster</LastName><ForeName>Hans-Christoph</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Psychotherapy and Psychosomatics, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Margarete-H&#xf6;ppel-Platz 1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sommer</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg, Josef-Schneider-Stra&#xdf;e 11, Haus B1, 97080, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101634491</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion tensor imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dorsolateral prefrontal cortex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gray matter volume</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HF-rTMS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromodulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proton MR spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting-state functional MRI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Laura Ackermann, Daniel Zeller, Thorsten Odorfer, Gy&#xf6;rgy A. Homola, Thomas Kampf, Mirko Pham, Hans-Christoph Aster and Claudia Sommer have no conflict of interest to declare. Thorsten Odorfer has consulted for TEVA. Daniel Zeller has consulted for Novartis and has been on the Advisory board of Biogen. He has given a talk for Angelini Pharma and received travel compensation. Claudia Sommer has given educational talks for Alnylam, argenx, CSL Behring, Grifols, GSK, Kedrion, Novartis, Pfizer, Takeda, TEVA. She has consulted for Akigai, Algiax, Annexon, argenx, Bayer, CSL-Behring, Grifols, Kedrion, Nevro, Sanofi, Takeda, TEVA. Claudia Sommer is an Editorial Board member of Pain and Therapy and deputy editor of the European Journal of Neurology. She was not involved in the selection of peer reviewers for the manuscript nor any of the subsequent editorial decisions. Laura Ackermann, Gy&#xf6;rgy A. Homola, Thomas Kampf, Mirko Pham and Hans-Christoph Aster have nothing to disclose. Laura Ackermann changed her affiliation during the completion of the manuscript to the Department of Oto-Rhino-Laryngology, Head and Neck Surgery of the University Hospital W&#xfc;rzburg. Ethical Approval: All patients gave written informed consent to the study according to the Declaration of Helsinki. The Ethics Committee of the University of W&#xfc;rzburg Medical Faculty approved the study (140/19).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40884738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40122-025-00770-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40122-025-00770-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Eich W, B&#xe4;r KJ, Bernateck M, et al. Definition, classification, clinical diagnosis and prognosis of fibromyalgia syndrome: Updated guidelines 2017 and overview of systematic review articles. Schmerz. 2017;31(3):231&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28421273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ. Fibromyalgia: a clinical review. J Am Med Assoc. 2014;311(15):1547&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;user W, Ablin J, Fitzcharles MA, et al. Fibromyalgia. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2015;1: 15022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Burgmer M, Friedel E, et al. Etiology and pathophysiology of fibromyalgia syndrome: Updated guidelines 2017, overview of systematic review articles and overview of studies on small fiber neuropathy in FMS subgroups. Schmerz. 2017;31(3):239&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28493226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer C, H&#xe4;user W, Alten R, et al. Drug therapy of fibromyalgia syndrome. Systematic review, meta-analysis and guideline. Schmerz. 2012;26(3):297&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22760463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aster HC, Evdokimov D, Braun A, &#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Sommer C. Analgesic medication in fibromyalgia patients: a cross-sectional study. Pain Res Manag. 2022;2022:1217717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9553668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;user W, Jung E, Erbsl&#xf6;h-M&#xf6;ller B, et al. The German fibromyalgia consumer reports: a cross-sectional survey. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2012;13:74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22607517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3444387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macfarlane GJ, Kronisch C, Dean LE, et al. EULAR revised recommendations for the management of fibromyalgia. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76(2):318&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini PM, Burke D, Chen R, et al. Non-invasive electrical and magnetic stimulation of the brain, spinal cord, roots and peripheral nerves: basic principles and procedures for routine clinical and research application. An updated report from an I.F.C.N. committee. Clin Neurophysiol. 2015;126(6):1071&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25797650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6350257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefaucheur JP, Antal A, Ahdab R, et al. The use of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) and transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) to relieve pain. Brain Stimul. 2008;1(4):337&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr EM, Kotb H, Kamel NF, Ahmed MA, Sadek R, Rothwell JC. Long-lasting antalgic effects of daily sessions of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in central and peripheral neuropathic pain. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2005;76(6):833&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15897507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1739662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefaucheur J-P, Drouot X, Keravel Y, Nguyen J-P. Pain relief induced by repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of precentral cortex. NeuroReport. 2001;12(13):2963&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11588611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attal N, Poindessous-Jazat F, De Chauvigny E, et al. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for neuropathic pain: a randomized multicentre sham-controlled trial. Brain. 2021;144(11):3328&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borckardt JJ, Reeves ST, Weinstein M, et al. Significant analgesic effects of one session of postoperative left prefrontal cortex repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation: a replication study. Brain Stimul. 2008;1(2):122&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19759838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2744083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brighina F, Curatolo M, Cosentino G, et al. Brain modulation by electric currents in Fibromyalgia: a structured review on non-invasive approach with transcranial electrical stimulation. Front Hum Neurosci. 2019;13:40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30804771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6378756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passard A, Attal N, Benadhira R, et al. Effects of unilateral repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the motor cortex on chronic widespread pain in fibromyalgia. Brain. 2007;130(Pt 10):2661&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C-M, Wang S-J, Su T-P, et al. Analgesic effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on modified 2010 criteria-diagnosed fibromyalgia: pilot study. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2019;73(4):187&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar S, Mattoo B, Kumar U, Bhatia R. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the prefrontal cortex for fibromyalgia syndrome: a randomised controlled trial with 6-month follow-up. Adv Rheumatol. 2020;60(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari VK, Kumar A, Nanda S, et al. Effect of neuronavigated repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on pain, cognition and cortical excitability in fibromyalgia syndrome. Neurol Sci. 2024;45(7):3421&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38270728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery DH, Holtzheimer PE 3rd, Fawaz W, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation reduces pain in patients with major depression: a sham-controlled study. J Nerv Ment Dis. 2007;195(5):378&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17502802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgibbon BM, Hoy KE, Knox LA, et al. Evidence for the improvement of fatigue in fibromyalgia: a 4-week left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation randomized-controlled trial. Eur J Pain. 2018;22(7):1255&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29542208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altas EU, Askin A, Be&#x15f;iro&#x11f;lu L, Tosun A. Is high-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the left primary motor cortex superior to the stimulation of the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in fibromyalgia syndrome? Somatosens Mot Res. 2019;36(1):56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mhalla A, Baudic S, de Andrade DC, et al. Long-term maintenance of the analgesic effects of transcranial magnetic stimulation in fibromyalgia. Pain. 2011;152(7):1478&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21397400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guinot M, Maindet C, Hodaj H, et al. Effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation and multicomponent therapy in patients with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2021;73(3):449&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31785190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Alventosa R, Ingl&#xe9;s M, Cort&#xe9;s-Amador S, Gimeno-Mallench L, Sempere-Rubio N, Serra-A&#xf1;&#xf3; P. Effectiveness of high-frequency transcranial magnetic stimulation and physical exercise in women with fibromyalgia: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/pzab159 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyer L, Dousset A, Roussel P, et al. rTMS in fibromyalgia: a randomized trial evaluating QoL and its brain metabolic substrate. Neurology. 2014;82(14):1231&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekin A, &#xd6;zdil E, G&#xfc;leken MD, et al. Efficacy of high frequency [10 Hz] repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the primary motor cortex in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome: a randomized, double blind, sham-controlled trial. J Musculoskelet Pain. 2014;22(1):20&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou W-H, Wang T-Y, Kang J-H. The effects of add-on non-invasive brain stimulation in fibromyalgia: a meta-analysis and meta-regression of randomized controlled trials. Rheumatology. 2016;55(8):1507&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27150193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Chang MC. Effect of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on pain management: a systematic narrative review. Front Neurol. 2020;11:114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7040236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su YC, Guo YH, Hsieh PC, Lin YC. Efficacy of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in fibromyalgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Clin Med. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10204669 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35011903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8745589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefaucheur JP, Aleman A, Baeken C, et al. Evidence-based guidelines on the therapeutic use of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS): an update (2014&#x2013;2018). Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131(2):474&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aster HC, Evdokimov D, Braun A, et al. CNS imaging characteristics in fibromyalgia patients with and without peripheral nerve involvement. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):6707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35469050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9038916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seminowicz DA, Moayedi M. The dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in acute and chronic pain. J Pain. 2017;18(9):1027&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5581265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassermann EM. Risk and safety of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation: report and suggested guidelines from the International Workshop on the Safety of Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation, June 5&#x2013;7, 1996. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1998;108(1):1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9474057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Sollmann N, Castrill&#xf3;n G, et al. Intranetwork and internetwork effects of navigated transcranial magnetic stimulation using low- and high-frequency pulse application to the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex: a combined rTMS-fMRI approach. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;37(2):131&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30335664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumford JA, Nichols TE. Power calculation for group fMRI studies accounting for arbitrary design and temporal autocorrelation. Neuroimage. 2008;39(1):261&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17919925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumford JA. A power calculation guide for fMRI studies. Soc Cogn Affect Neurosci. 2012;7(6):738&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22641837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3427872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajula J, Tohka J. How many is enough? Effect of sample size in inter-subject correlation analysis of fMRI. Comput Intell Neurosci. 2016;2016:2094601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26884746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4738700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evdokimov D, Frank J, Klitsch A, et al. Reduction of skin innervation is associated with a severe fibromyalgia phenotype. Ann Neurol. 2019;86(4):504&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31376174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F, Clauw DJ, Fitzcharles MA, et al. The American College of Rheumatology preliminary diagnostic criteria for fibromyalgia and measurement of symptom severity. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2010;62(5):600&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20461783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi S, Antal A, Bestmann S, et al. Safety and recommendations for TMS use in healthy subjects and patient populations, with updates on training, ethical and regulatory issues: expert guidelines. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132(1):269&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power JD, Cohen AL, Nelson SM, et al. Functional network organization of the human brain. Neuron. 2011;72(4):665&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22099467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3222858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odorfer TM, Homola GA, Reich MM, Volkmann J, Zeller D. Increased finger-tapping related cerebellar activation in cervical dystonia, enhanced by transcranial stimulation: an indicator of compensation? Front Neurol. 2019;10:231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6428698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MP, Turner JA, Romano JM, Fisher LD. Comparative reliability and validity of chronic pain intensity measures. Pain. 1999;83(2):157&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10534586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer C, Richter H, Rogausch JP, Frettl&#xf6;h J, Lungenhausen M, Maier C. A modified score to identify and discriminate neuropathic pain: a study on the German version of the Neuropathic Pain Symptom Inventory (NPSI). BMC Neurol. 2011;11:104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3180265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouhassira D, Attal N, Fermanian J, et al. Development and validation of the neuropathic pain symptom inventory. Pain. 2004;108(3):248&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15030944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer K, Sprott H, Mannion AF. Cross-cultural adaptation, reliability, and validity of the German version of the pain catastrophizing scale. J Psychosom Res. 2008;64(5):469&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18440399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radloff LS. The CES-D scale: a self-report depression scale for research in the general population. Appl Psychol Meas. 1977;1(3):385&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Offenbaecher M, Waltz M, Schoeps P. Validation of a German version of the Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire (FIQ-G). J Rheumatol. 2000;27(8):1984&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10955342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielberger CD, Gorsuch RL, Lushene RE. Manual for the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory. Palo Alto: Consulting Psychologists Press; 1970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aster H-C, Hahn V, Schmalzing M, et al. Comparison of gamma-aminobutyric acid, glutamate, and N-acetylaspartate concentrations in the insular cortex between patients with fibromyalgia, rheumatoid arthritis, and healthy controls: a magnetic resonance spectroscopy study. medRxiv. 2022:2022.09.15.22279963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale AM, Fischl B, Sereno MI. Cortical surface-based analysis I Segmentation and surface reconstruction. Neuroimage. 1999;9(2):179&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9931268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl B, Dale AM. Measuring the thickness of the human cerebral cortex from magnetic resonance images. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97(20):11050&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10984517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">27146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desikan RS, S&#xe9;gonne F, Fischl B, et al. An automated labeling system for subdividing the human cerebral cortex on MRI scans into gyral-based regions of interest. Neuroimage. 2006;31(3):968&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16530430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M, Schmansky NJ, Rosas HD, Fischl B. Within-subject template estimation for unbiased longitudinal image analysis. Neuroimage. 2012;61(4):1402&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22430496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M, Fischl B. Avoiding asymmetry-induced bias in longitudinal image processing. Neuroimage. 2011;57(1):19&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21376812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter M, Rosas HD, Fischl B. Highly accurate inverse consistent registration: a robust approach. Neuroimage. 2010;53(4):1181&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20637289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SM, Jenkinson M, Woolrich MW, et al. Advances in functional and structural MR image analysis and implementation as FSL. Neuroimage. 2004;23(Suppl 1):S208&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15501092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitfield-Gabrieli S, Nieto-Castanon A. Conn: a functional connectivity toolbox for correlated and anticorrelated brain networks. Brain Connect. 2012;2(3):125&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22642651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson M, Reynolds G, Kauppinen RA, Arvanitis TN, Peet AC. A constrained least-squares approach to the automated quantitation of in vivo <sup>1</sup>H magnetic resonance spectroscopy data. Magn Reson Med. 2011;65(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20878762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds G, Wilson M, Peet A, Arvanitis TN. An algorithm for the automated quantitation of metabolites in in vitro NMR signals. Magn Reson Med. 2006;56(6):1211&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17029227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullins PG, McGonigle DJ, O&#x2019;Gorman RL, et al. Current practice in the use of MEGA-PRESS spectroscopy for the detection of GABA. Neuroimage. 2014;86:43&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23246994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen JF, Backes WH, Nicolay K, Kooi ME. 1H MR spectroscopy of the brain: absolute quantification of metabolites. Radiology. 2006;240(2):318&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16864664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilir I, Askin A, Sengul I, Tosun A. Effects of high-frequency neuronavigated repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in fibromyalgia syndrome: a double-blinded, randomized controlled study. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100(2):138&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery DH, Zarkowski P, Krashin D, et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in the treatment of chronic widespread pain: a randomized controlled study. J ECT. 2015;31(1):57&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24755729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4205210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short BE, Borckardt JJ, Anderson BS, et al. Ten sessions of adjunctive left prefrontal rTMS significantly reduces fibromyalgia pain: a randomized, controlled pilot study. Pain. 2011;152(11):2477&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3199360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun P, Fang L, Zhang J, Liu Y, Wang G, Qi R. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for patients with fibromyalgia: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Pain Med. 2022;23(3):499&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34542624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toh EYJ, Ng JSP, McIntyre RS, et al. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for fibromyalgia: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychosom Med. 2022;84(4):400&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35100184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C-T, Wang S-J, Hirvonen J, et al. Antidepressant mechanism of add-on repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in medication-resistant depression using cerebral glucose metabolism. J Affect Disord. 2010;127(1):219&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20598753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borckardt JJ, Smith AR, Reeves ST, et al. A pilot study investigating the effects of fast left prefrontal rTMS on chronic neuropathic pain. Pain Med. 2009;10(5):840&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19594842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu PA, Xie JY, Liu H, Wen Y, Shao YJ, Bao X. Efficacy of high-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation at 10 Hz in fibromyalgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;104(1):151&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wathra RA, Mulsant BH, Reynolds CF, et al. Differential placebo responses for pharmacotherapy and neurostimulation in late-life depression. Neuromodulation Technol Neural Interface. 2023;26(8):1585&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernando-Garijo I, Jim&#xe9;nez-Del-Barrio S, Mingo-G&#xf3;mez T, Medrano-de-la-Fuente R, Ceballos-Laita L. Effectiveness of non-pharmacological conservative therapies in adults with fibromyalgia: a systematic review of high-quality clinical trials. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2022;35(1):3&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardy K, F&#xfc;ber N, K&#xf6;llner V, H&#xe4;user W. Efficacy of cognitive-behavioral therapies in fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and metaanalysis of randomized controlled trials. J Rheumatol. 2010;37(10):1991&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenberg DL, Burckhardt C, Crofford L. Management of fibromyalgia syndrome. J Am Med Assoc. 2004;292(19):2388&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg JT, Martinussen M, Flaten MA. The placebo analgesic effect in healthy individuals and patients: a meta-analysis. Psychosom Med. 2017;79(4):388&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27922566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colloca L, Benedetti F. How prior experience shapes placebo analgesia. Pain. 2006;124(1&#x2013;2):126&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16701952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinger R, Colloca L, Bingel U, Flor H. Placebo analgesia: clinical applications. Pain. 2014;155(6):1055&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24333780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razza LB, Moffa AH, Moreno ML, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis on placebo response to repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for depression trials. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2018;81:105&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29111404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke MJ, Romanella SM, Mencarelli L, et al. Placebo effects and neuromodulation for depression: a meta-analysis and evaluation of shared mechanisms. Mol Psychiatry. 2022;27(3):1658&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34903861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wager TD, Rilling JK, Smith EE, et al. Placebo-induced changes in fMRI in the anticipation and experience of pain. Science. 2004;303(5661):1162&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14976306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huneke NTM, Aslan IH, Fagan H, et al. Functional neuroimaging correlates of placebo response in patients with depressive or anxiety disorders: a systematic review. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol. 2022;25(6):433&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9211006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frangos E, &#x10c;eko M, Wang B, et al. Neural effects of placebo analgesia in fibromyalgia patients and healthy individuals. Pain. 2021;162(2):641&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozel FA, Johnson KA, Nahas Z, et al. Fractional anisotropy changes after several weeks of daily left high-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the prefrontal cortex to treat major depression. J ECT. 2011;27(1):5&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20559144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2975808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tateishi H, Nishihara M, Kawaguchi A, et al. Improvement of frontal lobe dysfunction and white matter integrity by rTMS in treatment-resistant depression. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2019;15:3079&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31806977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6842748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H, Zheng H, Li L, et al. High-frequency rTMS treatment increases white matter FA in the left middle frontal gyrus in young patients with treatment-resistant depression. J Affect Disord. 2012;136(3):249&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22217432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argaman Y, Granovsky Y, Sprecher E, Sinai A, Yarnitsky D, Weissman-Fogel I. Clinical effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation of the motor cortex are associated with changes in resting-state functional connectivity in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. J Pain. 2022;23(4):595&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, Borckardt JJ, Reeves ST, et al. A pilot functional MRI study of the effects of prefrontal rTMS on pain perception. Pain Med. 2013;14(7):999&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23647651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JJ, Borckardt JJ, Canterberry M, et al. Naloxone-reversible modulation of pain circuitry by left prefrontal rTMS. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2013;38(7):1189&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23314221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3656361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reithler J, Peters JC, Sack AT. Multimodal transcranial magnetic stimulation: using concurrent neuroimaging to reveal the neural network dynamics of noninvasive brain stimulation. Prog Neurobiol. 2011;94(2):149&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Niehaus JK, Dinc F, et al. Neural circuit basis of placebo pain relief. Nature. 2024;632(8027):1092&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39048016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11358037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krienen FM, Buckner RL. Segregated fronto-cerebellar circuits revealed by intrinsic functional connectivity. Cereb Cortex. 2009;19(10):2485&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19592571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2742600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napadow V, LaCount L, Park K, As-Sanie S, Clauw DJ, Harris RE. Intrinsic brain connectivity in fibromyalgia is associated with chronic pain intensity. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62(8):2545&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20506181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2921024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen KB, Kosek E, Wicksell R, et al. Cognitive behavioral therapy increases pain-evoked activation of the prefrontal cortex in patients with fibromyalgia. Pain. 2012;153(7):1495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22617632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullins PG, Rowland LM, Jung RE, Sibbitt WL. A novel technique to study the brain&#x2019;s response to pain: proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Neuroimage. 2005;26(2):642&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15907322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RE, Sundgren PC, Pang Y, et al. Dynamic levels of glutamate within the insula are associated with improvements in multiple pain domains in fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58(3):903&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18311814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RE, Sundgren PC, Craig AD, et al. Elevated insular glutamate in fibromyalgia is associated with experimental pain. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;60(10):3146&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19790053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2827610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayed N, Andres E, Rojas G, et al. Brain dysfunction in fibromyalgia and somatization disorder using proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy: a controlled study. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2012;126(2):115&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22211322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayed N, Olivan-Bl&#xe1;zquez B, Herrera-Mercadal P, et al. Changes in metabolites after treatment with memantine in fibromyalgia. A double-blind randomized controlled trial with magnetic resonance spectroscopy with a 6-month follow-up. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2014;20(11):999&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25230216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6493189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayed N, Andr&#xe9;s E, Viguera L, Modrego PJ, Garcia-Campayo J. Higher glutamate+glutamine and reduction of N-acetylaspartate in posterior cingulate according to age range in patients with cognitive impairment and/or pain. Acad Radiol. 2014;21(9):1211&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24981958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayed N, Garcia-Campayo J, Magall&#xf3;n R, et al. Localized 1H-NMR spectroscopy in patients with fibromyalgia: a controlled study of changes in cerebral glutamate/glutamine, inositol, choline, and N-acetylaspartate. Arthritis Res Ther. 2010;12(4):R134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20609227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2945024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feraco P, Bacci A, Pedrabissi F, et al. Metabolic abnormalities in pain-processing regions of patients with fibromyalgia: a 3T MR spectroscopy study. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2011;32(9):1585&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7965402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald&#xe9;s M, Collado A, Bargall&#xf3; N, et al. Increased glutamate/glutamine compounds in the brains of patients with fibromyalgia: a magnetic resonance spectroscopy study. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62(6):1829&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyke TL, Osmotherly PG, Baines S. Measuring glutamate levels in the brains of fibromyalgia patients and a potential role for glutamate in the pathophysiology of fibromyalgia symptoms: a systematic review. Clin J Pain. 2017;33(10):944&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28033157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YH, Kim H, Lee D, et al. Abnormal neurometabolites in fibromyalgia patients: magnetic resonance spectroscopy study. Mol Pain. 2021;17:1744806921990946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7887674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zunhammer M, Schweizer LM, Witte V, Harris RE, Bingel U, Schmidt-Wilcke T. Combined glutamate and glutamine levels in pain-processing brain regions are associated with individual pain sensitivity. Pain. 2016;157(10):2248&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27649042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baeken C, Lefaucheur JP, Van Schuerbeek P. The impact of accelerated high frequency rTMS on brain neurochemicals in treatment-resistant depression: insights from (1)H MR spectroscopy. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(9):1664&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan MJ, Chhetry BT, Liston C, Mann JJ, Dubin M. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex induces brain morphological changes in regions associated with a treatment-resistant major depressive episode: an exploratory analysis. Brain Stimul. 2016;9(4):577&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27017072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5554068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalhuisen I, Ackermans E, Martens L, et al. Longitudinal effects of rTMS on neuroplasticity in chronic treatment-resistant depression. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2021;271(1):39&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32385741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boes AD, Uitermarkt BD, Albazron FM, et al. Rostral anterior cingulate cortex is a structural correlate of repetitive TMS treatment response in depression. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(3):575&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29454551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6136654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald PB, Benitez J, de Castella A, Daskalakis ZJ, Brown TL, Kulkarni J. A randomized, controlled trial of sequential bilateral repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for treatment-resistant depression. Am J Psychiatry. 2006;163(1):88&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16390894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fregni F, Pascual-Leone A. Technology insight: noninvasive brain stimulation in neurology&#x2014;perspectives on the therapeutic potential of rTMS and tDCS. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2007;3(7):383&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17611487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connell NE, Marston L, Spencer S, DeSouza LH, Wand BM. Non-invasive brain stimulation techniques for chronic pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018;4(4): Cd008208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29652088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>