<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40599614</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2049-9442</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomedical reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiac function and mortality of stem cell therapy in patients with coronary artery disease who underwent coronary artery bypass graft without heart failure: A meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>147</StartPage><MedlinePgn>147</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">147</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3892/br.2025.2025</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coronary artery disease (CAD) is a common disease and can be treated with coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) in specific cases. Stem cell therapy has been shown to be effective in patients with CAD who underwent CABG in several settings but limited to those without heart failure. The aim of the present study was to evaluate whether stem cell therapy is effective in patients with CAD who underwent CABG and had no heart failure. The present systematic review investigated wether there was any improvement in cardiac function or reduction of mortality in patients with CAD who received CABG and did not have heart failure. The types of studies included in this systematic review were randomized controlled trials. In total, four databases were used for a systematic search: PubMed, CENTRAL database, Scopus, and CINAHL Plus. The results were reported as the mean difference of left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) and risk ratio of mortality rate between stem cell therapy vs. controls. There were 125 studies retrieved from a search in the four aforementioned databases; of those, seven studies met the study criteria. Regarding the outcome of cardiac function, the standardized mean difference of LVEF between the experimental and the control groups was 0.17 (95% CI: -0.09, 0.44). The risk ratio of mortality was also not statistically significant (1.59; 95% CI: 0.68, 3.73). Stem cell therapy did not exert significant improvement of the LVEF or the mortality rate compared with controls, in patients with CAD who underwent CABG and had no heart failure. Further studies are required to confirm the results of the present study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Jansirirat et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jansirirat</LastName><ForeName>Thanut</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Khon Kaen University, Khon Kaen 40002, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khamsai</LastName><ForeName>Sittichai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Khon Kaen University, Khon Kaen 40002, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sawanyawisuth</LastName><ForeName>Kittisak</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Khon Kaen University, Khon Kaen 40002, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Biomed Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101613227</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2049-9434</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">left ventricular ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stem cell</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40599614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12209992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/br.2025.2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">BR-23-3-02025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stark B, Johnson C, Roth GA. Global prevalence of coronary artery disease: An update from the global burden of disease study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024;83 (13 Suppl)(S2320)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid N, Haider S, Abdullah M, Asghar S, Laghari MA, Rajeswaran Y. Trends and disparities in coronary artery disease prevalence among U.S. adults from 2019 to 2022. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2024;49(102645) doi: 10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2024.102645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2024.102645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38796947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillis LD, Smith PK, Anderson JL, Bittl JA, Bridges CR, Byrne JG, Cigarroa JE, Disesa VJ, Hiratzka LF, Hutter AM Jr, et al. 2011 ACCF/AHA guideline for coronary artery bypass graft surgery: A report of the American college of cardiology foundation/American heart association task force on practice guidelines. Circulation. 2011;124:e652&#x2013;e735. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0b013e31823b5fee.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0b013e31823b5fee</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22064599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brovman EY, James ME, Alexander B, Rao N, Cobey FC. The association between institutional mortality after coronary artery bypass grafting at one year and mortality rates at 30 days. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2022;36:86&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2021.08.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jvca.2021.08.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34600830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayyat KS, Argawi A, Mende M, Steinhoff G, Borger MA, Deebis AM, McCurry KR, Garbade J. Combined coronary artery bypass surgery with bone marrow stem cell transplantation: Are we there yet? Ann Thorac Surg. 2019;108:1913&#x2013;1921. doi: 10.1016/j.athoracsur.2019.05.094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.athoracsur.2019.05.094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31398356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soetisna TW, Thamrin AMH, Permadijana D, Ramadhani ANE, Sugisman null, Santoso A, Mansyur M. Intramyocardial stem cell transplantation during coronary artery bypass surgery safely improves cardiac function: Meta-analysis of 20 randomized clinical trials. J Clin Med. 2023;12(4430) doi: 10.3390/jcm12134430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12134430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10342819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37445467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Yang Z, Shao L, Shen H, Teng X, Chen Y, Ding Y, Fan J, Yu Y, Shen Z. Clinical outcomes by consolidation of bone marrow stem cell therapy and coronary artery bypass graft in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: A meta-analysis. Cell Transplant. 2023;32(9636897231152381) doi: 10.1177/09636897231152381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09636897231152381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9932762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36786355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee MN, Bolli R, Hare JM. Clinical studies of cell therapy in cardiovascular medicine: Recent developments and future directions. Circ Res. 2018;123:266&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.118.311217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.118.311217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29976692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawunyavisuth B, Ngamjarus C, Sawanyawisuth K. Adherence to continuous positive airway pressure therapy in pediatric patients with obstructive sleep apnea: A meta-analysis. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2023;19:143&#x2013;162. doi: 10.2147/TCRM.S358737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/TCRM.S358737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9904217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36761690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namwaing P, Ngamjarus C, Sakaew W, Sawunyavisuth B, Sawanyawisuth K, Khamsai S, Srichaphan T. Chest physical therapy and outcomes in primary spontaneous pneumothorax: A systematic review. J Med Assoc Tha. 2021;104 (Suppl 4):S165&#x2013;S168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Thompson S, Deeks J, Altman D. Statistical heterogeneity in systematic reviews of clinical trials: A critical appraisal of guidelines and practice. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2002;7:51&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1258/1355819021927674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/1355819021927674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, Savovic J, Schulz KF, Weeks L, Sterne JA, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343(d5928) doi: 10.1136/bmj.d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamm C, Kleine HD, Choi YH, Dunkelmann S, Lauffs JA, Lorenzen B, David A, Liebold A, Nienaber C, Zurakowski D, et al. Intramyocardial delivery of CD133+ bone marrow cells and coronary artery bypass grafting for chronic ischemic heart disease: Safety and efficacy studies. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2007;133:717&#x2013;725. doi: 10.1016/j.jtcvs.2006.08.077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcvs.2006.08.077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17320570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang KL, Chin D, Leyva F, Foley P, Kubal C, Chalil S, Srinivasan L, Bernhardt L, Stevens S, Shenje LT, Gali&#xf1;anes M. Randomized, controlled trial of intramuscular or intracoronary injection of autologous bone marrow cells into scarred myocardium during CABG versus CABG alone. Nat Clin Pract Cardiovasc Med. 2008;5:663&#x2013;670. doi: 10.1038/ncpcardio1321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncpcardio1321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18711405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menasch&#xe9; P, Alfieri O, Janssens S, McKenna W, Reichenspurner H, Trinquart L, Vilquin JT, Marolleau JP, Seymour B, Larghero J, et al. The myoblast autologous grafting in ischemic cardiomyopathy (MAGIC) trial: First randomized placebo-controlled study of myoblast transplantation. Circulation. 2008;117:1189&#x2013;1200. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.734103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.734103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18285565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brickwedel J, Gulbins H, Reichenspurner H. Long-term follow-up after autologous skeletal myoblast transplantation in ischaemic heart disease. Interact Cardiovasc Thorac Surg. 2014;18:61&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1093/icvts/ivt434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icvts/ivt434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3867044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24130088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soetisna TW, Sukmawan R, Setianto B, Mansyur M, Murni TW, Listiyaningsih E, Santoso A. Combined transepicardial and transseptal implantation of autologous CD 133+ bone marrow cells during bypass grafting improves cardiac function in patients with low ejection fraction. J Card Surg. 2020;35:740&#x2013;746. doi: 10.1111/jocs.14454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocs.14454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32048356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soetisna TW. A new hope of CD133+ bone marrow stem cell for functional exercise capacity improvement in low ejection fraction coronary artery bypass graft patients: A clinical trial. Bali Med J. 2021;10:229&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasseri BA, Ebell W, Dandel M, Kukucka M, Gebker R, Doltra A, Knosalla C, Choi YH, Hetzer R, Stamm C. Autologous CD133+ bone marrow cells and bypass grafting for regeneration of ischaemic myocardium: the Cardio133 trial. Eur Heart J. 2014;35:1263&#x2013;1274. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehu007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24497345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Camacho FT, Wechsler AS, Lahey S, Culliford AT, Jordan D, Gold JP, Higgins RS, Smith CR, Hannan EL. Risk score for predicting long-term mortality after coronary artery bypass graft surgery. Circulation. 2012;125:2423&#x2013;2430. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.111.055939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.111.055939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3422677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22547673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goncharov M, Mejia OAV, Arthur CPDS, Orlandi BMM, Sousa A, Oliveira MAP, Atik FA, Segalote RC, Tiveron MG, de Barros E Silva PGM, et al. Mortality risk prediction in high-risk patients undergoing coronary artery bypass grafting: Are traditional risk scores accurate? PLoS One. 2021;16(e0255662) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0255662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0255662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8330943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamsai S, Mahawarakorn P, Limpawattana P, Chindaprasirt J, Sukeepaisarnjaroen W, Silaruks S, Senthong V, Sawunyavisuth B, Sawanyawisuth K. Prevalence and factors correlated with hypertension secondary from obstructive sleep apnea. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2021;16(777) doi: 10.4081/mrm.2021.777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/mrm.2021.777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang D, Fan T, Gao S, Jin Y, Zhang M, Ono M. Application of mesenchymal stem cell sheet to treatment of ischemic heart disease. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2021;12(384) doi: 10.1186/s13287-021-02451-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-021-02451-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8261909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34233729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicent L, &#xc1;lvarez-Garc&#xed;a J, Vazquez-Garcia R, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Juanatey JR, Rivera M, Segovia J, Pascual-Figal D, Bover R, Worner F, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Avil&#xe9;s F, et al. Coronary artery disease and prognosis of heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. J Clin Med. 2023;12(3028) doi: 10.3390/jcm12083028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12083028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10143946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37109365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purek L, Laule-Kilian K, Christ A, Klima T, Pfisterer ME, Perruchoud AP, Mueller C. Coronary artery disease and outcome in acute congestive heart failure. Heart. 2006;92:598&#x2013;602. doi: 10.1136/hrt.2005.066464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/hrt.2005.066464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1860938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16159982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Han D, Liang P, Li Y, Cao F. The current dilemma and breakthrough of stem cell therapy in ischemic heart disease. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9(636136) doi: 10.3389/fcell.2021.636136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.636136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8100527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamsai S, Kachenchart S, Sawunyavisuth B, Limpawattana P, Chindaprasirt J, Senthong V, Chotmongkol V, Pongkulkiat P, Sawanyawisuth K. Prevalence and risk factors of obstructive sleep apnea in hypertensive emergency. J Emerg Trauma Shock. 2021;14:104&#x2013;107. doi: 10.4103/JETS.JETS_47_20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/JETS.JETS_47_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8312912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34321809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeerasuwannakul B, Sawunyavisuth B, Khamsai S, Sawanyawisuth K. Prevalence and risk factors of proteinuria in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Asia Pac J Sci Technol. 2021;26:APST&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manasirisuk P, Chainirun N, Tiamkao S, Lertsinudom S, Phunikhom K, Sawunyavisuth B, Sawanyawisuth K. Efficacy of generic atorvastatin in a real-world setting. Clin Pharmacol. 2021;13:45&#x2013;51. doi: 10.2147/CPAA.S285750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CPAA.S285750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33707972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawunyavisuth B, Ngamjarus C, Sawanyawisuth K. A meta-analysis to identify factors associated with CPAP machine purchasing in patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Biomed Rep. 2022;16(45) doi: 10.3892/br.2022.1528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/br.2022.1528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9112380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35620316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawunyavisuth B, Ngamjarus C, Sawanyawisuth K. Any effective intervention to improve CPAP adherence in children with obstructive sleep apnea: A systematic review. Glob Pediatr Health. 2021;8(2333794X211019884) doi: 10.1177/2333794X211019884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2333794X211019884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8165832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34104700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>