<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40676400</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-4919</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular and cellular biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Cell Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resveratrol improves lipid profile and recovers heart function in postoperative CABG patients.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11010-025-05351-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiovascular diseases (CVD), especially coronary artery disease (CAD), are among the most important causes of mortality in the world. Coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) is a standard treatment for this disease, but it may be associated with complications in the postoperative period. This study investigated the effect of resveratrol (RES), a potent antioxidant and anti-inflammatory molecule, on cardiovascular indices and oxidative stress in patients after CABG surgery. This randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial was carried out at the Bushehr Heart Center in Bushehr, Iran. A total of 60 patients undergoing CABG were randomly assigned in equal numbers to either the intervention group or the control group. The intervention group received RES capsules for 60 days, and the control group received a placebo for the same duration. Cardiovascular function and biochemical parameters, including lipid profile, cardiac enzymes, and markers of oxidative stress and inflammation, were measured at the beginning and end of the intervention. Compared to the control group, RES intake significantly reduced systolic blood pressure (SBP), triglyceride (TG), total cholesterol (TC), low-density lipoprotein (LDL), and improved ejection fraction (EF). Although decreases in cardiac enzymes, including creatine phosphokinase (CPK) and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH), were observed in the RES group, these changes were not statistically significant. Also, the two groups showed no significant differences in diastolic blood pressure (DBP), HDL, or oxidative stress markers. RES supplementation protects patients after CABG by improving cardiovascular function and lipid profiles.Trial registration: IRCT20111119008129N12, first trial registration date: 2022-06-18.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadi</LastName><ForeName>Parisa</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akbarzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Samad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Neshat</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoodi</LastName><ForeName>Marzieh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Epidemiology, Addiction and Lifestyle Research Center, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amini</LastName><ForeName>Azam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Netticadan</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canadian Centre for Agri-Food Research in Health and Medicine, Winnipeg, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rezaei</LastName><ForeName>Mikaeil</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran. Mikaeilrezaei50@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Movahed</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran. amovahed58@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Cell Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0364456</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0300-8177</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CVD (CVD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery disease (CAD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RES (RES)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran, under approval number IR.BPUMS.REC.1401.024. Consent to participate: Written informed consent was obtained from all participants before their enrollment in the study, and they provided full consent to participate in the research.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40676400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11010-025-05351-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11010-025-05351-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aje TO, Miller M (2009) Cardiovascular disease: A global problem extending into the developing world. World J Cardiol 1(1):3&#x2013;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21160570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2998801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Cesare M, Perel P, Taylor S, Kabudula C, Bixby H, Gaziano TA et al (2024) The heart of the world. Glob Heart 19(1):11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38273998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10809869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawsherwan Bin W, Le Z, Mubarik S, Fu G, Wang Y (2022) Prediction of cardiovascular diseases mortality- and disability-adjusted life-years attributed to modifiable dietary risk factors from 1990 to 2030 among East Asian countries and the world. Front Nutr 9:898978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36324616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9618868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahjehan RD, Bhutta BS. Coronary Artery Disease. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing Copyright &#xa9; 2024, StatPearls Publishing LLC.; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Leyte DJ, Zepeda-Garc&#xed;a O, Dom&#xed;nguez-P&#xe9;rez M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garrido A, Villarreal-Molina T, Jacobo-Albavera L (2021) Endothelial dysfunction, inflammation and coronary artery disease: potential biomarkers and promising therapeutical approaches. Int J Mol Sci 22(8):3850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8068178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komilovich EBZ (2023) Coronary artery disease. Eur J Modern Med Prac 3(12):81&#x2013;87</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukicevic P, Klisic A, Neskovic V, Babic L, Mikic A, Bogavac-Stanojevic N et al (2021) Oxidative stress in patients before and after on-pump and off-pump coronary artery bypass grafting: relationship with syntax score. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2021:3315951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8352695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulicka-Grodzicka J, Szczepaniak P, Jozefczuk E, Urbanski K, Siedlinski M, Niewiara &#x141; et al (2023) Systemic and local vascular inflammation and arterial reactive oxygen species generation in patients with advanced cardiovascular diseases. Front Cardiovas Med 10:1230051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslov LN, Naryzhnaya NV, Sirotina M, Mukhomedzyanov AV, Kurbatov BK, Boshchenko AA et al (2023) Do reactive oxygen species damage or protect the heart in ischemia and reperfusion? Analysis on experimental and clinical data. J Biomed Res 37(4):268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37503710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10387750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang M, Lu Y, Xin L, Gao J, Shang C, Jiang Z et al (2021) Role of oxidative stress in reperfusion following myocardial ischemia and its treatments. Oxid Med Cell Longev. https://doi.org/10.1155/2021/6614009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35096261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8723883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez MG, Shotwell MS, Hennessy C, Pretorius M, McIlroy DR, Kimlinger MJ et al (2024) Intraoperative oxygen treatment, oxidative stress, and organ injury following cardiac surgery: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg 159(10):1106&#x2013;1116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39110454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin S, Kang PM (2024) A systematic review on advances in management of oxidative stress-associated cardiovascular diseases. Antioxidants 13(8):923</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39199169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11351257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Q, Liu S, Sun Y, Chen C, Yang S, Lin M et al (2023) Targeting oxidative stress as a preventive and therapeutic approach for cardiovascular disease. J Transl Med 21(1):519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37533007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10394930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pashkow FJ (2011) Oxidative stress and inflammation in heart disease: do antioxidants have a role in treatment and/or prevention? Int J Inflamm 2011(1):514623</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauf A, Imran M, Suleria HAR, Ahmad B, Peters DG, Mubarak MS (2017) A comprehensive review of the health perspectives of resveratrol. Food Funct 8(12):4284&#x2013;4305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29044265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash V, Bose C, Sunilkumar D, Cherian RM, Thomas SS, Nair BG (2024) Resveratrol as a promising nutraceutical: implications in gut microbiota modulation, inflammatory disorders, and colorectal cancer. Int J Mol Sci 25(6):3370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38542344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10970219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko JH, Sethi G, Um JY, Shanmugam MK, Arfuso F, Kumar AP et al (2017) The role of resveratrol in cancer therapy. Int J Mol Sci. 18(12):2589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29194365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5751192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnefont-Rousselot D (2016) Resveratrol and cardiovascular diseases. Nutrients 8(5):250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4882663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang DD, Shi G, Jiang Y, Yao C, Zhu C (2020) A review on the potential of Resveratrol in prevention and therapy of diabetes and diabetic complications. Biomed Pharmacother 125:109767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izzo C, Annunziata M, Melara G, Sciorio R, Dallio M, Masarone M et al (2021) The role of resveratrol in liver disease: a comprehensive review from in vitro to clinical trials. Nutrients 13(3):933</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33805795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7999728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azargoonjahromi A, Abutalebian F (2024) Unraveling the therapeutic efficacy of resveratrol in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: an umbrella review of systematic evidence. Nutr Metab (Lond) 21(1):15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38504306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankauskas SS, Mone P, Santulli G (2022) From resveratrol to ISIDE11: how to activate SIRT1 and improve endothelial function? New therapeutic insights for methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase deficiency. Cell Mol Life Sci 79(8):451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35895130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9843588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng CK, Luo JY, Lau CW, Chen ZY, Tian XY, Huang Y (2020) Pharmacological basis and new insights of resveratrol action in the cardiovascular system. Br J Pharmacol 177(6):1258&#x2013;1277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31347157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Militaru C, Donoiu I, Craciun A, Scorei ID, Bulearca AM, Scorei RI (2013) Oral resveratrol and calcium fructoborate supplementation in subjects with stable angina pectoris: effects on lipid profiles, inflammation markers, and quality of life. Nutrition 29(1):178&#x2013;183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin F, Siwik DA, Luptak I, Hou X, Wang L, Higuchi A et al (2012) The polyphenols resveratrol and S17834 prevent the structural and functional sequelae of diet-induced metabolic heart disease in mice. Circulation 125(14):1757&#x2013;1764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22388319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3354628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capurso C, Bellanti F, Lo Buglio A, Vendemiale G (2023) Cardioprotective effects of resveratrol in the mediterranean diet: a short narrative review. Dietetics 2(2):174&#x2013;190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favero G, Franceschetti L, Rodella LF, Rezzani R (2015) Sirtuins, aging, and cardiovascular risks. Age (Dordr) 37(4):9804</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26099749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magyar K, Halmosi R, Palfi A, Feher G, Czopf L, Fulop A et al (2012) Cardioprotection by resveratrol: A human clinical trial in patients with stable coronary artery disease. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc 50:179&#x2013;187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22240353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia N, F&#xf6;rstermann U, Li H (2014) Resveratrol and endothelial nitric oxide. Molecules 19:16102&#x2013;16121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25302702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6270738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JM, Hsieh TC (2011) Resveratrol: a cardioprotective substance. Ann N Y Acad Sci 1215:16&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21261637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt CA, Heiss EH, Dirsch VM (2010) Effect of resveratrol on endothelial cell function: Molecular mechanisms. Biofactors 36:342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20730905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia N, F&#xf6;rstermann U, Li H (2017) Effects of resveratrol on eNOS in the endothelium and the perivascular adipose tissue. Ann N Y Acad Sci 1403:132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28672425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockcroft JR (2005) Exploring vascular benefits of endothelium-derived nitric oxide. Am J Hypertens 18(S6):177S-S183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voetsch B, Jin RC, Loscalzo J (2004) Nitric oxide insufficiency and atherothrombosis. Histochem Cell Biol 122(4):353&#x2013;367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15338226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibbe M, Billiar T, Tzeng E (1999) Inducible nitric oxide synthase and vascular injury. Cardiovasc Res 43(3):650&#x2013;657</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10690336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrovski G, Gurusamy N, Das DK (2011) Resveratrol in cardiovascular health and disease. Ann New York Acad Sci 1215:22&#x2013;33</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das M, Das DK (2010) Resveratrol and cardiovascular health. Mol Aspects Med 31(6):503&#x2013;512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20837050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan E, Zhang L, Jiang S, Bai Y (2008) Beneficial effects of resveratrol on atherosclerosis. J Med Food 11(4):610&#x2013;614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19053850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Xia N, Hasselwander S, Daiber A (2019) Resveratrol and vascular function. Int J Mol Sci 20:2155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31052341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6539341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccioni G, Gammone MA, Tettamanti G, Bergante S, Pluchinotta F, D&#x2019;Orazio N (2015) Resveratrol and anti-atherogenic effects. Int J Food Sci Nutr 66:603&#x2013;610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26306466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmas D, editor - 1-Resveratrol : natural properties against atherosclerosis , associated pro-inflammatory effects and aging 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmas D, Jannin B, Latruffe N (2005) Resveratrol: preventing properties against vascular alterations and ageing. Mol Nutr Food Res 49(5):377&#x2013;395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15830334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrougui H, Grenier G, Loued S, Drouin G, Khalil A (2009) A new insight into resveratrol as an atheroprotective compound: inhibition of lipid peroxidation and enhancement of cholesterol efflux. Atherosclerosis 207(2):420&#x2013;427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19552907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad K (2012) Resveratrol, wine, and atherosclerosis. Int J Angiol 21:007&#x2013;018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gal R, Praksch D, Kenyeres P, Rabai M, Toth K, Halmosi R et al (2020) Hemorheological alterations in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction treated by resveratrol. Cardiovasc Ther 2020:7262474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32695229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7350166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gal R, Deres L, Horvath O, Eros K, Sandor B, Urban P et al (2020) Resveratrol improves heart function by moderating inflammatory processes in patients with systolic heart failure. Antioxidants (Basel) 9(11):1108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu W, Fu Y-C, Wang W (2012) Cellular and molecular effects of resveratrol in health and disease. J Cell Biochem 113:752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22065601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun ZM, Guan P, Luo LF, Qin LY, Wang N, Zhao YS et al (2020) Resveratrol protects against CIH-induced myocardial injury by targeting Nrf2 and blocking NLRP3 inflammasome activation. Life Sci 245:117362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31996295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, editor Sirtuin 1 and Oxidative Stress 192014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon SH, Choi HR, Kang YA, Park KC (2017) Depigmenting effect of resveratrol is dependent on FOXO3a activation without SIRT1 activation. Int J Mol Sci 18(6):1213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28590410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5486036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidary Moghaddam R, Samimi Z, Asgary S, Mohammadi P, Hozeifi S, Hoseinzadeh-Chahkandak F et al (2022) Natural AMPK activators in cardiovascular disease prevention. Front Pharmacol. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2021.738420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35046800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8762275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaito A, Al-Mansoob M, Ahmad SMS, Haider MZ, Eid AH, Posadino AM et al (2023) Resveratrol-mediated regulation of mitochondria biogenesis-associated pathways in neurodegenerative diseases: molecular insights and potential therapeutic applications. Curr Neuropharmacol 21(5):1184&#x2013;1201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10286596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoukry HS, Ammar HI, Rashed LA, Zikri MB, Shamaa AA, Abou Elfadl SG et al (2017) Prophylactic supplementation of resveratrol is more effective than its therapeutic use against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity. PLoS ONE 12(7):e0181535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28727797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5519168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung LM, Su MJ, Chen JK (2004) Resveratrol protects myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury through both NO-dependent and NO-independent mechanisms. Free Radic Biol Med 36(6):774&#x2013;781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurusamy N, Lekli I, Mukherjee S, Ray D, Ahsan MK, Gherghiceanu M et al (2010) Cardioprotection by resveratrol: a novel mechanism via autophagy involving the mTORC2 pathway. Cardiovasc Res 86(1):103&#x2013;112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19959541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Si L-Y (2012) Resveratrol role in cardiovascular and metabolic health and potential mechanisms of action. Nutr Res 32(9):648&#x2013;658</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23084637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>