<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40786860</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-0132</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of nursing sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Nurs Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a culture-specific behavior modification program on glycated hemoglobin and blood pressure among adults with diabetes and hypertension: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>328</StartPage><EndPage>334</EndPage><MedlinePgn>328-334</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijnss.2025.06.013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to determine the effect of a culture-specific behavior modification program on glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) and blood pressure among adults with diabetes and hypertension.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study was a single-blind randomized controlled trial design. From January to May 2024, a total of 60 patients with uncontrolled type 2 diabetes and hypertension from the primary care unit of a hospital in northeastern (Isan) Thailand were recruited. The intervention group received the usual care supplemented by a culture-specific behavior modification programm implemented through interactive classes and online web application consisting of information, motivation, and behavioral skills (diet, exercise, and medication use), the control group received the usual care. HbA1c and blood pressure measurements were collected at both baseline and at 12 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 51 patients completed the study, the intervention group (<i>n</i> = 26) and control group (<i>n</i> = 25), respectively. After 12 weeks, 23.1 % of patients in the intervention group could maintain their HbA1c &lt; 7.0 %; those with poorly controlled HbA1c decreased from 7.7 % at baseline to 3.8 % at 12 weeks. After 12 weeks, 69.2 % of intervention group participants could maintain systolic blood pressure &lt;130 mmHg and 53.8 % could keep diastolic blood pressure &lt;80 mmHg. Analysis revealed that HbA1c, systolic and diastolic blood pressure levels in the intervention group were lower than the control group after the intervention (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). There was a statistically significant difference a linear combination of HbA1c and blood pressure (systolic and diastolic BP levels) between time and group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">These results suggest that healthcare providers can incorporate elements of this program to manage blood glucose and blood pressure effectively. Future studies should consider a longitudinal design with a larger sample size and include outcomes of lipid levels to confirm long-term motivation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Numsang</LastName><ForeName>Patcharee</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thanasilp</LastName><ForeName>Sureeporn</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asian Wisdom Care Research Unit, Faculty of Nursing, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thato</LastName><ForeName>Ratsiri</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit for Enhancing Well-being in Vulnerable and Chronic Illness Populations, Faculty of Nursing, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Nurs Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101660887</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2352-0132</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behavior modification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glycated hemoglobin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40786860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12332442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnss.2025.06.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2352-0132(25)00084-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Petrie J.R., Guzik T.J., Touyz R.M. Diabetes, hypertension, and cardiovascular disease: clinical insights and vascular mechanisms. Can J Cardiol. 2018;34(5):575&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1016/j.cjca.2017.12.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjca.2017.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5953551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitorus N., Suriani O., Yunita Suryaputri I., Dermawan Purba F., Satria Hanafi A. Association between blood pressure and quality of life of patients with diabetes mellitus type 2 in the bogor city Indonesia. Open Access Maced J Med Sci. 2022;10:136&#x2013;140. doi: 10.3889/oamjms.2022.8172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2022.8172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayyem R., Hamdan A., Alhmmadi K., Eissa Y., Al-Adwi M., Al-Haswsa Z., et al. Association of glycemic control with different diets followed by patients with type 2 diabetes: findings from Qatar biobank data. Front Nutr. 2022;9:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2022.813880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.813880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9127728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee 5. Facilitating positive health behaviors and well-being to improve health outcomes: standards of care in diabetes-2024. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(Suppl 1):S77&#x2013;S110. doi: 10.2337/dc24-S005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc24-S005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10725816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38078584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lertwiriyanan R. The relevant factors for controlling blood sugar and blood pressure of diabetes mellitus and hypertension patients in mae phag sub-district, sansai district, Chiang Mai province. Lanna Public Health Journal. 2013;9(3):216&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal S. Cultural factors influencing the eating behaviours of type 2 diabetes in the British south-asian population: a scoping review of the literature. J Glob Health Rep. 2023;7:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.29392/001c.84191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29392/001c.84191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Numsang P., Oumtanee A., Kurat S., Sananok R., Kraichan S., Sarapoke P. &#x201c;Failure to control blood sugar&#x201d; experiences of persons with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Int J Nurs Sci. 2023;10(4):527&#x2013;532. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnss.2023.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnss.2023.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10667290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38020838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HDC Database of Ministry of Public Health  Illness with important non-communicable diseases of standard reporting group. Ministry of Public Health (Thailand) 2024 https://hdcservice.moph.go.th</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srihakhot S. Mor lum's adaptation amid cultural changes in the 21st century. Journal of Music and Performing Arts. 2022;4(2):79&#x2013;94. https://so03.tci-thaijo.org/index.php/JournalofMUSPAKKU/article/view/258580/176034 Khon Kaen University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thailand Foundation  Mor lam-the spirit of Isan. https://www.thailandfoundation.or.th/th/culture_heritage/mor-lum-the-spirit-of-isan/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimpakun S. Mor lam and its existence in the midst of social and cultural changes. Journal of Fine and Applied Arts Khon Kaen University. 2010;2(1):66&#x2013;88. https://fa.kku.ac.th/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/29.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phettone P., Kerdchantuk P., Suttiruksa S. Effects of pharmaceutical care with food education according to Isan life style in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Thai Pharm Health Sci J. 2021;16(2):120&#x2013;129. https://ejournals.swu.ac.th/index.php/pharm/article/view/13666/11078</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinyo K., Phinyo P., Aphiphatkan W., Pangsuk P., Niyomsat Y., Janhauna S., Mahem K. Effects of the north eastern (esan) Thai folk dance exercise program on physical fitness and blood sugar levels in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Songklanagarind Journal of Nursing. 2020;40(3):1&#x2013;14. https://he02.tci-thaijo.org/index.php/nur-psu/article/view/245446/167419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tongterm T., Kaewmas J. Development of exercise program by applying soeng Sa nai dance for elderly with hypertension. Institute of Vocational Education Southern Region 3 Journal. 2022;2(1):87&#x2013;97. https://so08.tci-thaijo.org/index.php/KRIS/article/view/3220/2335</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bustami B., Abdurrahman A., Amiruddin A. The role of nurse education in enhancing knowledge and skills of diabetes management in patients. PoS. 2023;9(7):2050&#x2013;2058. doi: 10.22178/pos.94-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22178/pos.94-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher W.A., Fisher J.D., Jennifer H. Blackwell Publishing Ltd.; 2003. Social psychological foundations of health and illness.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasar K.S., Asiret G.D., Yilmaz C.K., Canlar S. The effect of model-based telephone counseling on HbA1c and self-management for individuals with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Prim Care Diabetes. 2022;16(1):41&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.pcd.2021.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcd.2021.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu D.H., Cai Y.M., Graffy J., Holman D., Zhao Z.Z., Simmons D. Association between systolic blood pressure and cardiovascular inpatient cost moderated by peer- support intervention among adult patients with type 2 diabetes: a 2-cohort study. Can J Diabetes. 2021;45(2):179&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1016/j.jcjd.2020.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcjd.2020.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33046400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetes Association of Thailand  Clinical practice guideline for diabetes 2023. Bangkok: Srimuang Printing. 2023 https://thaipedendo.org/clinical-practice-guideline-for-diabetes-2023/ (Original work published in Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewers B., Blond M.B., Bruun J.M., Vilsb&#xf8;ll T. Comparing the effectiveness of different dietary educational approaches for carbohydrate counting on glycemic control in adults with type 1 diabetes: findings from the DIET-CARB study, a randomized controlled trial. Nutrients. 2024;16(21):3745. doi: 10.3390/nu16213745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16213745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11547945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39519579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim S.M.H., Shahat E.A., Amer L.A., Aljohani A.K. The impact of using carbohydrate counting on managing diabetic patients: a review. Cureus. 2023;15(11):1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.7759/cureus.48998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.48998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10726644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38111457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D., Hopewell S., Schulz K.F., Montori V., G&#xf8;tzsche P.C., Devereaux P.J., et al. CONSORT 2010 explanation and elaboration: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. Int J Surg. 2012;10(1):28&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsu.2011.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2011.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112(1):155&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1037//0033-2909.112.1.155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0033-2909.112.1.155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paula T.P., Viana L.V., Neto A.T.Z., Leit&#xe3;o C.B., Gross J.L., Azevedo M.J. Effects of the DASH diet and walking on blood pressure in patients with type 2 diabetes and uncontrolled hypertension: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Hypertens. 2015;17(11):895&#x2013;901. doi: 10.1111/jch.12597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jch.12597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26041459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Numsang P., Thanasilp S., Thato R. Development of a new tool for monitoring the eating, exercise, and medication use among diabetes persons with hypertension. J Health Sci Med Res. 2025;43:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.31584/jhsmr.20251139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31584/jhsmr.20251139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thai Hypertension Society . Vol. 2024. Thai Hypertension Society; Bangkok: 2019. (Thai guidelines on the treatment of hypertension). [in Thai]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwasnicka D., Dombrowski S.U., White M., Sniehotta F. Theoretical explanations for maintenance of behaviour change: a systematic review of behaviour theories. Health Psychol Rev. 2016;10(3):277&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1080/17437199.2016.1151372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17437199.2016.1151372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4975085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26854092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muntner P., Shimbo D., Carey R.M., Charleston J.B., Gaillard T., Misra S., et al. Measurement of blood pressure in humans: A scientific statement from the American Heart Association. 2019;73(5):e35&#x2013;e66. doi: 10.1161/HYP.0000000000000087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYP.0000000000000087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11409525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30827125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng Z., Wang J., Lyu W., Li X., Ye W., Zheng W., et al. Effectiveness of a theory-based tailored mHealth physical activity intervention for women undergoing chemotherapy for breast cancer: a quasi-experimental study. Int J Nurs Sci. 2024;11(4):405&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnss.2024.08.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnss.2024.08.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11740309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39830917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari S., Aghamolaei T., Hosseini Z., Mohseni S. The effectiveness of educational intervention based on information-motivation-behavioral skills model in improving self-care behaviors of patients with hypertension. Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2023;10(4):304&#x2013;315. doi: 10.32598/JPM.10.4.35.25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32598/JPM.10.4.35.25</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashwan Z.I., Khalil H.A., Khonji L.M., Narayanan G., Altheeb M.K., Pradeep R., et al. Effect of empowerment-based interventions on self-efficacy and self-care capacity among patients with sickle cell disease: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Nurs Sci. 2025;12(1):42&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnss.2024.12.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnss.2024.12.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11846553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39990988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugartemendia-Yerobi M., Kortajarena M., Elordi U., Zinkunegi-Zubizarreta N., Zarrazquin I., Calvo-Aguirre J.J., et al. Effects of a multicomponent physical exercise programme on perceived health-related quality of life and on depressive symptoms in older adults living in long-term nursing homes. Int J Nurs Sci. 2023;10(1):16&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnss.2022.12.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnss.2022.12.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9969169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Prentice-Hall; Englewood Cliffs: 1977. Social learning theory.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan FCJH, Oka P, Dambha-Miller H, Tan NC. The association between self-efficacy and self-care in essential hypertension: a systematic review. BMC Fam Pract 2021;22(44): 2-12. 10.1186/s12875-021-01391-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12875-021-01391-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33618661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z., Liu K., Or C., Chen J., Yan M., Wang H. An examination of the socio-demographic correlates of patient adherence to self-management behaviors and the mediating roles of health attitudes and self-efficacy among patients with coexisting type 2 diabetes and hypertension. BMC Public Health. 2020;20:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1186/s12889-020-09274-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-09274-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32787809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flood D., Edwards E.W., Giovannini D., Ridley E., Rosende A., Herman W.H., et al. Integrating hypertension and diabetes management in primary health care settings: HEARTS as a tool. Rev Panam Salud P&#xfa;blic. 2022;46:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.26633/RPSP.2022.150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26633/RPSP.2022.150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9440730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36071915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehmer K.R., &#xc1;lvarez-Villalobos N.A., Barakat S., de Leon-Gutierrez H., Ruiz-Hernandez F.G., Elizondo-Oma&#xf1;a G.G., et al. The impact of health and wellness coaching on patient-important outcomes in chronic illness care: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Patient Educ Counsel. 2023;117:1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2023.107975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2023.107975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10964774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37738790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner J.J., Ufholz K., Yamajala P. Recent findings on the effectiveness of peer support for patients with type 2 diabetes. Curr Cardiovasc Risk Rep. 2024;18(5):65&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1007/s12170-024-00737-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12170-024-00737-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidi S., Gholamnezhad Z., Kasraie N., Sahebkar A. The effects of self -efficacy and physical activity improving methods on the quality of life in patients with diabetes: a systematic review. J Diabetes Res. 2022:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1155/2022/2884933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/2884933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9348907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35936392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee 10. cardiovascular disease and risk management: standards of care in diabetes-2024. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(Suppl 1):S179&#x2013;S218. doi: 10.2337/dc24-S010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc24-S010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10725811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38078592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>