<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40936783</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-2258</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gastroenterology and hepatology from bed to bench</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor modulators in the management of inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>120</StartPage><EndPage>131</EndPage><MedlinePgn>120-131</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22037/ghfbb.v18i2.3134</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the efficacy and safety of sphingosine-1-phosphate (S1P) receptor modulators in treating ulcerative colitis (UC) and Crohn's disease (CD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) is a chronic immune-mediated condition that remains challenging to manage. S1P receptor modulators offer a novel therapeutic approach by targeting immune cell trafficking, potentially improving disease outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic review and meta-analysis were conducted by searching PubMed, Scopus, and Cochrane Library major electronic databases for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) investigating S1P receptor modulators in IBD. Clinical outcomes assessed included clinical remission, clinical response, endoscopic improvement, histologic remission, and serious adverse events. Pooled odds ratios (OR) with 95% confidence intervals (CI) were calculated using a fixed-effects model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seven RCTs with a total of 2,597 patients were included. S1P receptor modulators significantly improved clinical remission (OR = 1.49, 95% CI: 1.21-1.84, p &lt; 0.001), histologic remission (OR = 1.74, 95% CI: 1.31-2.31, p &lt; 0.001), endoscopic improvement (OR = 1.58, 95% CI: 1.23-2.04, p &lt; 0.001), and clinical response (OR = 1.27, 95% CI: 1.05-1.54, p = 0.01). The risk of serious adverse events did not significantly differ between treatment and placebo groups (OR = 1.28, 95% CI: 0.92-1.80, p = 0.14), suggesting a favorable safety profile.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This meta-analysis supports S1P receptor modulators, particularly ozanimod and etrasimod, as effective and safe treatments for UC. Further studies are needed to assess long-term safety and direct comparisons with existing biologic therapies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025, Gastroenterology and Hepatology From Bed to Bench (GHFBB).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darmadi</LastName><ForeName>Darmadi</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas of Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ariestine</LastName><ForeName>Dina Aprillia</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas of Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Herwindo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas of Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sitepu</LastName><ForeName>Yan Indra Fajar</ForeName><Initials>YIF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas of Sumatera Utara, Medan, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101525875</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-2258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical remission</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopic improvement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory bowel disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sphingosine-1-phosphate (S1P) receptor modulators</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40936783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12421927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22037/ghfbb.v18i2.3134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alatab S, Sepanlou SG, Ikuta K, Vahedi H, Bisignano C, Safiri S, et al. The global, regional, and national burden of inflammatory bowel disease in 195 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;5:17&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7026709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31648971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Kwon JE, Cho ML. Immunological pathogenesis of inflammatory bowel disease. Intest Res. 2018;16:26&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5797268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29422795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DT, Ananthakrishnan AN, Siegel CA, Sauer BG, Long MD. ACG clinical guideline: ulcerative colitis in adults. Am J Gastroenterol. 2019;114:384&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30840605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porro GB, Cassinotti A, Ferrara E, Maconi G, Ardizzone S. Review article: the management of steroid dependency in ulcerative colitis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;26:1039&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17767462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon JP, McEwan PC, Maguire A, Sugrue DM, Puelles J. Characterizing unmet medical need and the potential role of new biologic treatment options in patients with ulcerative colitis and Crohn&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and clinician surveys. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2015;27:804&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4892747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25933126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parigi TL, Roda G, Argollo M, Gilardi D, Danese S. Is there a role for therapeutic sphingolipids in inflammatory bowel disease? Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;14:1031&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31874053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott FL, Clemons B, Brooks J, Brahmachary E, Powell R, Dedman H, et al. Ozanimod (RPC1063) is a potent sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor-1 (S1P1) and receptor-5 (S1P5) agonist with autoimmune disease-modifying activity. Br J Pharmacol. 2016;173:1778&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4867749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26990079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hla T, Brinkmann V. Sphingosine 1-phosphate (S1P): physiology and the effects of S1P receptor modulation. Neurology. 2011;76:142&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21339489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrin-Biroulet L, Christopher R, Behan D, Lassen C. Modulation of sphingosine-1-phosphate in inflammatory bowel disease. Autoimmun Rev. 2017;16:495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28279838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Jeldres T, Tyler CJ, Boyer JD, Karuppuchamy T, Bamias G, Dulai PS, et al. Cell trafficking interference in inflammatory bowel disease: therapeutic interventions based on basic pathogenesis concepts. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2019;25:537&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6327230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera J, Proia RL, Olivera A. The alliance of sphingosine-1-phosphate and its receptors in immunity. Nat Rev Immunol. 2008;8:753&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2600775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18787560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karuppuchamy T, Behrens EH, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Cabrera P, Sarkisyan G, Gima L, Boyer JD, et al. Sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor-1 (S1P1) is expressed by lymphocytes, dendritic cells, and endothelium and modulated during inflammatory bowel disease. Mucosal Immunol. 2017;10:1183&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27049060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsolais D, Rosen H. Chemical modulators of sphingosine-1-phosphate receptors as barrier-oriented therapeutic molecules. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2009;8:297&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19300460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborn WJ, Van Assche G, Reinisch W, Colombel JF, D&#x2019;Haens G, Wolf DC, et al. Adalimumab induces and maintains clinical remission in patients with moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2012;142:257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22062358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivera P, Danese S, Pouillon L, Bonovas S, Peyrin-Biroulet L. Effectiveness of golimumab in ulcerative colitis: a review of the real-world evidence. Dig Liver Dis. 2019;51:761&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30555013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radeke HH, Stein J, Van Assche G, Rogler G, Lakatos PL, Muellershausen F, et al. A multicentre, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group study to evaluate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of the S1P receptor agonist KRP203 in patients with moderately active refractory ulcerative colitis. Inflamm Intest Dis. 2020;5:165&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33313070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborn WJ, Vermeire S, Peyrin-Biroulet L, Dubinsky MC, Panes J, Yarur A, et al. Etrasimod as induction and maintenance therapy for ulcerative colitis (ELEVATE): two randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 studies. Lancet. 2023;401:1184&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36871574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborn WJ, Feagan BG, Hanauer S, Vermeire S, Ghosh S, Liu WJ, et al. Long-term efficacy and safety of ozanimod in moderately to severely active ulcerative colitis: results from the open-label extension of the randomized, phase 2 TOUCHSTONE study. J Crohns Colitis. 2021;15:1236&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborn WJ, Peyrin-Biroulet L, Zhang J, Chiorean M, Vermeire S, Lee SD, et al. Efficacy and safety of etrasimod in a phase 2 randomized trial of patients with ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2020;158:550&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeire S, Chiorean M, Pan&#xe9;s J, Peyrin-Biroulet L, Zhang J, Sands BE, et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of etrasimod for ulcerative colitis: results from the open-label extension of the OASIS study. J Crohns Colitis. 2021;15:123&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8218705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33475734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborn WJ, Feagan BG, D&#x2019;Haens G, Wolf DC, Jovanovic I, Hanauer SB, et al. Ozanimod as induction and maintenance therapy for ulcerative colitis. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:1280&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborn WJ, Feagan BG, Wolf DC, D&#x2019;Haens G, Vermeire S, Hanauer SB, et al. Ozanimod induction and maintenance treatment for ulcerative colitis. N Engl J Med. 2016;374:1751&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasa JS, Olivera PA, Danese S, Peyrin-Biroulet L. Efficacy and safety of biologics and small molecule drugs for patients with moderate-to-severe ulcerative colitis: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;7:161&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34856198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubinsky MC, Betts K, Eren D, Tang W, Yin L, Gupte-Singh K. Comparative efficacy and safety of ozanimod and ustekinumab in patients with moderately to severely active ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2022;162:S1500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Haens G, Danese S, Davies M, Watanabe M, Hibi T. A phase II, multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled study to evaluate safety, tolerability, and efficacy of amiselimod in patients with moderate to severe active Crohn&#x2019;s disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16:1452&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34758080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>