<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40862177</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2277-9175</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced biomedical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Biomed Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Efficacy of Focused Extracorporeal Shockwave Therapy for the Knee Osteoarthritis: A Clinical Trial Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>56</StartPage><MedlinePgn>56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">56</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/abr.abr_202_21</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Osteoarthritis is the most common form of degenerative arthritis. To date, varieties of management approaches have been recommended for osteoarthritis, but their outcomes are not consistent. In the current study, it is aimed to assess the efficacy of focused shockwave therapy for the treatment of knee osteoarthritis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The current randomized clinical trial was conducted on 42 patients (22 cases and 20 controls, with mean age of 58.02 &#xb1; 9.90 years) with knee osteoarthritis in 2018-2019, in Isfahan, Iran. Both groups received topical analgesic plus hot pack and celecoxib 200 mg 14d. The cases underwent shockwave therapy, whereas the controls underwent sham shockwave therapy. Pain score based on visual analog scale (VAS), Knee injury and Outcome Osteoarthritis Score (KOOS) and Roles and Maudsley scores were assessed basically and within 12 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Disease-related symptoms (as a part of KOOS questionnaire) improved following the interventions in both groups (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) but the comparison between groups found no significant differences, whereas daily activities (<i>P</i> = 0.01) and knee-related quality of life (<i>P</i> = 0.003) only promoted among shockwave group. Comparison of two groups merely revealed the superiority of shockwave regarding the knee-related quality of life (<i>P</i> = 0.003) and pain based on VAS score (0.005). Other entities of KOSS and Roles and Maudsley scores were not statistically different between cases and controls (<i>P</i> &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We found that focused shockwave use can appropriately rehabilitate the knee function and reduce knee osteoarthritis pain. Further studies to assess the best dose and the best location of shockwave administration are strongly recommended.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Advanced Biomedical Research.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vahdatpour</LastName><ForeName>Babak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mortazavi</LastName><ForeName>Faezeh Sadat</ForeName><Initials>FS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haghighat</LastName><ForeName>Shila</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saleki Mehrjerdi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mortazavi</LastName><ForeName>Zahra Sadat</ForeName><Initials>ZS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Biomed Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101586897</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2277-9175</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Focused shockwave therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40862177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12373052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/abr.abr_202_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ABR-14-56</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lawrence RC, Felson DT, Helmick CG, Arnold LM, Choi H, Deyo RA, et al. Estimates of the prevalence of arthritis and other rheumatic conditions in the United States. Part II. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:26&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3266664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18163497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshpande BR, Katz JN, Solomon DH, Yelin EH, Hunter DJ, Messier SP, et al. Number of persons with symptomatic knee osteoarthritis in the US: Impact of race and ethnicity, age, sex, and obesity. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2016;68:1743&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5319385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27014966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peat G, McCarney R, Croft P. Knee pain and osteoarthritis in older adults: A review of community burden and current use of primary health care. Ann Rheum Dis. 2001;60:91&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11156538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofat N, Ejindu V, Kiely P. What makes osteoarthritis painful? The evidence for local and central pain processing. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2011;50:2157&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Kim JY, Choi CM, Lee JK, Kee HS, Jung KI, et al. The dose-related effects of extracorporeal shock wave therapy for knee osteoarthritis. Ann Rehabil Med. 2015;39:616&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannuru RR, Osani MC, Vaysbrot EE, Arden NK, Bennell K, Bierma-Zeinstra SM, et al. OARSI guidelines for the non-surgical management of knee, hip, and polyarticular osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2019;27:1578&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31278997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CJ. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy in musculoskeletal disorders. J Orthop Surg Res. 2012;7:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3342893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22433113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahdatpour B, Sajadieh S, Bateni V, Karami M, Sajjadieh H. Extracorporeal shock wave therapy in patients with plantar fasciitis. A randomized, placebo-controlled trial with ultrasonographic and subjective outcome assessments. J Res Med Sci. 2012;17:834&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3697207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23826009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahdatpour B, Kiyani A, Dehghan F. Effect of extracorporeal shock wave therapy on the treatment of patients with carpal tunnel syndrome. Adv Biomed Res. 2016;5:120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4976534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27563630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An S, Li J, Xie W, Yin N, Li Y, Hu Y. Extracorporeal shockwave treatment in knee osteoarthritis: Therapeutic effects and possible mechanism. Biosci Rep. 2020;40:BSR20200926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7670564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33074309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein MM, Nabhan AF, Fayaz NA. Effect of shock wave therapy on knee osteoarthritis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Rom Soc Cell Biol. 2021;25:14743&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftekharsadat B, Jahanjoo F, Toopchizadeh V, Heidari F, Ahmadi R, Babaei-Ghazani A. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy and physiotherapy in patients with moderate knee osteoarthritis. Crescent J Med Biol Sci. 2020;7:518&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura M, Alamino S, Hsing WT, Alfieri FM, Schmitz C, Battistella LR. Radial extracorporeal shock wave therapy for disabling pain due to severe primary knee osteoarthritis. J Rehabil Med. 2017;49:54&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27904912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Pan Y, Yang Q, Guo ZG, Yue Q, Meng QG. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy for the treatment of knee osteoarthritis: A retrospective study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2018;97:e11418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6076154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29979441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auersperg V, Trieb K. Extracorporeal shock wave therapy: An update. EFORT Open Rev. 2020;5:584&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7608508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33204500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang QW, Zhang QY, Gao FQ, Sun W. Focused extra-corporeal shockwave treatment during early stage of osteonecrosis of femoral head. Chin Med J (Engl) 2019;132:1867&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6759127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31306227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su W, Lin Y, Wang G, Geng Z, Wang Z, Hou D, et al. Prospective clinical study on extracorporeal shock wave therapy combined with platelet-rich plasma injection for knee osteoarthritis. Zhongguo Xiu Fu Chong Jian Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2019;33:1527&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8355794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maemichi T, Tsutsui T, Okunuki T, Hoshiba T, Kumai T. Pain relief after extracorporeal shock wave therapy for patellar tendinopathy: An ultrasound evaluation of morphology and blood flow. Appl Sci. 2021;11:8748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knobloch K, Hellweg M, Sorg H, Nedelka T. Focused electromagnetic high-energetic extracorporeal shockwave (ESWT) reduces pain levels in the nodular state of Dupuytren&#x2019;s disease &#x2013; A randomized controlled trial (DupuyShock) Lasers Med Sci. 2021;37:323&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosrawi S, Taheri P, Ketabi M. Investigating the effect of extracorporeal shock wave therapy on reducing chronic pain in patients with Pes anserine bursitis: A randomized, clinical- controlled trial. Adv Biomed Res. 2017;6:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5468784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28626745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman R, Asch E, Bloch D, Bole G, Borenstein D, Brandt K, et al. Development of criteria for the classification and reporting of osteoarthritis. Classification of osteoarthritis of the knee. Diagnostic and Therapeutic Criteria Committee of the American Rheumatism Association. Arthritis Rheum. 1986;29:1039&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3741515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellgren JH, Lawrence JS. Radiological assessment of osteo-arthrosis. Ann Rheum Dis. 1957;16:494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1006995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13498604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Lee S, Choi S, Choi YH, Lee K. The effects of extracorporeal shock wave therapy on the pain and function of patients with degenerative knee arthritis. J Phys Ther Sci. 2017;29:536&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5361028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28356649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz J, Melzack R. Measurement of pain. Surg Clin North Am. 1999;79:231&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10352653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraei-Pour S, Salavati M, Akhbari B, Kazem-Nezhad A. Translation and adaptation of knee injury and osteoarthritis outcome score (koos) in to persian and testing persian version reliability among Iranians with osteoarthritis. Arch Rehabil. 2007;8:42&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CJ, Huang CY, Hsu SL, Chen JH, Cheng JH. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy in osteoporotic osteoarthritis of the knee in rats: An experiment in animals. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2015;23:A313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4095692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24994452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Nalesso G, Mobasheri A, Mozafari M. Aging and osteoarthritis: Central role of the extracellular matrix. Ageing Res Rev. 2017;40:20&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28774716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ediz L, &#xd6;zg&#xf6;k&#xe7;e M. Effectiveness of extracorporeal shock wave therapy to treat primary medial knee osteoarthritis with and without bone marrow edema in elderly patients. Turk J Geriatr. 2018;21:394&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Jing R, Shi Z, Zhao B, Ai Q, Xing G. Efficacy of extracorporeal shockwave therapy for knee osteoarthritis: A randomized controlled trial. J Surg Res. 2013;185:661&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23953895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CJ, Cheng JH, Huang CY, Hsu SL, Lee FY, Yip HK. Medial tibial subchondral bone is the key target for extracorporeal shockwave therapy in early osteoarthritis of the knee. Am J Transl Res. 2017;9:1720&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5411920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Z, Liu B, Liu G, Chen J, Li Y, Chen J, et al. A randomized controlled trial on the effects of low-dose extracorporeal shockwave therapy in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2019;100:1695&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31194946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CJ, Weng LH, Ko JY, Sun YC, Yang YJ, Wang FS. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy shows chondroprotective effects in osteoarthritic rat knee. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2011;131:1153&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21387139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CJ, Hsu SL, Weng LH, Sun YC, Wang FS. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy shows a number of treatment related chondroprotective effect in osteoarthritis of the knee in rats. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2013;14:44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23356403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>