<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40815363</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1867-1314</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Probiotics and antimicrobial proteins</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Probiotics on Markers of Oxidative/Nitrosative Stress and Damage Associated with Inflammation in Non-communicable Diseases: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Randomized Placebo-Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12602-025-10710-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Inflammation and oxidative/nitrosative stress (O&amp;NS) are serious complications in non-communicable diseases (NCDs), including endocrine and metabolic and neurodegenerative diseases. The beneficial probiotic microbes, such as Lactobacillus, Bifidobacterium, and Streptococcus, can decrease O&amp;NS and inflammation. We conducted this systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) with aims to elucidate the effects of probiotics on O&amp;NS and inflammation in NCDs. A systematic search of PubMed, Scopus, and EMBASE resulted in the inclusion of studies if they met the eligibility criteria. Methodological quality was assessed using the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2 tool. Data (combined effect size) were analyzed using Meta-Essentials software. Fifteen studies/16 trials with a total of 807 participants (421 cases/386 controls) were reviewed. There was high and moderate certainty of evidence (GRADE) for the effectiveness of probiotic intervention (vs. placebo) in increasing (&#x2191;) glutathione (GSH) levels (SMD(SE)&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.89 (0.51)/p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, 95%CI&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.23 to 2.1, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;92.77%) and total antioxidant capacity (TAC) (SMD(SE)&#x2009;=&#x2009;0. 75 (0.22)/p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01, 95%CI 0.28 to 1.23, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;87.50%) as well as decreased (&#x2193;) malondialdehyde (MDA) (SMD(SE)&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.03 (0.31)/p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01, 95%CI 0.37 to 1.7, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;93.88%) and C-reactive protein (hsCRP) (SMD(SE)&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.74 (0.36)/p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, 95%CI&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.07 to 1.55, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;94.32%). There were no effects on nitric oxide, 8-hydroxy-2'-deoxyguanosine, interleukin-6, and tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1;. Subgroup analysis to reduce heterogeneity indicated probiotic effectiveness on strain number (one/&#x2191;GSH), age bracket (41-60&#xa0;years/&#x2193;MDA or&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;61&#xa0;years/&#x2193;hsCRP), and NCD (nervous system/neurodegenerative diseases/&#x2191;GSH and &#x2193;hsCRP or rheumatoid arthritis/polycystic ovary syndrome/&#x2191;TAC). An overall low risk of bias was observed. In conclusion, probiotics may have beneficial effects on markers of O&amp;NS and inflammation in patients with NCDs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Natanny Swerts</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Analysis, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Federal University of Alfenas, Alfenas, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Cerdeira</LastName><ForeName>Cl&#xe1;udio Daniel</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7242-8028</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, Alfenas, Minas Gerais, Brazil. daniel.cerdeira.84@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Reis</LastName><ForeName>Tiago Marques</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical and Toxicological Analysis, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Federal University of Alfenas, Alfenas, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues</LastName><ForeName>Maria Rita</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Clinical Analysis, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Federal University of Alfenas, Alfenas, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101484100</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1867-1306</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bifidobacterium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lactobacillus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CRP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dysbiosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GSH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total antioxidant capacity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40815363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12602-025-10710-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12602-025-10710-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Raygan F, Rezavandi Z, Bahmani F, Ostadmohammadi V, Ali Mansournia M, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M, Borzabadi S, Asemi Z (2018) The effects of probiotic supplementation on metabolic status in type 2 diabetic patients with coronary heart disease. Diabetol Metab Syndr 10:51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6008939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong PL, Laight D, Aspinall RJ, Higginson A, Cummings MH (2021) A randomised placebo controlled trial of VSL#3&#xae; probiotic on biomarkers of cardiovascular risk and liver injury in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. BMC Gastroenterol 21:144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33794784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8015038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan R, Pechenyak B, Vyas U, Ranganathan P, Weinberg A, Liang P, Mallappallil MC, Norin AJ, Friedman EA, Saggi SJ (2014) Randomized controlled trial of strain-specific probiotic formulation (Renadyl) in dialysis patients. Biomed Res Int 2014:568571. https://doi.org/10.1155/2014/568571</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunst C, Schmid S, Michalski M et al (2023) The influence of gut microbiota on oxidative stress and the immune system. Biomedicines 11(5):1388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10216031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi S, Ghane MR, Goodarzi H, Faraji M, Shahjooie F, Javadzadeh HR (2021) The effect of probiotic supplements on oxidative stress in various diseases: a systematic review. J Appl Biotechnol Rep 8(4):326&#x2013;331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryan JF, O&#x2019;Riordan KJ, Cowan CSM et al (2013) The microbiota-gut-brain axis. Physiol Rev 99:1877&#x2013;201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asghari KM, Dolatkhah N, Ayromlou H, Mirnasiri F, Dadfar T, Hashemian M (2023) The effect of probiotic supplementation on the clinical and para-clinical findings of multiple sclerosis: a randomized clinical trial. Sci Rep 13:18577</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37903945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10616192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke MS, Evans MD, Dizdaroglu M, Lunec J (2003) Oxidative DNA damage: mechanisms, mutation, and disease. FASEB J 17:1195&#x2013;1214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12832285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghfouri AH, Afrakoti LGMP, Kavyani Z, Nogourani ZS, Musazadeh V, Jafarlou M, Dehghan P (2023) The role of probiotic supplementation in inflammatory biomarkers in adults: an umbrella meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Inflammopharmacol 31(5):2253&#x2013;2268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jomova K, Raptova R, Alomar SY et al (2023) Reactive oxygen species, toxicity, oxidative stress, and antioxidants: chronic diseases and aging. Arch Toxicol 97:2499&#x2013;2574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37597078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10475008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agahi A, Hamidi GA, Daneshvar R et al (2018) Does severity of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease contribute to its responsiveness to modifying gut microbiota? A double blind clinical trial. Front Neurol 9:662</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30158897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6104449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamtaji OR, Taghizadeh M, Kakhaki DR, Kouchaki E, Bahmani F et al (2019) Clinical and metabolic response to probiotic administration in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Nut 38:1031e1035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhgarjand C, Vahabi V, Shab-Bidar S, Anoushirvani A, Djafarian K (2024) The effects of probiotic supplements on oxidative stress and inflammation in subjects with mild and moderate Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Inflammopharmacology 32:1413&#x2013;1420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38319476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu YC, Huang YY, Tsai SY, Kuo YW, Lin JH et al (2024) Efficacy of probiotic supplements on brain-derived neurotrophic factor, inflammatory biomarkers, oxidative stress and cognitive function in patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s dementia: a 12 week randomized, double-blind active-controlled study. Nutrients 16:16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkasheh G, Kashani-Poor Z, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M et al (2016) Clinical and metabolic response to probiotic administration in patients with major depressive disorder: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Nutrition 32(3):315&#x2013;320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26706022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabouri S, Esmailzadeh M, Sadeghinejad A, Shahrbabaki Me, Asadikaram G, Nikvarz N (2022) The effect of adjunctive probiotics on markers of inflammation and oxidative stress in bipolar disorder: a double-blind, randomized, controlled trial. J Psychiatr Pract 28:373&#x2013;382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36074106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim A, Muhammad T, Shah I, Khan J, Qaisar R (2022) A multistrain probiotic reduces sarcopenia by modulating Wnt signaling biomarkers in patients with chronic heart failure. J Cardiol 80:449&#x2013;455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35750555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaghef-Mehrabany E, Alipour B, Homayouni-Rad A, Sharif SK, Asghari-Jafarabadi M, Zavvari S (2014) Probiotic supplementation improves inflammatory status in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Nutrition 30(4):430&#x2013;435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24355439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaghef-Mehrabany E, Homayouni-Rad A, Alipour B, Sharif S-K, Vaghef-Mehrabany L, Alipour-Ajiry S (2016) Effects of probiotic supplementation on oxidative stress indices in women with rheumatoid arthritis: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. J Am Coll Nutr 35:291&#x2013;299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25856220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asemi Z, Zare Z, Shakeri H, Sabihi SS, Esmaillzadeh A (2013) Effect of multispecies probiotic supplements on metabolic profiles, hs-CRP, and oxidative stress in patients with type 2 diabetes. Ann Nutr Metab 63:1&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23899653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miraghajani M, Zaghian N, Mirlohi M, Feizi A, Ghiasvand R (2017) The impact of probiotic soy milk consumption on oxidative stress among type 2 diabetic kidney disease patients: a randomized controlled clinical trial. J Ren Nutr 27(5):317&#x2013;324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28579313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani A, Mojarrad MZ, Bahmani F, Taghizadeh M, Ramezani M, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M, Jafari P, Esmaillzadeh A, Asemi Z (2017) Probiotic supplementation in diabetic hemodialysis patients has beneficial metabolic effects. Kidney Int 91:435&#x2013;442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27927601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajifaraji M, Jahanjou F, Abbasalizadeh F, Aghamohammadzadeh N, Abbasi MM, Dolatkhah N (2018) Effect of probiotic supplements in women with gestational diabetes mellitus on inflammation and oxidative stress biomarkers: a randomized clinical trial. Asia Pac J Clin Nutr 27(3):581&#x2013;591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29737805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moylan S, Berk M, Dean OM et al (2014) Oxidative &amp; nitrosative stress in depression: why so much stress? Neurosci Biobehav Rev 45:46&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24858007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabrizi R, Ostadmohammadi V, Akbari M et al (2019) The effects of probiotic supplementation on clinical symptom, weight loss, glycemic control, lipid and hormonal profiles, biomarkers of inflammation, and oxidative stress in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins 14(1):1&#x2013;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohlouli J, Namjoo I, Borzoo-Isfahani M et al (2021) Effect of probiotics on oxidative stress and inflammatory status in diabetic nephropathy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Heliyon 7:e05925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7808957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Lv C, Song J, Li J (2021) Effect of probiotic supplementation on cognitive function and metabolic status in mild cognitive impairment and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a meta-analysis. Front Nutr 8:757673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34957177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8692377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TTU, Kim HW, Kim W (2021) Effects of probiotics, prebiotics, and synbiotics on uremic toxins, inflammation, and oxidative stress in hemodialysis patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med 10:4456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34640474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8509328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y, Quan J, Xiong L, Luo Y, Yi B (2022) Probiotics improve renal function, glucose, lipids, inflammation and oxidative stress in diabetic kidney disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ren Fail 44:862&#x2013;880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35611435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9154786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naseri K, Saadati S, Ghaemi F et al (2023) The effects of&#xa0;probiotic and&#xa0;symbiotic supplementation on&#xa0;inflammation, oxidative stress, and&#xa0;circulating adiponectin and&#xa0;leptin concentration in&#xa0;subjects with&#xa0;prediabetes and&#xa0;type 2 diabetes mellitus: a&#xa0;GRADE-assessed systematic review, meta-analysis, and&#xa0;meta-regression of&#xa0;randomized clinical trials. Eur J Nutr 62:543&#x2013;561</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerdeira CD, Silva NS, dos Reis TM, Rodrigues MR (2023) Efficacy of probiotics on gut microbiome alpha-diversity and inflammatory markers in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PROSPERO CRD42023440106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, Savovi&#x107; J, Schulz KF, Weeks L, Sterne JA (2011) The cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 343:d5928</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S (eds) (2011) Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 5.1.0. The Cochrane Collaboration,&#xa0;UK, Ed. Wiley</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton M, Chan S, Tipping CJ, Stratton A, Neto AS et al (2023) The effect of mobilization at 6 months after critical illness &#x2013; meta-analysis. NEJM Evid 2(2):12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/EVIDoa2200234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maru&#x161;i&#x107; MF, Fidahi&#x107; M, Cepeha CM, Farcas LG, Tseke A et al (2020) Methodological tools and sensitivity analysis for assessing quality or risk of bias used in systematic reviews published in the high-impact anesthesiology journals. BMC Med Res Methodol 20:121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suurmond R, Rhee R, Hak T (2017) Introduction, comparison and validation of meta-essentials: a free and simple tool for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods 8:537&#x2013;553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28801932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5725669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D (2013) Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: a practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol 4:863</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3840331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV (2007) Effect sizes in cluster-randomized designs. J Educ Behav Stat 32(4):341&#x2013;370</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG (2003) Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ 327(7414):557e60</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins D, Best D, Briss PA et al (2004) GRADE working group. Grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ 328:1490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R, Hill S (2016) How to GRADE the quality of the evidence. Cochrane Consumers and Communication Group, Version 3.0. available at https://cccrg.cochrane.org/author-resources</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea BJ, Reeves BC, Wells G, Thuku M, Hamel C et al (2017) AMSTAR 2: a critical appraisal tool for systematic reviews that include randomized or non-randomized studies of healthcare interventions, or both. BMJ 358:j4008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM et al (2021) The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic review. BMJ 372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mafi A, Namazi G, Soleimani A, Bahmani F, Aghadavod E, Asemi Z (2018) Metabolic and genetic response to probiotics supplementation in patients with diabetic nephropathy: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Food Funct 9(9):4763&#x2013;4770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohseni S, Bayani M, Bahmani F, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M, Bayani MA et al (2018) The beneficial effects of probiotic administration on wound healing and metabolic status in patients with diabetic foot ulcer: a randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 34(3):e2970</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karamali M, Eghbalpour S, Rajabi S, Jamilian M, Bahmani F et al (2018) Effects of probiotic supplementation on hormonal profiles, biomarkers of inflammation and oxidative stress in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Arch Iran Med 21:1&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29664663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C, Yang H, Geng Q, Ma Q, Long Y, Zhou C, Chen M (2015) Association of oxidative stress biomarkers with gestational diabetes mellitus in pregnant women: a case-control study. PLoS One 10:e0126490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25915047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4411158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippin LI, Vercelio R, Marroni NP, Xavier RM (2008) Redox signaling and inflammatory response in rheumatoid arthritis. Clin Exp Immunol 152:415&#x2013;422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18422737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2453196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H, Dong X, Chen M, Zou Z (2020) Efficacy of probiotics on cognition, and biomarkers of inflammation and oxidative stress in adults with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease or mild cognitive impairment &#x2014; a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Aging 12(4):4010&#x2013;4039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moayyedi P, Ford AC, Talley NJ, Cremonini F, Foxx-Orenstein AE, Brandt LJ, Quigley EMM (2010) The efficacy of probiotics in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review. Gut 59:325e332</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>