<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40993830</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2520-1026</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC rheumatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of writing based on self-compassion on body image and psychological distress among women with systemic lupus erythematosus: a randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41927-025-00565-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Women with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) are at risk for body image (BI) disturbances and its resultant psychological distress (PD). The aim of this study was to examine the effects of self-compassion (SC)-based writing on BI and PD among women with SLE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this randomized clinical trial, which was done in 2022-2023, 86 women with SLE were selected and randomly allocated to an intervention group (IG) and a control group (CG). Participants in the IG were instructed to engage in SC-based writing that emphasized the concepts of common humanity, mindfulness, and self-kindness. Six blank pages were provided, each featuring a question related to self-compassion for participants to address. Conversely, the CG was also provided with papers and asked to respond to questions that were unrelated to SC. Data were collected before, immediately after, and one month after the intervention (T1-T3) using a demographic and clinical characteristics questionnaire, the SLE Disease Activity Index, the Body Image Lupus Scale(BILS), the Depression Anxiety Stress Scale, the Self-Compassion Scale, and the Body Image Quality of Life Inventory(BIQLI). The SPSS software (v. 22.0) was employed for data analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Groups did not significantly differ from each other respecting baseline demographic and clinical characteristics and baseline mean scores of the main study outcomes. However, there were significant between-group differences respecting the mean scores of BI (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.028), stress (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003), anxiety (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003), and SC (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) at T2 and the mean scores of stress (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.023), anxiety (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.029), and SC (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) at T3. Moreover, between-group differences respecting the other study outcomes at T2 and T3 were insignificant (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">SC-based writing significantly increases SC among women with SLE. Patients may be encouraged to engage in SC-based writing through education about this technique. Investigating alternative strategies or implementing the intervention at different time intervals may be beneficial for improving the BILS, PD, and BIQLI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study was registered in the Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials in February 14, 2022 (code: IRCT20220107053656N1).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amouei</LastName><ForeName>Kimya</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-8775-6824</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Post box 6459, Mirkhani Street (East Nosrat), Tohid Square, Tehran, 1419733171, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manookian</LastName><ForeName>Arpi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0607-0731</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Post box 6459, Mirkhani Street (East Nosrat), Tohid Square, Tehran, 1419733171, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faezi</LastName><ForeName>Seyedeh Tahereh</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5828-7556</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Research Centre, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Shariati Hospital, Jalal-e-Al-e-Ahmad Hwy, NorthKargar Street, Tehran, 1411713135, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sayadi</LastName><ForeName>Leila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7613-3051</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing and Midwifery Care Research Centre, School of Nursing &amp; Midwifery, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Post box 6459, Mirkhani Street (East Nosrat), Tohid Square, Tehran, 1419733171, Iran. sayadi117@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>1401.1.160.57379</GrantID><Agency>Tehran University of Medical Sciences and Health Services</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101738571</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2520-1026</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study involves human participants. This study was approved in December 20, 2021, by the research ethics committees of School of Nursing and Midwifery &amp; Rehabilitation - Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran (ethics code: IR.TUMS.FNM.REC.1400.176). Informed written consent for participation was obtained from all participants. Consent for publication: Not be required. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40993830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12462039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41927-025-00565-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41927-025-00565-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yeoh S-A, Dias SS, Isenberg DA. Advances in systemic lupus erythematosus. Medicine. 2018;46(2):84&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues L, Sim-Sim MM, Sousa L, Faria&#x2010;Sch&#xfc;tzer DB, Surita FG. Self&#x2010;concept and body image of people living with lupus: a systematic review. Int J Rheum Dis. 2021;24(11):1339&#x2013;53. 10.1111/1756-185X.14187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolly M, Pickard AS, Sequeira W, Wallace DJ, Solem CT, Mikolaitis RA, et al. A brief assessment tool for body image in systemic lupus erythematosus. Body Image. 2012;9(2):279&#x2013;84. 10.1016/j.bodyim.2011.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MM, Kimble LP, Body, Image. Depression symptoms, and health-related quality of life in black women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Nurs Womens Health. 2022;26(5):363&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.nwh.2022.07.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9659411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36002068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artoni P, Chierici M, Arnone F, Cigarini C, De Bernardis E, Galeazzi G, et al. Body perception treatment, a possible way to treat body image disturbance in eating disorders: a case&#x2013;control efficacy study. Eat Weight Disord. 2021;26(2):499&#x2013;514. 10.1007/s40519-020-00875-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32124409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini SA, Padhy RK. Body image distortion (archived). In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025 Jan&#x2013; [cited 2023 Sep 4]. PMID: 31536191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31536191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naraindas AM, Cooney SM. Body image disturbance, interoceptive sensibility and the body schema across female adulthood: a pre-registered study. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1285216. 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1285216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10720753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38098520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B, He Y, Chen H, Zhao C, Zhu L, Gao Y, et al. Body image disturbances have impact on the sexual problems in Chinese systemic lupus erythematosus patients. J Immunol Res. 2015;2015:204513. 10.1155/2015/204513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4451262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26090484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Shi S, Cui H, Li Y, Liu Z, Yao L, et al. What are the predictive factors of body image disturbance in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus? A cross-sectional study in China. BMJ Open. 2022;12(11):e060049. 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-060049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9703306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36428020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen B, Zhang A, Liu J, Da Z, Xu X, Liu H, et al. Body image disturbance and quality of life in Chinese patients with ankylosing spondylitis. Psychol Psychother. 2014;87(3):324&#x2013;37. 10.1111/papt.12016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24123522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palagini L, Mosca M, Tani C, Gemignani A, Mauri M, Bombardieri S. Depression and systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review. Lupus. 2013;22(5):409&#x2013;16. 10.1177/0961203313477227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23427220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong J, Aspey L, Bao G, Haynes T, Lim SS, Drenkard C. Chronic cutaneous lupus erythematosus: depression burden and associated factors. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2019;20(3):465&#x2013;75. 10.1007/s40257-019-00429-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6534449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30877492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alturaymi MA, Almadhi OF, Alageel YS, Bin Dayel M, Alsubayyil MS, Alkhateeb BF. The association between prolonged use of oral corticosteroids and mental disorders: do steroids have a role in developing mental. Disorders? Cureus. 2023;15(4):e37627. 10.7759/cureus.37627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10185922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37200642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CC, Chan KL, Cheung EF, Yip PS. Suicidal ideation in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: incidence and risk factors. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2014;53(4):714&#x2013;21. 10.1093/rheumatology/ket404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24361695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drenkard C, Aspey LD, Bao G, Gordon C, Theis K, Helmick C, et al. Relationship between skin-related quality of life, psychosocial stress, and race in cutaneous lupus erythematosus. Poster session presented at American College of Rheumatology Convergence; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Carrasco M, Mendoza-Pinto C, Cardiel MH, M&#xe9;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez S, Garc&#xed;a-Villase&#xf1;or A, Jim&#xe9;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez C, et al. Health related quality of life in Mexican women with systemic lupus erythematosus: a descriptive study using SF-36 and LupusQoL(C). Lupus. 2012;21(11):1219&#x2013;24. 10.1177/0961203312456749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyedoshohadaee M, Khachian A, Seyedfatemi N, Mahmoudi M. The effect of short-term training course by nurses on body image in patients with burn injuries. World J Plast Surg. 2019;8(3):359. 10.29252/wjps.8.3.359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6790268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31620339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari M, Hunt C, Harrysunker A, Abbott MJ, Beath AP, Einstein DA. Self-compassion interventions and psychosocial outcomes: a meta-analysis of RCTs. Mindfulness. 2019;10(8):1455&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przezdziecki A, Sherman KA. Modifying affective and cognitive responses regarding body image difficulties in breast cancer survivors using a self-compassion-based writing intervention. Mindfulness. 2016;7(5):1142&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neff K, Germer C. Self-compassion and psychological. The Oxford Handbook of Compassion Science; 2017. p. 371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay-Jones A, Kane R, Rees C. Self&#x2010;compassion online: a pilot study of an internet&#x2010;based self&#x2010;compassion cultivation program for psychology trainees. J Clin Psychol. 2017;73(7):797&#x2013;816. 10.1002/jclp.22375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27787877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherman KA, Przezdziecki A, Alcorso J, Kilby CJ, Elder E, Boyages J, et al. Reducing body image&#x2013;related distress in women with breast cancer using a structured online writing exercise: results from the my changed body randomized controlled trial. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36(19):1930&#x2013;40. 10.1200/JCO.2017.76.3318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29688834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert P, McEwan K, Gibbons L, Chotai S, Duarte J, Matos M. Fears of compassion and happiness in relation to alexithymia, mindfulness, and self-criticism. Psychol Psychother. 2012;85(4):374&#x2013;90. 10.1111/j.2044-8341.2011.02046.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23080529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherman KA, Roper T, Kilby CJ. Enhancing self-compassion in individuals with visible skin conditions: randomised pilot of the &#x2018;my changed body&#x2019; self-compassion writing intervention. Health Psychol Behav Med. 2019;7(1):62&#x2013;77. 10.1080/21642850.2019.1587298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34040839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Campayo J, Barcelo-Soler A, Mart&#xed;nez-Rubio D, Navarrete J, Perez-Aranda A, Feliu-Soler A, et al. Exploring the relationship between self-compassion and compassion for others: the role of psychological distress and wellbeing. Assessment. 2024;31(5):1038&#x2013;51. 10.1177/10731911231203966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11134997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37840255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel SB, Van Lankveld JJ, Oldenburg HS, Hahn DE, Kieffer JM, Gerritsma MA, et al. Internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy realizes long-term improvement in the sexual functioning and body image of breast cancer survivors. J Sex Marital Ther. 2018;44(5):485&#x2013;96. 10.1080/0092623X.2017.1408047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esplen MJ, Wong J, Warner E, Toner B. Restoring body image after cancer (ReBIC): results of a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36(8):749&#x2013;56. 10.1200/JCO.2017.74.8244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29356610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morone G, Iosa M, Fusco A, Scappaticci A, Alcuri MR, Saraceni VM, et al. Effects of a multidisciplinary educational rehabilitative intervention in breast cancer survivors: the role of body image on quality of life outcomes. ScientificWorldJournal. 2014;2014:451935. 10.1155/2014/451935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4227364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25405222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Tian Y, Li J, Zhao X. Effect of targeted nursing applied to SLE patients. Exp Ther Med. 2016;11(6):2209&#x2013;12. 10.3892/etm.2016.3173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4887837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27284302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown TA, Chorpita BF, Korotitsch W, Barlow DH. Psychometric properties of the depression anxiety stress scales (DASS) in clinical samples. Behav Res Ther. 1997;35(1):79&#x2013;89. 10.1016/s0005-7967(96)00068-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9009048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asghari A, Saed F, Dibajnia P. Psychometric properties of the depression anxiety stress Scales-21 (DASS-21) in a non-clinical Iranian sample. Int J Psychol. 2008;2(2):82&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raes F, Pommier E, Neff KD, Van Gucht D. Construction and factorial validation of a short form of the self-compassion scale. Clin Psychol Psychother. 2011;18(3):250&#x2013;55. 10.1002/cpp.702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21584907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazi M, Rajabi G, Maghami E, Jelodari A. Confirmatory factor analysis of the Persian version of the self-compassion rating scale-revised. Psychol Models Methods. 2015;6(19):31&#x2013;46. (In Persian).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash TF, Fleming EC. The impact of body image experiences: development of the body image quality of life inventory. Int J Eat Disord. 2002;31(4):455&#x2013;60. 10.1002/eat.10033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11948650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash TF, Jakatdar TA, Williams EF. The body image quality of life inventory: further validation with college men and women. Body Image. 2004;1(3):279&#x2013;87. 10.1016/S1740-1445(03)00023-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18089159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seekis V, Bradley GL, Duffy A. The effectiveness of self-compassion and self-esteem writing tasks in reducing body image concerns. Body Image. 2017;23:206&#x2013;13. 10.1016/j.bodyim.2017.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29198366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati Nezhad L, Sattari Mahmudi P, Shayegh E, Eftekhari A, Karimzadeh Viyarsagh S. Investigating the relationship between lack of self-compassion and social support: the mediating role of disease awareness in women with autoimmune diseases. Razavi Int J Med. 2025;13(1):197&#x2013;207. 10.30483/rijm.2025.254516.1319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Zhang W, Liu C, Qiang W, Lu Q. Association of self-compassion and body image disturbance among young breast cancer patients: mediating effect of body surveillance and body shame. Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs. 2023;10(4):100199. 10.1016/j.apjon.2023.100199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10009058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36923469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes M, Brown SL, Campbell S, Dandy S, Cherry MG. Self-compassion and anxiety and depression in chronic physical illness populations: a systematic review. Mindfulness. 2021;12:1597&#x2013;610. 10.1007/s12671-021-01602-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Gouveia J, Duarte C, Matos M, Fr&#xe1;guas S. The protective role of self&#x2010;compassion in relation to psychopathology symptoms and quality of life in chronic and in cancer patients. Clin Psychol Psychother. 2014;21(4):311&#x2013;23. 10.1002/cpp.1838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23526623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han A, Kim TH. Effects of self-compassion interventions on reducing depressive symptoms, anxiety, and stress: a meta-analysis. Mindfulness. 2023;1&#x2013;29. 10.1007/s12671-023-02148-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10239723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37362192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leary MR, Tate EB, Adams CE, Batts Allen A, Hancock J. Self-compassion and reactions to unpleasant self-relevant events: the implications of treating oneself kindly. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2007;92(5):887. 10.1037/0022-3514.92.5.887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17484611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neff K. Self-Compassion: an alternative conceptualization of a healthyattitudetoward oneself. Self Identity. 2003;2(2):85&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przezdziecki A, Sherman KA, Baillie A, Taylor A, Foley E, Stalgis-Bilinski K. My changed body: breast cancer, body image, distress and self&#x2010;compassion. Psycho&#x2010;oncology. 2013;22(8):1872&#x2013;79. 10.1002/pon.3230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23203842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przezdziecki A, Alcorso J, Sherman KA. My changed body: background, development and acceptability of a self-compassion based writing activity for female survivors of breast cancer. Patient Educ Couns. 2016;99(5):870&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.pec.2015.12.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26754617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todorov N, Sherman KA, Kilby CJ, Australia BCN. Self-compassion and hope in the context of body image disturbance and distress in breast cancer survivors. Psycho&#x2010;oncology. 2019;28(10):2025&#x2013;32. 10.1002/pon.5187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31369188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Yao J, Wang J, Wu L, Gao Y, Xie J, et al. The predictive role of self-compassion in cancer patients&#x2019; symptoms of depression, anxiety, and fatigue: a longitudinal study. Psychooncology. 2019;28(9):1918&#x2013;25. 10.1002/pon.5174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia ACM, Junior JBC, Sarto KK, da Silva Marcelo CA, das, Chagas Paiva EM, Nogueira DA, et al. Quality of life, self-compassion and mindfulness in cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy: a cross-sectional study. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2021:51:101924. 10.1016/j.ejon.2021.101924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33610930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei L, Xie J, Wu L, Yao J, Zhu L, Liu A. Profiles of self-compassion and psychological outcomes in cancer patients. Psychooncology. 2023;32(1):25&#x2013;33. 10.1002/pon.5931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreisoerner A, Junker NM, Van Dick R. The relationship among the components of self-compassion: a pilot study using a compassionate writing intervention to enhance self-kindness, common humanity, and mindfulness. J Happiness Stud. 2021;22:21&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi R, Sajjadian I, Jaffari F. The effectiveness of compassion-focused therapy on anxiety, depression and suicidal thoughts in women with vitiligo. Dermatology Cosmet. 2019;10(1):18&#x2013;29. (In Persian).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muftin Z, Gilbert P, Thompson AR. A randomized controlled feasibility trial of online compassion-focused self&#x2010;help for psoriasis. Br J Dermatol. 2022;186(6):955&#x2013;62. 10.1111/bjd.21020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35041766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei AM, Tayyebeh S, Ahmad G, Elham A, MohammadJafar Bahre D. Effectiveness of treatment based on acceptance and commitment, compassion-based therapy and combination therapy on depression, anxiety quality of life in patients with lupus. J Health Psychol. 2020;9(33):127&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alok R, Das SK, Agarwal GG, Salwahan L, Srivastava R. Relationship of severity of depression, anxiety and stress with severity of fibromyalgia. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2011;29(6 Suppl 69):S70&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22243551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>