<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40963258</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1360-0443</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Addiction (Abingdon, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Addiction</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intersectionality in cigarette smoking cessation: A latent class analysis to predict 12-month cessation in a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/add.70185</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Currently, smoking cessation intervention research on marginalized populations focuses on a single attribute (e.g. race). However, these attributes intersect and research on this intersectionality has been rare. This study applied latent class analysis (LCA) to examine how multiple theory-driven baseline factors interact and predict 12-month 30-day point prevalence abstinence from cigarette smoking in 2415 adult participants in a digital smoking cessation intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Theory-based analysis of a randomized trial with 12-month smoking cessation follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">United States (US).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 2415 adults who smoke that were recruited from all 50&#x2009;US states and enrolled in the trial between May 2017 and September 2018.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION AND COMPARATOR" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In the parent RCT, participants were randomized to receive iCanQuit, an Acceptance and Commitment Therapy-based smartphone smoking cessation app (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1214) or QuitGuide, a US Clinical Practice Guidelines-based smoking cessation app (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1201) for 12&#x2009;months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MEASUREMENTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Guided by Sheffer et al.,six theory-based factors were examined, including social identities: gender, race and ethnicity, marital status, sexual and gender minority (SGM) identity and socio-economic status (SES; education, income, employment); and lived experiences: positive screen for experiencing depression symptoms. Social identity and lived experiences data were collected via baseline questionnaires. The primary smoking cessation outcome was self-reported complete-case 30-day point prevalence abstinence at 12&#x2009;months. SAS PROC LCA was used to identify classes based on the six selected factors and to predict 12-month smoking cessation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A 4-class model showed the best goodness-of-fit statistics and interpretability. Participants in class 1 (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;352, 14.6%) were more likely to be women, individuals of Black race and those with single marital status. Participants in class 2 (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;322, 13.3%) were more likely to be men, SGM individuals and socioeconomically advantaged, as indicated by higher education, higher income or employment. Participants in class 3 (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;368, 15.2%) were socioeconomically disadvantaged and screened positive for experiencing depression symptoms at baseline (CES-D <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"> <mml:semantics><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x2265;</mml:mo></mml:mrow> <mml:annotation>$$ \ge $$</mml:annotation></mml:semantics> </mml:math> 16). Finally, participants in class 4 (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1373, 56.9%) were more likely to be women, individuals of White race and married. Class 2 had the highest smoking cessation rate (32.8%) at 12&#x2009;months, followed by class 1 (27.3%), class 4 (24.2%) and class 3 (15.4%). Compared with class 2, class 3 had 63% lower odds of quitting smoking (odds ratio&#x2009;=&#xa0;0.37; 95% confidence interval = 0.20-0.71, P&#xa0;=&#x2009;0.016).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">People with both socioeconomic disadvantage and symptoms of depression appear to have a harder time quitting smoking than other people who try to quit.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Society for the Study of Addiction.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santiago-Torres</LastName><ForeName>Margarita</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6051-3172</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health Sciences, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mull</LastName><ForeName>Kristin E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health Sciences, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Dingjing</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexander</LastName><ForeName>Adam C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>TSET Health Promotion Research Center, Stephenson Cancer Center, University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center, Oklahoma City, OK, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nollen</LastName><ForeName>Nicole L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0943-0061</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Prevention and Control Program, University of Kansas Cancer Center, Kansas City, KS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health, University of Kansas School of Medicine, Kansas City, KS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sullivan</LastName><ForeName>Brianna M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health Sciences, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zvolensky</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Houston, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HEALTH Institute, University of Houston, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bricker</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Public Health Sciences, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01CA192849</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Addiction</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304118</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0965-2140</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression disorder symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intersectionality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">latent class analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lived experiences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">marginalized populations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">race/ethnicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sexual and gender identities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smoking cessation inequities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social identities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">socio&#x2010;economic status</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40963258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.70185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Smoking cessation. A report of the surgeon general Atlanta, GA: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall JM, Carlson K. Marginalization: a revisitation with integration of scholarship on globalization, intersectionality, privilege, microaggressions, and implicit biases. ANS Adv Nurs Sci. 2016;39(3):200&#x2013;215. https://doi.org/10.1097/ANS.0000000000000123</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi K, Jones JT, Ruybal AL, McNeel TS, Duarte DA, Webb Hooper M. Trends in education&#x2010;related smoking disparities among U.S. black or African American and white adults: intersections of race, sex, and region. Nicotine Tob Res. 2023;25(4):718&#x2013;728. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntac238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho JY, Elo IT. The contribution of smoking to black&#x2010;white differences in U.S. mortality. Demography. 2013;50(2):545&#x2013;568. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13524-012-0159-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kcomt L, Evans&#x2010;Polce RJ, Engstrom CW, West BT, McCabe SE. Discrimination, sexual orientation discrimination, and severity of tobacco use disorder in the United States: results from the national epidemiologic survey on alcohol and related conditions&#x2010;III. Nicotine Tob Res. 2021;23(6):920&#x2013;930. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntaa197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrazola RA, Griffin T, Lunsford NB, Kittner D, Bammeke P, Courtney&#x2010;Long EA, et al. US cigarette smoking disparities by race and ethnicity &#x2010; keep going and going! Prev Chronic Dis. 2023;20:E45. https://doi.org/10.5888/pcd20.220375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekas HM, Lopez&#x2010;Cevallos D, Routen A. Exploring the intersections of structural inequities and health disparities: the challenge and opportunity of recognizing racism as a public health crisis. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):1423. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-023-16359-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson B, Emberson J, Lacey B, Lewington S, Peto R, Jemal A, et al. Association between smoking, smoking cessation, and mortality by race, ethnicity, and sex among US adults. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5(10):e2231480. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.31480</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Kenfield S, Song Y, Rosner B, Qiu W, Sesso HD, et al. Cigarette smoking cessation and total and cause&#x2010;specific mortality: a 22&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up study among US male physicians. Arch Intern Med. 2011;171(21):1956&#x2013;1959. https://doi.org/10.1001/archinternmed.2011.539</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson B, Emberson J, Lacey B, Lewington S, Peto R, Islami F. Association of Smoking Initiation and Cessation across the life course and cancer mortality: prospective study of 410 000 US adults. JAMA Oncol. 2021;7(12):1901&#x2013;1903. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.4949</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowleg L, Malekzadeh AN, AuBuchon KE, Ghabrial MA, Bauer GR. Rare exemplars and missed opportunities: intersectionality within current sexual and gender diversity research and scholarship in psychology. Curr Opin Psychol. 2023;49:101511. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2022.101511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crenshaw K. Demarginalizing the intersection of race and sex: a black feminist critique of antidiscrimination doctrine, feminist theory and antiracist politics. Univ Chic Leg Forum. 1989;139&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankivsky O. Women's health, men's health, and gender and health: implications of intersectionality. Soc Sci Med. 2012;74(11):1712&#x2013;1720. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.11.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budge SL, Thai JL, Tebbe EA, Howard KAS. The intersection of race, sexual orientation, socioeconomic status, trans identity, and mental health outcomes. Counsel Psychol. 2016;44(7):1025&#x2013;1049. https://doi.org/10.1177/0011000015609046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agenor M. Future directions for incorporating intersectionality into quantitative population Health Research. Am J Public Health. 2020;110(6):803&#x2013;806. https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2020.305610</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter LN, Lam CY, Cinciripini PM, Wetter DW. Intersectionality and smoking cessation: exploring various approaches for understanding health inequities. Nicotine Tob Res. 2021;23(1):115&#x2013;123. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntaa052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyatt TR, Johnson M, Zaidi Z. Intersectionality: a means for centering power and oppression in research. Adv Health Sci Educ Theory Pract. 2022;27(3):863&#x2013;875. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10459-022-10110-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young R, Ayiasi RM, Shung&#x2010;King M, Morgan R. Health systems of oppression: applying intersectionality in health systems to expose hidden inequities. Health Policy Plan. 2021;36(5):819. https://doi.org/10.1093/heapol/czaa179</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffer CE, Williams JM, Erwin DO, Smith PH, Carl E, Ostroff JS. Tobacco&#x2010;related disparities viewed through the lens of intersectionality. Nicotine Tob Res. 2022;24(2):285&#x2013;288. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntab193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan ASL, Hinds JT, Smith PH, Antin T, Lee JP, Ostroff JS, et al. Incorporating intersectionality as a framework for equity&#x2010;minded tobacco control research: a call for collective action toward a paradigm shift. Nicotine Tob Res. 2023;25(1):73&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntac110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi WS, Beebe LA, Nazir N, Kaur B, Hopkins M, Talawyma M, et al. All nations breath of life: a randomized trial of smoking cessation for American Indians. Am J Prev Med. 2016;51(5):743&#x2013;751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb Hooper M, Antoni MH, Okuyemi K, Dietz NA, Resnicow K. Randomized controlled trial of group&#x2010;based culturally specific cognitive behavioral therapy among African American smokers. Nicotine Tob Res. 2017;19(3):333&#x2013;341. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntw181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons VN, Sutton SK, Medina&#x2010;Ramirez P, Martinez U, Brandon KO, Byrne MM, et al. Self&#x2010;help smoking cessation intervention for Spanish&#x2010;speaking Hispanics/Latinxs in the United States: a randomized controlled trial. Cancer. 2022;128(5):984&#x2013;994. https://doi.org/10.1002/cncr.33986</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel EA, Thrul J, Humfleet GL, Delucchi KL, Ramo DE. Smoking cessation intervention trial outcomes for sexual and gender minority young adults. Health Psychol. 2019;38(1):12&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1037/hea0000698</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purnell JQ, Peppone LJ, Alcaraz K, McQueen A, Guido JJ, Carroll JK, et al. Perceived discrimination, psychological distress, and current smoking status: results from the behavioral risk factor surveillance system reactions to race module, 2004&#x2010;2008. Am J Public Health. 2012;102(5):844&#x2013;851. https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2012.300694</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendzor DE, Businelle MS, Reitzel LR, Rios DM, Scheuermann TS, Pulvers K, et al. Everyday discrimination is associated with nicotine dependence among African American, Latino, and white smokers. Nicotine Tob Res. 2014;16(6):633&#x2013;640. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntt198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila JC, Sokolovsky AW, Nollen NL, Lee J, Schmid CH, Ahluwalia JS. The effect of race/ethnicity and adversities on smoking cessation among U.S. adult smokers. Addict Behav. 2022;131:107332. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addbeh.2022.107332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen RA, Cha AE, Terlizzi EP, Martinez ME. Demographic variation in health insurance coverage: United States, 2019. Natl Health Stat Rep. 2021;(159):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter&#x2010;Pokras OD, Feldman RH, Kanamori M, Rivera I, Chen L, Baezconde&#x2010;Garbanati L, et al. Barriers and facilitators to smoking cessation among Latino adults. J Natl Med Assoc. 2011;103(5):423&#x2013;431. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0027-9684(15)30339-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelius ME, Loretan CG, Jamal A, Davis Lynn BC, Mayer M, Alcantara IC, et al. Tobacco product use among adults &#x2010; United States, 2021. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2023;72(18):475&#x2013;483. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm7218a1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuma KK, Pierce JP, Fagan P, Nguyen&#x2010;Grozavu FT, Leas EC, Messer K, et al. Racial/ethnic disparities across indicators of cigarette smoking in the era of increased tobacco control, 1992&#x2010;2019. Nicotine Tob Res. 2021;23(6):909&#x2013;919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parent MC, DeBlaere C, Moradi B. Approaches to research on intersectionality: perspectives on gender, LGBT, and racial/ethnic identities. Sex Roles. 2013;68(11&#x2010;12):639&#x2013;645. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11199-013-0283-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King JL, Shan L, Azagba S. Trends in sexual orientation disparities in cigarette smoking: intersections between race/ethnicity and sex. Prev Med. 2021;153:106760. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2021.106760</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Berg CJ, Weber AA, Vu M, Nguyen J, Haardorfer R, et al. Tobacco use at the intersection of sex and sexual identity in the U.S., 2007&#x2010;2020: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Prev Med. 2021;60(3):415&#x2013;424. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amepre.2020.09.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tami&#x2010;Maury I, Sharma A, Chen M, Blalock J, Ortiz J, Weaver L, et al. Comparing smoking behavior between female&#x2010;to&#x2010;male and male&#x2010;to&#x2010;female transgender adults. Tob Prev Cessat. 2020;6(January):2. https://doi.org/10.18332/tpc/114513</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PH, Bessette AJ, Weinberger AH, Sheffer CE, McKee SA. Sex/gender differences in smoking cessation: a review. Prev Med. 2016;92:135&#x2013;140. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2016.07.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verplaetse TL, Smith PH, Pittman BP, Mazure CM, McKee SA. Associations of gender, smoking, and stress with transitions in major depression diagnoses. Yale J Biol Med. 2016;89(2):123&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence D, Mitrou F, Zubrick SR. Non&#x2010;specific psychological distress, smoking status and smoking cessation: United States National Health Interview Survey 2005. BMC Public Health. 2011;11(1):256. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-11-256</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasser K, Boyd JW, Woolhandler S, Himmelstein DU, McCormick D, Bor DH. Smoking and mental illness: a population&#x2010;based prevalence study. JAMA. 2000;284(20):2606&#x2013;2610. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.284.20.2606</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberger AH, Kashan RS, Shpigel DM, Esan H, Taha F, Lee CJ, et al. Depression and cigarette smoking behavior: a critical review of population&#x2010;based studies. Am J Drug Alcohol Abuse. 2017;43(4):416&#x2013;431. https://doi.org/10.3109/00952990.2016.1171327</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiscock R, Dobbie F, Bauld L. Smoking cessation and socioeconomic status: an update of existing evidence from a National Evaluation of English stop smoking services. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:274056. https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/274056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention. Vital signs: current cigarette smoking among adults aged &#x2265;18 years with mental illness &#x2014; United States, 2009&#x2013;2011. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2013;62(5):81&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberger AH, Bandiera FC, Leventhal AM, Dierker LC, Gbedemah M, Tidey JW, et al. Socioeconomic disparities in smoking among U.S. adults with depression, 2005&#x2010;2014. Am J Prev Med. 2018;54(6):765&#x2013;775. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amepre.2018.02.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendzor DE, Businelle MS, Costello TJ, Castro Y, Reitzel LR, Cofta&#x2010;Woerpel LM, et al. Financial strain and smoking cessation among racially/ethnically diverse smokers. Am J Public Health. 2010;100(4):702&#x2013;706. https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2009.172676</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim&#x2010;Mozeleski JE, Seligman HK, Yen IH, Shaw SJ, Buchanan DR, Tsoh JY. Changes in food insecurity and smoking status over time: analysis of the 2003 and 2015 panel study of income dynamics. Am J Health Promot. 2019;33(5):698&#x2013;707. https://doi.org/10.1177/0890117118814397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widome R, Joseph AM, Hammett P, Van Ryn M, Nelson DB, Nyman JA, et al. Associations between smoking behaviors and financial stress among low&#x2010;income smokers. Prev Med Rep. 2015;2:911&#x2013;915. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2015.10.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bricker JB, Watson NL, Mull KE, Sullivan BM, Heffner JL. Efficacy of smartphone applications for smoking cessation: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;180(11):1472&#x2013;1480. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.4055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babb S, Malarcher A, Schauer G, Asman K, Jamal A. Quitting smoking among adults&#x2014;United States, 2000&#x2010;2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2017;65(52):1457&#x2013;1464. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm6552a1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd CM, Carter Andrews DJ. Variations in students' perceived reasons for, sources of, and forms of in&#x2010;school discrimination: a latent class analysis. J Sch Psychol. 2016;57:1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsp.2016.05.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer GR, Mahendran M, Walwyn C, Shokoohi M. Latent variable and clustering methods in intersectionality research: systematic review of methods applications. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2022;57(2):221&#x2013;237. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127-021-02195-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan A, Thomas M, Vittinghoff E, Bowleg L, Mangurian C, Wesson P. An investigation of quantitative methods for assessing intersectionality in health research: a systematic review. SSM Popul Health. 2021;16:100977. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssmph.2021.100977</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radloff LS. The CES&#x2010;D scale: a self&#x2010;report depression scale for research in the general population. Appl Psychol Measur. 1977;1(3):385&#x2013;401. https://doi.org/10.1177/014662167700100306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindberg MH, Chen G, Olsen JA, Abelsen B. Combining education and income into a socioeconomic position score for use in studies of health inequalities. BMC Public Health. 2022;22(1):969. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-022-13366-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazard B, Chui Z, Harber&#x2010;Aschan L, MacCrimmon S, Bakolis I, Rimes K, et al. Barrier or stressor? The role of discrimination experiences in health service use. BMC Public Health. 2018;18(1):1354. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-018-6267-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa R, Dahl C, Aung WP, Bjertness E. Urban&#x2010;rural differences in overweight and obesity among 25&#x2010;64 years old Myanmar residents: a cross&#x2010;sectional, nationwide survey. BMJ Open. 2021;11(3):e042561. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2020-042561</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poverty Guidelines &#x2010; Health and Human Services Poverty Guidelines for 2017 [Internet]. 2017. https://aspe.hhs.gov/topics/poverty-economic-mobility/poverty-guidelines/prior-hhs-poverty-guidelines-federal-register-references/2017-poverty-guidelines</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glover L, Lilly AG, Justice AE, Howard AG, Staley BS, Wang Y, et al. DNA methylation near MAD1L1, KDM2B, and SOCS3 mediates the effect of socioeconomic status on elevated body mass index in African American adults. Hum Mol Genet. 2024;33(20):1748&#x2013;1757. https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddae112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West R, Hajek P, Stead L, Stapleton J. Outcome criteria in smoking cessation trials: proposal for a common standard. Addiction. 2005;100(3):299&#x2013;303. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1360-0443.2004.00995.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JT, Anic GM, Rostron BL, Tanwar M, Chang CM. Cigarette smoking reduction and health risks: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Nicotine Tob Res. 2021;23(4):635&#x2013;642. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntaa156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanza ST, Dziak JJ, Huang L, Wagner AT, Collins LM. Proc LCA &amp; Proc LTA users' guide (version 1.3.2) Penn State: University Park: The Methodology Center; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enders CK. The impact of nonnormality on full information maximum&#x2010;likelihood estimation for structural equation models with missing data. Psychol Methods. 2001;6(4):352&#x2013;370. https://doi.org/10.1037/1082-989X.6.4.352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanza ST, Collins LM, Lemmon DR, Schafer JL. PROC LCA: a SAS procedure for latent class analysis. Struct Equ Modeling. 2007;14(4):671&#x2013;694. https://doi.org/10.1080/10705510701575602</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akaike H. A new look at the statistical model identification. IEEE Trans Automat Contr. 1974;19(7):716&#x2013;723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozdogan H. Model&#x2010;selection and Akaike's information criterion (AIC): the general theory and its analytical extensions. Psychometrika. 1987;52(3):345&#x2013;370. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02294361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TH, Dayton CM. Model selection information criteria for non&#x2010;nested latent class models. J Educ Behav Stat. 1997;22(3):249&#x2013;264. https://doi.org/10.3102/10769986022003249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramaswamy V, Desarbo WS, Reibstein DJ, Robinson WT. An empirical pooling approach for estimating marketing mix elasticities with PIMS data. Mar Sci. 1993;12(1):103&#x2013;124. https://doi.org/10.1287/mksc.12.1.103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz G. Estimating the dimension of a model. Ann Stat. 1978;6(2):461&#x2013;464. https://doi.org/10.1214/aos/1176344136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sclove LS. Application of model&#x2010;selection criteria to some problems in multivariate analysis. Psychometrika. 1987;52:333&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. ggplot2: elegant graphics for data analysis New York, NY: Springer&#x2010;Verlag; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. 2023. R: a language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. Accessed April 16, 2024. https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziak JJ, Bray B, Wagner A. Distal BCH SAS macro users' guide (version 1.1) University Park (PA): The Methodology Center, Pennsylvania State University; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolck A, Croon M, Hagenaars J. Estimating latent structure models with categorical variables: one&#x2010;step versus three&#x2010;step estimators. Political Anal. 2004;12(1):3&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1093/pan/mph001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm S. A simple sequentially rejective multiple test procedure. Scand J Stat. 1979;6:65&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drope J, Liber AC, Cahn Z, Stoklosa M, Kennedy R, Douglas CE, et al. Who's still smoking? Disparities in adult cigarette smoking prevalence in the United States. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018;68(2):106&#x2013;115. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21444</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leventhal AM, Bello MS, Galstyan E, Higgins ST, Barrington&#x2010;Trimis JL. Association of Cumulative Socioeconomic and Health&#x2010;Related Disadvantage with Disparities in smoking prevalence in the United States, 2008 to 2017. JAMA Intern Med. 2019;179(6):777&#x2013;785. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamainternmed.2019.0192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zvolensky MJ, Bakhshaie J, Garey L, Kauffman BY, Heggeness LF, Schmidt NB. Cumulative vulnerabilities and smoking abstinence: a test from a randomized clinical trial. Behav Res Ther. 2023;162:104272. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brat.2023.104272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeCarlo Santiago C, Wadsworth ME, Stump J. Socioeconomic status, neighborhood disadvantage, and poverty&#x2010;related stress: prospective effects on psychological syndromes among diverse low&#x2010;income families. J Econ Psyshol. 2011;32(2):218&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joep.2009.10.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson R, Westley T, Gariepy G, Austin N, Nandi A. Neighborhood socioeconomic conditions and depression: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2015;50(11):1641&#x2013;1656. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127-015-1092-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonevski B, Randell M, Paul C, Chapman K, Twyman L, Bryant J, et al. Reaching the hard&#x2010;to&#x2010;reach: a systematic review of strategies for improving health and medical research with socially disadvantaged groups. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14(1):42. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2288-14-42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger JM, Hershman DL, Albain KS, Moinpour CM, Petersen JA, Burg K, et al. Patient income level and cancer clinical trial participation. J Clin Oncol. 2013;31(5):536&#x2013;542. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2012.45.4553</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wijk EC, Landais LL, Harting J. Understanding the multitude of barriers that prevent smokers in lower socioeconomic groups from accessing smoking cessation support: a literature review. Prev Med. 2019;123:143&#x2013;151. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2019.03.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheldon CW, Kaufman AR, Kasza KA, Moser RP. Tobacco use among adults by sexual orientation: findings from the population assessment of tobacco and health study. LGBT Health. 2018;5(1):33&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1089/lgbt.2017.0175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amroussia N, Gustafsson PE, Pearson JL. Do inequalities add up? Intersectional inequalities in smoking by sexual orientation and education among U.S. adults. Prev Med Rep. 2020;17:101032. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2019.101032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PH, Kasza KA, Hyland A, Fong GT, Borland R, Brady K, et al. Gender differences in medication use and cigarette smoking cessation: results from the international tobacco control four country survey. Nicotine Tob Res. 2015;17(4):463&#x2013;472. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntu212</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PH, Weinberger AH, Zhang J, Emme E, Mazure CM, McKee SA. Sex differences in smoking cessation pharmacotherapy comparative efficacy: a network meta&#x2010;analysis. Nicotine Tob Res. 2017;19(3):273&#x2013;281. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntw144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsey MW Jr, Chen&#x2010;Sankey JC, Reese&#x2010;Smith J, Choi K. Association between marital status and cigarette smoking: variation by race and ethnicity. Prev Med. 2019;119:48&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2018.12.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb Hooper M, Kolar SK. Distress, race/ethnicity and smoking cessation in treatment&#x2010;seekers: implications for disparity elimination. Addiction. 2015;110(9):1495&#x2013;1504. https://doi.org/10.1111/add.12990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broms U, Silventoinen K, Lahelma E, Koskenvuo M, Kaprio J. Smoking cessation by socioeconomic status and marital status: the contribution of smoking behavior and family background. Nicotine Tob Res. 2004;6(3):447&#x2013;455. https://doi.org/10.1080/14622200410001696637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlow AF, Liu F, Young LE, Coreas SI, Rahman T, Unger JB, et al. Sexual and gender identity disparities in nicotine and tobacco use susceptibility and prevalence: disaggregating emerging identities among adolescents from California, USA. Nicotine Tob Res. 2024;26(2):203&#x2013;211. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntad131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amroussia N, Pearson JL, Gustafsson PE. What drives us apart? Decomposing intersectional inequalities in cigarette smoking by education and sexual orientation among U.S. adults. Int J Equity Health. 2019;18(1):109. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12939-019-1015-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson CD, Stupplebeen DA, Wilkinson ML, Zhang X, Williams RJ. Intersectional disparities in youth tobacco use by sexual and/or gender minority status and race and/or ethnicity. Nicotine Tob Res. 2023;25(5):898&#x2013;907. https://doi.org/10.1093/ntr/ntac264</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglalang DD, Avila JC, Ahluwalia JS, Murphy CM, Alexander AC, Nollen NL. The role of financial strain and educational attainment on smoking abstinence of African Americans and whites who smoke. Ethn Dis. 2022;32(3):223&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.18865/ed.32.3.223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nollen NL, Mayo MS, Sanderson Cox L, Benowitz NL, Tyndale RF, Ellerbeck EF, et al. Factors that explain differences in abstinence between black and white smokers: a prospective intervention study. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2019;111(10):1078&#x2013;1087. https://doi.org/10.1093/jnci/djz001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbec A, Brown J, Shahab L, West R. Lessons learned from unsuccessful use of personal carbon monoxide monitors to remotely assess abstinence in a pragmatic trial of a smartphone stop smoking app &#x2010; a secondary analysis. Addict Behav Rep. 2019;9:100122. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.abrep.2018.07.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrul J, Meacham MC, Ramo DE. A novel and remote biochemical verification method of smoking abstinence: predictors of participant compliance. Tob Prev Cessation. 2018;4(20):1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziak JJ, Bray BC, Zhang J, Zhang M, Lanza ST. Comparing the performance of improved classify&#x2010;analyze approaches for distal outcomes in latent profile analysis. Methodology (Gott). 2016;12(4):107&#x2013;116. https://doi.org/10.1027/1614-2241/a000114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty EA, Cartmell K, Griffin S, Heo M, Chen L, Britt JL, et al. Discrimination and adverse perinatal health outcomes: a latent class analysis. Prev Chronic Dis. 2023;20:E96. https://doi.org/10.5888/pcd20.230094</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakk Z, Vermunt JK. Robustness of stepwise latent class modeling with continuous distal outcomes. Struct Equ Modeling. 2016;23(1):20&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1080/10705511.2014.955104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schisterman EF, Cole SR, Platt RW. Overadjustment bias and unnecessary adjustment in epidemiologic studies. Epidemiology. 2009;20(4):488&#x2013;495. https://doi.org/10.1097/EDE.0b013e3181a819a1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohrer JM. Thinking clearly about correlations and causation: graphical causal models for observational data. Adv Methods Pract Psychol Sci. 2018;1(1):27&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1177/2515245917745629</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>