<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40974957</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2772-963X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>10 Pt 2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JACC. Advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JACC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Early Intervention vs Conservative Management in Severe Asymptomatic Aortic Stenosis: A Critical Review of Randomized Evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102178</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102178</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacadv.2025.102178</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2772-963X(25)00603-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aortic stenosis (AS) is a progressive disease that may remain asymptomatic despite underlying myocardial damage. Management of asymptomatic severe AS remains controversial, especially in the current era of safer surgical and transcatheter valve replacement. This critical review examines 4 randomized controlled trials-AVATAR (Aortic Valve Replacement Vs Conservative Treatment in Asymptomatic Severe Aortic Stenosis), RECOVERY (Randomized Comparison of Early Surgery vs Conventional Treatment in Very Severe Aortic Stenosis), EARLY TAVR (Evaluation of TAVR Compared to Surveillance for Patients with Asymptomatic Severe Aortic Stenosis), and EVOLVED (Early Valve Replacement Guided by Biomarkers of Left Ventricular Decompensation in Asymptomatic Patients with Severe Aortic Stenosis)-comparing early aortic valve replacement with conservative management. While early intervention reduces composite endpoints involving heart failure hospitalization, individual trials have not demonstrated consistent mortality or stroke benefits. Importantly, sudden cardiac death was rare across all trials, and close surveillance appeared to be a key determinant of outcomes in the conservative arms. Differences in surveillance intensity, trial populations, and valve types limit pooled interpretations. Current evidence supports a tailored approach: conservative management is reasonable when reliable follow-up can be ensured, while early aortic valve replacement may benefit selected patients. Ongoing trials will help clarify long-term outcomes, optimal timing, and risk stratification strategies in asymptomatic AS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dayan</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro Cardiovascular Universitario, Universidad de la Republica, Montevideo, Uruguay.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marin-Cuartas</LastName><ForeName>Mateo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Department of Cardiac Surgery, Leipzig Heart Center, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Caterina</LastName><ForeName>Raffaele</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chair of Cardiology, University of Pisa and Cardiology Division 1, Pisa University Hospital, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Waha</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Department of Cardiac Surgery, Leipzig Heart Center, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Mieghem</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Interventional Cardiology, Thoraxcenter, Cardiovascular Institute, Erasmus University Medical Center, Rotterdam, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borger</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Department of Cardiac Surgery, Leipzig Heart Center, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonow</LastName><ForeName>Robert O</ForeName><Initials>RO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatt</LastName><ForeName>Deepak L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mount Sinai Fuster Heart Hospital, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, USA. Electronic address: DLBhattMD@post.Harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JACC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918419284106676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2772-963X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SAVR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAVI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAVR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">asymptomatic severe aortic stenosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical aortic valve replacement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcatheter aortic valve implantation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcatheter aortic valve replacement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding support and author disclosures Dr De Caterina has received fees, honoraria, and research funding from Sanofi-Aventis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bayer, BMS/Pfizer, Daiichi Sankyo, Novartis, Merck, Portola, Roche, AstraZeneca, Menarini, Guidotti, Milestone, Amarin, Noventure, and Amgen, all unrelated to this topic. Dr Van Mieghem has received institutional research grants from Abbott, Boston Scientific, Edwards Lifesciences, Medtronic, Meril, Pie Medical, PulseCath BV, and Teleflex; and has received consultancy fees from Abbott, Abiomed, Alleviant Medical Inc, AncorValve, Anteris, Approxima Srl, Bolt Medical, Boston Scientific, Daiichi Sankyo, LUMA Vision, Materialise, Medtronic, Pie Medical, Polares, PulseCath BV, and Siemens. Dr Borger declares that his hospital received speakers&#x2019; honoraria and/or consulting fees on his behalf from Edwards Lifesciences, Medtronic, Abbott, and Artivion. Dr Bhatt has served on advisory boards for Angiowave, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, CellProthera, Cereno Scientific, E-Star Biotech, High Enroll, Janssen, Level Ex, McKinsey, Medscape Cardiology, Merck, NirvaMed, Novo Nordisk, Stasys; Tourmaline Bio; on the board of directors for American Heart Association New York City, Angiowave (stock options), Bristol Myers Squibb (stock), DRS.LINQ (stock options), and High Enroll (stock); has served as a consultant for Broadview Ventures, Corcept Therapeutics, GlaxoSmithKline, Hims, SFJ, Summa Therapeutics, and Youngene; has served on data monitoring committees for Acesion Pharma, Assistance Publique-H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris, Baim Institute for Clinical Research (formerly Harvard Clinical Research Institute, for the PORTICO trial, funded by St. Jude Medical, now Abbott), Boston Scientific (Chair, PEITHO trial), Cleveland Clinic, Contego Medical (Chair, PERFORMANCE 2), Duke Clinical Research Institute, Mayo Clinic, Mount Sinai School of Medicine (for the ENVISAGE trial, funded by Daiichi Sankyo; for the ABILITY-DM trial, funded by Concept Medical; for ALLAY-HF, funded by Alleviant Medical), Novartis, Population Health Research Institute; Rutgers University (for the NIH-funded MINT Trial); has received honoraria from American College of Cardiology (Senior Associate Editor, Clinical Trials and News, ACC.org; Chair, ACC Accreditation Oversight Committee), Arnold and Porter law firm (work related to Sanofi/Bristol Myers Squibb clopidogrel litigation), Baim Institute for Clinical Research (formerly Harvard Clinical Research Institute; AEGIS-II executive committee funded by CSL Behring), Belvoir Publications (Editor in Chief, Harvard Heart Letter), Canadian Medical and Surgical Knowledge Translation Research Group (clinical trial steering committees), CSL Behring (AHA lecture), Cowen and Company, Duke Clinical Research Institute (clinical trial steering committees, including for the PRONOUNCE trial, funded by Ferring Pharmaceuticals), HMP Global (Editor in Chief, Journal of Invasive Cardiology), Journal of the American College of Cardiology (Guest Editor; Associate Editor), Level Ex, Medtelligence/ReachMD (CME steering committees), MJH Life Sciences, Oakstone CME (Course Director, Comprehensive Review of Interventional Cardiology), Piper Sandler, Population Health Research Institute (for the COMPASS operations committee, publications committee, steering committee, and USA national co-leader, funded by Bayer), WebMD (CME steering committees), Wiley (steering committee); other: Clinical Cardiology (Deputy Editor); patent: Sotagliflozin (named on a patent for sotagliflozin assigned to Brigham and Women's Hospital who assigned to Lexicon; neither I nor Brigham and Women's Hospital receive any income from this patent); has received research funding from Abbott, Acesion Pharma, Afimmune, Aker Biomarine, Alnylam, Amarin, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Beren, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardax, CellProthera, Cereno Scientific, Chiesi, CinCor, Cleerly, CSL Behring, Faraday Pharmaceuticals, Ferring Pharmaceuticals, Fractyl, Garmin, HLS Therapeutics, Idorsia, Ironwood, Ischemix, Janssen, Javelin, Lexicon, Lilly, Medtronic, Merck, Moderna, MyoKardia, NirvaMed, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Otsuka, Owkin, Pfizer, PhaseBio, PLx Pharma, Recardio, Regeneron, Reid Hoffman Foundation, Roche, Sanofi, Stasys, Synaptic, The Medicines Company, Youngene, and 89Bio; has received royalties from Elsevier (Editor, Braunwald&#x2019;s Heart Disease); and has served as site co-investigator for Cleerly. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40974957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacadv.2025.102178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2772-963X(25)00603-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>