<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40910693</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-8871</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical Internet research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Internet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Insights Into How Digital Health Interventions Shape Outcomes for Emerging Adults Living With Type 1 Diabetes: Qualitative Realist Process Evaluation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70401</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70401</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70401</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/70401</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Emerging adults living with type 1 diabetes (T1D) need targeted support to equip them with the knowledge and motivation required for self-management, particularly as they transition from pediatric to adult care. While multicomponent digital health interventions have shown promise in addressing their multifaceted needs, traditional effectiveness studies provide little, if any, insights into which components work effectively, how they function, and for whom.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to explore the implementation of a multicomponent, text message-based digital intervention (Keeping in Touch; KiT) to provide early insights into which components may shape participants' transition experiences and how. The secondary objective was to explore which subgroups, defined by individual characteristics, may benefit most from the intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Embedded within a broader randomized controlled trial, we conducted a qualitative realist evaluation with intervention-arm participants who had engaged with KiT for a minimum of 3 months. One-on-one semistructured realist interviews were conducted in a teacher-learner cycle to test the initial program theory. The initial program theory included several pathways through which the 5 intervention components (ie, T1D self-management information and suggestions, transition support information, problem-solving support, stress management strategies, and transition reminders) were hypothesized to influence a range of theorized outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 16 interviews were completed with intervention participants. All 5 KiT intervention components were reported to shape participants' transition experiences positively but to varying degrees. T1D self-management information and suggestions presented a universal positive impact across all participants. However, the effectiveness of problem-solving support and stress management strategies varied depending on participants' individual characteristics (eg, duration of diabetes, perceived access to information, and baseline diabetes distress). Rather than acting through parallel independent mechanisms, KiT appeared to support participants' transition experiences via multiple chains of interconnected mechanisms, often beginning with knowledge or reinforcement and contributing to changes in motivation (eg, self-efficacy and diabetes distress). Interview participants described tangible improvement in mechanisms and proximal outcomes (eg, diabetes knowledge and self-efficacy).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A multicomponent, text message-based digital intervention could support emerging adults living with T1D during their transition to adult care by enhancing their knowledge and motivation for self-management. Participant subgroups responded differently to various intervention components, which highlights that one-size-fits-all approaches are likely inadequate. Digital interventions should be developed and studied in a variety of subgroups and contexts to optimize their reach. Interventions for emerging adults living with T1D might benefit from targeting those who are more recently diagnosed with relatively lower baseline levels of diabetes knowledge and self-efficacy or higher levels of diabetes distress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">RR2-10.2196/46115.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Ruoxi Wang, Balpreet Panesar, Mikayla Sonnenberg, Alanna Landry, Anne-Sophie Brazeau, Marley Greenberg, Meranda Nakhla, Ian Zenlea, Elise Mok, Jessica C Kichler, Ellen B Goldbloom, Gillian L Booth, M&#xe9;lanie Henderson, Rayzel Shulman, Laura Desveaux. Originally published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research (https://www.jmir.org), 05.09.2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ruoxi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9695-0582</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Better Health, Trillium Health Partners, Mississauga, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panesar</LastName><ForeName>Balpreet</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5492-3615</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Better Health, Trillium Health Partners, Mississauga, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonnenberg</LastName><ForeName>Mikayla</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8389-0784</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, The Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Health Evaluative Sciences, SickKids Research Institute, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Landry</LastName><ForeName>Alanna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9222-8613</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CDE Oak Valley Health, Markham, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brazeau</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Sophie</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2699-2920</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Nutrition, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greenberg</LastName><ForeName>Marley</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7678-8699</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Action Canada, Canadian Institutes for Health Research (CIHR) Strategy for Patient-Oriented Research Network in Chronic Disease, Toronto General Hospital, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakhla</LastName><ForeName>Meranda</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5833-5303</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>McGill University, Montreal Children's Hospital, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zenlea</LastName><ForeName>Ian</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9284-0872</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Better Health, Trillium Health Partners, Mississauga, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temerty Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy, Management and Evaluation, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mok</LastName><ForeName>Elise</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-3234-2296</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Outcomes Research and Evaluation, Research Institute of the McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kichler</LastName><ForeName>Jessica C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0133-0194</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Windsor, Windsor, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldbloom</LastName><ForeName>Ellen B</ForeName><Initials>EB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6582-2924</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Booth</LastName><ForeName>Gillian L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2769-6522</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temerty Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy, Management and Evaluation, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MAP Centre for Urban Health Solutions, Unity Health Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henderson</LastName><ForeName>M&#xe9;lanie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0102-2389</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre de Recherche CHU Sainte-Justine, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shulman</LastName><ForeName>Rayzel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9943-1529</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, The Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temerty Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy, Management and Evaluation, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Health Evaluative Sciences, Sickkids Research Institute, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Desveaux</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3429-1865</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Better Health, Trillium Health Partners, Mississauga, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy, Management and Evaluation, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Internet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959882</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1438-8871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003922" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060145" MajorTopicYN="Y">Text Messaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012648" MajorTopicYN="N">Self Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073278" MajorTopicYN="N">Self-Management</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000097103" MajorTopicYN="N">Digital Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emerging adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">realist evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transition care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 1 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: IZ received research grants from Diabetes Canada, Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation (JDRF) Canada, and Canadian Institutes for Health Research (CIHR) and received advisory board fees from Abbott Diabetes Care, Dexcom, and Novo Nordisk Inc Canada.
JCK received research grants from Diabetes Canada, JDRF Canada, CIHR, Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council (SSHRC), National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK) of National Institutes of Health (NIH), WE-SPARK Health Institute, and the University of Windsor; JCK was also on the consulting and advisory panel for the Diabetes Link, Provincial Council for Maternal and Child Health: Paediatric Diabetes Network, JDRF, Diabetes Action Canada, and T1D Toolkit. JCK received honoraria for speaking engagement from American Diabetes Association, Children with Diabetes, Connected in Motion, Diabetes Canada, JDRF Canada, Diabetes+Mental Health, Wolastoqey Tribal Council, Diabetes Care Program of Nova Scotia, and the Charles H Best Diabetes Centre.
MH is a recipient of the Canadian Society of Endocrinology and Metabolism Young Investigator Award. She is funded by the senior salary awards from Fonds de recherche du Qu&#xe9;bec Sant&#xe9;. She holds research grants from the CIHR, the Heart and Stroke Foundation of Canada, the Fonds de recherche du Qu&#xe9;bec Sant&#xe9;, and Diab&#xe8;te Qu&#xe9;bec.
ASB is a research scholar from Fonds de recherche du Qu&#xe9;bec-Sant&#xe9; and holds research grants from the CIHR, Diab&#xe8;te Qu&#xe9;bec, Mitacs, and Breakthrough T1D. ASB received speaker honorarium from Dexcom Canada.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40910693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12449673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/70401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v27i1e70401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gregory GA, Robinson TI, Linklater SE, Wang F, Colagiuri S, de Beaufort C, Donaghue KC, International Diabetes Federation Diabetes Atlas Type 1 Diabetes in Adults Special Interest Group. Magliano DJ, Maniam J, Orchard TJ, Rai P, Ogle GD. Global incidence, prevalence, and mortality of type 1 diabetes in 2021 with projection to 2040: a modelling study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022 Oct;10(10):741&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00218-2.S2213-8587(22)00218-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(22)00218-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36113507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetes Control and Complications Trial Research Group Effect of intensive diabetes treatment on the development and progression of long-term complications in adolescents with insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus: Diabetes Control and Complications Trial. Diabetes Control and Complications Trial Research Group. J Pediatr. 1994 Aug;125(2):177&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1016/s0022-3476(94)70190-3.a56496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-3476(94)70190-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8040759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood D, Crapnell T, Lau L, Bennett A, Lotstein D, Ferris M. Emerging adulthood as a critical stage in the life course. In: Halfon N, Forrest CB, Lerner RM, Faustman EM, editors. Handbook of Life Course Health Development. Cham, Switzerland: Springer; 2018. pp. 123&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31314293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Raymond JK, Schutta MH, Cardillo S, Miller VA, Long JA. An adult health care-based pediatric to adult transition program for emerging adults with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Educ. 2017 Feb 15;43(1):87&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1177/0145721716677098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0145721716677098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28118128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey KC, Wolpert HA, Rhodes ET, Laffel LM, Kleinman K, Beste MG, Wolfsdorf JI, Finkelstein JA. Health care transition in patients with type 1 diabetes: young adult experiences and relationship to glycemic control. Diabetes Care. 2012 Aug;35(8):1716&#x2013;22. doi: 10.2337/dc11-2434. 
 
dc11-2434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc11-2434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3402251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22699289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyatak EA, Sequeira PA, Whittemore R, Vigen CP, Peters AL, Weigensberg MJ. Challenges contributing to disrupted transition from paediatric to adult diabetes care in young adults with type 1 diabetes. Diabet Med. 2014 Dec 26;31(12):1615&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1111/dme.12485. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.12485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4221576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24798586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters A, Laffel L, American Diabetes Association Transitions Working Group  Diabetes care for emerging adults: recommendations for transition from pediatric to adult diabetes care systems: a position statement of the American Diabetes Association, with representation by the American College of Osteopathic Family Physicians, the American Academy of Pediatrics, the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists, the American Osteopathic Association, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Children with Diabetes, The Endocrine Society, the International Society for Pediatric and Adolescent Diabetes, Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation International, the National Diabetes Education Program, and the Pediatric Endocrine Society (formerly Lawson Wilkins Pediatric Endocrine Society) Diabetes Care. 2011 Nov;34(11):2477&#x2013;85. doi: 10.2337/dc11-1723. 
 
34/11/2477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc11-1723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22025785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dovey-Pearce G, Christie D. Transition in diabetes: young people move on &#x2013; we should too. Paediatr Child Health. 2013 Apr;23(4):174&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.paed.2012.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paed.2012.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Los E, Ulrich J, Guttmann-Bauman I. Technology use in transition-age patients with type 1 diabetes: reality and promises. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2016 May;10(3):662&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1177/1932296816632543. 
 
1932296816632543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1932296816632543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5038542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rideout V, Robb MB. The common sense census: media use by tweens and teens. Common Sense Media. 2019.  [2025-05-29].  
 https://surexpositionecrans.fr/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/2019-census-8-to-18-full-report-updated.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal S, Nunn CA, Rotondi M, Couperthwaite AB, Reiser S, Simone A, Katzman DK, Cafazzo JA, Palmert MR. A mobile app for the self-management of type 1 diabetes among adolescents: a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2017 Jun 19;5(6):e82. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.7336. 
 
v5i6e82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.7336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng AH, Crowe TC, Ball K, Rasmussen B. A mHealth support program for Australian young adults with type 1 diabetes: a mixed methods study. Digit Health. 2019 Oct 15;5:2055207619882179. doi: 10.1177/2055207619882179. 
 
10.1177_2055207619882179</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055207619882179?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub0pubmed</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055207619882179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6796202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31662880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin VL, Waller A, Pagliari C, Greene S. A randomized controlled trial of sweet talk, a text-messaging system to support young people with diabetes. Diabet Med. 2006 Dec;23(12):1332&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1111/j.1464-5491.2006.01989.x. 
 
DME1989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-5491.2006.01989.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-5491.2006.01989.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaic T, Robinson T, Goldbloom E, Gallego P, Hramiak I, Lawson ML, Malcolm J, Mahon J, Morrison D, Parikh A, Simone A, Stein R, Uvarov A, Clarson C, JDRF Canadian Clinical Trial CCTN1102 Study Group  Closing the gap: results of the multicenter Canadian randomized controlled trial of structured transition in young adults with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2019 Jun 09;42(6):1018&#x2013;26. doi: 10.2337/dc18-2187. 
 
dc18-2187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2431-13-163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc18-2187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31010873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rami B, Popow C, Horn W, Waldhoer T, Schober E. Telemedical support to improve glycemic control in adolescents with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Eur J Pediatr. 2006 Oct;165(10):701&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1007/s00431-006-0156-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-006-0156-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16670859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cafazzo JA, Casselman M, Hamming N, Katzman DK, Palmert MR. Design of an mHealth app for the self-management of adolescent type 1 diabetes: a pilot study. J Med Internet Res. 2012 May 08;14(3):e70. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2058. 
 
v14i3e70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22564332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butalia S, Crawford SG, McGuire KA, Dyjur DK, Mercer JR, Pacaud D. Improved transition to adult care in youth with type 1 diabetes: a pragmatic clinical trial. Diabetologia. 2021 Apr 13;64(4):758&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1007/s00125-020-05368-1.10.1007/s00125-020-05368-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-020-05368-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33439284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Humphrey C, Hughes J, Macfarlane F, Butler C, Pawson R. How do you modernize a health service? A realist evaluation of whole-scale transformation in london. Milbank Q. 2009 Jun 04;87(2):391&#x2013;416. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-0009.2009.00562.x. 
 
MILQ562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0009.2009.00562.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19523123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nebot Giralt A, N&#xf6;stlinger C, Lee J, Salami O, Lallemant M, Onyango-Ouma W, Nyamongo I, Marchal B. Understanding acceptance of and adherence to a new formulation of paediatric antiretroviral treatment in the form of pellets (LPV/r)-a realist evaluation. PLoS One. 2019 Aug 21;14(8):e0220408. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0220408. 
 
PONE-D-19-07545</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0220408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0220408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6703671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31433803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, Craig P, Baird J, Blazeby JM, Boyd KA, Craig N, French DP, McIntosh E, Petticrew M, Rycroft-Malone J, White M, Moore L. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2021 Sep 30;374:n2061. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n2061. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n2061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breton M, Smithman MA, Sasseville M, Kreindler SA, Sutherland JM, Beaus&#xe9;jour M, Green M, Marshall EG, Jbilou J, Shaw J, Brousselle A, Contandriopoulos D, Crooks VA, Wong ST. How the design and implementation of centralized waiting lists influence their use and effect on access to healthcare - a realist review. Health Policy. 2020 Aug;124(8):787&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1016/j.healthpol.2020.05.023. 
 
S0168-8510(20)30120-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthpol.2020.05.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams F, Wong JS, Nikoo M, Outadi A, Moazen-Zadeh E, Kamel MM, Song MJ, Jang KL, Krausz RM. Understanding eHealth cognitive behavioral therapy targeting substance use: realist review. J Med Internet Res. 2021 Jan 21;23(1):e20557. doi: 10.2196/20557. 
 
v23i1e20557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/20557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33475520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brorsson AL, Bratt EL, Moons P, Ek A, Jelleryd E, Torbj&#xf6;rnsdotter T, Sparud-Lundin C. Randomised controlled trial of a person-centred transition programme for adolescents with type 1 diabetes (STEPSTONES-DIAB): a study protocol. BMJ Open. 2020 Apr 14;10(4):e036496. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-036496. 
 
bmjopen-2019-036496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-036496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7200039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes-Walker DJ, Llewellyn AC, Farrell K. A transition care programme which improves diabetes control and reduces hospital admission rates in young adults with Type 1 diabetes aged 15-25 years. Diabet Med. 2007 Jul;24(7):764&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1111/j.1464-5491.2007.02152.x.DME2152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-5491.2007.02152.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17535294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane JT, Ferguson A, Hall J, McElligott M, Miller M, Lane PH, Pfeffer E. Glycemic control over 3 years in a young adult clinic for patients with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2007 Dec;78(3):385&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2007.04.014.S0168-8227(07)00301-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2007.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17602780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyatak EA, Sequeira PA, Vigen CL, Weigensberg MJ, Wood JR, Montoya L, Ruelas V, Peters AL. Clinical and psychosocial outcomes of a structured transition program among young adults with type 1 diabetes. J Adolesc Health. 2017 Feb;60(2):212&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.jadohealth.2016.09.004. 
 
S1054-139X(16)30348-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2016.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5253301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27889401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xf8;island DH, Arsand E, Sk&#xe5;rderud F. Improving diabetes care for young people with type 1 diabetes through visual learning on mobile phones: mixed-methods study. J Med Internet Res. 2012 Aug 06;14(4):e111. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2155. 
 
v14i4e111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3803161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22868871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White M, O'Connell MA, Cameron FJ. Clinic attendance and disengagement of young adults with type 1 diabetes after transition of care from paediatric to adult services (TrACeD): a randomised, open-label, controlled trial. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2017 Dec;1(4):274&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/S2352-4642(17)30089-5.S2352-4642(17)30089-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-4642(17)30089-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30169183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Rouleau G, Booth GL, Brazeau AS, El-Dassouki N, Taylor M, Cafazzo JA, Greenberg M, Nakhla M, Shulman R, Desveaux L. Understanding whether and how a digital health intervention improves transition care for emerging adults living with type 1 diabetes: protocol for a mixed methods realist evaluation. JMIR Res Protoc. 2023 Sep 13;12:e46115. doi: 10.2196/46115. 
 
v12i1e46115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/46115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10534286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37703070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanmugalingham G, Mok E, Cafazzo JA, Desveaux L, Brazeau A, Booth GL, Greenberg M, Kichler J, Rac VE, Austin P, Goldbloom E, Henderson M, Landry A, Zenlea I, Taylor M, Nakhla M, Shulman R. Text message-based intervention, Keeping in Touch (KiT), to support youth as they transition to adult type 1 diabetes care: a protocol for a multisite randomised controlled superiority trial. BMJ Open. 2023 May 08;13(5):e071396. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-071396. 
 
bmjopen-2022-071396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-071396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10174028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37156577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, van Stralen MM, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011 Apr 23;6:42. doi: 10.1186/1748-5908-6-42. 
 
1748-5908-6-42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R. Modeling health behavior change: how to predict and modify the adoption and maintenance of health behaviors. Appl Psychol. 2008 Jan 30;57(1):1&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1111/j.1464-0597.2007.00325.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-0597.2007.00325.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis FD. Perceived usefulness, perceived ease of use, and user acceptance of information technology. MIS Q. 1989 Sep;13(3):319. doi: 10.2307/249008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/249008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong G, Westhorp G, Manzano A, Greenhalgh J, Jagosh J, Greenhalgh T. RAMESES II reporting standards for realist evaluations. BMC Med. 2016 Jun 24;14(1):96. doi: 10.1186/s12916-016-0643-1. 
 
10.1186/s12916-016-0643-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-016-0643-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-016-0643-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4920991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27342217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malterud K, Siersma VD, Guassora AD. Sample size in qualitative interview studies: guided by information power. Qual Health Res. 2016 Nov;26(13):1753&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1177/1049732315617444.1049732315617444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315617444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26613970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukumbang FC, Marchal B, Van Belle S, van Wyk B. Using the realist interview approach to maintain theoretical awareness in realist studies. Qual Res. 2019 Oct 23;20(4):485&#x2013;515. doi: 10.1177/1468794119881985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1468794119881985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The realist interview. The RAMESES II Project. 2017.  [2025-06-20].  
 https://www.ramesesproject.org/media/RAMESES_II_Realist_interviewing.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short CE, DeSmet A, Woods C, Williams SL, Maher C, Middelweerd A, M&#xfc;ller AM, Wark PA, Vandelanotte C, Poppe L, Hingle MD, Crutzen R. Measuring engagement in eHealth and mHealth behavior change interventions: viewpoint of methodologies. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Nov 16;20(11):e292. doi: 10.2196/jmir.9397. 
 
v20i11e292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6269627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30446482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Yardley L, West R, Patrick K, Greaves F. Developing and evaluating digital interventions to promote behavior change in health and health care: recommendations resulting from an international workshop. J Med Internet Res. 2017 Jun 29;19(6):e232. doi: 10.2196/jmir.7126. 
 
v19i6e232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.7126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28663162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signal V, McLeod M, Stanley J, Stairmand J, Sukumaran N, Thompson D, Henderson K, Davies C, Krebs J, Dowell A, Grainger R, Sarfati D. A mobile- and web-based health intervention program for diabetes and prediabetes self-management (BetaMe/Melon): process evaluation following a randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2020 Dec 01;22(12):e19150. doi: 10.2196/19150. 
 
v22i12e19150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7738254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33258776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cussler EC, Teixeira PJ, Going SB, Houtkooper LB, Metcalfe LL, Blew RM, Ricketts JR, Lohman J, Stanford VA, Lohman TG. Maintenance of weight loss in overweight middle-aged women through the internet. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2008 May;16(5):1052&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1038/oby.2008.19. 
 
oby200819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2008.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2008.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzano A. The craft of interviewing in realist evaluation. Evaluation. 2016 Apr 05;22(3):342&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1177/1356389016638615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1356389016638615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvale S. InterViews: An Introduction to Qualitative Research Interviewing. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmore B, McAuliffe E, Power J, Valli&#xe8;res F. Data analysis and synthesis within a realist evaluation: toward more transparent methodological approaches. Int J Qual Methods. 2019 Jul 03;18:160940691985975. doi: 10.1177/1609406919859754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406919859754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Thematic Analysis: A Practical Guide. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publication; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Conceptual and design thinking for thematic analysis. Qual Psychol. 2022 Feb 13;9(1):3&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1037/qup0000196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/qup0000196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retroduction in realist evaluation. The RAMESES II Project. 2017.  [2024-01-29].  
 https://www.ramesesproject.org/media/RAMESES_II_Retroduction.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley M, Bunn F, Goodman C. Supporting general hospital staff to provide dementia sensitive care: a realist evaluation. Int J Nurs Stud. 2019 Aug;96:61&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2018.10.004. 
 
S0020-7489(18)30249-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2018.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goicolea I, Hurtig AK, San Sebastian MS, Vives-Cases C, Marchal B. Developing a programme theory to explain how primary health care teams learn to respond to intimate partner violence: a realist case-study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015 Jun 09;15(1):228. doi: 10.1186/s12913-015-0899-8. 
 
10.1186/s12913-015-0899-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-0899-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-0899-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4460973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26054758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuckartz U, R&#xe4;diker S. Analyzing Qualitative Data with MAXQDA: Text, Audio, and Video. New York, NY: Springer; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partridge SR, Allman-Farinelli M, McGeechan K, Balestracci K, Wong AT, Hebden L, Harris MF, Bauman A, Phongsavan P. Process evaluation of TXT2BFiT: a multi-component mHealth randomised controlled trial to prevent weight gain in young adults. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2016 Jan 19;13(1):7. doi: 10.1186/s12966-016-0329-2. 
 
10.1186/s12966-016-0329-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-016-0329-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-016-0329-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4717560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26785637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li WH, Ho LL, Cheung AT, Wong MP, Cheung DY, Xia W, Lam TH. A general health promotion approach to helping smokers with non-communicable diseases quit smoking: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Front Public Health. 2022 Oct 18;10:957547. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2022.957547. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.957547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9623171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36330106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batch BC, Spratt SE, Blalock DV, Benditz C, Weiss A, Dolor RJ, Cho AH. General behavioral engagement and changes in clinical and cognitive outcomes of patients with type 2 diabetes using the Time2Focus mobile app for diabetes education: pilot evaluation. J Med Internet Res. 2021 Jan 20;23(1):e17537. doi: 10.2196/17537. 
 
v23i1e17537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7857941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33470947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rempel GR, Ballantyne RT, Magill-Evans J, Nicholas DB, Mackie AS. Texting teens in transition: the use of text messages in clinical intervention research. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2014 Nov 06;2(4):e45. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.3232. 
 
v2i4e45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.3232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4260009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25379624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hm AK, Jensen ML, S&#xf8;rensen MR, Stargardt T. Real-world evidence of user engagement with mobile health for diabetes management: longitudinal observational study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020 Nov 06;8(11):e22212. doi: 10.2196/22212. 
 
v8i11e22212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/22212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7679206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcuzzi A, Klevanger NE, Aasdahl L, Gismervik S, Bach K, Mork PJ, Nordstoga AL. An artificial intelligence-based app for self-management of low back and neck pain in specialist care: process evaluation from a randomized clinical trial. JMIR Hum Factors. 2024 Jul 09;11:e55716. doi: 10.2196/55716. 
 
v11i1e55716</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/55716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11267091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38980710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taki S, Russell CG, Lymer S, Laws R, Campbell K, Appleton J, Ong K, Denney-Wilson E. A mixed methods study to explore the effects of program design elements and participant characteristics on parents' engagement with an mHealth program to promote healthy infant feeding: the growing healthy program. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2019 Jun 25;10:397. doi: 10.3389/fendo.2019.00397. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2019.00397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6603091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31293515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon N, Namadingo H, Cooper S, Bobrow K, Mwantisi C, Nyasulu M, Sicwebu N, Crampin A, Levitt N, Farmer A. Process evaluation of a brief messaging intervention to improve diabetes treatment adherence in sub-Saharan Africa. BMC Public Health. 2021 Aug 21;21(1):1576. doi: 10.1186/s12889-021-11552-8. 
 
10.1186/s12889-021-11552-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-021-11552-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-021-11552-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8379852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson A, Whitehead L, Ritchie L. Factors influencing the ability to self-manage diabetes for adults living with type 1 or 2 diabetes. Int J Nurs Stud. 2014 Jan;51(1):111&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2013.01.006.S0020-7489(13)00031-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2013.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23473390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz M, Erbad A, Belhaouari SB, Almourad MB, Altuwairiqi M, Ali R. Who uses mHealth apps? Identifying user archetypes of mHealth apps. Digit Health. 2023 Jan 22;9:20552076231152175. doi: 10.1177/20552076231152175. 
 
10.1177_20552076231152175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076231152175?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub0pubmed</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076231152175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36714545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kn&#xf6;chelmann A, Healy K, Frese T, Kantelhardt E, Mikolajczyk R, Meyer G, Schildmann J, Steckelberg A, Herke M. User profiles in digitalized healthcare: active, potential, and rejecting - a cross-sectional study using latent class analysis. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024 Sep 17;24(1):1083. doi: 10.1186/s12913-024-11523-w. 
 
10.1186/s12913-024-11523-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-11523-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-11523-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11409736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39289720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Klooster I, Wentzel J, Sieverink F, Linssen G, Wesselink R, van Gemert-Pijnen L. Personas for better targeted eHealth technologies: user-centered design approach. JMIR Hum Factors. 2022 Mar 15;9(1):e24172. doi: 10.2196/24172. 
 
v9i1e24172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8965674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35289759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt M, Lu J, Luo W, Cheng L, Lee M, Huang R, Weng Y, Kichler JC, Corathers SD, Jacobsen LM, Albanese-O Neill A, Smith L, Westen S, Gutierrez-Colina AM, Heckaman L, Wetter SE, Driscoll KA, Modi A. Learning experience design of an mHealth self-management intervention for adolescents with type 1 diabetes. Educ Technol Res Dev. 2022 Oct 19;70(6):2171&#x2013;209. doi: 10.1007/s11423-022-10160-6. 
 
10160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11423-022-10160-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36278247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeStourgeon L, Bergner E, Datye K, Streisand R, Jaser S. Evaluation of study engagement with an mHealth intervention (THR1VE) to treat diabetes distress in teens with type 1 diabetes: randomized clinical trial. JMIR Pediatr Parent. 2023 Oct 05;6:e47089. doi: 10.2196/47089. 
 
v6i1e47089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/47089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10594399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37800881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton C, Comer M, Pruette C, Psoter K, Riekert K. Text messaging adherence intervention for adolescents and young adults with chronic kidney disease: pilot randomized controlled trial and stakeholder interviews. J Med Internet Res. 2020 Aug 14;22(8):e19861. doi: 10.2196/19861. 
 
v22i8e19861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32795983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desveaux L, Shaw J, Saragosa M, Soobiah C, Marani H, Hensel J, Agarwal P, Onabajo N, Bhatia RS, Jeffs L. A mobile app to improve self-management of individuals with type 2 diabetes: qualitative realist evaluation. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Mar 16;20(3):e81. doi: 10.2196/jmir.8712. 
 
v20i3e81</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.8712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5878364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandborg J, Henriksson P, Larsen E, Lindqvist A, Rutberg S, S&#xf6;derstr&#xf6;m E, Maddison R, L&#xf6;f M. Participants' engagement and satisfaction with a smartphone app intended to support healthy weight gain, diet, and physical activity during pregnancy: qualitative study within the HealthyMoms trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2021 Mar 05;9(3):e26159. doi: 10.2196/26159. 
 
v9i3e26159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/26159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7980113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33666554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaser SS, Whittemore R, Choi L, Nwosu S, Russell WE. Randomized trial of a positive psychology intervention for adolescents with type 1 diabetes. J Pediatr Psychol. 2019 Jun 01;44(5):620&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1093/jpepsy/jsz006. 
 
5370313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpepsy/jsz006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30840084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin-Abbas B, Jabbari M, Al-Fares A, El-Dali A, Al-Orifi F. Effect of mobile phone short text messages on glycaemic control in children with type 1 diabetes. J Telemed Telecare. 2014 Apr 18;20(3):153&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1177/1357633X14529244.1357633X14529244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1357633X14529244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24643953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamanillo-Campos R, Fiol-deRoque MA, Serrano-Ripoll MJ, Mira-Mart&#xed;nez S, Ricci-Cabello I. Development and evaluation of DiabeText, a personalized mHealth intervention to support medication adherence and lifestyle change behaviour in patients with type 2 diabetes in Spain: a mixed-methods phase II pragmatic randomized controlled clinical trial. Int J Med Inform. 2023 Aug;176:105103. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2023.105103.S1386-5056(23)00121-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2023.105103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37267809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin-Jung L, Hsiao-Yean C, Yeu-Hui C, Kuan-Chia L, Hui-Chuan H. Effects of mobile health interventions on improving glycemic stability and quality of life in patients with type 1 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Res Nurs Health. 2021 Feb;44(1):187&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1002/nur.22094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nur.22094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33368403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Shu W, Du J, Du M, Wang P, Xue M, Zheng H, Jiang Y, Yin S, Liang D, Wang R, Hou L. Mobile health in the management of type 1 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Endocr Disord. 2019 Feb 13;19(1):21. doi: 10.1186/s12902-019-0347-6. 
 
10.1186/s12902-019-0347-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12902-019-0347-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12902-019-0347-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6375163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30760280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson R, Whittaker R, Jiang Y, Maddison R, Shepherd M, McNamara C, Cutfield R, Khanolkar M, Murphy R. Effectiveness of text message based, diabetes self management support programme (SMS4BG): two arm, parallel randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2018 May 17;361:k1959. doi: 10.1136/bmj.k1959. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.k1959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5957049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29773539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castens&#xf8;e-Seidenfaden P, Husted GR, Jensen AK, Hommel E, Olsen B, Pedersen-Bjergaard U, Kensing F, Teilmann G. Testing a smartphone app (young with diabetes) to improve self-management of diabetes over 12 months: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 Jun 26;6(6):e141. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.9487. 
 
v6i6e141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.9487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29945861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agiostratidou G, Anhalt H, Ball D, Blonde L, Gourgari E, Harriman KN, Kowalski AJ, Madden P, McAuliffe-Fogarty AH, McElwee-Malloy M, Peters A, Raman S, Reifschneider K, Rubin K, Weinzimer SA. Standardizing clinically meaningful outcome measures beyond HbA for type 1 diabetes: a consensus report of the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists, the American Association of Diabetes Educators, the American Diabetes Association, the Endocrine Society, JDRF International, The Leona M. and Harry B. Helmsley Charitable Trust, the Pediatric Endocrine Society, and the T1D exchange. Diabetes Care. 2017 Dec 21;40(12):1622&#x2013;30. doi: 10.2337/dc17-1624. 
 
40/12/1622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc17-1624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5864122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29162582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Faulkner MS, Fritz H, Fadoju D, Muir A, Abowd GD, Head L, Arriaga RI. A pilot randomized trial of text-messaging for symptom awareness and diabetes knowledge in adolescents with type 1 diabetes. J Pediatr Nurs. 2015 Nov;30(6):850&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.pedn.2015.02.002. 
 
S0882-5963(15)00034-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pedn.2015.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4546930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25720675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coorey G, Peiris D, Neubeck L, Redfern J. A realist evaluation approach to explaining the role of context in the impact of a complex eHealth intervention for improving prevention of cardiovascular disease. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020 Aug 18;20(1):764. doi: 10.1186/s12913-020-05597-5. 
 
10.1186/s12913-020-05597-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-05597-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-05597-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7433103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham Q, Cafazzo JA, Feifer A. Adoption, acceptability, and effectiveness of a mobile health app for personalized prostate cancer survivorship care: protocol for a realist case study of the Ned App. JMIR Res Protoc. 2017 Oct 12;6(10):e197. doi: 10.2196/resprot.8051. 
 
v6i10e197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/resprot.8051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5658643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29025699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal P, Mukerji G, Desveaux L, Ivers NM, Bhattacharyya O, Hensel JM, Shaw J, Bouck Z, Jamieson T, Onabajo N, Cooper M, Marani H, Jeffs L, Bhatia RS. Mobile app for improved self-management of type 2 diabetes: multicenter pragmatic randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 Jan 10;7(1):e10321. doi: 10.2196/10321. 
 
v7i1e10321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6329896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30632972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desveaux L, Halko R, Marani H, Feldman S, Ivers NM. Importance of team functioning as a target of quality improvement initiatives in nursing homes: a qualitative process evaluation. J Contin Educ Health Prof. 2019;39(1):21&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1097/CEH.0000000000000238. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CEH.0000000000000238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6400643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coster WJ. Making the best match: selecting outcome measures for clinical trials and outcome studies. Am J Occup Ther. 2013;67(2):162&#x2013;70. doi: 10.5014/ajot.2013.006015. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2013.006015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3628620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23433270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn CC, Butler EC, Swasey KK, Shardell MD, Terrin MD, Barr EA, Gruber-Baldini AL. Mobile diabetes intervention study of patient engagement and impact on blood glucose: mixed methods analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 Feb 02;6(2):e31. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.9265. 
 
v6i2e31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.9265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5816260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29396389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumel A, Kane JM. Examining predictors of real-world user engagement with self-guided eHealth interventions: analysis of mobile apps and websites using a novel dataset. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Dec 14;20(12):e11491. doi: 10.2196/11491. 
 
v20i12e11491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30552077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psihogios AM, King-Dowling S, O'Hagan B, Darabos K, Maurer L, Young J, Fleisher L, Barakat LP, Szalda D, Hill-Kayser CE, Schwartz LA. Contextual predictors of engagement in a tailored mHealth intervention for adolescent and young adult cancer survivors. Ann Behav Med. 2021 Nov 18;55(12):1220&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1093/abm/kaab008. 
 
6154959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/abm/kaab008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8825221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33674863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graffigna G, Barello S, Bonanomi A, Menichetti J. The motivating function of healthcare professional in eHealth and mHealth interventions for type 2 diabetes patients and the mediating role of patient engagement. J Diabetes Res. 2016;2016:2974521. doi: 10.1155/2016/2974521. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/2974521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/2974521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4736395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26881243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litterbach EK, Russell CG, Taki S, Denney-Wilson E, Campbell KJ, Laws RA. Factors influencing engagement and behavioral determinants of infant feeding in an mHealth program: qualitative evaluation of the growing healthy program. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2017 Dec 18;5(12):e196. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.8515. 
 
v5i12e196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.8515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5748479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29254908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>