<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40035059</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-142X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of nursing studies advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Nurs Stud Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of person-centred care within the Stepstones transition program for adolescents with congenital heart disease - a document analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100308</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100308</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100308</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijnsa.2025.100308</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Transition programs are pivotal in ensuring successful transition to adulthood and transfer to adult care for adolescents with chronic conditions. Healthcare providers must therefore support adolescents in increasing their empowerment to gain active participation in health and care. The Stepstones transition program is based on a person-centred care approach and has been evaluated in a randomized controlled trial. However, the extent to which the person-centred care approach was implemented needs further exploration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate how a person-centred care approach was implemented based on a documentation analysis of the Stepstones transition program for adolescents with congenital heart disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A deductive qualitative design employing analysis of the documentation used in the Stepstones transition program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The documentation derives from the consultations in the two interventions centres in the Stepstones randomized controlled trial. The trial was conducted between 2017 and 2021. Data sources included in this study were: The adolescents' written narratives, documentation of the person-centred conversations, and goalsetting in the transition plans.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Documentation for adolescents with congenital heart disease, randomized to the intervention group (<i>n</i> = 59) at the two intervention centres was included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Directed content analysis was used to evaluate how person-centred care was described in the documentation. The analysis was based on the three cornerstones of person-centred care: initiating, establishing and safeguarding partnership, in this study between the adolescent and the transition coordinator during the transition program. The data were deductively sorted into aspects of relevance for person-centred care and adolescent health. For the written narratives an inductive analysis was thereafter undertaken.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A partnership between the transition coordinator and the adolescent was initiated through the adolescents' written narrative and established using a psychosocial interview guide. This outlined a spectrum of aspects important to person-centred and adolescent-oriented approach, such as resources, risks/obstacles, and needs. The goalsetting process describes goals commonly agreed upon and how to accomplish them. A solid foundation of self-awareness regarding personal capacities and learning needs contributed to the development of knowledge, understanding, and fostered independence to various degrees.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Stepstones transition program for adolescents with congenital heart disease implemented several person-centred components, such as eliciting narratives, collaborative goal setting, and tailoring support needs. The documentation had limitations in fully reflecting the person-centred practices employed, highlighting opportunities for improvement in person-centred documentation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TWEETABLE ABSTRACT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">"The study delves into the implementation of person-centred care in the Stepstones transition program for adolescents with congenital heart disease, revealing strengths and areas for improvement in documentation."</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burstr&#xf6;m</LastName><ForeName>&#xc5;sa</ForeName><Initials>&#xc5;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. Neurobiology, Care Science and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saarij&#xe4;rvi</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. Neurobiology, Care Science and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Danderyd Hospital Corporation, Danderyd, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skogby</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Region V&#xe4;stra G&#xf6;taland, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Children's Heart Center, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brorsson</LastName><ForeName>Anna Lena</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. Neurobiology, Care Science and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Astrid Lindgren Children's Hospital, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bratt</LastName><ForeName>Ewa-Lena</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Region V&#xe4;stra G&#xf6;taland, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Children's Heart Center, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Care Sciences, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sparud-Lundin</LastName><ForeName>Carina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Care Sciences, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Nurs Stud Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769252</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-142X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Document analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart defects, Congenital</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient-Centered care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Person-Centred care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transfer of care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transition of care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40035059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11875196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnsa.2025.100308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-142X(25)00018-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acuna Mora M., Sparud-Lundin C., Bratt E.L., Moons P. Person-centred transition programme to empower adolescents with congenital heart disease in the transition to adulthood: a study protocol for a hybrid randomised controlled trial (STEPSTONES project) BMJ Open. 2017;7(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5719650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acu&#xf1;a Mora M., Saarij&#xe4;rvi M., Sparud-Lundin C., Moons P., Bratt E.L. Empowering young persons with congenital heart disease: using intervention mapping to develop a transition program - The STEPSTONES Project. J. Pediatr. Nurs. 2020;50:e8&#x2013;e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31669495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acu&#xf1;a Mora M., Sparud-Lundin C., Fernlund E., Fadl S., Kalliopi K., Rydberg A., Burstr&#xf6;m &#xc5;., Hanseus K., Moons P., Bratt E.L. The longitudinal association between patient empowerment and patient-reported outcomes: what is the direction of effect? PLoS. One. 2022;17(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner H., De Backer J., Babu-Narayan S.V., Budts W., Chessa M., Diller G.P., Lung B., Kluin J., Lang I.M., Meijboom F., Moons P., Mulder B.J.M., Oechslin E., Roos-Hesselink J.W., Schwerzmann M., Sondergaard L., Zeppenfeld K., Group E.S.C.S.D. 2020 ESC guidelines for the management of adult congenital heart disease. Eur. Heart. J. 2021;42(6):563&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekhet A., Zauszniewski J. Methodological triangulation: an approach to understanding data. Nurse Res. 2012;20:40&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23316537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg S.K., Hertz P.G. Outpatient nursing clinic for congenital heart disease patients: copenhagen Transition Program. J. Cardiovasc. Nurs. 2007;22(6):488&#x2013;492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18090190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bratt E.L., Mora M.A., Sparud-Lundin C., Saarij&#xe4;rvi M., Burstr&#xf6;m &#xc5;., Skogby S., Fernlund E., Fadl S., Rydberg A., Hanseus K., Kazamia K., Moons P. Effectiveness of the STEPSTONES Transition Program for adolescents with congenital heart disease-A randomized controlled trial. J. Adolesc. Health. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37032211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britten N., Moore L., Lydahl D., Naldemirci O., Elam M., Wolf A. Elaboration of the Gothenburg model of person-centred care. Health Expect. 2017;20(3):407&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5433540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27193725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie D., Viner R. Adolescent development. BMJ. 2005;330(7486):301&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC548185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15695279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen E., Mackenzie R.G., Yates G.L. HEADSS, a psychosocial risk assessment instrument: implications for designing effective intervention programs for runaway youth. J. Adolesc. Health. 1991;12(7):539&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1772892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooley W.C., Sagerman P.J., Pediatrics A.A.o., Physicians A.A.o.F., Physicians A.C.o., Group T.C.R.A. Supporting the health care transition from adolescence to adulthood in the medical home. Pediatrics. 2011;128(1):182&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21708806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne I., Sheehan A., Heery E., While A.E. Healthcare transition for adolescents and young adults with long-term conditions: qualitative study of patients, parents and healthcare professionals' experiences. J. Clin. Nurs. 2019;28(21&#x2013;22):4062&#x2013;4076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig P., Dieppe P., Macintyre S., Michie S., Nazareth I., Petticrew M., Guidance M.R.C. Developing and evaluating complex interventions: the new Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2008;337:a1655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2769032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18824488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekman I., Swedberg K., Taft C., Lindseth A., Norberg A., Brink E., Carlsson J., Dahlin-Ivanoff S., Johansson I.L., Kjellgren K., Lid&#xe9;n E., &#xd6;hl&#xe9;n J., Olsson L.E., Ros&#xe9;n H., Rydmark M., Sunnerhagen K.S. Person-centered care&#x2013;ready for prime time. Eur. J. Cardiovasc. Nurs. 2011;10(4):248&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPM, 2024. Swedish Ethical Review Authority (EPM). https://etikprovningsmyndigheten.se/en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fife, S.T., &amp; Gossner, J.D., 2024. Deductive qualitative analysis: evaluating, expanding, and refining theory.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flocco S.F., Dellafiore F., Caruso R., Giamberti A., Micheletti A., Negura D.G., Piazza L., Carminati M., Chessa M. Improving health perception through a transition care model for adolescents with congenital heart disease. J. Cardiovasc. Med. 2019;20(4):253&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30676496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heath G., Farre A., Shaw K. Parenting a child with chronic illness as they transition into adulthood: a systematic review and thematic synthesis of parents' experiences. Patient. Educ. Couns. 2017;100(1):76&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27693084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilderson D., Moons P., Van der Elst K., Luyckx K., Wouters C., Westhovens R. The clinical impact of a brief transition programme for young people with juvenile idiopathic arthritis: results of the DON'T RETARD project. Rheumatology. 2016;55(1):133&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26320142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh H.F., Shannon S.E. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual. Health Res. 2005;15(9):1277&#x2013;1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson I., Fors A., Ekman I., Ulin K. Documentation of person-centred health plans for patients with acute coronary syndrome. Eur. J. Cardiovasc. Nurs. 2018;17(2):114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28657364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John A.S., Jackson J.L., Moons P., Uzark K., Mackie A.S., Timmins S., Lopez K.N., Kovacs A.H., Gurvitz M., Cardiology A.H.A.A.W.c.H.D.C.o.t.C.o.L.c.H.D.a.H.H.i.t.Y.a.t.C.o.C., Nursing C.o.C.a.S., Council on Arteriosclerosis T.r.a.V.B., Council a.S. Advances in managing transition to adulthood for adolescents with congenital heart disease: a practical approach to transition program design: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. J. Am. Heart Assoc. 2022;11(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35297271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K.R., McMorris B.J., MapelLentz S., Scal P. Improving self-management skills through patient-centered communication. J. Adolesc. Health. 2015;57(6):666&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26592334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokorelias K.M., Lee T.J., Bayley M., Seto E., Toulany A., Nelson M.L.A., Dimitropoulos G., Penner M., Simpson R., Munce S.E.P. I have eight different files at eight different places": perspectives of youths and their Family caregivers on transitioning from pediatric to Adult Rehabilitation and Community services. J. Clin. Med. 2023;12(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9960001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36836228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lydahl D., Britten N., Wolf A., Naldemirci &#xd6;., Lloyd H., Heckemann B. Exploring documentation in Person-centred care: a content analysis of care plans. Int. J. Older. People Nurs. 2022;17(5):e12461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9540033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35393772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackie A.S., Rempel G.R., Kovacs A.H., Kaufman M., Rankin K.N., Jelen A., Yaskina M., Sananes R., Oechslin E., Dragieva D., Mustafa S., Williams E., Schuh M., Manlhiot C., Anthony S.J., Magill-Evans J., Nicholas D., McCrindle B.W. Transition intervention for adolescents with congenital heart disease. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 2018;71(16):1768&#x2013;1777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29673467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazur A., Dembinski L., Schrier L., Hadjipanayis A., Michaud P.A. European Academy of Paediatric consensus statement on successful transition from paediatric to adult care for adolescents with chronic conditions. Acta Paediatr. 2017;106(8):1354&#x2013;1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28471516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWilliam C.L. Patients, persons or partners? Involving those with chronic disease in their care. Chronic. Illn. 2009;5(4):277&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medicine S.f.A.H.a. Transition to adulthood for youth with chronic conditions and special health care needs. J. Adolesc. Health. 2020;66(5):631&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32331627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moons P., Bratt E.L., De Backer J., Goossens E., Hornung T., Tutarel O., Zuhlke L., Araujo J.J., Callus E., Gabriel H., Shahid N., Sliwa K., Verstappen A., Yang H.L., Thomet C. Transition to adulthood and transfer to adult care of adolescents with congenital heart disease: a global consensus statement of the ESC Association of Cardiovascular Nursing and Allied Professions (ACNAP), the ESC Working Group on Adult Congenital Heart Disease (WG ACHD), the Association for European Paediatric and Congenital Cardiology (AEPC), the Pan-African Society of Cardiology (PASCAR), the Asia-Pacific Pediatric Cardiac Society (APPCS), the Inter-American Society of Cardiology (IASC), the Cardiac Society of Australia and New Zealand (CSANZ), the International Society for Adult Congenital Heart Disease (ISACHD), the World Heart Federation (WHF), the European Congenital Heart Disease Organisation (ECHDO), and the Global Alliance for Rheumatic and Congenital Hearts (Global ARCH) Eur. Heart. J. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8560210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34198319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien B.C., Harris I.B., Beckman T.J., Reed D.A., Cook D.A. Standards for reporting qualitative research: a synthesis of recommendations. Acad. Med. 2014;89(9):1245&#x2013;1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;hl&#xe9;n J., Bj&#xf6;rkman I., Siira E., Kirkevold M. Personhood: philosophies, applications and critiques in healthcare. Nurs. Philos. 2022;23(3):e12400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35723006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulvirenti M., McMillan J., Lawn S. Empowerment, patient centred care and self-management. Health Expect. 2014;17(3):303&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5060728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22212306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravens E., Becker J., Pape L., Ernst G. Psychosocial benefit and adherenceof adolescents with chronic diseases participating in transition programs: a systematic review. J. Transit. Med. 2020;2(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roick J., Danker H., Kersting A., Briest S., Dietrich A., Dietz A., Einenkel J., Papsdorf K., Lordick F., Meixensberger J., M&#xf6;ssner J., Niederwieser D., Prietzel T., Schiefke F., Stolzenburg J.U., Wirtz H., Singer S. Factors associated with non-participation and dropout among cancer patients in a cluster-randomised controlled trial. Eur. J. Cancer Care. 2018;27(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28134477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saarij&#xe4;rvi M., Wallin L., Moons P., Gyllensten H., Bratt E.L. Factors affecting adolescents' participation in randomized controlled trials evaluating the effectiveness of healthcare interventions: the case of the STEPSTONES project. BMC. Med. Res. Methodol. 2020;20(1):205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7398069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saarij&#xe4;rvi M., Wallin L., Moons P., Gyllensten H., Bratt E.L. Implementation fidelity of a transition program for adolescents with congenital heart disease: the STEPSTONES project. BMC. Health Serv. Res. 2022;22(1):153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saarij&#xe4;rvi M., Wallin L., Moons P., Gyllensten H., Bratt E.L. Mechanisms of impact and experiences of a person-centred transition programme for adolescents with CHD: the Stepstones project. BMC. Health Serv. Res. 2021;21(1):573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8194131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34112174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saarij&#xe4;rvi M., Wallin L., Moons P., Gyllensten H., Bratt E.L. Transition program for adolescents with congenital heart disease in transition to adulthood: protocol for a mixed-method process evaluation study (the STEPSTONES project) BMJ Open. 2019;9(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6687006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31377699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K., Matthews L., Simpson S.A., Craig P., Baird J., Blazeby J.M., Boyd K.A., Craig N., French D.P., McIntosh E., Petticrew M., Rycroft-Malone J., White M., Moore L. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2021;374:n2061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small N., Bower P., Chew-Graham C.A., Whalley D., Protheroe J. Patient empowerment in long-term conditions: development and preliminary testing of a new measure. BMC. Health Serv. Res. 2013;13:263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23835131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varty M., Speller-Brown B., Phillips L., Kelly K.P. Youths' Experiences of transition from pediatric to adult care: an updated qualitative metasynthesis. J. Pediatr. Nurs. 2020;55:201&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32966960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller D., Bailey S., Zolfaghari E., Ho J., Feuerlicht D., Ross K., Steinbeck K. Psychosocial assessment of adolescents and young adults in paediatric hospital settings: patient and staff perspectives on implementation of the e-HEEADSSS. BMC. Health Serv. Res. 2023;23(1):683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37349759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical A. World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMa. 2013;310(20):2191&#x2013;2194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>