<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40895096</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An efficient approach for detecting atrial fibrillation in ischemic stroke patients using a wearable device: a prospective multicenter substudy of the STABLED trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1560495</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1560495</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1560495</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2025.1560495</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Stroke caused by atrial fibrillation (AF) is associated with high mortality and severe morbidity. Screening patients for AF may facilitate early initiation of anticoagulant therapy and prevent recurrent stroke; therefore, strategies to effectively detect AF in stroke patients are important.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This prospective multicenter study was conducted between April 27, 2020 and March 31, 2021 at seven sites in Japan, as a substudy of the STABLED trial, a multicenter prospective randomized study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of catheter ablation with anticoagulant therapy using edoxaban in patients with ischemic stroke and AF. This substudy included 241 patients who suffered ischemic stroke but had no diagnosis of AF. Patients were monitored with Duranta, a wearable non-invasive wireless patch ECG system. The primary outcome was the detection rate for AF while wearing Duranta.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Of the 241 patients, 66.8% were men, and the mean age was 71.0&#x202f;years. AF was detected in 21 of the 241 patients (8.7, 95% CI: 5.4-12.4) during follow-up using the Duranta wearable ECG system. ECG data were recorded for 7&#x202f;days in all patients. The median number of days from stroke onset to Duranta placement was 2.0, but this duration varied considerably (median; IQR, 0-22.0). An adverse event of dermal pruritus was observed in 1 of the 241 patients (0.4%). Determinants for the detection of AF in patients with no previous history of AF were dyslipidemia and left atrial dimension.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Wearable wireless patch ECG systems such as Duranta are simple and efficient devices for detecting AF. In patients with ischemic stroke and no diagnosis of AF, their use for detecting new AF may provide benefit through early initiation of anticoagulants and prevention of recurrent stroke.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Saito, Nishiyama, Otsuka, Sakamoto, Okubo, Iguchi, Yamaguchi, Okada, Hamaguchi, Yonehara, Fukuzawa, Takita, Katano and Kimura.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Saito</LastName><ForeName>Tomonari</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medicine, Nippon Medical School, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Nishiyama</LastName><ForeName>Yasuhiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medicine, Nippon Medical School, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medicine, Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medical Sciences, University of Fukui, Fukui, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otsuka</LastName><ForeName>Toshiaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hygiene and Public Health, Graduate School of Medicine, Nippon Medical School, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakamoto</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medicine, Nippon Medical School, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okubo</LastName><ForeName>Seiji</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cerebrovascular Medicine, NTT Medical Center Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iguchi</LastName><ForeName>Yasuyuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The Jikei University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Keiji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ichinomiya Nishi Hospital, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okada</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cerebrovascular Medicine and Neurology, National Hospital Organization Kyushu Medical Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Hirotoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kita-Harima Medical Center, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yonehara</LastName><ForeName>Toshiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Saiseikai Kumamoto Hospital, Kumamoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuzawa</LastName><ForeName>Masayuki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Primary Medical Science Department, Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takita</LastName><ForeName>Atsushi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Data Intelligence Department, Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katano</LastName><ForeName>Takehiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medicine, Nippon Medical School, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimura</LastName><ForeName>Kazumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Graduate School of Medicine, Nippon Medical School, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemic stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multicenter study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prospective study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wearable device</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that this study received funding from Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. The funder had the following involvement in the study: study design, data analysis planning, data interpretation, and decision to submit the manuscript for publication. The funder but had no direct involvement in data management, direct access, or statistical analysis. YN, TS, and YO received personal fees from Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. YS, SO, YI, KY, and HH received lecture fees from Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. MF and AT are employees of Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. KK received lecture fees and research funding from Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40895096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12391382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2025.1560495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tai S-Y, Cheon S, Yamaoka Y, Chien Y-W, Lu T-H. Changes in the rankings of leading causes of death in Japan, Korea, and Taiwan from 1998 to 2018: a comparison of three ranking lists. BMC Public Health. (2022) 22:926. doi: 10.1186/s12889-022-13278-7, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-022-13278-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9086411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35538508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura K, Minematsu K, Yamaguchi T. Atrial fibrillation as a predictive factor for severe stroke and early death in 15,831 patients with acute ischaemic stroke. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. (2005) 76:679&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1136/jnnp.2004.048827, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2004.048827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15834026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazurek M, Shantsila E, Lane DA, Wolff A, Proietti M, Lip GYH. Secondary versus primary stroke prevention in atrial fibrillation: insights from the Darlington atrial fibrillation registry. Stroke. (2017) 48:2198&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1161/strokeaha.116.016146, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.116.016146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshimura S, Koga M, Sato S, Todo K, Yamagami H, Kumamoto M, et al. Two-year outcomes of anticoagulation for acute ischemic stroke with Nonvalvular atrial fibrillation - SAMURAI-NVAF study. Circ J. (2018) 82:1935&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1253/circj.CJ-18-0067, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.CJ-18-0067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29863095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung CE, Su D, Turakhia MP, Lansberg MG. Diagnostic yield of extended cardiac patch monitoring in patients with stroke or TIA. Front Neurol. (2014) 5:266. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2014.00266, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2014.00266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4290477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25628595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung S, Lee HA, Kang IS, Shin SH, Chang Y, Woo Shin D, et al. Clinical implications of atrial fibrillation detection using wearable devices in patients with cryptogenic stroke (CANDLE-AF) trial: design and rationale. Front Cardiovasc Med. (2022) 9:837958. doi: 10.3389/fcvm.2022.837958, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.837958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9013795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halcox JPJ, Wareham K, Cardew A, Gilmore M, Barry JP, Phillips C, et al. Assessment of remote heart rhythm sampling using the AliveCor heart monitor to screen for atrial fibrillation: the REHEARSE-AF study. Circulation. (2017) 136:1784&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1161/circulationaha.117.030583, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.117.030583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto K, Harada N, Kasamaki Y. Can a patch electrocardiographic device be a leading actor for detecting atrial fibrillation? - diversifying electrocardiographic monitoring devices. Circ J. (2022) 86:189&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1253/circj.CJ-21-0644, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.CJ-21-0644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakamoto Y, Nishiyama Y, Iwasaki YK, Daida H, Toyoda K, Kitagawa K, et al. Design and rationale of the STroke secondary prevention with catheter ABLation and EDoxaban clinical trial in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation: the STABLED study. J Cardiol. (2019) 74:539&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1016/j.jjcc.2019.06.002, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jjcc.2019.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31337525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt B, Coats AJS, Tsutsui H, Abdelhamid CM, Adamopoulos S, Albert N, et al. Universal definition and classification of heart failure: a report of the Heart Failure Society of America, heart failure Association of the European Society of cardiology, Japanese heart failure society and writing Committee of the Universal Definition of heart failure: endorsed by the Canadian heart failure society, heart failure Association of India, Cardiac Society of Australia and new Zealand, and Chinese heart failure association. Eur J Heart Fail. (2021) 23:352&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.2115, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.2115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33605000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart RG, Coull BM, Hart D. Early recurrent embolism associated with nonvalvular atrial fibrillation: a retrospective study. Stroke. (1983) 14:688&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1161/01.str.14.5.688, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.str.14.5.688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6658950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paciaroni M, Agnelli G, Falocci N, Caso V, Becattini C, Marcheselli S, et al. Early recurrence and cerebral bleeding in patients with acute ischemic stroke and atrial fibrillation: effect of anticoagulation and its timing: the RAF study. Stroke. (2015) 46:2175&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1161/strokeaha.115.008891, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.115.008891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26130094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins P, MacFarlane PW, Dawson J, McInnes GT, Langhorne P, Lees KR. Noninvasive cardiac event monitoring to detect atrial fibrillation after ischemic stroke: a randomized, controlled trial. Stroke. (2013) 44:2525&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1161/strokeaha.113.001927, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.113.001927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23899913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabaudon D, Sztajzel J, Sievert K, Landis T, Sztajzel R. Usefulness of ambulatory 7-day ECG monitoring for the detection of atrial fibrillation and flutter after acute stroke and transient ischemic attack. Stroke. (2004) 35:1647&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1161/01.STR.0000131269.69502.d9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.0000131269.69502.d9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrarini C, Di Stefano V, Russo M, Dono F, Di Pietro M, Furia N, et al. ECG monitoring of post-stroke occurring arrhythmias: an observational study using 7-day Holter ECG. Sci Rep. (2022) 12:228. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-04285-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-04285-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8741921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein RA, Kamel H, Granger CB, Piccini JP, Sethi PP, Katz JM, et al. Effect of long-term continuous cardiac monitoring vs usual care on detection of atrial fibrillation in patients with stroke attributed to large- or small-vessel disease: the STROKE-AF randomized clinical trial. JAMA. (2021) 325:2169&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.6470, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.6470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8170544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34061145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagris D, Papanikolaou A, Kvernland A, Korompoki E, Frontera JA, Troxel AB, et al. COVID-19 and ischemic stroke. Eur J Neurol. (2021) 28:3826&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1111/ene.15008, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.15008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8444875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34224187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchhof P, Camm AJ, Goette A, Brandes A, Eckardt L, Elvan A, et al. Early rhythm-control therapy in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. (2020) 383:1305&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2019422, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2019422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindricks G, Potpara T, Dagres N, Arbelo E, Bax JJ, Blomstr&#xf6;m-Lundqvist C, et al. 2020 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation developed in collaboration with the European Association for Cardio-Thoracic Surgery (EACTS): the task force for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) developed with the special contribution of the European heart rhythm association (EHRA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J. (2021) 42:373&#x2013;498. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa612, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noubiap JJ, Agbaedeng TA, Kamtchum-Tatuene J, Fitzgerald JL, Middeldorp ME, Kleinig T, et al. Rhythm monitoring strategies for atrial fibrillation detection in patients with cryptogenic stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. (2021) 34:100780. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcha.2021.100780, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcha.2021.100780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33948484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez MV, Mahaffey KW, Hedlin H, Rumsfeld JS, Garcia A, Ferris T, et al. Large-scale assessment of a smartwatch to identify atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. (2019) 381:1909&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1901183, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1901183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31722151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladstone DJ, Wachter R, Schmalstieg-Bahr K, Quinn FR, Hummers E, Ivers N, et al. Screening for atrial fibrillation in the older population: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Cardiol. (2021) 6:558&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2021.0038, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2021.0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33625468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan B, Tu H, Lam C, Swift C, Ho MS, Mok VCT, et al. Nurse led smartphone electrographic monitoring for atrial fibrillation after ischemic stroke: SPOT-AF. J Stroke. (2020) 22:387&#x2013;95. doi: 10.5853/jos.2020.00689, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5853/jos.2020.00689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7568969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao MT, Yu CC, Lin LY, Pan KH, Tsai TH, Wu YC, et al. Impact of recording length and other arrhythmias on atrial fibrillation detection from wrist photoplethysmogram using smartwatches. Sci Rep. (2022) 12:5364. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-09181-1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-09181-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinhubl SR, Waalen J, Edwards AM, Ariniello LM, Mehta RR, Ebner GS, et al. Effect of a home-based wearable continuous ECG monitoring patch on detection of undiagnosed atrial fibrillation: the mSToPS randomized clinical trial. JAMA. (2018) 320:146&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.8102, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2018.8102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29998336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki Y, Toyoda K, Iguchi Y, Hirano T, Metoki N, Tomoda M, et al. Atrial fibrillation after ischemic stroke detected by chest strap-style 7-day Holter monitoring and the risk predictors: EDUCATE-ESUS. J Atheroscler Thromb. (2021) 28:544&#x2013;54. doi: 10.5551/jat.58420, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5551/jat.58420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8193782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32801289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger JJ, Arora R, Green D, Greenland P, Lee DC, Lloyd-Jones DM, et al. Evaluating the atrial myopathy underlying atrial fibrillation: identifying the Arrhythmogenic and Thrombogenic substrate. Circulation. (2015) 132:278&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1161/circulationaha.115.016795, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.115.016795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4520257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26216085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang TS, Barnes ME, Bailey KR, Leibson CL, Montgomery SC, Takemoto Y, et al. Left atrial volume: important risk marker of incident atrial fibrillation in 1655 older men and women. Mayo Clin Proc. (2001) 76:467&#x2013;75. doi: 10.4065/76.5.467, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4065/76.5.467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11357793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwamm LH, Kamel H, Granger CB, Piccini JP, Katz JM, Sethi PP, et al. Predictors of atrial fibrillation in patients with stroke attributed to large- or small-vessel disease: a Prespecified secondary analysis of the STROKE AF randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. (2023) 80:99&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2022.4038, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2022.4038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9664367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36374508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Angelis MV, Di Stefano V, Franciotti R, Furia N, Di Girolamo E, Onofrj M, et al. Cryptogenic stroke and atrial fibrillation in a real-world population: the role of insertable cardiac monitors. Sci Rep. (2020) 10:3230. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-60180-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-60180-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7040015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32094376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Gao L, Wang Z, Guan B, Guan X, Wang B, et al. Lipid profile and incidence of atrial fibrillation: a prospective cohort study in China. Clin Cardiol. (2018) 41:314&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1002/clc.22864, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.22864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6490045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29575115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe H, Tanabe N, Yagihara N, Watanabe T, Aizawa Y, Kodama M. Association between lipid profile and risk of atrial fibrillation. Circ J. (2011) 75:2767&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1253/circj.cj-11-0780, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.cj-11-0780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagris D, Harrison SL, Lip GYH. Lipids and atrial fibrillation: new insights into a paradox. PLoS Med. (2022) 19:e1004067. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1004067, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1004067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9371346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding M, Wennberg A, Gigante B, Walldius G, Hammar N, Modig K. Lipid levels in midlife and risk of atrial fibrillation over 3 decades-experience from the Swedish AMORIS cohort: a cohort study. PLoS Med. (2022) 19:e1004044. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1004044, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1004044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9371362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Xie Z, Li J, Chen C, Cai W, Dong Y, et al. Meta-analysis of metabolic syndrome and its individual components with risk of atrial fibrillation in different populations. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. (2021) 21:90. doi: 10.1186/s12872-021-01858-1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-021-01858-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33588759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>