<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32644471</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK559045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246">Nonarteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaur</LastName><ForeName>Kirandeep</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gomabai Netralaya and Research Centre</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Margolin</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Toronto</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy (NAION) is the most common cause of optic nerve swelling and optic neuropathy in adults older than 50.&#xa0;Risk factors that have been strongly associated with NAION include hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, diabetes mellitus, cardio- and cerebrovascular disease, and obstructive sleep apnea (OSA).&#xa0;Although the exact pathogenesis of NAION has not been elucidated,&#xa0;the prevailing theory is that it is caused by hypoperfusion of the&#xa0;short posterior ciliary arteries supplying the optic nerve, which then causes ischemia that induces swelling of the portion of the optic nerve traveling through the small opening in a scleral canal. This swelling, in turn, leads to compartment syndrome involving neighboring axons that are now compressed in a space limited by the small opening in the scleral canal, resulting in apoptosis and death of the ganglion cells whose axons comprise the optic nerve. The natural history of NAION has been elucidated in the Ischemic Optic Neuropathy Decompression Trial (IONDT), which demonstrated that about 30% of patients regain 3 or more lines of vision at 2-year follow-up, 20% lose 3 or more lines of vision, and, in the majority of patients, the vision remains unchanged after the onset. In reality, visual acuity&#xa0;does not change in most patients after the acute event has resolved, and those who can see a few lines are more likely to learn to improve their fixation. NAION is the most common cause of acute optic neuropathy in individuals&#xa0;older than 50. This condition represents a significant cause of irreversible visual loss worldwide. NAION is a multifactorial condition characterized by the sudden, painless vision loss, often accompanied by swelling of the optic disc, typically affecting one eye. The impact of NAION on the patients' quality of life, along with its elusive pathophysiology, makes it a critical topic for continued clinical education, especially among ophthalmologists, neurologists, internists, and primary care providers. NAION is considered a small vessel disease affecting the short posterior ciliary arteries that supply the anterior portion of the optic nerve head. NAION&#xa0;is distinct from arteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy (AAION), which is typically caused by giant cell arteritis (GCA) and requires urgent systemic corticosteroid therapy. In contrast, NAION is not associated with systemic vasculitis, and its management remains largely supportive, as there is no universally accepted, proven treatment to reverse or significantly improve visual outcomes. However, understanding its risk factors, natural history, and emerging management options is essential for both prevention and early diagnosis. The pathogenesis of NAION is not entirely understood. Still, the prevailing theory posits that a transient drop in perfusion pressure&#x2014;due to systemic hypotension, nocturnal hypotension, or small vessel disease&#x2014;leads to infarction of the anterior optic nerve head. This infarction causes axoplasmic stasis and edema within a confined space&#x2014;the scleral canal&#x2014;setting off a vicious cycle of compression, ischemia, and further damage to adjacent axons. In patients predisposed to NAION, the optic nerve head often displays a crowded disc appearance or a small cup-to-disc ratio (disc-at-risk), making it particularly vulnerable to this compartment syndrome. Numerous systemic and ocular risk factors have been associated with NAION, including&#xa0;systemic hypertension, diabetes mellitus, hyperlipidemia, OSA, nocturnal hypotension, and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Additionally, phosphodiesterase inhibitors, such as sildenafil, have been implicated in precipitating NAION in predisposed individuals. There is also evidence to suggest a genetic predisposition, particularly involving polymorphisms in genes related to vascular autoregulation and thrombophilia. Recognition and control of modifiable systemic risk factors can help reduce the likelihood of bilateral involvement, which occurs in approximately 15% to 25% of patients. The clinical presentation of NAION is typically a sudden, painless monocular vision loss, often first noticed upon awakening. Patients often report inferior altitudinal visual field defects, although central and diffuse patterns are also observed. Visual acuity at presentation varies, ranging from 20/20 to no light perception, but the majority of patients fall within the 20/60 to 20/200 range. Relative afferent pupillary defect (RAPD) is almost always present in unilateral cases. Fundus examination in the acute phase reveals sectoral or diffuse optic disc swelling, often accompanied by peripapillary hemorrhages and absence of disc cupping. The diagnosis of NAION is primarily clinical, based on history, fundoscopic findings, and exclusion of other causes of optic neuropathy. However, ancillary testing such as optical coherence tomography (OCT) can provide objective evidence of optic nerve head edema and subsequent thinning of the retinal nerve fiber layer (RNFL) during the atrophic phase. Visual field testing is essential to document the pattern and severity of field loss. Fluorescein angiography may be used to identify delayed filling of the optic disc and to exclude mimickers such as inflammatory or infiltrative optic neuropathies. The laboratory workup is typically focused on ruling out arteritic etiologies, including erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), C-reactive protein (CRP), and temporal artery biopsy when GCA is suspected. The natural history of NAION has been studied extensively. The IONDT, a pivotal randomized controlled study, found that spontaneous visual recovery occurs in approximately 30% of patients, 20% experience further deterioration, and 50% remain stable. Notably, the study also showed that surgical decompression of the optic nerve did not improve visual outcomes and carried a risk of harm. These findings underscore the importance of conservative management and highlight the critical need for modifying risk factors. Although visual acuity does not typically improve significantly in most patients after the acute event, neuroplasticity and fixation adaptation may still lead to functional improvement. Therefore, low vision rehabilitation and early counseling are essential components of care. Patient education should focus on lifestyle modifications, including optimizing blood pressure and glycemic control, managing dyslipidemia, screening for and treating OSA, and avoiding nocturnal hypotension by adjusting antihypertensive therapy. Recent studies have explored various pharmacological and nonpharmacological interventions, including corticosteroids, anti-vascular endothelial growth factor (anti-VEGF) agents, neuroprotective drugs, and hyperbaric oxygen therapy; however, none have demonstrated conclusive benefits in large-scale randomized trials. Clinical trials investigating neuroprotective strategies and optic nerve regeneration remain an area of ongoing research, offering hope for future interventions. The interprofessional team plays a central role in&#xa0;managing NAION. Ophthalmologists lead the diagnostic process and provide patient education. Primary care physicians and internists should be engaged to address systemic comorbidities and reduce future vascular events. Sleep specialists should evaluate and manage suspected OSA. Neurologists may be consulted to rule out central causes or when the diagnosis is uncertain. Low vision specialists, occupational therapists, and rehabilitation counselors play a crucial role in helping patients adapt to vision loss and maintain their independence. Pharmacists play a key role in medication reconciliation, particularly in preventing adverse drug events related to systemic hypotension. From an educational perspective, there is a clear need to improve awareness among healthcare providers regarding the early signs of NAION and the importance of system workup. Many cases are initially misdiagnosed or under-evaluated, leading to delayed identification of modifiable risk factors and missed opportunities for systemic intervention. Continuing education should aim to bridge this gap by enhancing clinicians' ability to identify at-risk patients, recognize early signs and symptoms, and coordinate comprehensive, interprofessional care. In summary, NAION remains a challenging optic neuropathy with a poorly understood pathophysiology, limited treatment options, and a significant impact on quality of life. The sudden and often permanent nature of vision loss places a psychological burden on patients and demands sensitive counseling and support. Although treatment options remain limited, the multidisciplinary management of risk factors and patient-centered care are critical in improving long-term outcomes and preventing bilateral involvement. With increasing understanding of vascular and neurodegenerative mechanisms, future therapeutic targets may emerge, underscoring the importance of ongoing clinical research and interprofessional collaboration in the care of this complex condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s7">Toxicokinetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s8">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s9">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s10">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s11">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s12">Pertinent Studies and Ongoing Trials</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s13">Treatment Planning</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s14">Toxicity and Adverse Effect Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s15">Staging</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s16">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s17">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s18">Postoperative and Rehabilitation Care</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s19">Consultations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s20">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s21">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s22">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s23">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-26246" sec="article-26246.s24">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hayreh SS. Ischemic optic neuropathy. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2009 Jan;28(1):34-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19063989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer EL, Pepin S. Obstructive sleep apnea and nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: evidence for an association. J Clin Sleep Med. 2013 Jun 15;9(6):613-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3659384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23772197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ischemic Optic Neuropathy Decompression Trial: twenty-four-month update. Arch Ophthalmol. 2000 Jun;118(6):793-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvetat ML, Pellegrini F, Spadea L, Salati C, Zeppieri M. Non-Arteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy (NA-AION): A Comprehensive Overview. Vision (Basel) 2023 Nov 09;7(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10661278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37987292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Cui Y, Mo Z, Huang X, Chi M, Guo T, Huang Z. A 54-year-old male with posterior ischemic optic neuropathy misdiagnosed as ophthalmic artery occlusion. BMC Ophthalmol. 2025 Jul 01;25(1):377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12218827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40597944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzakgider NK, Karaca Adiyeke S, Aytogan H. Understanding the Etiopathogenesis of Non-Arteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy with Laboratory Findings. Beyoglu Eye J. 2024;9(1):8-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10944851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38504965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller NR, Arnold AC. Current concepts in the diagnosis, pathogenesis and management of nonarteritic anterior ischaemic optic neuropathy. Eye (Lond) 2015 Jan;29(1):65-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4289822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouthour W, Biousse V, Newman NJ. Diagnosis of Optic Disc Oedema: Fundus Features, Ocular Imaging Findings, and Artificial Intelligence. Neuroophthalmology. 2023;47(4):177-192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10332214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37434667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The ischemic optic neuropathy decompression trial (IONDT): design and methods. Control Clin Trials. 1998 Jun;19(3):276-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Nispen RM, Virgili G, Hoeben M, Langelaan M, Klevering J, Keunen JE, van Rens GH. Low vision rehabilitation for better quality of life in visually impaired adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020 Jan 27;1(1):CD006543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31985055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micun Z, Dobrzy&#x144;ska W, Sie&#x15b;kiewicz M, Zawadzka I, Dmuchowska DA, Wojewodzka-Zelezniakowicz M, Konopi&#x144;ska J. Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy in Ophthalmology: A Narrative Review. J Clin Med. 2023 Dec 20;13(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10779579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38202036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bialer OY, Stiebel-Kalish H. Evaluation and management of nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: a national survey. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2024 Oct;262(10):3323-3330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11458737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38748211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons A, Henderson AD. Non-Arteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy: Challenges for the Future. Front Ophthalmol (Lausanne) 2022;2:848710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11182325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38983540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biousse V, Newman NJ. Ischemic Optic Neuropathies. N Engl J Med. 2015 Oct 22;373(17):1677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26488706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biousse V, Newman NJ. Ischemic Optic Neuropathies. N Engl J Med. 2015 Jun 18;372(25):2428-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26083207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma RA, Newman NJ, Biousse V. New concepts on acute ocular ischemia. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019 Feb;32(1):19-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30461463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamann S, Malmqvist L, Wegener M, Fard MA, Biousse V, Bursztyn L, Citirak G, Costello F, Crum AV, Digre K, Fraser JA, Huna-Baron R, Katz B, Lawlor M, Newman NJ, Peragallo JH, Petzold A, Sibony PA, Subramanian PS, Warner JEA, Wong SH, Fraser CL, Optic Disc Drusen Studies Consortium Young Adults With Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy: A Multicenter Optic Disc Drusen Study. Am J Ophthalmol. 2020 Sep;217:174-181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr NM, Chew SS, Danesh-Meyer HV. Non-arteritic anterior ischaemic optic neuropathy: a review and update. J Clin Neurosci. 2009 Aug;16(8):994-1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19596112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biousse V, Newman N. Retinal and optic nerve ischemia. Continuum (Minneap Minn) 2014 Aug;20(4 Neuro-ophthalmology):838-56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10563953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25099097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayreh SS, Zimmerman MB, Podhajsky P, Alward WL. Nocturnal arterial hypotension and its role in optic nerve head and ocular ischemic disorders. Am J Ophthalmol. 1994 May 15;117(5):603-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8172267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labowsky MT, Rizzo JF. The Controversy of Chronotherapy: Emerging Evidence regarding Bedtime Dosing of Antihypertensive Medications in Non-Arteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy. Semin Ophthalmol. 2023 Jan;38(1):99-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36625504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XT, Zhong YF, Xue YQ, Li SQ, Wang BY, Zhang GQ, Hidasa I, Zhang H. Clinical Features of Central Retinal Vein Occlusion in Young Patients. Ophthalmol Ther. 2022 Aug;11(4):1409-1422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9191544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35697973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel RA, Hall DA, Eichenseer S, Bailey M. Movement Disorders and Hematologic Diseases. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2021 Feb;8(2):193-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33553488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souto JC, Almasy L, Borrell M, Blanco-Vaca F, Mateo J, Soria JM, Coll I, Felices R, Stone W, Fontcuberta J, Blangero J. Genetic susceptibility to thrombosis and its relationship to physiological risk factors: the GAIT study. Genetic Analysis of Idiopathic Thrombophilia. Am J Hum Genet. 2000 Dec;67(6):1452-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11038326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer E, Gale J, Crowston JG, Wells AP. Optic Nerve Head Drusen: An Update. Neuroophthalmology. 2018 Dec;42(6):367-384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6276953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30524490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citirak G, Malmqvist L, Hamann S. Analysis of Systemic Risk Factors and Post-Insult Visual Development in a Danish Cohort of Patients with Nonarteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy. Clin Ophthalmol. 2022;16:3415-3424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9560866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36249446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Grossman D, Arnold AC, Sloan FA. Incidence of nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: increased risk among diabetic patients. Ophthalmology. 2011 May;118(5):959-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3087834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21439645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins EJ, Bruce BB, Newman NJ, Biousse V. Treatment of nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. Surv Ophthalmol. 2010 Jan-Feb;55(1):47-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20006051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;ller-Leimk&#xfc;hler AM. Gender differences in cardiovascular disease and comorbid depression. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2007;9(1):71-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17506227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szanto D, Wang JK, Woods B, Garvin MK, Johnson BA, Kardon RH, Linton EF, Kupersmith MJ. Deep Learning Differentiates Papilledema, NAION, and Healthy Eyes With Unsegmented 3D OCT Volumes. Am J Ophthalmol. 2025 Sep;277:249-259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40447246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsche K, Ehrmann DA. Obstructive sleep apnea and metabolic dysfunction in polycystic ovary syndrome. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 Oct;24(5):717-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3030192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elam AR, Blachley TS, Stein JD. Geographic Variation in the Use of Diagnostic Testing of Patients with Newly Diagnosed Open-Angle Glaucoma. Ophthalmology. 2016 Mar;123(3):522-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9252164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26610719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu M, Wang SY, Singh K, Lin SC. Association between visual field defects and quality of life in the United States. Ophthalmology. 2014 Mar;121(3):733-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24342021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tournaire-Marques E. [Ischemic optic neuropathies]. J Fr Ophtalmol. 2020 Jun;43(6):552-558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32451139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waisberg E, Micieli JA. Neuro-Ophthalmological Optic Nerve Cupping: An Overview. Eye Brain. 2021;13:255-268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8684388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34934377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KM, Kim JM, Lee EJ, Kim TW. Anterior Optic Nerve Head Perfusion is Dependent on Adjacent Parapapillary Choroidal perfusion. Sci Rep. 2019 Jul 29;9(1):10999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31358897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Zhang L, Wang H, Wang Q, Jia W, Wang R, Wang R, Cui Z. Structural-Functional Correlation in Non-Arteritic Acute Ischemic Optic Neuropathy. Eye Brain. 2025;17:13-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12057633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40336777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbay J, Walter E, Kerman T, Amitai N, Gabay O, Hazan I, Abuhasira R, Tsumi E. Hypoperfusion states could increase the risk of non-arteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. PLoS One. 2024;19(11):e0313098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11588264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39585890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilley A, Bove GM. Disruption of axoplasmic transport induces mechanical sensitivity in intact rat C-fibre nociceptor axons. J Physiol. 2008 Jan 15;586(2):593-604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18006580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin LA, Louhab A. Apoptosis of retinal ganglion cells in anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. Arch Ophthalmol. 1996 Apr;114(4):488-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8602791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandoo A, van Zanten JJ, Metsios GS, Carroll D, Kitas GD. The endothelium and its role in regulating vascular tone. Open Cardiovasc Med J. 2010 Dec 23;4:302-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3040999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21339899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima MO, Rogers HJ. Hypercoagulable states: an algorithmic approach to laboratory testing and update on monitoring of direct oral anticoagulants. Blood Res. 2014 Jun;49(2):85-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4090343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25025009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater BJ, Vilson FL, Guo Y, Weinreich D, Hwang S, Bernstein SL. Optic nerve inflammation and demyelination in a rodent model of nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2013 Dec 05;54(13):7952-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3854773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24065807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fague L, Liu YA, Marsh-Armstrong N. The basic science of optic nerve regeneration. Ann Transl Med. 2021 Aug;9(15):1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8421956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34532413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas NR, Ghosh PS, Chowdhury M, Saurabh K, Roy R. Multicolor imaging in optic disc swelling. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2017 Nov;65(11):1251-1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5700612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29133670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bialer OY, Stiebel-Kalish H. Clinical characteristics of progressive nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. Int J Ophthalmol. 2021;14(4):517-522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8025159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33875941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian R, Zhou Y, Ren Y, Zhang Y, Tang W. Wallerian degeneration: From mechanism to disease to imaging. Heliyon. 2025 Jan 15;11(1):e40729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11730939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39811315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaguona VB. Differential diagnoses of the pale/white/atrophic disc. Community Eye Health. 2016;29(96):71-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5365044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28381908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt-Kastner R, Wietasch K, Weigel H, Eysel UT. Immunohistochemical staining for glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) after deafferentation or ischemic infarction in rat visual system: features of reactive and damaged astrocytes. Int J Dev Neurosci. 1993 Apr;11(2):157-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7687085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Guo Y, Slater BJ, Miller NR, Bernstein SL. Axonal degeneration, regeneration and ganglion cell death in a rodent model of anterior ischemic optic neuropathy (rAION). Exp Eye Res. 2010 Aug;91(2):286-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2907443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Sun M, Chen B, Xu X, Chen X, Wang Y, Xu Q, Zhou H, Wei S. Optic disc edema with decreased visual function after high-altitude exposure. BMC Ophthalmol. 2025 Apr 24;25(1):242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12020192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hor M, Baradeiya AM, Qasim H, Nasr M, Mohammad A. Non-Arteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy Associated With the Use of Phosphodiesterase Type 5 Inhibitors: A Literature Review. Cureus. 2022 Aug;14(8):e27642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9437418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36072219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilania RK, Arora A, Agarwal A, Jindal AK, Aggarwal K, Krishnan G, Suri D, Gupta A, Singh S, Gupta V. LINEZOLID-INDUCED MITOCHONDRIAL TOXICITY PRESENTING AS RETINAL NERVE FIBER LAYER MICROCYSTS AND OPTIC AND PERIPHERAL NEUROPATHY IN A PATIENT WITH CHRONIC GRANULOMATOUS DISEASE. Retin Cases Brief Rep. 2021 May 01;15(3):224-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pazhayattil GS, Shirali AC. Drug-induced impairment of renal function. Int J Nephrol Renovasc Dis. 2014;7:457-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4270362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25540591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhassani RY, Bagadood RM, Balubaid RN, Barno HI, Alahmadi MO, Ayoub NA. Drug Therapies Affecting Renal Function: An Overview. Cureus. 2021 Nov;13(11):e19924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8712249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34976524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil AD, Biousse V, Newman NJ. Ischemic Optic Neuropathies: Current Concepts. Ann Indian Acad Neurol. 2022 Oct;25(Suppl 2):S54-S58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9795705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaphiades MS, Al-Sadah ZM, Kline LB. Nonarteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy: Exceptions to the Rules. J Neuroophthalmol. 2021 Jun 01;41(2):e139-e141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32441900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoorbakht H, Bagherkashi F. Optic neuritis, its differential diagnosis and management. Open Ophthalmol J. 2012;6:65-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3414716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22888383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrie JR, Guzik TJ, Touyz RM. Diabetes, Hypertension, and Cardiovascular Disease: Clinical Insights and Vascular Mechanisms. Can J Cardiol. 2018 May;34(5):575-584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5953551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson L, Rebello R, Rodriguez AR. Relative Afferent Pupillary Defect with Normal Vision: Unique Localisation to the Contralateral Brachium of the Superior Colliculus. Neuroophthalmology. 2020 Apr;44(2):128-130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32395164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock SC, Hubbe RE. Color vision in anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep. 2020 Sep;19:100823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharfuddin Ahmed M, Ullah AY, Barman N, Ratan ZA, Mostafa S, Khaleque A, Kabir S, Khan MH, Haque MA. Risk factors associated with elevated intraocular pressure: a population-based study in a rural community of Bangladesh. BMJ Open Ophthalmol. 2023 Oct;8(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10582991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37844969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassi ST, Mohana KP. Optical coherence tomography in papilledema and pseudopapilledema with and without optic nerve head drusen. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2014 Dec;62(12):1146-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4313495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25579359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins P, Teixeira V, Teixeira FJ, Canastro M, Palha A, Fonseca JE, Ponte C. Giant cell arteritis with normal inflammatory markers: case report and review of the literature. Clin Rheumatol. 2020 Oct;39(10):3115-3125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32472460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadway DC. How to test for a relative afferent pupillary defect (RAPD). Community Eye Health. 2012;25(79-80):58-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23520419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey N, Chandrakar AK, Garg ML. Tests for color vision deficiency: Is it time to revise the standards? Indian J Ophthalmol. 2015 Sep;63(9):752-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26632139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedar S, Ghate D, Corbett JJ. Visual fields in neuro-ophthalmology. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2011 Mar-Apr;59(2):103-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3116538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21350279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamirel C, Newman NJ, Biousse V. Optical coherence tomography (OCT) in optic neuritis and multiple sclerosis. Rev Neurol (Paris) 2010 Dec;166(12):978-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20605617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold AC, Badr MA, Hepler RS. Fluorescein angiography in nonischemic optic disc edema. Arch Ophthalmol. 1996 Mar;114(3):293-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8600889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kermani TA, Schmidt J, Crowson CS, Ytterberg SR, Hunder GG, Matteson EL, Warrington KJ. Utility of erythrocyte sedimentation rate and C-reactive protein for the diagnosis of giant cell arteritis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2012 Jun;41(6):866-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22119103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kumari B, Kaushik A, Banerjee A, Mahto M, Bansal A. Relation Between HbA1c and Lipid Profile Among Prediabetics, Diabetics, and Non-diabetics: A Hospital-Based Cross-Sectional Analysis. Cureus. 2022 Dec;14(12):e32909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9870815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36699757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dragoni F, Chiarotti F, Rosano G, Simioni P, Tormene D, Mazzucconi MG, Cafolla A, Avvisati G. Thrombophilic screening in young patients (&lt; 40 years) with idiopathic ischemic stroke: a controlled study. Thromb Res. 2011 Feb;127(2):85-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21172722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casais P, Meschengieser SS, Gennari LC, Alberto MF, Sanchez-Luceros A, Blanco AN, Lazzari MA. Antiphospholipid antibodies and hyperhomocysteinaemia in patients with vascular occlusive disease. Thromb Haemost. 2006 Jul;96(1):19-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16807646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig IF, Pascoe AR, Kini A, Lee AG. Giant cell arteritis: early diagnosis is key. Eye Brain. 2019;11:1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6340646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30697092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayreh SS, Zimmerman MB. Nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: natural history of visual outcome. Ophthalmology. 2008 Feb;115(2):298-305.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2782939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17698200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rootman DB, Gill HS, Margolin EA. Intravitreal bevacizumab for the treatment of nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: a prospective trial. Eye (Lond) 2013 Apr;27(4):538-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23370417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeler C, Cestari DM. Non-Arteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy (NAION): A Review and Update on Animal Models. Semin Ophthalmol. 2016;31(1-2):99-106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26959135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayreh SS, Zimmerman MB. Non-arteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: role of systemic corticosteroid therapy. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2008 Jul;246(7):1029-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18404273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sena DF, Lindsley K. Neuroprotection for treatment of glaucoma in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017 Jan 25;1(1):CD006539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5370094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH, Shin GR, Choi YJ. Risk Factors for Non-arteritic Anterior Ischaemic Optic Neuropathy in a Korean Population. Neuroophthalmology. 2017 Apr;41(2):68-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5354107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adedayo AM, Olafiranye O, Smith D, Hill A, Zizi F, Brown C, Jean-Louis G. Obstructive sleep apnea and dyslipidemia: evidence and underlying mechanism. Sleep Breath. 2014 Mar;18(1):13-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4805366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22903801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding N, Sang Y, Chen J, Ballew SH, Kalbaugh CA, Salameh MJ, Blaha MJ, Allison M, Heiss G, Selvin E, Coresh J, Matsushita K. Cigarette Smoking, Smoking Cessation, and Long-Term Risk of 3&#xa0;Major&#xa0;Atherosclerotic Diseases. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019 Jul 30;74(4):498-507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31345423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickersin K, Li T. Surgery for nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015 Mar 12;2015(3):CD001538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4439207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25763979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit DP, Meyer D. Intravitreal bevacizumab: an analysis of the evidence. Clin Ophthalmol. 2007 Sep;1(3):273-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19668481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demmin DL, Silverstein SM. Visual Impairment and Mental Health: Unmet Needs and Treatment Options. Clin Ophthalmol. 2020;14:4229-4251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33299297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stunkel L, Mackay DD, Bruce BB, Newman NJ, Biousse V. Referral Patterns in Neuro-Ophthalmology. J Neuroophthalmol. 2020 Dec;40(4):485-493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31609835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz JC, Takayama K. Enzymatic synthesis of 2-O-alpha-D-mannopyranosyl-methyl-alpha-D-mannopyranoside by a cell-free particulate system of Mycobacterium smegmatis. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1976 May 28;428(3):563-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayreh SS. Ocular vascular occlusive disorders: natural history of visual outcome. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2014 Jul;41:1-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4073304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowacka B, Lubi&#x144;ski W, Ka&#x17a;mierczak B. Myelin Oligodendrocyte Glycoprotein (MOG) Antibody-Associated Optic Neuritis - A Case Report and Literature Review. Int Med Case Rep J. 2024;17:391-399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11069371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38708316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rath EZ, Hazan Z, Adamsky K, Solomon A, Segal ZI, Levin LA. Randomized Controlled Phase 2a Study of RPh201 in Previous Nonarteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy. J Neuroophthalmol. 2019 Sep;39(3):291-298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6705418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31430268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo C, Vuong LN, Micieli JA. Recent advances and future directions on the use of optical coherence tomography in neuro-ophthalmology. Taiwan J Ophthalmol. 2021 Jan-Mar;11(1):3-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7971436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falavarjani KG, Modarres M. Erythropoietin; a novel neuroprotective agent for ocular disorders. J Ophthalmic Vis Res. 2011 Jan;6(1):76-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3306067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22454713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsukura H, Takeda H, Tachiki T, Sakai K, Tanabe T, Muramatsu T. [Relationship of serum adrenaline level and the state of extracorporeal circulation]. Nihon Kyobu Geka Gakkai Zasshi. 1986 Jul;34(7):990-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3772197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ness T, Bley TA, Schmidt WA, Lamprecht P. The diagnosis and treatment of giant cell arteritis. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2013 May;110(21):376-85; quiz 386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3679627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23795218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Jo SH. Nighttime administration of antihypertensive medication: a review of chronotherapy in hypertension. Korean J Intern Med. 2024 Mar;39(2):205-214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10918378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37967524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salomon O, Huna-Baron R, Steinberg DM, Kurtz S, Seligsohn U. Role of aspirin in reducing the frequency of second eye involvement in patients with non-arteritic anterior ischaemic optic neuropathy. Eye (Lond) 1999 Jun;13 ( Pt 3a):357-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10624433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atchison E, Barkmeier A. The Role of Systemic Risk Factors in Diabetic Retinopathy. Curr Ophthalmol Rep. 2016;4(2):84-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5432556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28580199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dervenis N, Mikropoulou AM, Tranos P, Dervenis P. Ranibizumab in the Treatment of Diabetic Macular Edema: A Review of the Current Status, Unmet Needs, and Emerging Challenges. Adv Ther. 2017 Jun;34(6):1270-1282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5487872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28484955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optic nerve decompression surgery for nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy (NAION) is not effective and may be harmful. The Ischemic Optic Neuropathy Decompression Trial Research Group. JAMA. 1995 Feb 22;273(8):625-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7844872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badla O, Badla BA, Almobayed A, Mendoza C, Kishor K, Bhattacharya SK. Ischemic Optic Neuropathy: A Review of Current and Potential Future Pharmacotherapies. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 2024 Sep 27;17(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11510045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39458922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedir HM, Sisay EA, Abiye AA. Enteric-Coated Aspirin and the Risk of Gastrointestinal Side Effects: A Systematic Review. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:4757-4763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34466020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose J. Statins and its hepatic effects: Newer data, implications, and changing recommendations. J Pharm Bioallied Sci. 2016 Jan-Mar;8(1):23-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4766774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26957864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper RG. CPAP Therapeutic Options for Obstructive Sleep Apnea. Pragmat Obs Res. 2020;11:67-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32765155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderBeek BL, Bonaffini SG, Ma L. The Association between Intravitreal Steroids and Post-Injection Endophthalmitis Rates. Ophthalmology. 2015 Nov;122(11):2311-2315.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4623879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26281823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman NJ. The ischemic optic neuropathy decompression trial. Arch Ophthalmol. 2007 Nov;125(11):1568-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17998521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishant P, Gurnani B, Singh P, Sinha S, Kaur K, Kumar A, Sinha RK. Current concepts and recent trends in endothelial keratoplasty. World J Transplant. 2025 Jun 18;15(2):102507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11886285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40535500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurnani B, Kaur K, Chaudhary S, Gandhi AS, Balakrishnan H, Mishra C, Gosalia H, Dhiman S, Joshi S, Nagtode AH, Jain S, Aguiar M, Rustagi IM. Nystagmus in Clinical Practice: From Diagnosis to Treatment-A Comprehensive Review. Clin Ophthalmol. 2025;19:1617-1657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12094828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40401036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemchoknatee P, Tangon D, Srisombut T. Risk factors of developing non-arteric ischemic optic neuropathy in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a single-center retrospective cohort study. Int J Ophthalmol. 2025;18(2):290-296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39967971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabel BA, Wang J, C&#xe1;rdenas-Morales L, Faiq M, Heim C. Mental stress as consequence and cause of vision loss: the dawn of psychosomatic ophthalmology for preventive and personalized medicine. EPMA J. 2018 Jun;9(2):133-160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5972137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29896314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur K, Gurnani B. StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2023. Aug 14, Low Vision Aids.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang MY, Keltner JL. Risk Factors for Fellow Eye Involvement in Nonarteritic Anterior Ischemic Optic Neuropathy. J Neuroophthalmol. 2019 Jun;39(2):147-152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deemer AD, Goldstein JE, Ramulu PY. Approaching rehabilitation in patients with advanced glaucoma. Eye (Lond) 2023 Jul;37(10):1993-2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10333291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36526861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee AG, Biousse V. Should steroids be offered to patients with nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy? J Neuroophthalmol. 2010 Jun;30(2):193-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20523196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurnani B, Kaur K. Response to letter regarding "Evaluating the novel role of ChatGPT-4 in addressing corneal ulcer queries: An AI-powered insight". Eur J Ophthalmol. 2025 Jul 09;:11206721251357376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40629931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, Isono H, Shimada K, Chino Y. A typical case of giant cell arteritis with vision loss due to delayed diagnosis. J Gen Fam Med. 2018 Jul;19(4):139-140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6030035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29998045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappuccio FP. The Role of Nocturnal Blood Pressure and Sleep Quality in Hypertension Management. Eur Cardiol. 2020 Feb;15:e60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7479543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32944089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayreh SS. Management of ischemic optic neuropathies. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2011 Mar-Apr;59(2):123-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3116541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21350282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Sahu V, Misra S, Rathore V, Gurnani B, Kaur K. Changes in various ocular parameters of patients undergoing hemodialysis. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2025 Jun 18;:11206721251349681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40530962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>