<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40896049</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Platelet-Rich Plasma (PRP) in the Management of Rotator Cuff Tears: A Case Series From a Tertiary Care Center.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e88965</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e88965</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e88965</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.88965</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the short-term tendon healing response to a single ultrasound-guided autologous platelet-rich plasma (PRP) injection in patients aged 25-60 years with clinically and ultrasonographically confirmed unilateral, partial- to full-thickness rotator cuff tears.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This descriptive case series was conducted at the Department of Orthopedic and Spine Surgery, Ghurki Trust Teaching Hospital, Lahore, from April 25 to October 24, 2018. A total of 90 patients aged 25 to 60 years, with clinically and ultrasonographically confirmed partial- and&#xa0;full-thickness rotator cuff tears, were enrolled. Patients with diabetes mellitus, bone infections (e.g., osteomyelitis), or muscular and skeletal dystrophies were excluded. All patients received a single PRP injection administered by the principal investigator. Follow-up assessments were conducted over a 12-week period, and tendon healing was evaluated using ultrasonography. Complete healing was defined as the absence of a tear on follow-up imaging.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ninety patients were included, mean age: 41.46 &#xb1; 9.05 years; 61 males (67.78%)&#xa0;and 29 females (32.22%). Most patients (55.56%) were aged 41-60 years, and right shoulder involvement was observed in 56.67% of cases. At 12 weeks, complete tendon healing was noted in 62 patients (68.89%), while 28 patients (31.11%) showed no healing. Stratified analysis revealed no statistically significant association between healing outcomes and age (p = 0.839), gender (p = 0.141), symptom duration (p = 0.900), BMI (p = 0.504), or affected side (p = 0.327).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PRP therapy was associated with a high rate of tendon healing on ultrasonographic assessment at 12 weeks in patients with partial- to full-thickness rotator cuff tears. While these findings suggest potential short-term structural benefits, they should be interpreted with caution due to the study's descriptive design, lack of a control group, and reliance on ultrasound. Although PRP may be a useful adjunct in conservative management, especially for non-surgical candidates, current evidence supports its role primarily in symptom relief. Larger randomized controlled trials with standardized protocols and functional outcomes are needed to establish its long-term efficacy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Iqbal et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Awais</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Ghurki Trust Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, The Dudley Group NHS Foundation Trust, Dudley, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mannan</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Ghurki Trust Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Surgery, University Hospitals Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalil</LastName><ForeName>Sarmad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Ghurki Trust Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, University Hospitals Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hameed</LastName><ForeName>Malik Haroon</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Ghurki Trust Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Kettering General Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, Kettering, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karim</LastName><ForeName>Faisal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Ghurki Trust Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, University Hospitals Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Zawar</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, University Hospitals Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carter</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, Kettering General Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, Kettering, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrivastava</LastName><ForeName>Nayan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Sancheti Institute for Orthopedics and Rehabilitation, Pune, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopedics, University Hospitals Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healing rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">platelet rich plasma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotator cuff tear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound assessment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. College of Physicians and Surgeons Pakistan issued approval CPSP/REU/OSG-2016-080-1677. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40896049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12392367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.88965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Varacallo M, El Bitar Y, Sina RE, Mair SD. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Rotator cuff syndrome.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Translational research on orthobiologics in the treatment of rotator cuff disease: from the laboratory to the operating room. Eliasberg CD, Trinh PM, Rodeo SA. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev. 2024;32:33&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38695501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotator cuff tears. Bedi A, Bishop J, Keener J, et al. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2024;10:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38332156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship of acromial architecture and diseases of the rotator cuff (Article in German) Bigliani LU, Ticker JB, Flatow EL, Soslowsky LJ, Mow VC. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1745540. Orthopade. 1991;20:302&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1745540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factors associated with symptomatic rotator cuff tears: the Rotator Cuff Outcomes Workgroup cohort study. Grusky AZ, Song A, Kim P, et al. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100:331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7969413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnetic resonance imaging, magnetic resonance arthrography and ultrasonography for assessing rotator cuff tears in people with shoulder pain for whom surgery is being considered. Lenza M, Buchbinder R, Takwoingi Y, Johnston RV, Hanchard NC, Faloppa F. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;2013:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24065456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modern diagnostic imaging technique applications and risk factors in the medical field: a review. Hussain S, Mubeen I, Ullah N, et al. Biomed Res Int. 2022;2022:5164970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9192206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35707373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accuracy of MRI, MR arthrography, and ultrasound in the diagnosis of rotator cuff tears: a meta-analysis. de Jesus JO, Parker L, Frangos AJ, Nazarian LN. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2009;192:1701&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19457838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet rich plasma in arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a prospective RCT study, 2-year follow-up. Randelli P, Arrigoni P, Ragone V, Aliprandi A, Cabitza P. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2011;20:518&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21570659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma injections in the treatment of chronic rotator cuff tendinopathy: a randomized controlled trial with 1-year follow-up. Kesikburun S, Tan AK, Yilmaz B, Ya&#x15f;ar E, Yazicio&#x11f;lu K. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41:2609&#x2013;2616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23893418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current status and advancements in platelet-rich plasma therapy. Pretorius J, Habash M, Ghobrial B, Alnajjar R, Ellanti P. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10652151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38021947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma injection in non-operative treatment of partial-thickness rotator cuff tears: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zhu P, Wang Z, Li H, Cai Y. J Rehabil Med. 2022;54:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35892292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma in arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: clinical and radiological results of a prospective randomized controlled trial study at 10-year follow-up. Randelli PS, Stoppani CA, Santarsiero G, Nocerino E, Menon A. Arthroscopy. 2022;38:51&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34052372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma augmentation of arthroscopic rotator cuff repair lowers retear rates and improves short-term postoperative functional outcome scores: a systematic review of meta-analyses. Ahmad Z, Ang S, Rushton N, Harvey A, Akhtar K, Dawson-Bowling S, Noorani A. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4:0&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9042896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35494273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subacromial platelet-rich plasma injections decrease pain and improve functional outcomes in patients with refractory rotator cuff tendinopathy. Rossi LA, Piuzzi N, Giunta D, Tanoira I, Brandariz R, Pasqualini I, Ranalletta M. Arthroscopy. 2021;37:2745&#x2013;2753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence-based indications of platelet-rich plasma therapy. Gupta S, Paliczak A, Delgado D. Expert Rev Hematol. 2021;14:97&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collagen and platelet-rich plasma in partial-thickness rotator cuff injuries. Friends or only indifferent neighbours? Randomised controlled trial. Godek P, Szczepanowska-Wolowiec B, Golicki D. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23:1109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9764482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36536333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A manual method to obtain platelet rich plasma. Marques FP, Ingham SJ, Forgas A, Franciozi CE, Sasaki PH, Abdalla RJ. Acta Ortop Bras. 2014;22:75&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4031249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24868183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Different preparation methods to obtain platelet components as a source of growth factors for local application. Zimmermann R, Jakubietz R, Jakubietz M, Strasser E, Schlegel A, Wiltfang J, Eckstein R. Transfusion. 2001;41:1217&#x2013;1224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11606819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma injection can be a viable alternative to corticosteroid injection for conservative treatment of rotator cuff disease: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Pang L, Xu Y, Li T, Li Y, Zhu J, Tang X. Arthroscopy. 2023;39:402&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35810976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma augmentation for arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a randomized controlled trial. Castricini R, Longo UG, De Benedetto M, et al. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39:258&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21160018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma in rotator cuff repair: a prospective randomized study. Malavolta EA, Gracitelli ME, Ferreira Neto AA, Assun&#xe7;&#xe3;o JH, Bordalo-Rodrigues M, de Camargo OP. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2446&#x2013;2454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25086065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich fibrin matrix in the management of arthroscopic repair of the rotator cuff: a prospective, randomized, double-blinded study. Weber SC, Kauffman JI, Parise C, Weber SJ, Katz SD. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41:263&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23204506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet rich plasma: hope or hype? Yaman R, Kinard TN. Ann Blood. 2022;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of platelet-rich plasma injections for the treatment of osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Xiong Y, Gong C, Peng X, et al. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023;10:1204144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10333515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37441691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive review on platelet-rich plasma activation: a key player in accelerating skin wound healing. Patel H, Pundkar A, Shrivastava S, Chandanwale R, Jaiswal AM. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10725573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38106716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>