<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41030699</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beta-Blockers in Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction: A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e91266</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e91266</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e91266</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.91266</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF) remains a significant global health burden, with beta-blockers serving as a cornerstone therapy due to their ability to modulate neurohormonal activation and improve outcomes. However, their efficacy in post-myocardial infarction (MI) patients with preserved ejection fraction (EF) remains debated. This systematic review evaluates the clinical effects of beta-blockers in HFrEF and post-MI populations to clarify their role across different patient phenotypes. Eight randomized controlled trials (RCTs) were systematically reviewed following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. Eligible studies assessed beta-blockers in HFrEF or post-MI patients, reporting outcomes such as mortality, hospitalizations, or changes in EF. Data were extracted independently by two reviewers, and risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2 tool. A narrative synthesis was performed due to heterogeneity in study designs and interventions. Beta-blockers demonstrated significant reductions in all-cause mortality and heart failure hospitalizations in chronic HFrEF patients. In contrast, they showed neutral effects on mortality and cardiovascular outcomes in post-MI patients with preserved EF. Safety profiles were favorable, with no excess adverse events. Methodological quality was high, with most trials rated as low risk of bias. Beta-blockers are highly effective in HFrEF but offer limited benefits in post-MI patients with preserved EF. These findings support phenotype-specific therapy, reinforcing guideline recommendations for HFrEF while questioning routine use in preserved EF post-MI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Elmobark et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elmobark</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Aberdeen Royal Infirmary, Aberdeen, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamad</LastName><ForeName>Fouad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, University Hospital Galway, Galway, IRL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassan Mutwali</LastName><ForeName>Lemia Gameil</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Primary Health Care, Oman Ministry of Health, Muscat, OMN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali Mohamed Zain</LastName><ForeName>Nora Qassem Alsyed</ForeName><Initials>NQA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, SEHA Salma Rehabilitation Hospital, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>Zainab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Heartlands Hospital, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Tartel Abdelhamed</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nizwa Hospital, Nizwa, OMN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassan Almzaini</LastName><ForeName>Othman Awad</ForeName><Initials>OA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Royal Papworth Hospital, Bedfordshire, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta-blockers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure with reduced ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preserved ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41030699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12477414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.91266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global public health burden of heart failure: an updated review. Shahim B, Kapelios CJ, Savarese G, Lund LH. Card Fail Rev. 2023;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10398425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent high burden of heart failure across the ejection fraction spectrum in a nationwide setting. Stolfo D, Lund LH, Benson L, Hage C, Sinagra G, Dahlstr&#xf6;m U, Savarese G. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9750084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unraveling the complex pathophysiology of heart failure: insights into the role of renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS) and sympathetic nervous system (SNS) Maryam Maryam, Varghese TP, Tazneem B. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2024;49:102411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38246316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blocker management in patients admitted for acute heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: a review and expert consensus opinion. Schurtz G, Mewton N, Lemesle G, et al. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1263482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38050613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart failure management with &#x3b2;-blockers: can we do better? de Oliveira MT Jr, Baptista R, Chavez-Leal SA, Bonatto MG. Curr Med Res Opin. 2024;40:43&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38597068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The use of &#x3b2;-blockers in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. Masarone D, Martucci ML, Errigo V, Pacileo G. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2021;8:101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The four pillars of HFrEF therapy: is it time to treat heart failure regardless of ejection fraction? Docherty KF, Bayes-Genis A, Butler J, Coats AJ, Drazner MH, Joyce E, Lam CS. Eur Heart J Suppl. 2022;24:0&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9762881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. BMJ. 2021;372:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. BMJ. 2019;366:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blockers in patients with myocardial infarction and preserved left ventricular ejection: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sabina M, Shah S, Grimm M, et al. J Clin Med. 2024;14:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11721919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term use of carvedilol in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction treated with primary percutaneous coronary intervention. Watanabe H, Ozasa N, Morimoto T, et al. PLoS One. 2018;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6112626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blockers after myocardial infarction and preserved ejection fraction. Yndigegn T, Lindahl B, Mars K, et al. N Engl J Med. 2024;390:1372&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38587241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blocker interruption or continuation after myocardial infarction. Silvain J, Cayla G, Ferrari E, et al. N Engl J Med. 2024;391:1277&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39213187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of metoprolol CR/XL in chronic heart failure. Metoprolol CR. https://cir.nii.ac.jp/crid/1571135650384141440. Lancet. 1999;353:2001&#x2013;2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10376614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of carvedilol on survival in severe chronic heart failure. Packer M, Coats AJ, Fowler MB, et al. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:1651&#x2013;1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of carvedilol and metoprolol on clinical outcomes in patients with chronic heart failure in the Carvedilol Or Metoprolol European Trial (COMET): randomised controlled trial. Poole-Wilson PA, Swedberg K, Cleland JG, et al. Lancet. 2003;362:7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A trial of the beta-blocker bucindolol in patients with advanced chronic heart failure. Eichhorn EJ, Domanski MJ, Krause-Steinrauf H, Bristow MR, Lavori PW. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:1659&#x2013;1667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized trial to determine the effect of nebivolol on mortality and cardiovascular hospital admission in elderly patients with heart failure (SENIORS) Flather MD, Shibata MC, Coats AJ, et al. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:215&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta blockers in heart failure. Dargie HJ. Lancet (London, England) 2003;362:0&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34447992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x3b2;-Blocker use and clinical outcomes in stable outpatients with and without coronary artery disease. Bangalore S, Steg G, Deedwania P, et al. JAMA. 2012;308:1340&#x2013;1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23032550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanism of action of beta-blocking agents in heart failure. Bristow MR. Am J Cardiol. 1997;80:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9412540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of &#x3b2; blockers in patients with heart failure plus atrial fibrillation: an individual-patient data meta-analysis. Kotecha D, Holmes J, Krum H, et al. Lancet. 2014;384:2235&#x2013;2243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>org. 2008. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of metoprolol CR/XL in chronic heart failure: Metoprolol CR/XL Randomised Intervention Trial in-Congestive Heart Failure (MERIT-HF) MERIT-HF Study Group. Lancet. 1999;353:35320012007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x3b2; blockers and mortality after myocardial infarction in patients without heart failure: multicentre prospective cohort study. Puymirat E, Riant E, Aissaoui N, et al. BMJ. 2016;354:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5029148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27650822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of beta-blockade on mortality among high-risk and low-risk patients after myocardial infarction. Gottlieb SS, McCarter RJ, Vogel RA. N Engl J Med. 1998;339:489&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9709041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41029853</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiovascular diabetology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiovasc Diabetol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular and renal outcomes of dual combination therapies with glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and sodium-glucose transport protein 2 inhibitors: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>370</StartPage><MedlinePgn>370</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12933-025-02900-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Combination therapy with glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists (GLP-1RA), sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i), and/or finerenone offers a strategy to reduce the risk of adverse cardiovascular and renal outcomes. This study aimed to quantify the cardiorenal benefits of combination regimens with GLP-1RA, SGLT2i, and/or finerenone versus corresponding monotherapies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">MEDLINE and Embase were systematically searched, yielding four post hoc analyses of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and ten observational studies that met prespecified inclusion criteria. Among RCTs, a random-effects meta-regression was performed to assess whether the effect of GLP-1RAs on cardiorenal outcomes differed based on baseline SGLT2i use. Additionally, for observational studies, random-effects meta-analyses were performed to estimate the effect of combination therapy versus monotherapy on the risk of cardiorenal outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Across RCTs, p for interaction was&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05 for major adverse cardiac events (MACE) (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.730), cardiovascular (CV) mortality (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.889), non-fatal myocardial infarction (MI) (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.237), non-fatal stroke (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.696), all-cause mortality (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.682), heart failure (HF) hospitalization (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.257), and renal composite outcome (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.890), supporting that GLP-1RAs result in a consistent reduction in outcomes irrespective of baseline SGLT2i use. In observational trials, compared to SGLT2i monotherapy, GLP-1RA and SGLT2i combination therapy significantly reduced MACE (HR 0.59, 95% CI 0.47-0.75), MI (HR 0.73, 95% CI 0.61-0.88), stroke (HR 0.72, 95% CI 0.53-0.97), all-cause mortality (HR 0.57, 95% CI 0.48-0.67), and HF hospitalization/events (HR 0.71, 95% CI 0.59-0.86). Compared to GLP-1RA monotherapy, SGLT2i and GLP-1RA combination therapy significantly reduced CV mortality (HR 0.35, 95% CI 0.15-0.81), MI (HR 0.93, 95% CI 0.88-0.97), stroke (HR 0.92, 95% CI 0.88-0.96), all-cause mortality (HR 0.59, 95% 0.49-0.70), HF hospitalization/events (HR 0.84, 95% CI 0.81-0.88), and serious renal events (HR 0.43, 95% CI 0.23-0.80). Compared to either SGLT2i or finerenone monotherapy, SGLT2i and finerenone combination therapy significantly reduced all-cause mortality and major adverse kidney events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Combination therapy with GLP-1RA, SGLT2i, or finerenone confers cardiorenal protection beyond monotherapy in T2D, as supported by concordant evidence from RCTs and large real-world cohorts. These findings support broader clinical adoption of dual-agent strategies but also underscore the need for dedicated prospective trials powered to assess hard clinical outcomes with dual-agent strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shokravi</LastName><ForeName>Arveen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, V6T 1Z4, Canada. shokravi@student.ubc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seth</LastName><ForeName>Jayant</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, V6T 1Z4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mancini</LastName><ForeName>G B John</ForeName><Initials>GBJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, V6T 1Z4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Cardiovascular Innovation, Dilwari Cardiovascular Institute, Division of Cardiology, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, V5Z 1M9, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiovasc Diabetol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101147637</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-2840</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077203">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000097789">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D054795">Incretins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C576501">finerenone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000593833">GLP1R protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000067757">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009287">Naphthyridines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000097789" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054795" MajorTopicYN="Y">Incretins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007674" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064887" MajorTopicYN="N">Observational Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067757" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009287" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Naphthyridines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiometabolic risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combination therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Finerenone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GLP-1 receptor agonist</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renal outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SGLT2 inhibitor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. This study is a meta-analysis and did not involve direct recruitment of human participants. Competing interests: Arveen Shokravi, and Jayant Seth, have no conflicts of interest to declare. G.B. John Mancini reports receiving honoraria from Eli Lilly, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novo Nordisk, GlaxoSmithKline, and Bayer.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41029853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02900-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12933-025-02900-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Zhou XD, Shapiro MD, et al. Global burden of metabolic diseases, 1990&#x2013;2021. Metabolism. 2024;160: 155999. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.metabol.2024.155999 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2024.155999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39151887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu XY, Shi MQ, Jiang ZM, Xiao-Li, Tian JW, Su FF. Global, regional, and national burden of cardiovascular diseases attributable to metabolic risks across all age groups from 1990 to 2021: an analysis of the 2021 global burden of disease study data. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):1704. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-025-22702-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakris GL, Agarwal R, Anker SD, et al. Effect of finerenone on chronic kidney disease outcomes in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(23):2219&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2025845 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2025845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitt B, Filippatos G, Agarwal R, et al. Cardiovascular events with finerenone in kidney disease and type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(24):2252&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2110956 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2110956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, McMurray JJV, Vaduganathan M, et al. Finerenone in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(16):1475&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2407107 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2407107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39225278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee, ElSayed NA, McCoy RG, et al. Pharmacologic approaches to glycemic treatment: standards of care in diabetes&#x2014;2025. Diabetes Care. 2025;48(Supplement_1):S181&#x2013;206. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc25-S009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc25-S009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das SR, Everett BM, Birtcher KK, et al. 2020 Expert consensus decision pathway on novel therapies for cardiovascular risk reduction in patients with type 2 diabetes. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(9):1117&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2020.05.037 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.05.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32771263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7545583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx N, Federici M, Sch&#xfc;tt K, et al. 2023 ESC guidelines for the management of cardiovascular disease in patients with diabetes. Eur Heart J. 2023;44(39):4043&#x2013;140. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad192 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehad192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37622663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourdy P, Darmon P, Dievart F, Halimi JM, Guerci B. Combining glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists (GLP-1RAs) and sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors (SGLT2is) in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22(1):79. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-023-01798-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-01798-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37005640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10067319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossing P, Caramori ML, Chan JCN, et al. KDIGO 2022 clinical practice guideline for diabetes management in chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int. 2022;102(5):S1&#x2013;127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.kint.2022.06.008 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2022.06.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaneethan SD, Bansal N, Cavanaugh KL, et al. KDOQI US commentary on the KDIGO 2024 clinical practice guideline for the evaluation and management of CKD. Am J Kidney Dis. 2025;85(2):135&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.ajkd.2024.08.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2024.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39556063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n71 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8479591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apperloo EM, Neuen BL, Fletcher RA, et al. Efficacy and safety of SGLT2 inhibitors with and without glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonists: a SMART-C collaborative meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2024;12(8):545&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(24)00155-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(24)00155-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38991584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossing P, Agarwal R, Anker SD, et al. Finerenone in patients across the spectrum of chronic kidney disease and type 2 diabetes by glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist use. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2023;25(2):407&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.14883 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.14883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36193847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossing P, Anker SD, Filippatos G, et al. Finerenone in patients with chronic kidney disease and type 2 diabetes by sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor treatment: the FIDELITY analysis. Diabetes Care. 2022;45(12):2991&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc22-0294 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc22-0294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35972218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9862372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Kulac IJ, et al. Effects of the nonsteroidal MRA finerenone with and without concomitant SGLT2 inhibitor use in heart failure. Circulation. 2025;151(2):149&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072055 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39340828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne J, Savovi&#x107; J, Page M, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Published online 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells G, Shea B, O&#x2019;Connell D, et al. The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses. Published online 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw. 2010. https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v036.i03 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v036.i03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer G, Carpenter JR, R&#xfc;cker G. Meta-analysis with R. London: Springer International Publishing; 2015. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-21416-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-21416-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves JS, Borges-Canha M, Vasques-N&#xf3;voa F, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonist therapy with and without SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with type 2 diabetes. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;82(6):517&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.05.048 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2023.05.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37532422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JFE, Rossing P, Bakris G, et al. Effects of semaglutide with and without concomitant SGLT2 inhibitor use in participants with type 2 diabetes and chronic kidney disease in the FLOW trial. Nat Med. 2024;30(10):2849&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-024-03133-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-03133-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38914124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11485243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx N, Deanfield JE, Mann JFE, et al. Oral semaglutide and cardiovascular outcomes in people with type 2 diabetes, according to SGLT2i use: prespecified analyses of the SOUL randomized trial. Circulation. 2025;151(23):1639&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.125.074545 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.125.074545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40156843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12144549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam CSP, Ramasundarahettige C, Branch KRH, et al. Efpeglenatide and clinical outcomes with and without concomitant Sodium-Glucose Cotransporter-2 inhibition use in type 2 diabetes: exploratory analysis of the AMPLITUDE-O trial. Circulation. 2022;145(8):565&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.057934 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.057934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34775781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire DK, Marx N, Mulvagh SL, et al. Oral semaglutide and cardiovascular outcomes in high-risk type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2501006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2501006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40802953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez AF, Green JB, Janmohamed S, et al. Albiglutide and cardiovascular outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease (Harmony outcomes): a double-blind, randomised placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2018;392(10157):1519&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32261-X .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32261-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30291013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkovic V, Tuttle KR, Rossing P, et al. Effects of semaglutide on chronic kidney disease in patients with type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(2):109&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2403347 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2403347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38785209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerstein HC, Sattar N, Rosenstock J, et al. Cardiovascular and renal outcomes with efpeglenatide in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(10):896&#x2013;907. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2108269 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2108269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang MH, Wang HY, Kan WC, et al. Cardio-kidney outcomes for combined versus monotherapy with finerenone or SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with CKD. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1093/ndt/gfaf064 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gfaf064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40199739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12477464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Fan Z, Li Y, Xiao B, He C. Combination treatment of SGLT2i and GLP-1RA associated with improved cardiovascular outcomes in type 2 diabetes patients with acute coronary syndrome: a propensity score-matched cohort study. Int J Cardiol. 2025;431: 133229. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2025.133229 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2025.133229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40187657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaiyakunapruk N, Tan X, Liang Y, Guevarra M, Xie L, Cheng AYY. Real-world effectiveness of adding newer generation GLP-1RA to SGLT2i in type 2 diabetes. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):177. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-025-02737-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02737-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12023599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simms-Williams N, Treves N, Yin H, et al. Effect of combination treatment with glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors on incidence of cardiovascular and serious renal events: population based cohort study. BMJ. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2023-078242 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2023-078242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38663919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11043905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel R, Wadid M, Makwana B, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists among patients with overweight or obesity, diabetes, and HFpEF on SGLT2 inhibitors. JACC: Heart Fail. 2024;12(11):1814&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchf.2024.07.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchf.2024.07.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39207323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marfella R, Prattichizzo F, Sardu C, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists-SGLT-2 inhibitors combination therapy and cardiovascular events after acute myocardial infarction: an observational study in patients with type 2 diabetes. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):10. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-023-02118-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-02118-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38184582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10771648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhu J, Fang Y, Huang C, Liou H, Chen M, Tsai M. Enhanced renoprotective effects of combined glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes mellitus: real-world evidence. J Diabetes Investig. 2025;16(2):204&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1111/jdi.14361 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdi.14361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39569871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Vega D, Cinza-Sanjurjo S, Eiras S, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Juanatey JR. Combined sodium-glucose-transporters inhibitors and glucagon-like-peptide receptor agonist compared with monotherapy improves long-term survival: a real-world registry. Am J Med. 2024;137(8):761-769.e1. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.04.032 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2024.04.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38729592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley DR, Essa H, Austin P, et al. All-cause mortality and cardiovascular outcomes with sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors, glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and with combination therapy in people with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2023;25(10):2897&#x2013;909. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.15185 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.15185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37385958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez PD, Bhatia K, Bohra C, Mahmood K, Baruch L, Eng C. Benefits of adding glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonists to sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors in diabetic patients with atherosclerotic disease and heart failure. Am J Cardiol. 2022;181:87&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjcard.2022.07.012 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2022.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35963825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuen BL, Fletcher RA, Heath L, et al. Cardiovascular, kidney, and safety outcomes with GLP-1 receptor agonists alone and in combination with SGLT2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Circulation. 2024;150(22):1781&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071689 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39210781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Luo J, Jiang M, Wang K. The efficacy and safety of the combination therapy with GLP-1 receptor agonists and SGLT-2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13: 838277. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2022.838277 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.838277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35185588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8854770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal R, Green JB, Heerspink HJL, et al. Finerenone with empagliflozin in chronic kidney disease and type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2410659 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2410659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41020526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heerspink HJL, Greene T, Tighiouart H, et al. Change in albuminuria as a surrogate endpoint for progression of kidney disease: a meta-analysis of treatment effects in randomised clinical trials. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2019;7(2):128&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(18)30314-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(18)30314-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Filippatos G, Claggett BL, et al. Finerenone in heart failure and chronic kidney disease with type 2 diabetes: FINE-HEART pooled analysis of cardiovascular, kidney and mortality outcomes. Nat Med. 2024;30(12):3758&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-024-03264-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-03264-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39218030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11645272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colorado Prevention Center. A Study to Determine the Efficacy and Safety of Finerenone and SGLT2i in Combination in Hospitalized Patients with Heart Failure (CONFIRMATION-HF) (CONFIRMATION). https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06024746</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu CY. Observational studies: a review of study designs, challenges and strategies to reduce confounding. Int J Clin Pract. 2009;63(5):691&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1742-1241.2009.02056.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1742-1241.2009.02056.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19392919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangaswami J, Bhalla V, De Boer IH, et al. Cardiorenal protection with the newer antidiabetic agents in patients with diabetes and chronic kidney disease: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000920 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvatore T, Galiero R, Caturano A, et al. An overview of the cardiorenal protective mechanisms of SGLT2 inhibitors. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(7): 3651. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23073651 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23073651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35409011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8998569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ussher JR, Drucker DJ. Glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonists: cardiovascular benefits and mechanisms of action. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2023;20(7):463&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-023-00849-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41569-023-00849-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36977782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevella P, Ekinci EI, MacIsaac RJ. Potential kidney protective effects of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists. Nephrology. 2024;29(8):457&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1111/nep.14336 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nep.14336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39030739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park B, Bakbak E, Teoh H, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists and atherosclerosis protection: the vascular endothelium takes center stage. Am J Physiol-Heart Circ Physiol. 2024;326(5):H1159&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00574.2023 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00574.2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38426865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv R, Xu L, Che L, Liu S, Wang Y, Dong B. Cardiovascular-renal protective effect and molecular mechanism of finerenone in type 2 diabetic mellitus. Front Endocrinol. 2023;14:1125693. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2023.1125693 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1125693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vale C, Louren&#xe7;o IM, Jordan G, et al. Early combination therapy with SGLT2i and GLP -1 RA or dual GIP / GLP -1 RA in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2025;27(2):468&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.16077 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.16077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39604324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah M, Awad AS, Abdel-Rahman EM. Nonsteroidal mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist (finerenone) in cardiorenal disease. J Clin Med. 2023;12(19): 6285. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm12196285 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12196285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37834929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10573495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivas TR, Ho B, Kang J, Kaplan B. Post hoc analyses: after the facts. Transplantation. 2015;99(1):17&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1097/TP.0000000000000581 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TP.0000000000000581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25525920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 6.5 (Updated August 2024). Cochrane; 2024. https://www.training.cochrane.org/handbook</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrowman MA, Peek N, Lambie M, Martin GP, Sperrin M. How unmeasured confounding in a competing risks setting can affect treatment effect estimates in observational studies. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2019;19(1):166. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12874-019-0808-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-019-0808-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31366331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6668192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41029336</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiovascular diabetology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiovasc Diabetol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Type 2 diabetes, sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors and cardiovascular outcomes: real world evidence versus a randomised clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>371</StartPage><MedlinePgn>371</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12933-025-02924-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) have demonstrated cardiovascular benefits in randomised controlled trials (RCT). However, the controlled nature of RCTs and the selected trial populations limit their generalizability to real-world practice. Substantial methodological advances now enable robust estimation of absolute risks, risk differences, and continuous on-treatment effects, providing more clinically interpretable measures of SGLT2i effectiveness than previously possible with traditional models reliant on hazard ratios.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a target trial emulation using nationwide Danish registries to evaluate the real-world effectiveness of SGLT2i versus dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors (DPP4i) in individuals with type 2 diabetes (T2D) and cardiovascular disease (CVD). Outcomes included major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE), heart failure hospitalizations, and all-cause mortality. Absolute risks and risk differences for three years of continuous treatment were estimated using longitudinal targeted minimum loss-based estimation, adjusting for baseline and time-varying confounders.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 116,823 patients who redeemed SGLT2i or DPP4i for the first time, 13,524 met inclusion and exclusion criteria (SGLT2i: 6,025; DPP4i: 7,499). At three years, the risk of MACE was 11.5% for SGLT2i users versus 14.2% for DPP4i users (risk-difference: 2.8 percentage-points, 95% CI: 1.1-4.4%). Heart failure hospitalizations were lower by 5.1 percentage-points (95% CI: 4.3-6.0%), and all-cause mortality by 3.1 percentage-points (95% CI: 1.5-4.7%), all favoring SGLT2i. Notably, we also observed a risk reduction in stroke by 2.4 percentage-points (95% CI: 1.7-3.1%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates the real-world effectiveness of continuous SGLT2i treatment in reducing cardiovascular events in patients with T2D and CVD. The absolute benefit of SGLT2i was larger in a real world population than in the intention to treat estimate in clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yazdanfard</LastName><ForeName>Puriya Daniel W&#xfc;rtz</ForeName><Initials>PDW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Clinical and Translational Research, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Borgmester Ib Juuls Vej 83, 2730, Herlev, Denmark. puriya.daniel.wuertz.yazdanfard@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, North Zealand University Hospital, Hiller&#xf8;d, Denmark. puriya.daniel.wuertz.yazdanfard@regionh.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xf8;rensen</LastName><ForeName>Kathrine Kold</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Clinical and Translational Research, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Borgmester Ib Juuls Vej 83, 2730, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, North Zealand University Hospital, Hiller&#xf8;d, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zareini</LastName><ForeName>Bochra</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, North Zealand University Hospital, Hiller&#xf8;d, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedersen-Bjergaard</LastName><ForeName>Ulrik</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology Section, Department of Endocrinology and Nephrology, North Zealand University Hospital, Hiller&#xf8;d, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohlendorff</LastName><ForeName>Johan Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Biostatistics, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munch</LastName><ForeName>Anders</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Biostatistics, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Mikkel Porsborg</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Clinical and Translational Research, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Borgmester Ib Juuls Vej 83, 2730, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, North Zealand University Hospital, Hiller&#xf8;d, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prehospital Center, Region Zealand, Naestved, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasselbalch</LastName><ForeName>Rasmus Bo</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imberg</LastName><ForeName>Henrik</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tasseleus</LastName><ForeName>Viktor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health and Community Medicine, Institute of Medicine University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lind</LastName><ForeName>Marcus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, Institute of Medicine, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valabhji</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metabolism, Digestion and Reproduction, Faculty of Medicine, Chelsea and Westminster Hospital Campus, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choudhary</LastName><ForeName>Pratik</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khunti</LastName><ForeName>Kamlesh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmid</LastName><ForeName>Stefanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology and Medical Biometry, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Diabetes Research (DZD), Munich-Neuherberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lanzinger</LastName><ForeName>Stefanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology and Medical Biometry, Ulm University, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Diabetes Research (DZD), Munich-Neuherberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mader</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerds</LastName><ForeName>Thomas Alexander</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Biostatistics, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torp-Pedersen</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Clinical and Translational Research, Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Borgmester Ib Juuls Vej 83, 2730, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, North Zealand University Hospital, Hiller&#xf8;d, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Biostatistics, Department of Public Health, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>REDDIE consortium</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiovasc Diabetol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101147637</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-2840</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077203">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D054873">Dipeptidyl-Peptidase IV Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003718" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Denmark</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054873" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dipeptidyl-Peptidase IV Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="Y">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012042" MajorTopicYN="N">Registries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: Competing interests (none for authors if nothing is stated): CTP received study grants in the past 36 months from Bayer and Novo Nordisk. ML received payment to own company for education of diabetes by Boehringer Ingelheim, Novo Nordisk and Eli Lilly. UBP received lecture fees and personal payments by Abott, Novo Nordisk and Sanofi with the addition of EASD meeting support from the latter two. JKM is a member of advisory boards of Abbott Diabetes Care, Becton-Dickinson, Biomea Fusion, Dexcom, Eli Lilly, Embecta, Medtronic, myLife, Novo Nordisk A/S, Pharmasens, Roche Diabetes Care, Sanofi-Aventis, Tandem, Viatris and received speaker honoraria from A. Menarini Diagnostics, Abbott Diabetes Care, Dexcom, Eli Lilly, Medtrust, MSD, Novo Nordisk A/S, Roche Diabetes Care, Sanofi, Viatris and Ypsomed. She is a shareholder of decide Clinical Software GmbH and elyte Diagnostics and serves as CMO of elyte Diagnostics. KK has recieved consulting frees and payment as speaker from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Lilly, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi, Servier, Pfizer, Roche, Daiichi-Sankyo, Embecta and Nestle Health Science. With the addition of grants from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Lilly, MSD, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi, Servier, Oramed Pharmaceuticals, Roche, Daiichi-Sankyo, Applied Therapeutics. JV receives support/grants from &#x2018;The north west london NIHR applied research collaboration including other NIHR grants, EU Horizon / UKRI grant and CW+ the official charity of Chelsea Westminster hospital NHS foundation trust. Additionally, JV was International Advisor for the Ministry of Public Health in Qatar&#x2019;s &#x201c;Diabetes, Obesity and Atherosclerotic Cardiovascular Disease Strategy 2024 to 2030&#x201d;, for a 3-month period in 2024.PC has received personal fees from Medtronic, Insulet, Dexcom, Abbott, Vertex, Lilly, Novo Nordisk and Sanofi. He has received research support from Abbott, Dexcom, Medtronic, Sanofi and Novo Nordisk.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41029336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02924-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12933-025-02924-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zinman B, Wanner C, Lachin JM, Fitchett D, Bluhmki E, Hantel S, et al. Empagliflozin, cardiovascular outcomes, and mortality in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2015;373(22):2117&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1504720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duenas JAC, Sanchez PN, Bonilla CE. Comparison of clinical outcomes among cancer patients treated in and out of clinical trials. BMC Cancer. 2023;23(1):786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-023-11305-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37612602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10463452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanche P, Zareini B, Rasmussen PV. A hazard ratio above one does not necessarily mean higher risk, when using a time-dependent Cox model. Res Methods Med Health Sci. 2022;3(2):42&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wax Y, Galai N, Carey V, Simchen E. Cox regression models for intermediate events, with discharge from hospital as an example. Epidemiol Camb Mass. 1993;4(2):120&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00001648-199303000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;n MA. The hazards of hazard ratios. Epidemiol Camb Mass. 2010;21(1):13&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EDE.0b013e3181c1ea43</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansournia MA, Etminan M, Danaei G, Kaufman JS, Collins G. Handling time varying confounding in observational research. BMJ. 2017;359:j4587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j4587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29038130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen M, Schwab J, Gruber S, Blaser N, Schomaker M, van der Laan M. Targeted maximum likelihood Estimation for dynamic and static longitudinal marginal structural working models. J Causal Inference. 2014; 18(2):147&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jci-2013-0007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JB, Bethel MA, Armstrong PW, Buse JB, Engel SS, Garg J, et al. Effect of sitagliptin on cardiovascular outcomes in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2015 ;16(3):232&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;n MA, Wang W, Leaf DE. Target trial emulation: A framework for causal inference from observational data. JAMA. 2022;328(24):2446&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.21383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36508210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber S, Lee H, Phillips R, Ho M, van der Laan M. Developing a Targeted Learning-Based Statistical Analysis Plan. Stat Biopharm Res. 2023;15(3):468&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdanfard PD, S&#xf8;rensen KK, Consortium TR, Torp-Pedersen C. Statistical analysis plan: Emulation of a Target Trial in an EMPA-REG inspired population using the Danish registries. SGLT2i compared to DPP4i on Cardiovascular outcomes. 2024 July 10 [cited 2024 Dec 16]; Available from: https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.12705109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen CB. The Danish civil registration system. Scand J Public Health. 2011;39(7 Suppl):22&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt M, Schmidt SAJ, Sandegaard JL, Ehrenstein V, Pedersen L, S&#xf8;rensen HT. The Danish National patient registry: a review of content, data quality, and research potential. Clin Epidemiol. 2015;7:449&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CLEP.S91125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4655913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kildemoes HW, S&#xf8;rensen HT, Hallas J. The Danish National prescription registry. Scand J Public Health. 2011;39(7 Suppl):38&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helweg-Larsen K. The Danish register of causes of death. Scand J Public Health. 2011;39(7 Suppl):26&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baadsgaard M, Quitzau J. Danish registers on personal income and transfer payments. Scand J Public Health. 2011;39(7_suppl):103&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vm J, Aw R. Danish Education Registers. Scand J Public Health [Internet]. 2011 July [cited 2025 Jan 6];39(7 Suppl). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21775362/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendt JFH, Hansen AT, Ladefoged SA, S&#xf8;rensen HT, Pedersen L, Adelborg K. Existing data sources in clinical epidemiology: laboratory information system databases in Denmark. Clin Epidemiol. 2020;12:469&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CLEP.S245060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32547238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7244445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen ME, Kristensen JK, Reventlov Husted G, Cerqueira C, Rossing P. The Danish adult diabetes registry. Clin Epidemiol. 2016;8:429&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CLEP.S99518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27843339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5098513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Laan MJ, Gruber S. Targeted minimum loss based Estimation of causal effects of multiple time point interventions. Int J Biostat. 2012;8(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam H. A Cheap Bootstrap Method for Fast Inference [Internet]. arXiv; 2022 [cited 2024 Dec 16]. Available from: http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.00090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolisso P, Bergamaschi L, Gragnano F, Gallinoro E, Cesaro A, Sardu C, et al. Outcomes in diabetic patients treated with SGLT2-Inhibitors with acute myocardial infarction undergoing PCI: the SGLT2-I AMI PROTECT registry. Pharmacol Res. 2023;187:106597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36470546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolisso P, Belmonte M, Gallinoro E, Scarsini R, Bergamaschi L, Portolan L, et al. SGLT2-inhibitors in diabetic patients with severe aortic stenosis and cardiac damage undergoing transcatheter aortic valve implantation (TAVI). Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02504-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39574095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11583434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thein D, Christiansen MN, Mogensen UM, Bundgaard JS, R&#xf8;rth R, Madelaire C et al. Add-on therapy in metformin-treated patients with type 2 diabetes at moderate cardiovascular risk: a nationwide study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2020;19(1):107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nystr&#xf6;m T, Bodegard J, Nathanson D, Thuresson M, Norhammar A, Eriksson JW. Novel oral glucose-lowering drugs are associated with lower risk of all-cause mortality, cardiovascular events and severe hypoglycaemia compared with insulin in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2017;19(6):831&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohsaka S, Lam CSP, Kim DJ, Cavender MA, Norhammar A, J&#xf8;rgensen ME, et al. Risk of cardiovascular events and death associated with initiation of SGLT2 inhibitors compared with DPP&#x2013;4 inhibitors: an analysis from the CVD-REAL 2 multinational cohort study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2020;8(7):606&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasternak B, Ueda P, Eliasson B, Svensson AM, Franz&#xe9;n S, Gudbj&#xf6;rnsdottir S, et al. Use of sodium glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors and risk of major cardiovascular events and heart failure: Scandinavian register based cohort study. BMJ. 2019;366:l4772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31467044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6713906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang HY, Kim IW, Oh JM. Using real-world data for supporting regulatory decision making: comparison of cardiovascular and safety outcomes of an empagliflozin randomized clinical trial versus real-world data. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:928121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.928121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36110539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9468970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molero-Calafell J, Bur&#xf3;n A, Castells X, Porta M. Intention to treat and per protocol analyses: differences and similarities. J Clin Epidemiol [Internet]. 2024 Sept 1 [cited 2024 Dec 16];173. Available from: https://www.jclinepi.com/article/S0895&#x2013;4356%2824%2900213&#x2013;0/fulltext?utm_source=chatgpt.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y, Lim C, Watson JA, White NJ, Cooper BS. Non-adherence in non-inferiority trials: pitfalls and recommendations. BMJ. 2020 July 1;m2215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitkala KH, Strandberg TE. Clinical trials in older people. Age Ageing. 2022;51(5):afab282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afab282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9080968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock J, Perkovic V, Johansen OE, Cooper ME, Kahn SE, Marx N, et al. Effect of linagliptin vs placebo on major cardiovascular events in adults with type 2 diabetes and high cardiovascular and renal risk: the CARMELINA randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2019;321(1):69&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2018.18269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30418475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkovic V, Jardine MJ, Neal B, Bompoint S, Heerspink HJL, Charytan DM, et al. Canagliflozin and renal outcomes in type 2 diabetes and nephropathy. N Engl J Med. 2019;13(24):2295&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White WB, Cannon CP, Heller SR, Nissen SE, Bergenstal RM, Bakris GL, et al. Alogliptin after acute coronary syndrome in patients with type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2013;369(14):1327&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1305889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scirica BM, Bhatt DL, Braunwald E, Steg PG, Davidson J, Hirshberg B, et al. Saxagliptin and cardiovascular outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. N Engl J Med. 2013;369(14):1317&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1307684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Kosiborod M, Kim DJ, Kohsaka S, Lam CSP, Goh SY, et al. Cardiovascular outcomes with sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter&#x2013;2 inhibitors vs other glucose-lowering drugs in 13 countries across three continents: analysis of CVD-REAL data. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;31(1):159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armillotta M, Angeli F, Paolisso P, Belmonte M, Raschi E, Di Dalmazi G, et al. Cardiovascular therapeutic targets of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors beyond heart failure. Pharmacol Ther. 2025;1:270:108861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedele D, Casuso Alvarez M, Maida A, Vasumini N, Amicone S, Canton L, et al. Prevention of atrial fibrillation with SGLT2 inhibitors across the spectrum of cardiovascular disorders: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur Heart J - Cardiovasc Pharmacother. 2025;11(5):441&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ehjcvp/pvaf040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40464647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12342982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Laan MJ, Rose S. Targeted Learning in Data Science: Causal Inference for Complex Longitudinal Studies [Internet]. Springer International Publishing; 2018. (Springer Series in Statistics). Available from: https://books.google.dk/books?id=vKFTDwAAQBAJ</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernan MA, Robins JM. Causal Inference: What If [Internet]. CRC Press;, Chapman. &amp; Hall/CRC Monographs on Statistics &amp; Applied Probab). Available from: https://books.google.dk/books?id=_KnHIAAACAAJ</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41027509</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8414</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiac failure</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Card Fail</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Derivation of a Personalized Congestion Score Using a Chronic Implantable Inferior Vena Cava Management System in Heart Failure: An Analysis from the FUTURE-HF Trial Portfolio.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1071-9164(25)00430-0</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cardfail.2025.09.018</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Congestion is a principal driver of worsening heart failure (HF) and hospitalisation. The large, compliant Inferior Vena Cava (IVC) enables detection of congestion before increases in filling pressures. We developed a novel, patient-individualised congestion score (NORM Score) using daily ambulatory IVC measurements-area and collapsibility-from an implantable sensor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using clinical data from 2 early feasibility trials (FUTURE-HF; NCT04203576 and FUTURE-HF2; NCT05763407), a congestion Score (range: 0-100) was derived from daily supine IVC area (breath hold and free breathing) and collapsibility in patients implanted with a novel IVC sensor. A clinical alert was triggered if the score exceeded 70% of a patient's maximum for 5 of 7 days. Performance was evaluated against adjudicated HF events (HFEs) and NT-proBNP levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 63 patients (mean age 66-years, 75% NYHA III), 30 HFEs occurred in 18 individuals. Score predicted HFEs with 92.6% sensitivity, high predictive accuracy (C-statistic: 0.83) and low unexplained alert rate (0.57 per patient-year). Breaching the alert threshold was associated with an Odds Ratio of 18 (95% CI: 3.5-93.8) for hospitalization within 7 days. The congestion score was significantly associated with log-transformed NT-proBNP (&#x3b2;=5.64;95% CI: 3.23-8.05; p&lt;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The unique congestion score, derived from an ambulatory implantable IVC management system, was associated with NT-proBNP levels and predicted worsening HF events with high sensitivity. These findings, once validated in a pivotal randomized trial, will support use of this novel congestion score for early detection of HF decompensation, streamline clinical response, and enable personalized patient self-management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LAY SUMMARY" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Heart failure often causes fluid buildup, a leading reason for hospitalization. Traditional monitors may miss early signs. This study evaluated the NORM score, which uses an implantable sensor in the inferior vena cava to track daily vein size and movement. The score accurately detected early congestion and monitored NT-proBNP levels, suggesting it could enable earlier intervention and reduce hospital visits for heart failure patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fudim</LastName><ForeName>Marat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Duke University Medical Center, Durham, NC, USA. Electronic address: marat.fudim@duke.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehra</LastName><ForeName>Mandeep R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital Heart and Vascular Center and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damman</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Groningen, Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uriel</LastName><ForeName>Nir</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Columbia University Irving Medical Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalra</LastName><ForeName>Paul R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Queen Alexandra Hospital, Portsmouth Hospitals University NHS Trust, Portsmouth, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sweeney</LastName><ForeName>Fiachra</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundry Innovation &amp; Research1 Ltd DCU Alpha Innovation Campus, Old Finglas Road, Glasnevin, Dublin 11, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carmody</LastName><ForeName>Daire</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundry Innovation &amp; Research1 Ltd DCU Alpha Innovation Campus, Old Finglas Road, Glasnevin, Dublin 11, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundry Innovation &amp; Research1 Ltd DCU Alpha Innovation Campus, Old Finglas Road, Glasnevin, Dublin 11, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greene</LastName><ForeName>Barry R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foundry Innovation &amp; Research1 Ltd DCU Alpha Innovation Campus, Old Finglas Road, Glasnevin, Dublin 11, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Testani</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Future HF Portfolio Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Card Fail</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9442138</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1071-9164</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Congestion score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inferior vena cava</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Remote monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41027509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cardfail.2025.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1071-9164(25)00430-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41027306</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1768-3181</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>74</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annales de cardiologie et d'angeiologie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Cardiol Angeiol (Paris)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Left bundle branch area pacing and resynchronization in heart failure].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101955</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101955</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ancard.2025.101955</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0003-3928(25)00094-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Left bundle branch block pacing (LBBAP) is a recent technique for capturing conduction pathways to allow physiological ventricular activation. It is technically more reliable than Hisian pacing and can correct proximal left bundle branch block. In this context, numerous registries and the first small randomized studies have evaluated the benefit of left bundle branch block pacing compared to conventional resynchronization therapy, with encouraging results in favor of LBBAP. More robust randomized studies are underway. A consensus document has included this strategy as a possible first-line option and is recommended in cases of failure of conventional resynchronization therapy. Manufacturers are developing dedicated equipment with LBBAP pacing integrated into the defibrillation lead.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Masson SAS. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taieb</LastName><ForeName>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre hospitalier Aix en Provence Avenue des Tamaris 13100 Aix en Provence, France. Electronic address: jtaieb@ch-aix.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amara</LastName><ForeName>Walid</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre hospitalier Montfermeil 10 rue du General Leclerc, 93370 Montfermeil, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>fre</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Stimulation de l&#x2019;aire de la branche gauche et resynchronisation dans l&#x2019;insuffisance cardiaque.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Cardiol Angeiol (Paris)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0142167</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-3928</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aire branche gauche</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Left bundle branch area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Specialized conduction system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Voie de conduction sp&#xe9;cialis&#xe9;e</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>D&#xe9;claration de liens d&#x2019;int&#xe9;r&#xea;ts Les auteurs d&#xe9;clarent ne pas avoir de liens d&#x2019;int&#xe9;r&#xea;ts.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41027306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ancard.2025.101955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0003-3928(25)00094-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>