<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40955256</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Empagliflozin and Cardiovascular Outcomes: A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials in Populations With Diabetes and Heart Failure.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e90150</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e90150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e90150</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.90150</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiovascular disease is a principal cause of morbidity and mortality worldwide, disproportionately affecting individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and heart failure. Empagliflozin, a sodium-glucose cotransporter 2&#xa0;inhibitor, has shown promising cardioprotective effects beyond its glucose-lowering properties. This systematic review was conducted according to Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines, involving a comprehensive literature search of PubMed, Scopus, Embase, and Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL) from inception to May 2025. Randomized controlled trials evaluating empagliflozin in adult patients with T2DM or heart failure and reporting cardiovascular outcomes were included. A total of 13 RCTs comprising 21,669 participants were synthesized, encompassing a broad spectrum of populations, including high-risk T2DM, chronic heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF) and heart failure with preserved ejection fraction (HFpEF), and post-myocardial infarction cohorts. Empagliflozin was consistently associated with significant reductions in major adverse cardiovascular events, notably a 14-38% reduction in cardiovascular mortality and a 23-35% reduction in heart failure hospitalizations across key trials, such as EMPA-REG OUTCOME, EMPEROR-Reduced, and EMPEROR-Preserved. Smaller mechanistic studies highlighted additional benefits, including improvements in left ventricular function, cardiac remodeling, exercise capacity, and hemodynamic parameters. The safety profile of empagliflozin was favorable, with the main adverse event being an increased incidence of mild genital infections, and no excess in severe adverse or hypoglycemic events. Despite some heterogeneity in trial populations and follow-up, current evidence robustly supports empagliflozin as an effective and safe strategy to reduce cardiovascular risk in patients with T2DM and heart failure. Further research is warranted to explore long-term outcomes and expand indications to broader patient populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Ansar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ansar</LastName><ForeName>Farrukh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Alkhidmat Raazi Hospital, Rawalpindi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azzam</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Alkhidmat Raazi Hospital, Rawalpindi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zafar</LastName><ForeName>Usman</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Alkhidmat Raazi Hospital, Rawalpindi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Sabeeh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery, London, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghauri</LastName><ForeName>Fatima K</ForeName><Initials>FK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Bahawal Victoria Hospital, Bahawalpur, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>AbdulRehman M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Alkhidmat Raazi Hospital, Rawalpindi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehmood Khan</LastName><ForeName>Abdul Rafay</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Alkhidmat Raazi Hospital, Rawalpindi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalil</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Umair</ForeName><Initials>MU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Oxleas NHS Foundation Trust, London, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iftikhar</LastName><ForeName>Hamdah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Hazrat Bari Imam Sarkar (HBS) General Hospital, Islamabad, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faiz</LastName><ForeName>Abdul Rehman</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Quaid-e-Azam International Hospital, Islamabad, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Bilal</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Quaid-e-Azam International Hospital, Islamabad, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">a systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">empagliflozin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40955256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12433617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.90150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The heart of the world. Di Cesare M, Perel P, Taylor S, et al. Glob Heart. 2024;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10809869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38273998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of cardiovascular disease in type 2 diabetes: a systematic literature review of scientific evidence from across the world in 2007-2017. Einarson TR, Acs A, Ludwig C, Panton UH. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2018;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5994068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29884191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of care in diabetes-2023. ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, et al. Diabetes Care. 2023;46:19&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36507649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magliano DJ, Boyko EJ. International Diabetes Federation. Brussels, BE: International Diabetes Federation; 2021. IDF Diabetes Atlas. Tenth Edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determinants of cardiovascular disease among type 2 diabetic patients attending diabetic follow-up clinic in Arba Minch general hospital, southern Ethiopia: an unmatched case-control study. Annose RT, Asefa H, Gezahagn Y, Abebe G, Zewde TH. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2024;86:2467&#x2013;2473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11060215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38694275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular complications of diabetes mellitus in sub-Saharan Africa. Kengne AP, Amoah AG, Mbanya JC. Circulation. 2005;112:3592&#x2013;3601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glycemic control, HbA1c variability, and major cardiovascular adverse outcomes in type 2 diabetes patients with elevated cardiovascular risk: insights from the ACCORD study. Pei J, Wang X, Pei Z, Hu X. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10612188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37891565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors: understanding the mechanisms for therapeutic promise and persisting risks. Perry RJ, Shulman GI. J Biol Chem. 2020;295:14379&#x2013;14390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring the cardiovascular benefits of sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitors: expanding horizons beyond diabetes management. Fatima A, Rasool S, Devi S, et al. Cureus. 2023;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10613932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37908957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin, cardiovascular outcomes, and mortality in type 2 diabetes. Zinman B, Wanner C, Lachin JM, et al. N Engl J Med. 2015;373:2117&#x2013;2128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular and renal outcomes with empagliflozin in heart failure. Packer M, Anker SD, Butler J, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:1413&#x2013;1424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of empagliflozin on the total burden of cardiovascular and hospitalization events in the Asian and non-Asian populations of the EMPA-REG OUTCOME trial of patients with type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Kaku K, Wanner C, Anker SD, Pocock S, Yasui A, Mattheus M, Lund SS. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2022;24:662&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9305124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34908223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A safety evaluation of empagliflozin for the treatment of type 2 diabetes. Neeland IJ, Salahuddin U, McGuire DK. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2016;15:393&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4890479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26695551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin in heart failure with a preserved ejection fraction. Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, et al. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:1451&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin after acute myocardial infarction. Butler J, Jones WS, Udell JA, et al. N Engl J Med. 2024;390:1455&#x2013;1466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38587237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The SGLT2 inhibitor empagliflozin in patients hospitalized for acute heart failure: a multinational randomized trial. Voors AA, Angermann CE, Teerlink JR, et al. Nat Med. 2022;28:568&#x2013;574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35228754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized trial of empagliflozin in nondiabetic patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. Santos-Gallego CG, Vargas-Delgado AP, Requena-Ibanez JA, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77:243&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33197559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of empagliflozin on left ventricular volumes in patients with type 2 diabetes, or prediabetes, and heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (SUGAR-DM-HF) Lee MM, Brooksbank KJ, Wetherall K, et al. Circulation. 2021;143:516&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33186500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of empagliflozin on left ventricular mass in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus and coronary artery disease: the EMPA-HEART CardioLink-6 randomized clinical trial. Verma S, Mazer CD, Yan AT, et al. Circulation. 2019;140:1693&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31434508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal and cardiovascular effects of SGLT2 inhibition in combination with loop diuretics in patients with type 2 diabetes and chronic heart failure: the RECEDE-CHF trial. Mordi NA, Mordi IR, Singh JS, McCrimmon RJ, Struthers AD, Lang CC. Circulation. 2020;142:1713&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin in acute myocardial infarction: the EMMY trial. von Lewinski D, Kolesnik E, Tripolt NJ, et al. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:4421&#x2013;4432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9622301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of empagliflozin versus placebo on cardiac sympathetic activity in acute myocardial infarction patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: the EMBODY trial. Shimizu W, Kubota Y, Hoshika Y, et al. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2020;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7519555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32977831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twelve weeks of treatment with empagliflozin in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: a double-blinded, randomized, and placebo-controlled trial. Jensen J, Omar M, Kistorp C, et al. Am Heart J. 2020;228:47&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32798787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of empagliflozin on functional capacity, LV filling pressure, and cardiac reserves in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus and heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: a randomized controlled open-label trial. Ovchinnikov A, Potekhina A, Filatova A, Svirida O, Zherebchikova K, Ageev F, Belyavskiy E. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12065317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40346546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of empagliflozin on cardiovascular mortality and heart failure hospitalizations: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Rauf U, Ansar F, Ali MS, et al. Cureus. 2025;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12241828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40642671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left ventricular unloading in acute on chronic heart failure: from statements to clinical practice. Sacco A, Morici N, Oreglia JA, et al. J Pers Med. 2022;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9502778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36143247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sympathetic nervous system activation and heart failure: current state of evidence and the pathophysiology in the light of novel biomarkers. Borovac JA, D'Amario D, Bozic J, Glavas D. World J Cardiol. 2020;12:373&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7439452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32879702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin leads to faster improvement in arterial stiffness compared to dapagliflozin: a double-blind clinical. Campos EG, P&#xe1;ez FG, Becerra CG, et al. Life (Basel) 2025;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12113407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40430228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endothelial dysfunction: molecular mechanisms and clinical implications. Wang X, He B. MedComm (2020) 2024;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11261813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39040847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerging role of SGLT-2 inhibitors for the treatment of obesity. Pereira MJ, Eriksson JW. Drugs. 2019;79:219&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6394798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30701480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictors of weight reduction effectiveness of SGLT2 inhibitors in diabetes mellitus type 2 patients. Danpanichkul P, Manosroi W, Nilsirisuk T, Tosukhowong T. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10849059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38327904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin lowers serum uric acid in chronic kidney disease: exploratory analyses from the EMPA-KIDNEY trial. Mayne KJ, Sardell RJ, Staplin N, et al. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2025;40:720&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7616479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39277784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of EMPAgliflozin on markers of inflammation in patients with concomitant type 2 diabetes mellitus and coronary artery disease: the EMPA-CARD randomized controlled trial. Gohari S, Reshadmanesh T, Khodabandehloo H, et al. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2022;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9669535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36397128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of sodium glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors on atherosclerosis: from pharmacology to pre-clinical and clinical therapeutics. Liu Z, Ma X, Ilyas I, et al. Theranostics. 2021;11:4502&#x2013;4515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33754074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin improves cardiac energetics during ischaemia/reperfusion by directly increasing cardiac ketone utilization. Chase D, Eykyn TR, Shattock MJ, Chung YJ. Cardiovasc Res. 2023;119:2672&#x2013;2680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10730240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37819017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myocardial metabolism in heart failure. Ng SM, Neubauer S, Rider OJ. Curr Heart Fail Rep. 2023;20:63&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9977885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36800045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety of empagliflozin: an individual participant-level data meta-analysis from four large trials. Wanner C, Iliev H, Duarte N, Schueler E, Soares AR, Thanam V, Pfarr E. Adv Ther. 2024;41:2826&#x2013;2844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11213770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38771475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pooled safety and tolerability analysis of empagliflozin in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Schorling OK, Clark D, Zwiener I, Kaspers S, Lee J, Iliev H. Adv Ther. 2020;37:3463&#x2013;3484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32372290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of empagliflozin for type 2 diabetes mellitus: meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Zhang YJ, Han SL, Sun XF, et al. Medicine (Baltimore) 2018;97</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6221554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30412076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety profile of sodium glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors: a brief summary. Mascolo A, Di Napoli R, Balzano N, et al. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9532622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>