<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40804563</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-1497</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of general internal medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Gen Intern Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Influence of Depression, Positive Health Behaviors, and Weight Status on Glycated Hemoglobin: A Sequential Mediation Analysis of the INDEPENDENT Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11606-025-09810-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Collaborative care models (CoCM) improve both depression and cardiometabolic outcomes, but the mechanisms driving these effects remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine whether changes in depressive symptoms, positive health behaviors (PHBs), body mass index (BMI), and waist circumference mediate the effect of an adapted CoCM on glycemic control among adults with cardiometabolic risk in India.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Longitudinal structural equation modeling of data from the INtegrating DEPrEssioN and Diabetes TreatmENT (INDEPENDENT) Randomized Control Trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Adults in India with type 2 diabetes or elevated cardiometabolic risk factors and clinically significant depressive symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An adapted CoCM integrating behavioral activation (BA) within diabetes care, delivered by a multidisciplinary team to enhance engagement in self-care activities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Intervention exposure was the independent variable; mediators were depressive symptoms (Symptom Checklist-20), PHBs (Summary of Diabetes Self-Care Activities), BMI, and waist circumference; the primary outcome was hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c). Confirmatory factor analyses ensured measurement validity, with second-order factors capturing depressive symptom domains (anhedonia, somatization, internalizing symptoms, restlessness).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The intervention significantly reduced depressive symptoms from 0-6&#xa0;months (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.22, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and 6-12&#xa0;months (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.34, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and increased PHBs from 0-6&#xa0;months (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.15, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and 6-12&#xa0;months (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.11, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Higher depressive symptoms predicted lower PHBs at 6&#xa0;months (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.26, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and 12&#xa0;months (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.25, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). PHBs mediated reductions in BMI (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.08 to -0.09, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and waist circumference, which in turn mediated improvements in HbA1c.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">An adapted CoCM improved glycemic control and cardiometabolic risk by alleviating depressive symptoms, enhancing PHBs, and reducing BMI and waist circumference. Integrating BA within CoCM may be a key mechanism for optimizing outcomes in integrated cardiometabolic care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>Zach W</ForeName><Initials>ZW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7021-3536</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Georgia School of Social Work, Athens, GA, USA. zach.cooper@uga.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Leslie C M</ForeName><Initials>LCM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory University, Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory Global Diabetes Research Center, Woodruff Health Sciences Center and Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Shivani A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory Global Diabetes Research Center, Woodruff Health Sciences Center and Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aravind</LastName><ForeName>Sosale Ramachandra</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diacon Hospital, Bangalore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tandon</LastName><ForeName>Nikhil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anjana</LastName><ForeName>Ranjit Mohan</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Madras Diabetes Research Foundation [ICMR- Collaborating Centre of Excellence] &amp; Dr. Mohan's Diabetes Specialties Centre [IDF Centre of Excellence in Diabetes Care], Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poongothai</LastName><ForeName>Subramani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Madras Diabetes Research Foundation [ICMR- Collaborating Centre of Excellence] &amp; Dr. Mohan's Diabetes Specialties Centre [IDF Centre of Excellence in Diabetes Care], Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sridhar</LastName><ForeName>Gumpeny R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7446-1251</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrine and Diabetes Centre, Visakhapatnam, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohan</LastName><ForeName>Viswanathan</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5038-6210</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Madras Diabetes Research Foundation [ICMR- Collaborating Centre of Excellence] &amp; Dr. Mohan's Diabetes Specialties Centre [IDF Centre of Excellence in Diabetes Care], Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chwastiak</LastName><ForeName>Lydia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7266-2503</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory University, Department of Family and Preventive Medicine, School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory Global Diabetes Research Center, Woodruff Health Sciences Center and Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubert Department of Global Health, Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01MH100390</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Gen Intern Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8605834</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0884-8734</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations:. Conflict of Interest:: The authors have no conflicts of interest to report. Human Ethics and Consent to Participate:: This study was approved by Emory University. All participants provided informed consent before participating in the study. Participation was voluntary, and individuals could withdraw at any time without consequences. Data were collected and stored in accordance with ethical guidelines to ensure confidentiality and anonymity.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40804563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-025-09810-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11606-025-09810-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Magliano, D. J., Boyko, E. J., &amp; IDF Diabetes Atlas 10th edition scientific committee. IDF DIABETES ATLAS. (International Diabetes Federation, Brussels, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poongothai, S. et al. Association of depression with complications of type 2 diabetes--the Chennai Urban Rural Epidemiology Study (CURES- 102). J Assoc Physicians India 59, 644&#x2013;648 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22479744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly, R. C. et al. The psychosocial burdens of living with diabetes. Diabetic Medicine n/a, e15219 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anjana, R. M. et al. Metabolic non-communicable disease health report of India: the ICMR-INDIAB national cross-sectional study (ICMR-INDIAB-17). Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 11, 474&#x2013;489 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovner, B. W. &amp; Casten, R. J. Trust and Glycemic Control in Black Patients With Diabetic Retinopathy: A Pilot Study. Diabetes Spectrum 32, 152&#x2013;155 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31168287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6528393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson, P. J. &amp; Reiter, J. T. Behavioral Consultation and Primary Care. (Springer International Publishing, Cham, 2016). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-13954-8 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper, Z. &amp; Zerden, L. D. S. How COVID-19 has impacted integrated care practice: lessons from the frontlines. Social Work in Health Care 60, 146&#x2013;156 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper, Z. W., Mowbray, O., Ali, M. K. &amp; Johnson, L. C. M. Addressing depression and comorbid health conditions through solution-focused brief therapy in an integrated care setting: a randomized clinical trial. BMC Primary Care 25, 313 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39179982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11342549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katon, W. J. et al. Collaborative Care for Patients with Depression and Chronic Illnesses. New England Journal of Medicine 363, 2611&#x2013;2620 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21190455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, M. K. et al. Effect of a Collaborative Care Model on Depressive Symptoms and Glycated Hemoglobin, Blood Pressure, and Serum Cholesterol Among Patients With Depression and Diabetes in India: The INDEPENDENT Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA 324, 651&#x2013;662 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strosahl, K., Robinson, P. &amp; Gustavsson, T. Brief Interventions for Radical Change: Principles and Practice of Focused Acceptance and Commitment Therapy. vi, 288 (New Harbinger Publications, Oakland, CA, US, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodie, J. L., Isler, W. C., Hunter, C. &amp; Peterson, A. L. Using behavioral health consultants to treat insomnia in primary care: a clinical case series. Journal of Clinical Psychology 65, 294&#x2013;304 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19152339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogner, H. R. &amp; de Vries, H. F. Integrating type 2 diabetes mellitus and depression treatment among African Americans: A randomized controlled pilot trial. The Diabetes Educator 36, 284&#x2013;292 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20040705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper, Z. W., O&#x2019;Shields, J., Ali, M. K., Chwastiak, L. &amp; Johnson, L. C. M. Effects of Integrated Care Approaches to Address Co-occurring Depression and Diabetes: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Diabetes Care 47, 2291&#x2013;2304 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39602589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogner, H. R. &amp; de Vries, H. F. Integrating type 2 diabetes mellitus and depression treatment among African Americans: a randomized controlled pilot trial. Diabetes Educ 36, 284&#x2013;292 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20040705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ell, K. et al. Promotora assisted depression and self-care management among predominantly Latinos with concurrent chronic illness: Safety net care system clinical trial results. Contemp Clin Trials 61, 1&#x2013;9 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28684357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyo, M. L. L. D. et al. The TELE-DD Randomised Controlled Trial on Treatment Adherence in Patients with Type 2 Diabetes and Comorbid Depression: Clinical Outcomes after 18-Month Follow-Up. Int J Environ Res Public Health 20, 328 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36612650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9819481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Tena, A. et al. Effectiveness of a Psychoeducational Group Intervention Carried Out by Nurses for Patients with Depression and Physical Comorbidity in Primary Care: Randomized Clinical Trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18, 2948 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33805664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7998350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimal, P. et al. Collaborative care model for depression in rural Nepal: a mixed-methods implementation research study. BMJ Open 11, e048481 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8370561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coventry, P. et al. Integrated primary care for patients with mental and physical multimorbidity: cluster randomised controlled trial of collaborative care for patients with depression comorbid with diabetes or cardiovascular disease. BMJ 350, h638 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4353275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail, K. et al. Nurse-led psychological intervention for type 2 diabetes: a cluster randomised controlled trial (Diabetes-6 study) in primary care. Br J Gen Pract 68, e531&#x2013;e540 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30012812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6058638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan, K., Heylen, E., Johnson Pradeep, R., Mony, P. K. &amp; Ekstrand, M. L. Collaborative care compared to enhanced standard treatment of depression with co-morbid medical conditions among patients from rural South India: a cluster randomized controlled trial (HOPE Study). BMC Psychiatry 22, 394 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35698087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9195442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt, A., Bendig, E., Baumeister, H., Hermanns, N. &amp; Kulzer, B. Associations of depression and diabetes distress with self-management behavior and glycemic control. Health Psychology 40, 113&#x2013;124 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#x103;descu, S. et al. The association between Diabetes mellitus and Depression. J Med Life 9, 120&#x2013;125 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27453739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4863499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, S. &amp; Hussain, M. E. Obesity and diabetes: An update. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp; Reviews 11, 73&#x2013;79 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski, A. et al. The INtegrating DEPrEssioN and Diabetes treatmENT (INDEPENDENT) study: design and methods to address mental healthcare gaps in India. Contemp Clin Trials 60, 113&#x2013;124 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28642211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5580499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AIMS. Collaborative care| University of Washingtom|AIMS center. Collaborative Care https://aims.uw.edu/collaborative-care (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, L. C. M. et al. A realist process evaluation of the INtegrating DEPrEssioN and Diabetes treatmENT (INDEPENDENT) randomized controlled trial in India. American Journal of Medicine Open 8, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan, S. et al. Association of collaborative care intervention features with depression and metabolic outcomes in the INDEPENDENT study: A mixed methods study. Primary Care Diabetes 18, 319&#x2013;326 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38360505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11127790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soucy Chartier, I. &amp; Provencher, M. D. Behavioural activation for depression: Efficacy, effectiveness and dissemination. Journal of Affective Disorders 145, 292&#x2013;299 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, A. T., Carl, E., Cuijpers, P., Karyotaki, E. &amp; Smits, J. A. J. Looking beyond depression: a meta-analysis of the effect of behavioral activation on depression, anxiety, and activation. Psychological Medicine 51, 1491&#x2013;1504 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32138802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, L. C. M. et al. Factors that facilitate patient activation in the self-management of diabetes and depression among participants enrolled in an integrated chronic care model in India. Social Science &amp; Medicine 270, 113646 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zghebi, S. S. et al. Assessing the severity of Type 2 diabetes using clinical data-based measures: a systematic review. Diabetic Medicine 36, 688&#x2013;701 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30672017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee. 2. Diagnosis and Classification of Diabetes: Standards of Care in Diabetes&#x2014;2024. Diabetes Care 47, S20&#x2013;S42 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis, L. R., Lipman, R. S., Rickels, K., Uhlenhuth, E. H. &amp; Covi, L. The Hopkins Symptom Checklist (HSCL): A Measure of Primary Symptom Dimensions. (1974) https://doi.org/10.1159/000395070 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boothroyd, L., Dagnan, D. &amp; Muncer, S. PHQ-9: One factor or two? Psychiatry Research 271, 532&#x2013;534 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30553100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Startup, M., Rees, A. &amp; Barkham, M. Components of major depression examined via the Beck depression inventory. Journal of Affective Disorders 26, 251&#x2013;259 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1479138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toobert, D. J., Hampson, S. E. &amp; Glasgow, R. E. The summary of diabetes self-care activities measure: results from 7 studies and a revised scale. Diabetes Care 23, 943&#x2013;950 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10895844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayedi, A. et al. Anthropometric and adiposity indicators and risk of type 2 diabetes: systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of cohort studies. BMJ 376, e067516 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35042741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8764578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enders, C. K. &amp; Bandalos, D. L. The Relative Performance of Full Information Maximum Likelihood Estimation for Missing Data in Structural Equation Models. Structural Equation Modeling: A Multidisciplinary Journal 8, 430&#x2013;457 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosseel, Y. lavaan: An R Package for Structural Equation Modeling. Journal of Statistical Software 48, 1&#x2013;36 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogner, H. R., Morales, K. H., de Vries, H. F. &amp; Cappola, A. R. Integrated management of type 2 diabetes mellitus and depression treatment to improve medication adherence: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Fam Med 10, 15&#x2013;22 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22230826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3262455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, S. C., Luoma, J. B., Bond, F. W., Masuda, A. &amp; Lillis, J. Acceptance and Commitment Therapy: Model, processes and outcomes. Behaviour Research and Therapy 44, 1&#x2013;25 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16300724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villatte, J. L. et al. Acceptance and Commitment Therapy modules: Differential impact on treatment processes and outcomes. Behaviour Research and Therapy 77, 52&#x2013;61 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26716932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuyken, W. et al. How does mindfulness-based cognitive therapy work? Behaviour Research and Therapy 48, 1105&#x2013;1112 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20810101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Ravesteijn, H., Lucassen, P., Bor, H., van Wheel, C. &amp; Speckens, A. Mindfulness-Based Cognitive Therapy for Patients with Medically Unexplained Symptoms: A Randomized Controlled Trial - Abstract - Psychotherapy and Psychosomatics 2013, Vol. 82, No. 5 - Karger Publishers. 82, 299&#x2013;310 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, H. &amp; Ell, K. Depression remission, receipt of problem-solving therapy, and self-care behavior frequency among low-income, predominantly Hispanic diabetes patients. General Hospital Psychiatry 41, 38&#x2013;44 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27302721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4911635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goode, A. D., Winkler, E. A. H., Reeves, M. M. &amp; Eakin, E. G. Relationship between intervention dose and outcomes in living well with diabetes&#x2014;A randomized trial of a telephone-delivered lifestyle-based weight loss intervention. American Journal of Health Promotion 30, 120&#x2013;129 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25372235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>