<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40754745</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-726X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Catheterization and cardiovascular interventions : official journal of the Society for Cardiac Angiography &amp; Interventions</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Catheter Cardiovasc Interv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prognostic Benefit of the Target Vessel in Revascularization of Chronic Total Occluded Coronary Arteries: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ccd.70063</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Previous data have implied that percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) of chronic total occlusions (CTO) is dependent on target vessel. This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to investigate if the benefit of CTO revascularization with PCI is dependent on the target vessel.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive search of multiple databases was conducted to identify studies investigating CTO patients undergoing PCI in the left anterior descending artery (LAD), right coronary artery (RCA), or left circumflex artery (LCX). Outcomes for patients with successful CTO PCI were compared with those who did not undergo PCI stratified on target vessel. The primary outcome was all-cause mortality, while secondary outcomes included major adverse cardiac events (MACE) and cardiac death (CD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty observational studies were included after screening of 3053 studies. Successful CTO PCI was associated with a lower risk of all-cause mortality for LAD (Hazard ratio [HR]: 0.51 [0.42, 0.62], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0%) and LCX (HR: 0.63 [0.41, 0.97], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;40%) than no revascularization. The risk of MACE was only signficantly reduced after successful CTO PCI for LAD lesions (HR: 0.55 [0.47, 0.64], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, I&#xb2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0%), but not for LCX (HR: 0.52 [0.10, 2.62], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.43, I&#xb2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;73%) or RCA (HR: 0.65 [0.19, 2.28], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.50, I&#xb2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;83%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Successful CTO PCI in the LAD was consistently associated with lower all-cause mortality, MACE, and CD compared to non-revascularization, while results were variable for RCA and LCX. These findings emphasize the need for further randomized trials to clarify prognostic differences based on the target vessel.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skov</LastName><ForeName>Emil</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-0394-3434</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hansen</LastName><ForeName>Emilie Kj&#xe6;r</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mogensen</LastName><ForeName>Lone Juul-Hune</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christiansen</LastName><ForeName>Evald H&#xf8;j</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8740-4862</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holck</LastName><ForeName>Emil Nielsen</ForeName><Initials>EN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-6697-1073</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Catheter Cardiovasc Interv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100884139</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-1946</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic total occlusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta&#x2010;analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40754745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ccd.70063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Y. Hafeez and V. Varghese, &#x201c;Chronic Total Occlusion of the Coronary Artery.&#x201d; StatPearls (StatPearls Publishing Copyright 2024, StatPearls Publishing LLC, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. M. Jeroudi, M. E. Alomar, T. T. Michael, et al., &#x201c;Prevalence and Management of Coronary Chronic Total Occlusions in a Tertiary Veterans Affairs Hospital,&#x201d; Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions 84, no. 4 (2014): 637&#x2013;643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. R&#xe5;munddal, L. Hoebers, J. P. S. Henriques, et al., &#x201c;Chronic Total Occlusions in Sweden&#x2014;A Report From the Swedish Coronary Angiography and Angioplasty Registry (SCAAR),&#x201d; PLoS One 9, no. 8 (2014): e103850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. J. Neumann, M. Sousa&#x2010;Uva, A. Ahlsson, et al., &#x201c;2018 ESC/EACTS Guidelines on Myocardial Revascularization,&#x201d; European Heart Journal 40, no. 2 (2019): 87&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Vrints, F. Andreotti, K. C. Koskinas, et al., &#x201c;2024 ESC Guidelines for the Management of Chronic Coronary Syndromes,&#x201d; European Heart Journal 45, no. 36 (2024): 3415&#x2013;3537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Iannaccone, F. D'ascenzo, F. Piazza, et al., &#x201c;Optimal Medical Therapy vs. Coronary Revascularization for Patients Presenting With Chronic Total Occlusion: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials and Propensity Score Adjusted Studies,&#x201d; Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions 93, no. 6 (2019): E320&#x2013;e325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Ma, D. Li, J. Li, et al., &#x201c;Percutaneous Coronary Intervention Versus Optimal Medical Therapy for Patients With Chronic Total Occlusion: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis and Systematic Review,&#x201d; Journal of Thoracic Disease 10, no. 5 (2018): 2960&#x2013;2967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. R&#xe5;munddal, E. N. Holck, S. Karim, et al., &#x201c;International Randomized Trial on the Effect of Revascularization or Optimal Medical Therapy of Chronic Total Coronary Occlusions With Myocardial Ischemia&#x2014;ISCHEMIA&#x2010;CTO Trial&#x2014;Rationale and Design,&#x201d; American Heart Journal 257 (2023): 41&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. E. Christakopoulos, G. Christopoulos, M. Carlino, et al., &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Clinical Outcomes of Patients Who Underwent Percutaneous Coronary Interventions for Chronic Total Occlusions,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 115, no. 10 (2015): 1367&#x2013;1375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. S. Werner, V. Martin&#x2010;Yuste, D. Hildick&#x2010;Smith, et al., &#x201c;A Randomized Multicentre Trial to Compare Revascularization With Optimal Medical Therapy for the Treatment of Chronic Total Coronary Occlusions,&#x201d; European Heart Journal 39, no. 26 (2018): 2484&#x2013;2493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. H. Lee, S. W. Lee, H. S. Park, et al., &#x201c;Successful Recanalization of Native Coronary Chronic Total Occlusion Is Not Associated With Improved Long&#x2010;Term Survival,&#x201d; JACC: Cardiovascular Interventions 9, no. 6 (2016): 530&#x2013;538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Simsek, S. Kostantinis, J. Karacsonyi, et al., &#x201c;A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Clinical Outcomes of Patients Undergoing Chronic Total Occlusion Percutaneous Coronary Intervention,&#x201d; Journal of Invasive Cardiology 34, no. 11 (2022): E763&#x2013;e775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Yoneda, T. Takahashi, and K. Kishi, &#x201c;Over Ten Years' Follow&#x2010;Up of Chronic Total Coronary Occlusion Angioplasty,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Revascularization Medicine 25 (2021): 44&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. M. Safley, J. A. House, S. P. Marso, J. A. Grantham, and B. D. Rutherford, &#x201c;Improvement in Survival Following Successful Percutaneous Coronary Intervention of Coronary Chronic Total Occlusions: Variability by Target Vessel,&#x201d; JACC: Cardiovascular Interventions 1, no. 3 (2008): 295&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence Systematic Review Software, V.H.I., Melbourne, Australia, www.covidence.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Guyot, A. Ades, M. J. Ouwens, and N. J. Welton, &#x201c;Enhanced Secondary Analysis of Survival Data: Reconstructing the Data from Published Kaplan&#x2212;Meier Survival Curves,&#x201d; BMC Medical Research Methodology 12 (2012): 9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. T. Higgins, et al., &#x201c;Measuring Inconsistency In Meta&#x2010;Analyses,&#x201d; BMJ 327, no. 7414 (2003): 557&#x2013;560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Borenstein, J. P. T. Higgins, L. V. Hedges, and H. R. Rothstein, &#x201c;Basics of Meta&#x2010;Analysis: I(2) Is Not an Absolute Measure of Heterogeneity,&#x201d; Research Synthesis Methods 8, no. 1 (2017): 5&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. H. Ahn, J. H. Yang, Y. B. Song, et al., &#x201c;Impacto De La Localizaci&#xf3;n De La Oclusi&#xf3;n Coronaria Cr&#xf3;nica Total En La Supervivencia a Largo Plazo Tras Intervenci&#xf3;n Coronaria Percut&#xe1;nea,&#x201d; Revista Espa&#xf1;ola De Cardiolog&#xed;a 72, no. 9 (2019): 717&#x2013;723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Nakachi, S. Kohsaka, M. Yamane, et al., &#x201c;Scoring System for Identification of &#x201c;Survival Advantage&#x201d; After Successful Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in Patients With Chronic Total Occlusion,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 9, no. 5 (2020): 1319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Y. Choi, S. W. Rha, B. G. Choi, et al., &#x201c;Percutaneous Coronary Intervention for Chronic Total Occlusion in Single Coronary Arteries,&#x201d; Texas Heart Institute Journal 48, no. 2 (2021): e197023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kook, J. H. Yang, J. Y. Cho, et al., &#x201c;Differential Clinical Impact of Chronic Total Occlusion Revascularization Based on Left Ventricular Systolic Function,&#x201d; Clinical Research in Cardiology 110, no. 2 (2021): 237&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Scotti, C. Godino, A. Munaf&#xf2;, et al., &#x201c;Cardiac and Sudden Death After Chronic Total Occlusion Percutaneous Coronary Intervention: Prognostic Role of the Target Vessel,&#x201d; Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions 97, no. 6 (2021): E789&#x2013;e800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. Rha, B. G. Choi, M. J. Baek, et al., &#x201c;Five&#x2010;Year Outcomes of Successful Percutaneous Coronary Intervention With Drug&#x2010;Eluting Stents Versus Medical Therapy for Chronic Total Occlusions,&#x201d; Yonsei Medical Journal 59, no. 5 (2018): 602&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. H. Choo, Y. S. Koh, S. M. Seo, et al., &#x201c;Comparison of Successful Percutaneous Coronary Intervention Versus Optimal Medical Therapy in Patients With Coronary Chronic Total Occlusion,&#x201d; Journal of Cardiology 73, no. 2 (2019): 156&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Yamamoto, M. Natsuaki, T. Morimoto, et al., &#x201c;Long&#x2010;Term Outcomes After Percutaneous Coronary Intervention for Chronic Total Occlusion (from the CREDO&#x2010;Kyoto Registry Cohort&#x2010;2),&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 112, no. 6 (2013): 767&#x2013;774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. K. Park, S. H. Lee, K. H. Choi, et al., &#x201c;Late Survival Benefit of Percutaneous Coronary Intervention Compared With Medical Therapy in Patients With Coronary Chronic Total Occlusion: A 10&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up Study,&#x201d; Journal of the American Heart Association 10, no. 6 (2021): e019022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Valenti, M. Marrani, G. Cantini, et al., &#x201c;Impact of Chronic Total Occlusion Revascularization in Patients With Acute Myocardial Infarction Treated by Primary Percutaneous Coronary Intervention,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 114, no. 12 (2014): 1794&#x2013;1800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Cui and Z. Sheng, &#x201c;Outcomes of Percutaneous Coronary Intervention for Chronic Total Occlusions In the Elderly: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Clinical Cardiology 44, no. 1 (2021): 27&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Y. Choi, B. G. Choi, S. W. Rha, et al., &#x201c;Percutaneous Coronary Intervention Versus Optimal Medical Therapy for Chronic Total Coronary Occlusion With Well&#x2010;Developed Collaterals,&#x201d; Journal of the American Heart Association 6, no. 9 (2017): e006357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Tsai, W. C. Huang, H. I. Teng, Y. L. Tsai, and T. M. Lu, &#x201c;Long Term Clinical Impact of Successful Recanalization of Chronic Total Occlusion in Patients With and Without Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Diabetology 19, no. 1 (2020): 119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Mitomo, T. Naganuma, R. J. Jabbour, et al., &#x201c;Impact of Target Vessel on Long&#x2010;Term Cardiac Mortality After Successful Chronic Total Occlusion Percutaneous Coronary Intervention: Insights from a Japanese Multicenter Registry,&#x201d; International Journal of Cardiology 245 (2017): 77&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. E. Claessen, G. D. Dangas, C. Godino, et al., &#x201c;Impact of Target Vessel on Long&#x2010;Term Survival After Percutaneous Coronary Intervention for Chronic Total Occlusions,&#x201d; Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions 82, no. 1 (2013): 76&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Qin, L. Chen, L. Ge, J. Qian, J. Ma, and J. Ge, &#x201c;A Comparison of Long&#x2010;Term Clinical Outcomes Between Percutaneous Coronary Intervention (PCI) and Medical Therapy In Patients With Chronic Total Occlusion in Noninfarct&#x2010;Related Artery After PCI of Acute Myocardial Infarction,&#x201d; Clinical Cardiology 45, no. 1 (2022): 136&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. N. Holck, L. Jakosen, L. J. H. Mogensen, et al., &#x201c;Prognostic Impact of Target Vessel in Chronic Total Occlusions: A Population&#x2010;Based Cohort Study,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 232 (2024): 105&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Kwon, T. K. Park, K. H. Choi, et al., &#x201c;Chronic Total Occlusion Location and Outcomes After Percutaneous Coronary Intervention or Medical Therapy: Ten&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up of a Single&#x2010;Center Registry,&#x201d; Revista Espa&#xf1;ola de Cardiolog&#xed;a (English Edition), ahead of print, February 8, 2025, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rec.2025.01.015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Elsman, A. W. J. van&#x2009;'t Hof, J. C. A. Hoorntje, et al., &#x201c;Effect of Coronary Occlusion Site on Angiographic and Clinical Outcome in Acute Myocardial Infarction Patients Treated With Early Coronary Intervention,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 97, no. 8 (2006): 1137&#x2013;1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Elhendy, D. W. Mahoney, B. K. Khandheria, T. E. Paterick, K. N. Burger, and P. A. Pellikka, &#x201c;Prognostic Significance of the Location of Wall Motion Abnormalities During Exercise Echocardiography,&#x201d; Journal of the American College of Cardiology 40, no. 9 (2002): 1623&#x2013;1629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. Kirschbaum, T. Baks, M. van den Ent, et al., &#x201c;Evaluation of Left Ventricular Function Three Years After Percutaneous Recanalization of Chronic Total Coronary Occlusions,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 101, no. 2 (2008): 179&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Danchin, M. Angio&#xef;, R. Cador, et al., &#x201c;Effect of Late Percutaneous Angioplastic Recanalization of Total Coronary Artery Occlusion on Left Ventricular Remodeling, Ejection Fraction, and Regional Wall Motion,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 78, no. 7 (1996): 729&#x2013;735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Megaly, M. Saad, P. Tajti, et al., &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of the Impact of Successful Chronic Total Occlusion Percutaneous Coronary Intervention on Left Ventricular Systolic Function and Reverse Remodeling,&#x201d; Journal of Interventional Cardiology 31, no. 5 (2018): 562&#x2013;571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Megaly, S. Zakhour, J. Karacsonyi, et al., &#x201c;Outcomes of Chronic Total Occlusion Percutaneous Coronary Intervention of the Left Anterior Descending Artery,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 193 (2023): 75&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. S. Henriques, L. P. Hoebers, T. R&#xe5;munddal, et al., &#x201c;Percutaneous Intervention for Concurrent Chronic Total Occlusions in Patients With STEMI,&#x201d; Journal of the American College of Cardiology 68, no. 15 (2016): 1622&#x2013;1632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Lin, S. Chen, H. Yan, et al., &#x201c;Clinical Outcomes in Chronic Total Occlusion Revascularization Versus No Chronic Total Occlusion Revascularization: Variability by Target Vessel,&#x201d; Angiology 72, no. 6 (2021): 565&#x2013;574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. Lee, P. H. Lee, J. M. Ahn, et al., &#x201c;Randomized Trial Evaluating Percutaneous Coronary Intervention for the Treatment of Chronic Total Occlusion,&#x201d; Circulation 139, no. 14 (2019): 1674&#x2013;1683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Megaly, K. Buda, K. Mashayekhi, et al., &#x201c;Comparative Analysis of Patient Characteristics in Chronic Total Occlusion Revascularization Studies,&#x201d; JACC: Cardiovascular Interventions 15, no. 14 (2022): 1441&#x2013;1449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp. Stata 18 Base Reference Manual,&#x201d; In Meta Data &#x2014; Declare Meta&#x2010;Analysis Data. Stata Press, (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>