<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40995094</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative efficacy and safety of antidiabetic agents for post-transplant diabetes mellitus: a network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1653147</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1653147</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1653147</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2025.1653147</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Post-transplant diabetes mellitus (PTDM) significantly compromises patient and graft outcomes. Although multiple antidiabetic agents are available, their comparative efficacy and safety profiles in this population remain uncertain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic literature search was performed across PubMed, Web of Science, Embase, and Cochrane Library to identify clinical trials comparing antidiabetic therapies in PTDM patients. Risk of bias was assessed, and a network meta-analysis was conducted to estimate relative treatment effects. Treatment ranking probabilities, contribution plots, and funnel plots were used to evaluate hierarchy, study influence, and publication bias, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twelve studies-including 10 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and 2 cohort studies-encompassing 7,372 patients were analyzed. The network meta-analysis evaluated four outcomes: HbA1c, fasting plasma glucose (FPG), systolic blood pressure (SBP), and composite major adverse cardiovascular and kidney events (MACE and MAKE). Compared to placebo, insulin produced the greatest reductions in HbA1c (mean difference [MD]&#x202f;-&#x202f;0.35, 95% CI&#x202f;-&#x202f;0.90 to 0.20) and FPG (MD&#x202f;-&#x202f;9.06&#x202f;mmol/L, 95% CI&#x202f;-&#x202f;18.66 to 0.53). DPP-4 inhibitors showed the most pronounced decrease in SBP (MD&#x202f;-&#x202f;3.57&#x202f;mmHg, 95% CI&#x202f;-&#x202f;7.29 to 0.16). SGLT2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) demonstrated the strongest tendency to reduce MACE and MAKE events (MD&#x202f;-&#x202f;1.95, 95% CI&#x202f;-&#x202f;4.85 to 0.96). SUCRA plots indicated that insulin and SGLT2i ranked highest in glycemic control and safety profiles. Funnel plot analysis suggested a low risk of publication bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Insulin and SGLT2i represent the most efficacious and safest options among antidiabetic treatments for PTDM, supporting their preferential consideration in post-transplant diabetes management. Further large-scale, head-to-head trials are warranted to strengthen these findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Hu and Lan.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Shanbiao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kidney Transplantation, The Second Xiangya Hospital of Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center for Organ Transplantation in Hunan Province, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Gongbin</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kidney Transplantation, The Second Xiangya Hospital of Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center for Organ Transplantation in Hunan Province, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SGLT2i</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antidiabetic agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">new-onset diabetes after transplantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40995094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12454430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1653147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kesiraju S, Paritala P, Rao Ch UM, Sahariah S. New onset of diabetes after transplantation - an overview of epidemiology, mechanism of development and diagnosis. Transpl Immunol. (2014) 30:52&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.trim.2013.10.006, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trim.2013.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham PT, Pham PM, Pham SV, Pham PA, Pham PC. New onset diabetes after transplantation (NODAT): an overview. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. (2011) 4:175&#x2013;86. doi: 10.2147/DMSO.S19027, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DMSO.S19027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3131798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21760734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada H, Uchida J, Nishide S, Kabei K, Kosoku A, Maeda K, et al. Comparison of glucose tolerance between kidney transplant recipients and healthy controls. J Clin Med. (2019) 8:920. doi: 10.3390/jcm8070920, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm8070920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31252561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokodai K, Amada N, Haga I, Nakamura A, Kashiwadate T, Kawagishi N, et al. Pretransplant HbA1c is a useful predictor for the development of new-onset diabetes in renal transplant recipients receiving no or low-dose erythropoietin. Int J Endocrinol. (2014) 2014:436725. doi: 10.1155/2014/436725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/436725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4216713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharif A, Hecking M, de Vries APJ, Porrini E, Hornum M, Rasoul-Rockenschaub S, et al. Proceedings from an international consensus meeting on posttransplantation diabetes mellitus: recommendations and future directions. Am J Transplant. (2014) 14:1992&#x2013;2000. doi: 10.1111/ajt.12850, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajt.12850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4374739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25307034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane JT, Dagogo-Jack S. Approach to the patient with new-onset diabetes after transplant (NODAT). J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (2011) 96:3289&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1210/jc.2011-0657, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2011-0657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22058376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjelmesaeth J, Asberg A, Muller F, Hartmann A, Jenssen T. New-onset posttransplantation diabetes mellitus: insulin resistance or insulinopenia? Impact of immunosuppressive drugs, cytomegalovirus and hepatitis C virus infection. Curr Diabetes Rev. (2005) 1:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.2174/1573399052952604, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1573399052952604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18220577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson S, Cotiguala L, Tischer S, Park JM, McMurry K. Review of newer antidiabetic agents for diabetes Management in Kidney Transplant Recipients. Ann Pharmacother. (2021) 55:496&#x2013;508. doi: 10.1177/1060028020951955, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1060028020951955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32795145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin LC, Chen JY, Huang TTM, Wu VC. Association of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists with cardiovascular and kidney outcomes in type 2 diabetic kidney transplant recipients. Cardiovasc Diabetol. (2025) 24:87. doi: 10.1186/s12933-025-02649-0, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02649-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11846168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39984953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werzowa JM, S&#xe4;emann MD, Mohl A, Bergmann M, Kaltenecker CC, Brozek W, et al. A randomized controlled trial-based algorithm for insulin-pump therapy in hyperglycemic patients early after kidney transplantation. PLoS One. (2018) 13:e0193569. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0193569, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0193569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5843249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29518094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnasrallah B, Goh TL, Chan LW, Manley P, Pilmore H. Transplantation and diabetes (Transdiab): a pilot randomised controlled trial of metformin in impaired glucose tolerance after kidney transplantation. BMC Nephrol. (2019) 20:147. doi: 10.1186/s12882-019-1321-2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-019-1321-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6489311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31035960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae J, Lee MJ, Choe EY, Jung CH, Wang HJ, Kim MS, et al. Effects of dipeptidyl Peptidase-4 inhibitors on hyperglycemia and blood cyclosporine levels in renal transplant patients with diabetes: a pilot study. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul). (2016) 31:161&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3803/EnM.2016.31.1.161, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3803/EnM.2016.31.1.161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4803553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26754588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werzowa J, Hecking M, Haidinger M, Lechner F, D&#xf6;ller D, Pacini G, et al. Vildagliptin and pioglitazone in patients with impaired glucose tolerance after kidney transplantation: a randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Transplantation. (2013) 95:456&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1097/TP.0b013e318276a20e, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TP.0b013e318276a20e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23380864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidinger M, Werzowa J, Hecking M, Antlanger M, Stemer G, Pleiner J, et al. Efficacy and safety of vildagliptin in new-onset diabetes after kidney transplantation--a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Am J Transplant. (2014) 14:115&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1111/ajt.12518, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajt.12518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24279801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soliman AR, Fathy A, Khashab S, Shaheen N, Soliman MA. Sitagliptin might be a favorable antiobesity drug for new onset diabetes after a renal transplant. Exp Clin Transplant. (2013) 11:494&#x2013;8. doi: 10.6002/ect.2013.0018, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6002/ect.2013.0018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24344941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halden TAS, Kvitne KE, Midtvedt K, Rajakumar L, Robertsen I, Brox J, et al. Efficacy and safety of Empagliflozin in renal transplant recipients with posttransplant diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Care. (2019) 42:1067&#x2013;74. doi: 10.2337/dc19-0093, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc19-0093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halden TAS, &#xc5;sberg A, Vik K, Hartmann A, Jenssen T. Short-term efficacy and safety of sitagliptin treatment in long-term stable renal recipients with new-onset diabetes after transplantation. Nephrol Dial Transplant. (2014) 29:926&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gft536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gft536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24452849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odler B, Huemer M, Schwaiger E, Borenich A, Kurnikowski A, Krall M, et al. Influence of early postoperative basal insulin treatment and post-transplant diabetes mellitus risk on health-related quality of life in kidney transplant recipients-an analysis of data from a randomized controlled trial. Transpl Int. (2023) 36:11370. doi: 10.3389/ti.2023.11370, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ti.2023.11370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37600749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiruvengadam S, Hutchison B, Lim W, Bennett K, Daniels G, Cusack N, et al. Intensive monitoring for post-transplant diabetes mellitus and treatment with dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor therapy. Diabetes Metab Syndr. (2019) 13:1857&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.dsx.2019.04.020, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2019.04.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31235106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwaiger E, Krenn S, Kurnikowski A, Bergfeld L, P&#xe9;rez-S&#xe1;ez MJ, Frey A, et al. Early postoperative basal insulin therapy versus standard of Care for the Prevention of diabetes mellitus after kidney transplantation: a multicenter randomized trial. J Am Soc Nephrol. (2021) 32:2083&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2021010127, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2021010127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8455276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34330770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aftab S, Vetrivel Suresh R, Sherali N, Daniyal M, Tsouklidis N. Sodium-glucose Cotransporter-2 (SGLT-2) inhibitors: benefits in diabetics with cardiovascular disease. Cureus. (2020) 12:e10783. doi: 10.7759/cureus.10783, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.10783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7535950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaurasia PP, Dholariya S, Kotadiya F, Bhavsar M. A new Hope in type 2 diabetes mellitus management: sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors. Cureus. (2021) 13:e18300. doi: 10.7759/cureus.18300, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.18300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8548046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34722075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdous D, Berney X, Sanchez-Archidona AR, Jan M, Roujeau C, Lopez-Mejia IC, et al. A genetic screen identifies crat as a regulator of pancreatic beta-cell insulin secretion. Mol Metab. (2020) 37:100993. doi: 10.1016/j.molmet.2020.100993, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmet.2020.100993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7225740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadhu AR, Schwartz SS, Herman ME. The rationale for use of incretins in the management of new onset diabetes after transplantation (NODAT). Endocr Pract. (2015) 21:814&#x2013;22. doi: 10.4158/EP14569.RA, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4158/EP14569.RA</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25786557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miura H, Sakaguchi K, Okada Y, Yamada T, Otowa-Suematsu N, So A, et al. Effects of ipragliflozin on glycemic control, appetite and its related hormones: a prospective, multicenter, open-label study (SOAR-KOBE study). J Diabetes Investig. (2019) 10:1254&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1111/jdi.13015, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdi.13015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6717805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo E, Penno G, Del PS. Managing diabetic patients with moderate or severe renal impairment using DPP-4 inhibitors: focus on vildagliptin. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. (2013) 6:161&#x2013;70. doi: 10.2147/DMSO.S28951, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DMSO.S28951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3639752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23650450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boorsma EM, Beusekamp JC, ter Maaten JM, Figarska SM, Danser AHJ, van Veldhuisen DJ, et al. Effects of empagliflozin on renal sodium and glucose handling in patients with acute heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. (2021) 23:68&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.2066, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.2066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8048437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33251643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>