<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40885998</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of aerobic combined with resistance exercise on cardiopulmonary function in patients with coronary heart disease: a bayesian meta-analysis based on dose-response, baseline status, and other moderators.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>256</StartPage><MedlinePgn>256</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">256</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01314-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Coronary artery disease (CHD) is one of the major public health problems worldwide. International guidelines recommend ongoing management of metabolic abnormalities and improved prognosis through combined aerobic and resistance exercise (CE), and the aim of this study was to investigate the effects of CE and exercise dose on cardiorespiratory fitness, as measured by maximum oxygen uptake (VO2max), in patients with CHD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a systematic search of PubMed, Embase, the Cochrane Library, and Web of Science, with the search limited to the date of the inception of the database to January 2025 to identify randomized controlled trials (RCTs). Pairwise and regression meta-analyses of these results were conducted using Bayesian stratified models based on random effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The 12 RCTs included a total of 697 patients. The results show that CE significantly increased the VO<sub>2</sub>max of coronary heart disease patients compared with the control group that did not exercise (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.1&#xa0;ml/kg/min; 95%CrI: 2.57, 3.64; GRADE: Low). In addition, there is a nonlinear positive correlation between the weekly CE dose and the level of improvement in VO<sub>2</sub>max, with a minimum dose of 310 METs-min/week. The magnitude of VO<sub>2</sub>max improvement is more pronounced in patients with lower baseline cardiorespiratory fitness and gradually decreases with age.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">CE showed significant benefit in improving cardiorespiratory function in patients with CHD. In addition, even lower doses of CE (&#x2265;&#x2009;310 MET-min/week) improved cardiorespiratory fitness, and the gain was progressively apparent before reaching a critical threshold. The findings suggest that clinical practice should tailor exercise regimens to patient age and baseline VO<sub>2</sub>max.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-025-01314-z.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jianbo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Athletics and Physical Education, Beijing Sport University, No. 48 Information Road, Haidian District, Beijing, China. bsuzjb@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education Bureau of Fengnan District, Tangshan, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tao</LastName><ForeName>Jingjing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongguancun Third Primary School Science Park Branch, Beijing, China. tjj214913568kk@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>May Teo Xin</ForeName><Initials>MTX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Peking University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Frank Teo Li</ForeName><Initials>FTL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sport Science and Physical Education, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: No ethical approval and consent to participate was required because this study was all based on previously published data. Consent for publication: No applicable. Competing interests: The datasets used and/or analyzed in the current study can be obtained from the corresponding authors upon reasonable request.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40885998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12398111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01314-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01314-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ezzati M, Obermeyer Z, Tzoulaki I, et al. Contributions of risk factors and medical care to cardiovascular mortality trends. Nat Reviews Cardiol. 2015;12(9):508&#x2013;30. 10.1038/nrcardio.2015.82. [published Online First: 2015/06/17].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4945698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26076950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolina K, Wright FL, Rayner M, et al. Determinants of the decline in mortality from acute myocardial infarction in England between 2002 and 2010: linked National database study. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2012;344:d8059. 10.1136/bmj.d8059. [published Online First: 2012/01/27].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3266430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22279113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jernberg T, Hasvold P, Henriksson M, et al. Cardiovascular risk in post-myocardial infarction patients: nationwide real world data demonstrate the importance of a long-term perspective. Eur Heart J. 2015;36(19):1163&#x2013;70. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu505. [published Online First: 2015/01/15].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25586123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balady GJ, Williams MA, Ades PA, et al. Core components of cardiac rehabilitation/secondary prevention programs: 2007 update. Circulation. 2007;115(20):2675&#x2013;82. 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.180945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhu NV, Maiya AG, Prabhu NS. Impact of cardiac rehabilitation on functional capacity and physical activity after coronary revascularization: A scientific review. Cardiol Res Pract. 2020;2020:1236968. 10.1155/2020/1236968. [published Online First: 2020/04/11].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32274208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeod JC, Currier BS, Lowisz CV, et al. The influence of resistance exercise training prescription variables on skeletal muscle mass, strength, and physical function in healthy adults: an umbrella review. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13(1):47&#x2013;60. [published Online First: 2023/06/30].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37385345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angulo J, El Assar M, &#xc1;lvarez-Bustos A, et al. Physical activity and exercise: strategies to manage frailty. Redox Biol. 2020;35:101513. 10.1016/j.redox.2020.101513. [published Online First: 2020/04/03].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32234291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Siebert U, Schobersberger W. Resistance training in the treatment of the metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of resistance training on metabolic clustering in patients with abnormal glucose metabolism. Sports Med. 2010;40(5):397&#x2013;415. 10.2165/11531380-000000000-00000. [published Online First: 2010/05/04].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piepoli MF, Hoes AW, Agewall S, et al. 2016 European guidelines on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice: the sixth joint task force of the European society of cardiology and other societies on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice (constituted by representatives of 10 societies and by invited experts)Developed with the special contribution of the European Association for cardiovascular prevention &amp; Rehabilitation (EACPR). Eur Heart J. 2016;37(29):2315&#x2013;81. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehw106. [published Online First: 2016/05/26].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4986030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27222591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American college of sports medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1334&#x2013;59. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb. [published Online First: 2011/06/23].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brellenthin AG, Bennie JA, Lee DC. Aerobic or Muscle-Strengthening physical activity: which is better for health?? Curr Sports Med Rep. 2022;21(8):272&#x2013;79. 10.1249/jsr.0000000000000981. [published Online First: 2022/08/11].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9373235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Lee R, Stone AJ. Combined aerobic and resistance training for peak oxygen uptake, muscle strength, and hypertrophy after coronary artery disease: a systematic review and Meta-Analysis. J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2020;13(4):601&#x2013;11. 10.1007/s12265-019-09922-0. [published Online First: 2019/10/28].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31656988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S, Oh PI, Brooks D. Effect of combined aerobic and resistance training versus aerobic training alone in individuals with coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2012;19(1):81&#x2013;94. [published Online First: 2011/04/01].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21450617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavanagh T, Mertens DJ, Hamm LF, et al. Peak oxygen intake and cardiac mortality in women referred for cardiac rehabilitation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2003;42(12):2139&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.jacc.2003.07.028. [published Online First: 2003/12/19].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14680741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontes-Carvalho R, Azevedo AI, Sampaio F, et al. The effect of exercise training on diastolic and systolic function after acute myocardial infarction: A randomized study. Medicine. 2015;94(36):e1450. 10.1097/md.0000000000001450. [published Online First: 2015/09/12].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4616660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26356698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehti M, Valkeinen H, Sipil&#xe4; S, et al. Effects of aerobic and strength training on aerobic capacity, muscle strength, and gene expression of lymphomonocytes in patients with stable CAD. Am J Translational Res. 2020;12(8):4582&#x2013;93. [published Online First: 2020/09/12].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tofas T, Fatouros IG, Draganidis D, et al. Effects of cardiovascular, resistance and combined exercise training on cardiovascular, performance and blood redox parameters in coronary artery disease patients: an 8-Month training-Detraining randomized intervention. Antioxid (Basel Switzerland). 2021;10(3). 10.3390/antiox10030409. [published Online First: 2021/04/04].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8001546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheer A, Shah A, Ito Ramos de Oliveira B, et al. Twelve weeks of water-based circuit training exercise improves fitness, body fat and leg strength in people with stable coronary heart disease: a randomised trial. J Physiotherapy. 2021;67(4):284&#x2013;90. [published Online First: 2021/09/15].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 6.4. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2021;372:n71. 10.1136/bmj.n71. [published Online First: 2021/03/31].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlon PJ, Faxon DP, Audet A-M, et al. ACC/AHA guidelines for coronary angiography: executive summary and recommendations: a report of the American college of cardiology/american heart association task force on practice guidelines (Committee on coronary angiography) developed in collaboration with the society for cardiac angiography and interventions. Circulation. 1999;99(17):2345&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10226103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann SD, Willis EA, Ainsworth BE, et al. 2024 adult compendium of physical activities: A third update of the energy costs of human activities. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13(1):6&#x2013;12. 10.1016/j.jshs.2023.10.010. [published Online First: 2024/01/20].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38242596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al. The Cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2011;343:d5928. 10.1136/bmj.d5928. [published Online First: 2011/10/20].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins D, Best D, Briss PA, et al. Grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2004;328(7454):1490. 10.1136/bmj.328.7454.1490. [published Online First: 2004/06/19].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC428525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHAPTER 4. Effect Sizes Based on Means; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions 2023 [Available from: https://training.cochrane.org/handbook/current</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;rkner P-C. Advanced bayesian multilevel modeling with the R package Brms. R J. 2018;10:395&#x2013;411. 10.32614/RJ-2018-017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A. Prior distributions for variance parameters in hierarchical models. Bayesian Anal. 2006;1. 10.1214/06-BA117A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz IR, Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Troffaes MCM, et al. Iterative importance sampling with Markov chain Monte Carlo sampling in robust bayesian analysis. Comput Stat Data Anal. 2022;176:107558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks SP, Gelman A. General methods for monitoring convergence of iterative simulations. J Comput Graphical Stat. 1998;7(4):434&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Chu H, Murad MH, et al. Empirical comparison of publication bias tests in Meta-Analysis. J Gen Intern Med. 2018;33(8):1260&#x2013;67. 10.1007/s11606-018-4425-7. [published Online First: 2018/04/18].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6082203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29663281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo-G&#xf3;mez D, Salazar-Mart&#xed;nez E, Alfonso-Rosa RM, et al. Optimal dose and type of physical activity to improve glycemic control in people diagnosed with type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(2):295&#x2013;303. 10.2337/dc23-0800. [published Online First: 2024/01/19].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38241499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang C, Gao C, Zhang J, et al. Traditional Chinese medicine training for cardiac rehabilitation: a randomized comparison with aerobic and resistance training. Coron Artery Dis. 2019;30(5):360&#x2013;66. 10.1097/mca.0000000000000734. [published Online First: 2019/05/21].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31107694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokmakidis SP, Volaklis KA. Training and detraining effects of a combined-strength and aerobic exercise program on blood lipids in patients with coronary artery disease. J Cardpulm Rehabil. 2003;23(3):193&#x2013;200. 10.1097/00008483-200305000-00006. [published Online First: 2003/06/05].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12782903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trachsel LD, Nigam A, Fortier A, et al. Moderate-intensity continuous exercise is superior to high-intensity interval training in the proportion of VO(2peak) responders after ACS. Revista Esp De Cardiologia (English ed). 2020;73(9):725&#x2013;33. [published Online First: 2019/12/16].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31837947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volaklis KA, Douda HT, Kokkinos PF et al. Physiological alterations to detraining following prolonged combined strength and aerobic training in cardiac patients. European journal of cardiovascular prevention and rehabilitation: official journal of the European Society of Cardiology, Working Groups on Epidemiology &amp; Prevention and Cardiac Rehabilitation and Exercise Physiology. 2006;13(3):375&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;80. 10.1097/01.hjr.0000198922.42437.39 [published Online First: 2006/08/24].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vona M, Codeluppi GM, Iannino T, et al. Effects of different types of exercise training followed by detraining on endothelium-dependent dilation in patients with recent myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2009;119(12):1601&#x2013;8. 10.1161/circulationaha.108.821736. [published Online First: 2009/03/18].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh JH, Bilsborough W, Maiorana A, et al. Exercise training improves conduit vessel function in patients with coronary artery disease. J Appl Physiol (Bethesda Md: 1985). 2003;95(1):20&#x2013;5. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00012.2003. [published Online First: 2003/06/10].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12794092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. H. Leg strength and weight training in elderly patients with myocardial infarction. Japanese J Phys Fit Sports Med. 1999;48:559&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki E, Watanabe Y, Shimada K, et al. Effects of a phase III cardiac rehabilitation program on physical status and lipid profiles in elderly patients with coronary artery disease: Juntendo cardiac rehabilitation program (J-CARP). Circulation Journal: Official J Japanese Circulation Soc. 2008;72(8):1230&#x2013;4. 10.1253/circj.72.1230. [published Online First: 2008/07/26].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18654005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber MP, Myers J, Bonikowske AR, et al. Assessing cardiorespiratory fitness in clinical and community settings: lessons and advancements in the 100th year anniversary of VO(2max). Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;83:36&#x2013;42. 10.1016/j.pcad.2024.02.009. [published Online First: 2024/02/29].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38417771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghuveer G, Hartz J, Lubans DR et al. Cardiorespiratory Fitness in Youth: An Important Marker of Health: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2020;142(7):e101-e18. 10.1161/cir.0000000000000866 [published Online First: 2020/07/21].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7524041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32686505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coletti C, Acosta GF, Keslacy S, et al. Exercise-mediated reinnervation of skeletal muscle in elderly people: an update. Eur J Translational Myology. 2022;32(1). 10.4081/ejtm.2022.10416. [published Online First: 2022/03/03].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie J, Haberstroh M, Acosta T, et al. Independent and joint associations between leisure time physical activity and strength activities with mortality outcomes in older adults at least 65 years of age: A prospective cohort study. J Gerontol Biol Sci Med Sci. 2021;76(12):2122&#x2013;31. 10.1093/gerona/glab114. [published Online First: 2021/04/16].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33858013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkinos P, Faselis C, Samuel IBH, et al. Changes in cardiorespiratory fitness and survival in patients with or without cardiovascular disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81(12):1137&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.01.027. [published Online First: 2023/03/23].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36948729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebe D, Ehrman JK, Liguori G, et al. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. American College of Sports Medicine; 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World health organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62. 10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955. [published Online First: 2020/11/27].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasfy MM, Baggish AL. Exercise dose in clinical practice. Circulation. 2016;133(23):2297&#x2013;313. 10.1161/circulationaha.116.018093. [published Online First: 2016/06/09].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4902280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2007;116(9):1081-93. 10.1161/circulationaha.107.185649 [published Online First: 2007/08/03].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tj&#xf8;nna AE, Leinan IM, Bartnes AT, et al. Low- and high-volume of intensive endurance training significantly improves maximal oxygen uptake after 10-weeks of training in healthy men. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(5):e65382. 10.1371/journal.pone.0065382. [published Online First: 2013/06/05].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3667025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23734250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisl&#xf8;ff U, St&#xf8;ylen A, Loennechen JP, et al. Superior cardiovascular effect of aerobic interval training versus moderate continuous training in heart failure patients: a randomized study. Circulation. 2007;115(24):3086&#x2013;94. 10.1161/circulationaha.106.675041. [published Online First: 2007/06/06].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM, Jaramillo SA, Balasubramanyam A, et al. Effect of a lifestyle intervention on change in cardiorespiratory fitness in adults with type 2 diabetes: results from the look AHEAD study. Int J Obes. 2009;33(3):305&#x2013;16. 10.1038/ijo.2008.280. [published Online First: 2009/01/21].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>