<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40996475</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1934</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CNS drugs</Title><ISOAbbreviation>CNS Drugs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sodium-Glucose Cotransporter 2 Inhibitors: An Emerging Therapeutic Approach for Ischemic Stroke Management.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40263-025-01230-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2i), a cornerstone therapy for type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and heart failure, are emerging as a promising therapeutic class for the management of ischemic stroke (IS). Given that T2DM is a significant risk factor for IS, understanding the potential neuroprotective role of SGLT2i is of paramount clinical importance. This review provides a systematic and logically structured synthesis of the current evidence, beginning with foundational preclinical studies in animal models that consistently demonstrate a reduction in infarct volume and improved neurological outcomes. We then transition to the extensive clinical evidence, primarily from large-scale real-world observational studies, that has confirmed a significant reduction in stroke risk, particularly in high-risk T2DM populations. The strengths and limitations of this evidence base are critically appraised, highlighting the robustness of the findings while acknowledging the predominantly observational nature of the data and the lack of stroke-specific primary endpoints in major trials. The neuroprotective benefits of SGLT2i appear to be multifactorial; this review delves into the potential mechanisms, emphasizing a foundational, glucose-dependent pathway of ameliorating hyperglycemia-induced neurotoxicity, which is complemented by a suite of pleiotropic, glucose-independent effects, including the induction of mild ketosis, attenuation of neuroinflammation, and preservation of the neurovascular unit. Finally, we address the key clinical challenges to their application, such as the management of euglycemic ketoacidosis, and outline crucial directions for future research, underscoring the need for dedicated randomized trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yiwei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Shanxi Medical University, Jiefangnan 85 Road, Taiyuan, 030001, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Xinyuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Shanxi Medical University, Jiefangnan 85 Road, Taiyuan, 030001, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Changxin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8652-4283</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Jiefangnan 85 Road, Taiyuan, 030001, Shanxi, China. lichangxin0351@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>CNS Drugs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9431220</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1172-7047</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: All authors certify that they have no affiliations with or involvement in any organization or entity with any financial interest or non-financial interest in the subject matter or materials discussed in this manuscript. Ethical Approval: Not applicable. Consent&#xa0;to Participate: Not applicable. Consent to Publish: Not applicable. Data Availability: All data used in this review are available from the respective cited studies. Code Availability: Not applicable. Author Contributions: Yiwei Huang established the theme and scope of the review, systematically synthesized relevant literature, and drafted the initial manuscript. Xinyuan Yu contributed original insights and critical analysis, providing meticulous revisions that enhanced the depth of the discussion. Changxin Li offered valuable suggestions and conducted thorough revisions, ensuring linguistic fluency and adherence to formatting standards. All authors reviewed and approved the final manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40996475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-025-01230-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40263-025-01230-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen PH, et al. Classifying ischemic stroke, from TOAST to CISS. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2012;18(6):452&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1755-5949.2011.00292.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1755-5949.2011.00292.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22268862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6493455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, et al. Association of type 2 diabetes mellitus and glycemic control with intracranial plaque characteristics in patients with acute ischemic stroke. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2021;54(2):655&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmri.27614 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.27614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plitt A, McGuire DK, Giugliano RP. Atrial fibrillation, type 2 diabetes, and non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants: a review. JAMA Cardiol. 2017;2(4):442&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2016.5224 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2016.5224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koufakis T, et al. Sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors versus metformin as the first-line treatment for type 2 diabetes: is it time for a revolution? Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2023;37(2):315&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10557-021-07249-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10557-021-07249-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34476668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W, et al. Empagliflozin demonstrates neuroprotective and cardioprotective effects by reducing ischemia/reperfusion damage in rat models of ischemic stroke and myocardial infarction. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):8986. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-93483-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-93483-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40089564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11910632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, et al. Pre-ischaemic empagliflozin treatment attenuates blood-brain barrier disruption via &#x3b2;-catenin mediated protection of cerebral endothelial cells. Cardiovasc Res. 2025;121(5):788&#x2013;802. https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvaf026 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvaf026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40173314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takashima M, et al. Low-dose sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor ameliorates ischemic brain injury in mice through pericyte protection without glucose-lowering effects. Commun Biol. 2022;5(1):653. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42003-022-03605-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-022-03605-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35780235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9250510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim B, et al. Canagliflozin, an inhibitor of the NA(+)-coupled D-glucose cotransporter, sglt2, inhibits astrocyte swelling and brain swelling in cerebral ischemia. Cells. 2023. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells12182221 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12182221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37759444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10527352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin EF, Rifaai RA, Abdel-latif RG. Empagliflozin attenuates transient cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury in hyperglycemic rats via repressing oxidative&#x2013;inflammatory&#x2013;apoptotic pathway. Fundam Clin Pharmacol. 2020;34(5):548&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1111/fcp.12548 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/fcp.12548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32068294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa-nguanmoo P, et al. SGLT2-inhibitor and DPP-4 inhibitor improve brain function via attenuating mitochondrial dysfunction, insulin resistance, inflammation, and apoptosis in HFD-induced obese rats. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol. 2017;333:43&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.taap.2017.08.005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.taap.2017.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28807765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Latif RG, Rifaai RA, Amin EF. Empagliflozin alleviates neuronal apoptosis induced by cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury through HIF-1&#x3b1;/VEGF signaling pathway. Arch Pharm Res. 2020;43(5):514&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12272-020-01237-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12272-020-01237-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32436127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercalsteren E, et al. The SGLT2 inhibitor Empagliflozin promotes post-stroke functional recovery in diabetic mice. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):88. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-024-02174-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02174-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38424560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10905950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simanenkova A, et al. Microglia involvement into acute and chronic brain damage in diabetic rats: impact of GLP-1RA and SGLT-2i. Front Biosci Landmark. 2024;29(7):265. https://doi.org/10.31083/j.fbl2907265 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.fbl2907265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CX, et al. Cardiovascular outcomes associated with SGLT-2 inhibitors versus other glucose-lowering drugs in patients with type 2 diabetes: a real-world systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(2):e0244689. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0244689 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0244689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7895346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, et al. Comparative effect of glucose-lowering drugs for type 2 diabetes mellitus on stroke prevention: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab J. 2024;48(2):312&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.4093/dmj.2022.0421 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2022.0421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38273787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10995485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng PY, et al. Atherothrombotic outcomes after sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors versus dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors in patients with type 2 diabetes: a territory-wide retrospective cohort study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2025;14(1):e037207. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.124.037207 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.124.037207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39719404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, et al. Comparing ischemic cardiovascular effectiveness and safety between individual SGLT-2 inhibitors and DPP-4 inhibitors in patients with type 2 diabetes: a nationwide population-based cohort study. Front Pharmacol. 2024;15:1443175. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2024.1443175 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1443175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39545068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11561712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, et al. Comparison of sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor and dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor on the risks of new-onset atrial fibrillation, stroke and mortality in diabetic patients: a propensity score-matched study in Hong Kong. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2023;37(3):561&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10557-022-07319-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10557-022-07319-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin H, et al. Comparative effectiveness of individual sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors. JAMA Intern Med. 2025;185(3):302. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamainternmed.2024.7357 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2024.7357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39836397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantounou MA, et al. Meta-analysis of sotagliflozin, a dual sodium-glucose-cotransporter 1/2 inhibitor, for heart failure in type 2 diabetes. ESC Heart Fail. 2025;12(2):968&#x2013;79. https://doi.org/10.1002/ehf2.15036 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ehf2.15036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39257196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualotto E, et al. The effect of sodium-glucose transporter 2 inhibitors on stroke in patients with type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2024.107730 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2024.107730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38679214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TY, et al. Comparing clinical outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus after ischaemic stroke: sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors users versus non-users. A propensity score matching national cohort study. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2024;26(10):4501&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.15804 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.15804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39134462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima K, et al. The effect of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors on stroke and atrial fibrillation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2023;48(4):101582. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2022.101582 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2022.101582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36584726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkas F, et al. Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors and protection against stroke in patients with type 2 diabetes and impaired renal function: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30(5):105708. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105708 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33714073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, et al. Effect of SGLT2 inhibitors on stroke and atrial fibrillation in diabetic kidney disease: results from the CREDENCE trial and meta-analysis. Stroke. 2021;52(5):1545&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031623 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.031623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8078131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori Y, et al. Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors and cardiovascular events among patients with type 2 diabetes and low-to-normal body mass index: a nationwide cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):372. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-024-02478-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02478-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39438867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11515712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Q, et al. Canagliflozin attenuates hepatic steatosis and atherosclerosis progression in western diet-fed ApoE-knockout mice. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2022;16:4161&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.2147/DDDT.S388823 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DDDT.S388823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36510490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9741490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakatsu Y, et al. The SGLT2 inhibitor luseogliflozin rapidly normalizes aortic mRNA levels of inflammation-related but not lipid-metabolism-related genes and suppresses atherosclerosis in diabetic ApoE KO mice. Int J Mol Sci. 2017. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms18081704 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms18081704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5578094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irace C, et al. Empagliflozin influences blood viscosity and wall shear stress in subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus compared with incretin-based therapy. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2018;17(1):52. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-018-0695-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-018-0695-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29631585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5891980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, et al. Longitudinal assessment of coronary plaque regression related to sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor using coronary computed tomography angiography. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):267. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-024-02368-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02368-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39039597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11264370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka A, et al. Rationale and design of a multicenter randomized controlled study to evaluate the preventive effect of ipragliflozin on carotid atherosclerosis: the PROTECT study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2016;15(1):133. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-016-0449-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-016-0449-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27619983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5020545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardu C, et al. SGLT2-inhibitors effects on the coronary fibrous cap thickness and MACEs in diabetic patients with inducible myocardial ischemia and multi vessels non-obstructive coronary artery stenosis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22(1):80. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-023-01814-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-01814-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37005586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10067292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Onofrio N, et al. Sodium-glucose co-transporter2 expression and inflammatory activity in diabetic atherosclerotic plaques: effects of sodium-glucose co-transporter2 inhibitor treatment. Mol Metab. 2021;54:101337. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmet.2021.101337 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmet.2021.101337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34500107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8473552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganbaatar B, et al. Empagliflozin ameliorates endothelial dysfunction and suppresses atherogenesis in diabetic apolipoprotein E-deficient mice. Eur J Pharmacol. 2020;875:173040. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.173040 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.173040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32114052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terenzi DC, et al. Restoration of blood vessel regeneration in the era of combination SGLT2i and GLP-1RA therapy for diabetes and obesity. Cardiovasc Res. 2024;119(18):2858&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvae016 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvae016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38367275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Zhang X, Wang Q. Effects and mechanisms of SGLT2 inhibitors on the NLRP3 inflammasome, with a focus on atherosclerosis. Front Endocrinol. 2022;13:992937. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2022.992937 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2022.992937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kounatidis D, et al. SGLT-2 inhibitors and the inflammasome: what&#x2019;s next in the 21st century? Nutrients. 2023. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15102294 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15102294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37242177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10221012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terasaki M, et al. Amelioration of hyperglycemia with a sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor prevents macrophage-driven atherosclerosis through macrophage foam cell formation suppression in type 1 and type 2 diabetic mice. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(11):e0143396. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0143396 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0143396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26606676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4659635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu J, et al. Empagliflozin inhibits macrophage inflammation through AMPK signaling pathway and plays an anti-atherosclerosis role. Int J Cardiol. 2022;367:56&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.07.048 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.07.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35931206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdollahi E, et al. Dapagliflozin exerts anti-inflammatory effects via inhibition of LPS-induced TLR-4 overexpression and NF-&#x3ba;B activation in human endothelial cells and differentiated macrophages. Eur J Pharmacol. 2022;918:174715. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejphar.2021.174715 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2021.174715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spigoni V, et al. Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors antagonize lipotoxicity in human myeloid angiogenic cells and ADP-dependent activation in human platelets: potential relevance to prevention of cardiovascular events. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2020;19(1):46. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-020-01016-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-020-01016-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32264868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7140327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohlmorgen C, et al. Dapagliflozin reduces thrombin generation and platelet activation: implications for cardiovascular risk reduction in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetologia. 2021;64(8):1834&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-021-05498-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-021-05498-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34131781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8245397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashikata T, et al. Empagliflozin attenuates neointimal hyperplasia after drug-eluting-stent implantation in patients with type 2 diabetes. Heart Vessels. 2020;35(10):1378&#x2013;89. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00380-020-01621-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00380-020-01621-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32399662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, et al. Empagliflozin inhibits neointimal hyperplasia through attenuating endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition via TAK-1/NF-&#x3ba;B pathway. Eur J Pharmacol. 2023;954:175826. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejphar.2023.175826 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2023.175826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37321472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, et al. Canagliflozin ameliorates epithelial-mesenchymal transition in high-salt diet-induced hypertensive renal injury through restoration of sirtuin 3 expression and the reduction of oxidative stress. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2023;653:53&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbrc.2023.01.084 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2023.01.084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori Y, et al. Luseogliflozin attenuates neointimal hyperplasia after wire injury in high-fat diet-fed mice via inhibition of perivascular adipose tissue remodeling. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2019;18(1):143. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-019-0947-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-019-0947-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31672147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6823953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjerkreim AT, et al. Five-year readmission and mortality differ by ischemic stroke subtype. J Neurol Sci. 2019;403:31&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2019.06.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2019.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31185434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtagh B, Smalling RW. Cardioembolic stroke. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2006;8(4):310&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11883-006-0009-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-006-0009-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16822397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, et al. Canagliflozin and atrial fibrillation in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a secondary analysis from the CANVAS program and CREDENCE trial and meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2022;24(10):1927&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.14772 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.14772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fichadiya A, et al. Association between sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors and arrhythmic outcomes in patients with diabetes and pre-existing atrial fibrillation. Europace. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euae054 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/europace/euae054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38484180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10939462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey AK, et al. Sodium-glucose co-transporter inhibitors and atrial fibrillation: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10(17):e022222. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.121.022222 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.121.022222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34459238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8649253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishima H, et al. Efficacy of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors on outcomes after catheter ablation for atrial fibrillation. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2022;8(11):1393&#x2013;404. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacep.2022.08.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacep.2022.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36424008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameer MZ, et al. Cardiovascular outcomes with SGLT-2 inhibitors in individuals with diabetes and co-existing atrial fibrillation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2025;426:133083. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2025.133083 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2025.133083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39993659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim GK, et al. Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors and stroke risk in patients with atrial fibrillation. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1111/jce.16739 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jce.16739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40768925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua S-K, et al. Age-dependent effects of SGLT2 inhibitors on stroke risk in geriatric patients with diabetes and atrial fibrillation. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):27. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-024-02557-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02557-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39844160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11756094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H, et al. Assessing the benefit&#x2013;risk profile of newer glucose-lowering drugs: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomized outcome trials. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2025;27(3):1444&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.16147 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.16147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39723481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawzy AM, et al. Incident heart failure, arrhythmias and cardiovascular outcomes with sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitor use in patients with diabetes: insights from a global federated electronic medical record database. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2023;25(2):602&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.14854 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.14854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36054168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhadi NA, et al. Impact of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors on atrial fibrillation recurrence post-catheter ablation among patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2025;36(3):673&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1111/jce.16544 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jce.16544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39789826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11903381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho Y, et al. The effect of SGLT2 inhibitor in patients with type 2 diabetes and atrial fibrillation. PLoS ONE. 2025;20(2):e0314454. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0314454 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0314454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39919084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11805423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YY, et al. The impact of sodium-glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitors on dementia and cardiovascular events in diabetic patients with atrial fibrillation. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2024;40(2):e3775. https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.3775 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.3775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38340046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SN, et al. Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor prevents stroke in patients with diabetes and atrial fibrillation. J Am Heart Assoc. 2023;12(10):e027764. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.122.027764 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.122.027764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37183872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10227316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright EM, Loo DD, Hirayama BA. Biology of human sodium glucose transporters. Physiol Rev. 2011;91(2):733&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1152/physrev.00055.2009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00055.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiba Y, et al. Glucose, fructose, and urate transporters in the choroid plexus epithelium. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(19):7230. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21197230 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms21197230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7582461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawlos A, et al. Neuroprotective effect of SGLT2 inhibitors. Molecules. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26237213 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26237213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34885795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8659196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon S. Dapagliflozin: a review in type 2 diabetes. Drugs. 2019;79(10):1135&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40265-019-01148-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-019-01148-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31236801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6879440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saisho Y. SGLT2 inhibitors: the star in the treatment of type 2 diabetes? Diseases. 2020. https://doi.org/10.3390/diseases8020014 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diseases8020014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32403420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7349723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca-Correa JI, Correa-Rotter R. Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors mechanisms of action: a review. Front Med. 2021;8:777861. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.777861 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.777861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B, et al. The current role of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes mellitus management. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):83. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-022-01512-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-022-01512-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35614469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9134641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom S, et al. Hyperglycemia-driven neuroinflammation compromises BBB leading to memory loss in both diabetes mellitus (DM) type 1 and type 2 mouse models. Mol Neurobiol. 2019;56(3):1883&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-018-1195-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-018-1195-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29974394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;e MA, et al. Prolonged systemic hyperglycemia does not cause pericyte loss and permeability at the mouse blood-brain barrier. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):17462. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-35576-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-35576-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30498224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6265246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krinock MJ, Singhal NS. Diabetes, stroke, and neuroresilience: looking beyond hyperglycemia. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2021;1495(1):78&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1111/nyas.14583 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.14583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33638222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delalat S, et al. Dysregulated inflammation, oxidative stress, and protein quality control in diabetic HFpEF: unraveling mechanisms and therapeutic targets. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2025;24(1):211. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-025-02734-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-025-02734-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40369521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12080046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvin E, et al. Meta-analysis: glycosylated hemoglobin and cardiovascular disease in diabetes mellitus. Ann Intern Med. 2004;141(6):421&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-141-6-200409210-00007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-141-6-200409210-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15381515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, et al. Glycosylated hemoglobin in relationship to cardiovascular outcomes and death in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(8):e42551. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0042551 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0042551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22912709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3415427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denorme F, et al. Hyperglycemia exacerbates ischemic stroke outcome independent of platelet glucose uptake. J Thromb Haemost. 2021;19(2):536&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1111/jth.15154 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jth.15154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baranovicova E, et al. NMR metabolomic study of blood plasma in ischemic and ischemically preconditioned rats: an increased level of ketone bodies and decreased content of glycolytic products 24 h after global cerebral ischemia. J Physiol Biochem. 2018;74(3):417&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13105-018-0632-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13105-018-0632-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29752707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White H, Venkatesh B. Clinical review: ketones and brain injury. Crit Care. 2011;15(2):219. https://doi.org/10.1186/cc10020 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/cc10020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21489321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3219306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasselbalch SG, et al. Changes in cerebral blood flow and carbohydrate metabolism during acute hyperketonemia. Am J Physiol. 1996;270(5 Pt 1):E746&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpendo.1996.270.5.E746 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1996.270.5.E746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8967461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svart M, et al. Regional cerebral effects of ketone body infusion with 3-hydroxybutyrate in humans: reduced glucose uptake, unchanged oxygen consumption and increased blood flow by positron emission tomography. A randomized, controlled trial. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(2):e0190556. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0190556 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0190556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5830038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis. Circulation. 2022;146(18):1383&#x2013;405. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.061732 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.061732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36315602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9624240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow E, Clement S, Garg R. Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis in the era of SGLT-2 inhibitors. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjdrc-2023-003666 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjdrc-2023-003666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37797963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10551972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avgerinos KI, et al. Empagliflozin induced ketosis, upregulated IGF-1/insulin receptors and the canonical insulin signaling pathway in neurons, and decreased the excitatory neurotransmitter glutamate in the brain of non-diabetics. Cells. 2022;11(21):3372. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells11213372 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells11213372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36359767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9657243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai KK, et al. Ketogenic diet prevents cardiac arrest-induced cerebral ischemic neurodegeneration. J Neural Transm. 2008;115(7):1011&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00702-008-0050-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-008-0050-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18478178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaafi S, et al. Early motor-behavioral outcome of ischemic stroke with ketogenic diet preconditioning: interventional animal study. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2019;28(4):1032&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2018.12.024 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2018.12.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30658953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki M, et al. Beta-hydroxybutyrate, a cerebral function improving agent, protects rat brain against ischemic damage caused by permanent and transient focal cerebral ischemia. Jpn J Pharmacol. 2002;89(1):36&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1254/jjp.89.36 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1254/jjp.89.36</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12083741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y-H, et al. Ketone bodies promote stroke recovery via GAT-1-dependent cortical network remodeling. Cell Rep. 2023;42(4):112294. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2023.112294 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2023.112294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleiman SF, et al. Exercise promotes the expression of brain derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) through the action of the ketone body &#x3b2;-hydroxybutyrate. Elife. 2016. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.15092 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.15092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27253067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4915811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang J, et al. Molecular mechanisms of neuroprotection by ketone bodies and ketogenic diet in cerebral ischemia and neurodegenerative diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;25(1):124. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25010124 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25010124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38203294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10779133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gureev AP, et al. Beta-hydroxybutyrate mitigates sensorimotor and cognitive impairments in a photothrombosis-induced ischemic stroke in mice. Int J Mol Sci. 2024. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25115710 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25115710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39796065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11720470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metwally SAH, et al. Pharmacological inhibition of NHE1 protein increases white matter resilience and neurofunctional recovery after ischemic stroke. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(17):13289. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms241713289 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241713289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37686096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10488118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimke M, et al. Anti-inflammatory properties of the SGLT2 inhibitor empagliflozin in activated primary microglia. Cells. 2022;11(19):3107. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells11193107 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells11193107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36231069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9563452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamato M, et al. The early pathogenesis of diabetic retinopathy and its attenuation by sodium-glucose transporter 2 inhibitors. Diabetes. 2024;73(7):1153&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.2337/db22-0970 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db22-0970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38608284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11208076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr LH, et al. Canagliflozin attenuates chronic unpredictable mild stress induced neuroinflammation via modulating AMPK/mTOR autophagic signaling. Neuropharmacology. 2023;223:109293. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropharm.2022.109293 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2022.109293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36272443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, et al. Dapagliflozin ameliorates ovulation disorders via attenuating activated microglia-mediated hypothalamic inflammation in HFD-fed mice. Neuroendocrinology. 2024;114(4):331&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1159/000535420 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000535420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38147832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, et al. Empagliflozin targets Mfn1 and Opa1 to attenuate microglia-mediated neuroinflammation in retinal ischemia and reperfusion injury. J Neuroinflammation. 2023;20(1):296. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-023-02982-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-023-02982-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38082266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10714482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mashayekhi M, et al. Systemic and organ-specific anti-inflammatory effects of sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2024;35(5):425&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tem.2024.02.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2024.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38423898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11096060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee N, et al. Anti-inflammatory effects of empagliflozin and gemigliptin on LPS-stimulated macrophage via the IKK/NF-&#x3ba;B, MKK7/JNK, and JAK2/STAT1 signalling pathways. J Immunol Res. 2021;2021:1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1155/2021/9944880 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/9944880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q, et al. Empagliflozin alleviates neuroinflammation by inhibiting astrocyte activation in the brain and regulating gut microbiota of high-fat diet mice. J Affect Disord. 2024;360:229&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2024.05.150 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2024.05.150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38823591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, et al. Nox activation in reactive astrocytes regulates astrocytic LCN2 expression and neurodegeneration. Cell Death Dis. 2022;13(4):371. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-022-04831-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-022-04831-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9018876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakhal MM, et al. Repurposing SGLT2 inhibitors for neurological disorders: a focus on the autism spectrum disorder. Molecules. 2022;27(21):7174. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules27217174 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27217174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36364000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9653623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousa HH, Sharawy MH, Nader MA. Empagliflozin enhances neuroplasticity in rotenone-induced parkinsonism: role of BDNF, CREB and Npas4. Life Sci. 2023;312:121258. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2022.121258 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2022.121258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36462721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab HH, Safar MM, Shahin NN. Targeting ROS-dependent AKT/GSK-3&#x3b2;/NF-&#x3ba;B and DJ-1/Nrf2 pathways by dapagliflozin attenuates neuronal injury and motor dysfunction in rotenone-induced Parkinson&#x2019;s disease rat model. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2021;12(4):689&#x2013;703. https://doi.org/10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00722 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acschemneuro.0c00722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33543924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mone P, et al. SGLT2 inhibition via empagliflozin improves endothelial function and reduces mitochondrial oxidative stress: insights from frail hypertensive and diabetic patients. Hypertension. 2022;79(8):1633&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.122.19586 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.122.19586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35703100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrabi SS, Parvez S, Tabassum H. Ischemic stroke and mitochondria: mechanisms and targets. Protoplasma. 2020;257(2):335&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00709-019-01439-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00709-019-01439-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31612315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel AS, et al. Boosting amygdaloid GABAergic and neurotrophic machinery via dapagliflozin-enhanced LKB1/AMPK signaling in anxious demented rats. Life Sci. 2022;310:121002. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2022.121002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2022.121002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36191679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelkader NF, et al. Empagliflozin mitigates type 2 diabetes-associated peripheral neuropathy: a glucose-independent effect through AMPK signaling. Arch Pharm Res. 2022;45(7):475&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12272-022-01391-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12272-022-01391-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35767208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9325846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, et al. Dapagliflozin improves endothelial cell dysfunction by regulating mitochondrial production via the SIRT1/PGC-1&#x3b1; pathway in obese mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2022;615:123&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbrc.2022.05.022 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2022.05.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35609417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thierfelder KM, et al. Vertebral artery hypoplasia: frequency and effect on cerebellar blood flow characteristics. Stroke. 2014;45(5):1363&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1161/strokeaha.113.004188 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.113.004188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24699051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koepsell H. Glucose transporters in brain in health and disease. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch Eur J Physiol. 2020;472(9):1299&#x2013;343. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00424-020-02441-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00424-020-02441-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellut M, et al. NLPR3 inflammasome inhibition alleviates hypoxic endothelial cell death in vitro and protects blood-brain barrier integrity in murine stroke. Cell Death Dis. 2021;13(1):20. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41419-021-04379-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-021-04379-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34930895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8688414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, et al. Luseogliflozin, a sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor, reverses cerebrovascular dysfunction and cognitive impairments in 18-mo-old diabetic animals. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2022;322(2):H246&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00438.2021 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00438.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthman L, et al. Empagliflozin and dapagliflozin reduce ROS generation and restore NO bioavailability in tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1;-stimulated human coronary arterial endothelial cells. Cell Physiol Biochem Int J Exp Cell Physiol Biochem Pharmacol. 2019;53(5):865&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.3594/000000178 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3594/000000178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juni RP, et al. Empagliflozin restores chronic kidney disease-induced impairment of endothelial regulation of cardiomyocyte relaxation and contraction. Kidney Int. 2021;99(5):1088&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.kint.2020.12.013 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2020.12.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oelze M, et al. The sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitor empagliflozin improves diabetes-induced vascular dysfunction in the streptozotocin diabetes rat model by interfering with oxidative stress and glucotoxicity. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(11):e112394. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0112394 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0112394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25402275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4234367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aroor AR, et al. Glycemic control by the SGLT2 inhibitor empagliflozin decreases aortic stiffness, renal resistivity index and kidney injury. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2018;17(1):108. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-018-0750-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-018-0750-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30060748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6065158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim HM, et al. Glycemic control with ipragliflozin, a novel selective SGLT2 inhibitor, ameliorated endothelial dysfunction in streptozotocin-induced diabetic mouse. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2016;3:43. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2016.00043 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2016.00043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27833913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5080286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, et al. Dapagliflozin prevents oxidative stress-induced endothelial dysfunction via sirtuin 1 activation. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;165:115213. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115213 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37517289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden M, et al. Empagliflozin ameliorates type 2 diabetes-induced ultrastructural remodeling of the neurovascular unit and neuroglia in the female db/db mouse. Brain Sci. 2019;9(3):57. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci9030057 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci9030057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30866531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6468773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campeau M-A, Leask RL. Empagliflozin reduces endoplasmic reticulum stress associated TXNIP/NLRP3 activation in tunicamycin-stimulated aortic endothelial cells. Naunyn-Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol. 2024;397(1):267&#x2013;79. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00210-023-02607-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00210-023-02607-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37421429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durante W, Behnammanesh G, Peyton KJ. Effects of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors on vascular cell function and arterial remodeling. Int J Mol Sci. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22168786 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22168786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8396183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mylonas N, et al. Endothelial protection by sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors: a literature review of in vitro and in vivo studies. Int J Mol Sci. 2024. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25137274 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25137274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39000380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11242615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruckert C, et al. Empagliflozin prevents angiotensin II-induced hypertension related micro and macrovascular endothelial cell activation and diastolic dysfunction in rats despite persistent hypertension: role of endothelial SGLT1 and 2. Vasc Pharmacol. 2022;146:107095. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vph.2022.107095 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vph.2022.107095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyton KJ, et al. Canagliflozin inhibits human endothelial cell inflammation through the induction of heme oxygenase-1. Int J Mol Sci. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23158777 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23158777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9369341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabour MS, et al. Canagliflozin mitigates carfilzomib-induced endothelial apoptosis via an AMPK-dependent pathway. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;164:114907. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114907 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37247463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad RN, et al. Crosstalk among NLRP3 inflammasome, ET(B)R signaling, and mirnas in stress-induced depression-like behavior: a modulatory role for SGLT2 inhibitors. Neurotherapeutics. 2021;18(4):2664&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-021-01140-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-021-01140-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34664178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8804152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, et al. Canagliflozin protects against hyperglycemia-induced cerebrovascular injury by preventing blood-brain barrier (BBB) disruption via AMPK/Sp1/adenosine A2A receptor. Eur J Pharmacol. 2024;968:176381. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejphar.2024.176381 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2024.176381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38341077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao S, et al. Endothelial progenitor cells for ischemic stroke: update on basic research and application. Stem Cells Int. 2017;2017:1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/2193432 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/2193432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taguchi A, et al. Administration of CD34+ cells after stroke enhances neurogenesis via angiogenesis in a mouse model. J Clin Invest. 2004;114(3):330&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci20622 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci20622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15286799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">484977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan SJ, et al. Vascular endothelial growth factor 165-binding heparan sulfate promotes functional recovery from cerebral ischemia. Stroke. 2020;51(9):2844&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.119.025304 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.119.025304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakbak E, et al. Empagliflozin improves circulating vascular regenerative cell content in people without diabetes with risk factors for adverse cardiac remodeling. Am J Physiol Heart Circul Physiol. 2023;325(5):H1210&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00141.2023 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00141.2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandula SR, et al. Role of canagliflozin on function of CD34+ve endothelial progenitor cells (EPC) in patients with type 2 diabetes. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20(1):44. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-021-01235-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-021-01235-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33581737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7881606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, et al. Dapagliflozin restores diabetes-associated decline in vasculogenic capacity of endothelial progenitor cells via activating AMPK-mediated inhibition of inflammation and oxidative stress. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2023;671:205&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbrc.2023.05.094 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2023.05.094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37302296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonora BM, et al. Effects of SGLT2 inhibitors on circulating stem and progenitor cells in patients with type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2018;103(10):3773&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2018-00824 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2018-00824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess DA, et al. SGLT2 inhibition with empagliflozin increases circulating provascular progenitor cells in people with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cell Metab. 2019;30(4):609&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2019.08.015 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2019.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak BD, et al. Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis in a patient with acute stroke taking sodium glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitor. Ann Med Surg (2012). 2022;79:104118. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amsu.2022.104118 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amsu.2022.104118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussaini SA, et al. Late-onset euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis in a patient with massive stroke requiring decompressive craniectomy: a case report. Cureus. 2021;13(10):e18629. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.18629 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.18629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34765377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8575253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razok A, et al. Sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors induced euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis within four days of initiation. World J Diabetes. 2022;13(3):272&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.4239/wjd.v13.i3.272 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v13.i3.272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35432760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8984572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barski L, et al. Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis. Eur J Intern Med. 2019;63:9&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejim.2019.03.014 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2019.03.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30910328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umapathysivam MM, et al. Euglycemic ketoacidosis in two patients without diabetes after introduction of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor for heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(1):140&#x2013;3. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc23-1163 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc23-1163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37988720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock J, Ferrannini E. Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis: a predictable, detectable, and preventable safety concern with SGLT2 inhibitors. Diabetes Care. 2015;38(9):1638&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc15-1380 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc15-1380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26294774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujara S, Ioachimescu A. Prolonged ketosis in a patient with euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis secondary to dapagliflozin. J Investig Med High Impact Case Rep. 2017;5(2):2324709617710040. https://doi.org/10.1177/2324709617710040 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2324709617710040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28589154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5446101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian SV, et al. Diabetic ketoacidosis complicated by generalized venous thrombosis: a case report and review. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis. 2012;23(3):238&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1097/MBC.0b013e32834fb599 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MBC.0b013e32834fb599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22356837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Nor NS, et al. Ischaemic haemorrhagic stroke in a child with new onset type 1 diabetes mellitus. Eur Endocrinol. 2018;14(1):59&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.17925/EE.2018.14.1.59 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17925/EE.2018.14.1.59</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29922355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5954598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu H, Novikov A, Vallon V. Ketosis and diabetic ketoacidosis in response to SGLT2 inhibitors: basic mechanisms and therapeutic perspectives. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2017. https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.2886 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.2886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28099783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasa P, et al. Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis: a missed diagnosis. World J Diabetes. 2021;12(5):514&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.4239/wjd.v12.i5.514 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v12.i5.514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33995841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8107974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff R, Koh C-K. Isoproterenol induced insulin resistance leading to diabetic ketoacidosis in type 1 diabetes mellitus. Case Rep Endocrinol. 2018;2018:4328954. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/4328954 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/4328954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30647979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6311779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura G. Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors and stroke. Circ J. 2017;81(6):898. https://doi.org/10.1253/circj.CJ-17-0040 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.CJ-17-0040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallow KM, et al. Why do SGLT2 inhibitors reduce heart failure hospitalization? A differential volume regulation hypothesis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2018;20(3):479&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.13126 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.13126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29024278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, et al. Empagliflozin in patients with heart failure, reduced ejection fraction, and volume overload: EMPEROR-reduced trial. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77(11):1381&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2021.01.033 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.01.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazer CD, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on erythropoietin levels, iron stores, and red blood cell morphology in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus and coronary artery disease. Circulation. 2020;141(8):704&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.044235 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.044235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31707794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M. Alleviation of anemia by SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with CKD: mechanisms and results of long-term placebo-controlled trials. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2023;19(4):531&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.2215/cjn.0000000000000362 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/cjn.0000000000000362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37902773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11020424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira JP, et al. Impact of anaemia and the effect of empagliflozin in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: findings from EMPEROR-reduced. Eur J Heart Fail. 2022;24(4):708&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1002/ejhf.2409 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.2409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34957660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imprialos KP, et al. Stroke paradox with SGLT-2 inhibitors: a play of chance or a viscosity-mediated reality? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(3):249&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2016-314704 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2016-314704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27895093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong CKH, et al. Cardiovascular benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes, interaction with metformin and role of erythrocytosis: a self-controlled case series study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):92. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-022-01520-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-022-01520-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35658864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9166572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, et al. Inhibition of sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 improves anaemia in mice and humans with sickle cell disease, and reduces infarct size in a murine stroke model. J Cell Mol Med. 2024;28(17):e70091. https://doi.org/10.1111/jcmm.70091 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.70091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39267208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11392826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwere RB, Hewitt J. Myopathy in older people receiving statin therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2015;80(3):363&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1111/bcp.12687 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.12687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26032930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4574822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, et al. Statin-associated muscle symptoms (SAMS) in primary prevention for cardiovascular disease in older adults: a protocol for a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ Open. 2017;7(9):e017587. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2017-017587 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2017-017587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28963307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5623566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brailovski E, Kim RB, Juurlink D. Rosuvastatin myotoxicity after starting canagliflozin treatment: a case report. Ann Intern Med. 2020;173(7):585&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.7326/l20-0549 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/l20-0549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32744865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Hall S, Bach LA. Myopathy secondary to empagliflozin therapy in type 2 diabetes. Endocrinol Diabetes Metab Case Rep. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1530/edm-20-0017 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/edm-20-0017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7159254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner RM, Pirmohamed M. Statin-related myotoxicity: a comprehensive review of pharmacokinetic, pharmacogenomic and muscle components. J Clin Med. 2019. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm9010022 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9010022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31861911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7019839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalagkas PN, et al. Potential drug-drug interaction between sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors and statins: pharmacological and clinical evidence. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2021;17(6):697&#x2013;705. https://doi.org/10.1080/17425255.2021.1921735 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17425255.2021.1921735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devineni D, et al. Effect of canagliflozin on the pharmacokinetics of glyburide, metformin, and simvastatin in healthy participants. Clin Pharmacol Drug Dev. 2015;4(3):226&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1002/cpdd.166 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpdd.166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27140803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasichayanula S, et al. Lack of pharmacokinetic interactions between dapagliflozin and simvastatin, valsartan, warfarin, or digoxin. Adv Ther. 2012;29(2):163&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12325-011-0098-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-011-0098-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macha S, et al. Pharmacokinetics of empagliflozin, a sodium glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor, and simvastatin following co-administration in healthy volunteers. Int J Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2014;52(11):973&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.5414/CP202117 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5414/CP202117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25161155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawra VK, et al. Assessment of the drug interaction potential of ertugliflozin with sitagliptin, metformin, glimepiride, or simvastatin in healthy subjects. Clin Pharmacol Drug Dev. 2019;8(3):314&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1002/cpdd.472 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpdd.472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29786959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravel CA, et al. Concomitant use of statins and sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors and the risk of myotoxicity reporting: a disproportionality analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2023;89(8):2430&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1111/bcp.15711 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36912450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkabbani W, et al. Drug-drug interaction of the sodium glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors with statins and myopathy: a disproportionality analysis using adverse events reporting data. Drug Saf. 2022;45(3):287&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40264-022-01166-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-022-01166-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>