<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40918816</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association Between Sodium-Glucose Cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) Inhibitor Use and All-Cause Mortality in Patients With Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e89465</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e89465</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e89465</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.89465</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) reduce mortality in heart failure patients with reduced and preserved ejection fraction. Their potential benefits in pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH) are unknown. This study evaluates the relationship between SGLT2i use and all-cause mortality in patients with PAH.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using the TriNetX Research Network, we included patients diagnosed with PAH after January 1, 2013. Group A (SGLT2i group) included patients prescribed canagliflozin, dapagliflozin, empagliflozin, or ertugliflozin, and Group B (non-SGLT2i group) included patients not using these medications. Outcomes were assessed at one-, three-, and five-year intervals following the index event (PAH diagnosis and medication initiation). Propensity score matching was used to account for demographics and comorbidities. Matched cohorts included 7,998 patients in Group A and 8,006 in Group B.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Over one year, mortality occurred in 614 of 7,998 patients (7.7%) in Group A, whereas Group B experienced 1,251 deaths among 8,006 patients (15.6%), yielding a risk difference of 7.9% (p &lt; 0.0001). This mortality advantage associated with SGLT2i inhibitor use remained evident at the three-year mark, with 1,012 of 7,998 patients (12.7%) deceased in Group A compared to 1,930 of 8,006 (24.1%) in Group B, translating to an 11.5% absolute risk difference (p &lt; 0.0001). By five years, mortality had reached 1,139 out of 7,998 patients (14.2%) in Group A and 2,190 out of 8,006 (27.4%) in Group B, with a corresponding risk difference of 13.1% (p &lt; 0.0001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">SGLT2i use was associated with significant and sustained mortality reduction in PAH patients. A 13% absolute risk reduction at five years highlights the potential for a transformative impact on PAH management. Randomized controlled trials are warranted to confirm these findings and guide clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Lemonjava et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lemonjava</LastName><ForeName>Irakli</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Einstein Medical Center Philadelphia, Philadelphia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gudushauri</LastName><ForeName>Nino</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Einstein Medical Center Philadelphia, Philadelphia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tskhakaia</LastName><ForeName>Irakli</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Einstein Medical Center Philadelphia, Philadelphia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manzano</LastName><ForeName>Jose M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Subramanian</LastName><ForeName>Apoorva</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Einstein Medical Center Philadelphia, Philadelphia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lo</LastName><ForeName>Kevin B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azmaiparashvili</LastName><ForeName>Zurab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Einstein Medical Center Philadelphia, Philadelphia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">innovative therapies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">large database analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mortality benefit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (sglt2) inhibitors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40918816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12412193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.89465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The metabolic theory of pulmonary arterial hypertension. Paulin R, Michelakis ED. Circ Res. 2014;115:148&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24951764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension: a review. Ruopp NF, Cockrill BA. JAMA. 2022;327:1379&#x2013;1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35412560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inhaled pulmonary vasodilators: a narrative review. Liu K, Wang H, Yu SJ, Tu GW, Luo Z. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33987295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanistic phase II clinical trial of metformin in pulmonary arterial hypertension. Brittain EL, Niswender K, Agrawal V, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:18349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin in heart failure with a preserved ejection fraction. Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, et al. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:1451&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dapagliflozin in patients with chronic kidney disease. Heerspink HJ, Stef&#xe1;nsson BV, Correa-Rotter R, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:1436&#x2013;1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SGLT2 inhibitors as a potential therapeutic option for pulmonary hypertension: mechanisms and clinical perspectives. Tan JS, Wei Y, Chong L, Yang Y, Hu S, Wang Y. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2024;61:709&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38847284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on clinical practice guidelines. Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, et al. Circulation. 2022;145:895&#x2013;1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanisms of cardiorenal protection with SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with T2DM based on network pharmacology. Wang A, Li Z, Zhuo S, et al. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:857952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9169967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35677689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SGLT2 inhibitors attenuate nephrin loss and enhance TGF-&#x3b2;(1) secretion in type 2 diabetes patients with albuminuria: a randomized clinical trial. Tian Y, Chen XM, Liang XM, Wu XB, Yao CM. Sci Rep. 2022;12:15695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9489863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36127497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notch3 signalling and vascular remodelling in pulmonary arterial hypertension. Morris HE, Neves KB, Montezano AC, MacLean MR, Touyz RM. Clin Sci (Lond) 2019;133:2481&#x2013;2498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6928565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novel signaling pathways in pulmonary arterial hypertension (2015 Grover Conference Series) Awad KS, West JD, de Jesus Perez V, MacLean M. Pulm Circ. 2016;6:285&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5019081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors on vascular cell function and arterial remodeling. Durante W, Behnammanesh G, Peyton KJ. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8396183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endothelial protection by sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors: a literature review of in vitro and in vivo studies. Mylonas N, Nikolaou PE, Karakasis P, Stachteas P, Fragakis N, Andreadou I. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11242615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39000380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>