<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40365365</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0973-6131</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Apr</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of yoga</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Yoga</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Impact of Yoga Intervention on Psychological Symptoms in Irritable Bowel Syndrome Patients: A Randomized Controlled Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>58</StartPage><EndPage>66</EndPage><MedlinePgn>58-66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijoy.ijoy_200_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is an extremely prevalent gastrointestinal disorder that has an unfavorable impact on the living standard and IBS-related multiple symptoms. 11%-15% of people worldwide are suffering from IBS. Secondary symptoms such as depression or anxiety are experienced by IBS patients. Yoga practices combined with traditional medical treatment can be a successful therapy for IBS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The objective of this randomized control research was to observe the effectiveness of the yoga intervention as an add-on therapy in IBS patients with conventional treatment and its comparison with IBS with conventional treatment as a control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The suggested research is an open-blinded, prospective, randomly assigned, single-center, parallel-group, and end-point trial. Patients with IBS who satisfied the Rome &#x2163; criteria for diagnosis were recruited and randomly allocated into two groups: Intervention Group A (Yoga + conventional treatment) and Control Group B (Conventional treatment only). Group A (<i>n</i> = 85) received yoga intervention five times a week for 3 months, and Group B (<i>n</i> = 80) took their prescribed medication without yoga intervention. Psychological symptoms and IBS severity scores before and after yoga intervention were measured and compared with the control group with the help of validated questionnaires: Depression, Anxiety, and Stress Score (DASS-21) and IBS Severity Score, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The body weight and body mass index after 3 months of follow-up were significantly lowered (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) in the yoga intervention group as compared to the control group. The overall severity of IBS after yoga interventions in Group A (259.2 &#xb1; 49.9-256.1 &#xb1; 48.6, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.01) was significantly reduced than the control group (270 &#xb1; 56.6-271.9 &#xb1; 54.8, <i>P</i> &gt; 0.05). Moreover, the psychological stress (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) and anxiety (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01) scores were also significantly decreased after 3 months of follow-up in the yoga intervention group. The serum cortisol level was decreased in Group A. However, it could not reach a significant level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The current study indicates an affirmative result of yoga intervention along with conventional treatment for patients with IBS might be strongly advised.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 International Journal of Yoga.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Devi</LastName><ForeName>Diksha</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, King George's Medical University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattacharya</LastName><ForeName>Sandeep</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, King George's Medical University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiwari</LastName><ForeName>Sunita</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Dr. Ram Manohar Lohia Institute of Medical Sciences, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripathi</LastName><ForeName>Adarsh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, King George's Medical University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Kalpana</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, King George's Medical University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rungta</LastName><ForeName>Sumit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, King George's Medical University, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Yoga</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101313247</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0973-6131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">and Stress Score-21 scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serum cortisol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">yoga intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40365365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12068461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijoy.ijoy_200_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJY-18-58</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schumann D, Langhorst J, Dobos G, Cramer H. Randomised clinical trial: Yoga versus a low-FODMAP diet in patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2018;47:203&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29076171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley EM, Fried M, Gwee KA, Khalif I, Hungin AP, Lindberg G, et al. World Gastroenterology Organisation global guidelines irritable bowel syndrome: A global perspective update September 2015. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2016;50:704&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27623513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavuri V, Selvan P, Tabesh A, Raghuram N, Selvan SR. Remedial Yoga module improves symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome: Replication in the Wait-list group and sustained improvements at 6 months. Eur J Integr Med. 2015;7:609&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley EM, Abdel-Hamid H, Barbara G, Bhatia SJ, Boeckxstaens G, De Giorgio R, et al. A global perspective on irritable bowel syndrome: A consensus statement of the World Gastroenterology Organisation summit task force on irritable bowel syndrome. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2012;46:356&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22499071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole JA, Rothman KJ, Cabral HJ, Zhang Y, Farraye FA. Migraine, fibromyalgia, and depression among people with IBS: A prevalence study. BMC Gastroenterol. 2006;6:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1592499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17007634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkalash SH, Almagadi RA, Alamri SM, Al-amri LA, Al-amri MA, Al-amri JM, et al.  Prevalence and Risk Factors of Irritable Bowel Syndrome Among Adults in Al-Qunfudah Governorate, Saudi Arabia. Cureus. 2023.  Available from: https://www.cureus.com/articles/198283-prevalence-and-risk-factors-of-irritable-bowel-syndrome-among-adults-in-al-qunfudah-governorate-saudi-arabia . [Last accessed on 2024 Jun 11]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10711523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38090431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saluja RK. Successful Yoga Prana Vidya (YPV) healing treatment of Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS): A case report. IJMSCRS. 2022. p. 2. Available from: https://ijmscr.org/index.php/ijmscrs/article/view/184 . [Last accessed on 2024 Jun 10]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palanimurugan P, Arumugam V, Balakrishnan A, Annamalai G, Kuppusamy M, Venkateswaran ST, et al. Yoga and naturopathy intervention on psychological comorbidities and autonomic function for irritable bowel syndrome patient: A case study. Brain Behav Immun Integr. 2024;5:100042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surdea-Blaga T, B&#x103;ban A, Dumitrascu DL. Psychosocial determinants of Irritable bowel syndrome. World J Gastroenterol. 2012;18:616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3281218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22363132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnaout AY, Nerabani Y, Douba Z, Kassem LH, Arnaout K, Shabouk MB, et al. The prevalence and risk factors of irritable bowel syndrome (PRIBS study) among adults in low- and middle-income countries: A multicenter cross-sectional study. Health Sci Rep. 2023;6:e1592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10551279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37808932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeeshan MH, Vakkalagadda NP, Sree GS, Anne KK, Devi S, Parkash O, et al.  Irritable bowel syndrome in adults: Prevalence and risk factors. Ann Med Surg. 2022;81:104408. Available from: https://journals.lww.com/10.1016/j.amsu.2022.104408 . [Last accessed on 2024 Jul 05]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9486601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36147064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee A, Sarkhel S, Dhali GK, Paul I, Das A. A follow-up study of anxiety and depressive symptoms in Irritable bowel syndrome. Indian J Psychiatry. 2024;66:142&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10956588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38523769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DY, Kim E, Choi MH. Technical and clinical aspects of cortisol as a biochemical marker of chronic stress. BMB Rep. 2015;48:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4436856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25560699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Silva A, Marshall DA, Vallance J, Nasser Y, Rajagopalan V, MacKean G, et al. Meditation and yoga for irritable bowel syndrome: Study protocol for a randomised clinical trial (MY-IBS study) BMJ Open. 2022;12:e059604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9137346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thirthalli J, Naveen G, Rao M, Varambally S, Christopher R, Gangadhar B. Cortisol and antidepressant effects of yoga. Indian J Psychiatry. 2013;55:405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3768222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24049209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen YH, Nahas R. Complementary and alternative medicine for treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Can Fam Physician. 2009;55:143&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2642499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19221071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalit M, Nimisha NI, Jain K. Comparative effect of Yogasana and pranayama on depression, anxiety and stress levels in adults practitioners. Int J Indian Psychol. 2020;8:961&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra P, Mandal S, Sharma G, Kant S, Rai S, Yadav K, et al.  Effect of Structured Yoga Program on Stress and Well-being Among Frontline Healthcare Workers During COVID-19 Pandemic. Cureus [Internet] 2023.  Available from: https://www.cureus.com/articles/175587-effect-of-structured-yoga-program-on-stress-and-well-being-among-frontline-healthcare-workers-during-covid-19-pandemic . [Last accessed on 2024 Jun 11]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10482358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37680404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavuri V, Raghuram N, Malamud A, Selvan SR. Irritable bowel syndrome: Yoga as remedial therapy. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2015;2015:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4438173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26064164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshihara K, Hiramoto T, Oka T, Kubo C, Sudo N. Effect of 12 weeks of yoga training on the somatization, psychological symptoms, and stress-related biomarkers of healthy women. Biopsychosoc Med. 2014;8:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3892034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24383884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Szabo A. Effects of Yoga on stress among healthy adults: A systematic review. Altern Ther Health Med. 2020;26:AT6214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32088671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswajit Bhunia. Yoga to Manage Stress and Sports Performance. Inter J Appl Soc Sci. 2020;7:601&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palsson OS, Whitehead WE, Van Tilburg MA, Chang L, Chey W, Crowell MD, et al. Development and validation of the Rome IV diagnostic questionnaire for adults. Gastroenterology. 2016;150:1481&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setia G, Ramanathan M, Bhavanani AB, Prabu BS, Vinoth B, Ananthkrishnan N. Adjuvant yoga therapy for symptom management of functional dyspepsia: A case series. J Ayurveda Integr Med. 2023;14:100715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10213372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37216873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devi D, Bhattacharya S. Role of Asana, Pranayama, and meditation as an add-on therapy in regulation of hypertension. HTNJ. 2024;9:139&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta P. Health impacts of yoga and pranayama: A state-of-the-art review. Int J Prev Med. 2012;3:444&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3415184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22891145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis CY, Morris J, Whorwell PJ. The irritable bowel severity scoring system: A simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 1997;11:395&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9146781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry JD, Crawford JR. The short-form version of the Depression anxiety stress scales (DASS-21): Construct validity and normative data in a large non-clinical sample. Br J Clin Psychol. 2005;44:227&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16004657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akram Z, Khairnar MR, Kusumakar A, Kumar JS, Sabharwal H, Priyadarsini SS, et al. Updated B. G. Prasad socioeconomic status classification for the year 2023. J Indian Assoc Public Health Dent. 2023;21:204&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari S, Damodara Gowda KM, Sukesh N, Madhu LN, Kathyayini Effect of yoga therapy on body mass index and oxidative status. J Health Allied Scie NU. 2011;01:10&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turakitwanakan W, Mekseepralard C, Busarakumtragul P. Effects of mindfulness meditation on serum cortisol of medical students. J Med Assoc Thai. 2013;96(Suppl 1):S90&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23724462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern D, Lindfors E, Lal&#xe9;r L, Lindfors A, Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Lindfors P. Ashtangayoga for irritable bowel syndrome in a primary care setting: A feasibility study. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2024;36:e14744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38287465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baklouti S, Fekih-Romdhane F, Guelmami N, Bonsaksen T, Baklouti H, Aloui A, et al. The effect of web-based Hatha yoga on psychological distress and sleep quality in older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Complementary Therapies in Clinical Practice. 2023;50:101715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36521407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>