<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40929652</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5687</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of gastroenterology &amp; hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative effectiveness and safety of probiotics with psychotropic potential in mental health benefits in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MEG.0000000000003062</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The use of probiotics as a treatment for irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is gaining attention, with recent studies indicating that certain probiotics or combinations may have mental health benefits for patients with IBS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To systematically review and meta-analyze, using network meta-analysis (NWM), the comparative effectiveness and safety of probiotics with psychotropic potential on quality of life, depression, and anxiety in patients with IBS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Relevant randomized controlled trials (RCTs) were analyzed, using a Bayesian NWM, to compare the performance of probiotics with mental health benefits in IBS treatment. Treatment effectiveness was assessed using surfaces under cumulative ranking (SUCRA) values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis included 3154 participants assigned to nine different treatments: Bifidobacterium longum, Saccharomyces, Clostridium butyricum, Bifidobacterium lactis, Lactobacillus acidophilus, Lactobacillus casei strain Shirota, Lactobacillus plantarum, probiotic combinations, and placebo. B. longum and probiotic combinations were found to be significantly more effective than placebo. In terms of improving quality of life (QoL), B. longum was the most effective (SUCRA&#x2005;=&#x2005;89.7%), while L. plantarum was the least effective (SUCRA&#x2005;=&#x2005;14.9%). For alleviating depression and anxiety, the combination of probiotics (SUCRA&#x2005;=&#x2005;95.6%) and L. acidophilus (SUCRA&#x2005;=&#x2005;74.2%) showed the best results, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Some probiotics or combinations may offer benefits for patients with IBS in improving QoL, depression, and anxiety; however, as this is a developing field, additional research is necessary to fully understand the effectiveness, underlying mechanisms, and specific strains that may be advantageous. More high-quality RCTs are needed to substantiate these therapeutic possibilities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rokkas</LastName><ForeName>Theodore</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology Clinic, Henry Dunant Hospital, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, European University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekmektzoglou</LastName><ForeName>Konstantinos</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology Clinic, Henry Dunant Hospital, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, European University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsanou</LastName><ForeName>Evangelia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology of the Agricultural University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bricca</LastName><ForeName>Ludovica</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Hyigiene, Department of Life Sciences and Public Health, Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menni</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra-Eleftheria</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Golfakis</LastName><ForeName>Paraskevas</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hepatogastroenterology Unit, Second Department of Internal Medicine - Propaedeutic, Medical School, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, ''Attikon" University General Hospital, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotzampassi</LastName><ForeName>Katerina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9000874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-691X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">probiotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychobiotics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40929652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MEG.0000000000003062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042737-990000000-00587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Drossman DA. Functional gastrointestinal disorders: history, pathophysiology, clinical features and Rome IV. Gastroenterology 2016; 150:1262&#x2013;1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Sperber AD, Corsetti M, Camilleri M. Irritable bowel syndrome. Lancet 2020; 396:1675&#x2013;1688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oka P, Parr H, Barberio B, Black CJ, Savarino EV, Ford AC. Global prevalence of irritable bowel syndrome according to Rome III or IV criteria: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2020; 5:908&#x2013;917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperber AD, Bangdiwala SI, Drossman DA, Ghoshal UC, Simren M, Tack J, et al. Worldwide prevalence and burden of functional gastrointestinal disorders, results of Rome Foundation global study. Gastroenterology 2021; 160:99&#x2013;114.e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtmann GJ, Ford AC, Talley NJ. Pathophysiology of irritable bowel syndrome. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2016; 1:133&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black CJ, Burr NE, Camilleri M, Earnest DL, Quigley EM, Moayyedi P, et al. Efficacy of pharmacological therapies in patients with IBS with diarrhea or mixed stool pattern: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Gut 2020; 69:74&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasant DH, Paine PA, Black CJ, Houghton LA, Everitt HA, Corsetti M, et al. British Society of Gastroenterology guidelines on the management of irritable bowel syndrome. Gut 2021; 70:1214&#x2013;1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Card T, Enck P, Barbara G, Boeckxstaens GE, Santos J, Azpiroz F, et al. Post-infectious IBS: defining its clinical features and prognosis using an internet-based survey. United European Gastroenterol J 2018; 6:1245&#x2013;1253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durban A, Abellan JJ, Jimenez-Hernandez N, Artacho A, Garrigues V, Ortiz V, et al. Instability of the faecal microbiota in diarrhea predominant irritable bowel syndrome. FEMS Microbiol Ecol 2013; 86:581&#x2013;589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll IM, Ringel-Kulka T, Siddle JP, Ringel Y. Alterations in composition and diversity of the intestinal microbiota in patients with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Neurogastroenterol Motil 2012; 24:521&#x2013;30, e248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalanka-Tuovinen J, Salojarvi J, Salonen A, Immonen O, Garsed K, Kelly FM, et al. Faecal microbiota composition and host-microbe cross-talk following gastroenteritis and in postinfectious irritable bowel syndrome. Gut 2014; 63:1737&#x2013;1745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassinen A, Krogius-Kurikka L, Makivuokko H, Rinttil&#xe4; T, Paulin L, Corander J, et al. The fecal microbiota of irritable bowel syndrome patient differs significantly from that of healthy subjects. Gastroenterology 2007; 133:24&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ianiro G, Eusebi LH, Black CJ, Gasbarrini A, Cammarota G, Ford AC. Systematic review with meta-analysis: efficacy of faecal microbiota transplantation for the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2019; 50:240&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimentel M, Lembo A, Chey WD, Zakko S, Ringel Y, Yu J, et al.; TARGET Study Group. Rifaximin therapy for patients with irritable bowel syndrome without constipation. N Engl J Med 2011; 364:22&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokkas T, Niv Y, Gisbert JP, et al. The role of rifaximin in irritable bowel syndrome derived from a network meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Microb Health Dis 2020; 2:e333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Pimentel M, Brenner DM, Chey WD, Keefer LA, Long MD, Moshiree B. ACG clinical guideline: management of irritable bowel syndrome. Am J Gastroenterol 2021; 116:17&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill C, Guarner F, Reid G, Gibson GR, Merenstein DJ, Pot B, et al. Expert consensus document. The International Scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics consensus statement on the scope and appropriate use of the term probiotic. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2014; 11:506&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodoory VC, Khasawneh M, Black CJ, Quigley EMM, Moayyedi P, Ford AC. Efficacy of probiotics in irritable bowel syndrome: systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology 2023; 165:1206&#x2013;1218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Zhang C, Zhang J, Sun F, Duan L. Efficacy of probiotics for irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Front Cell Infect Microbiol 20222022; 12:859967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie P, Luo M, Deng X, Fan J, Xiong L. Outcome-specific efficacy of different probiotic strains and mixtures in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Nutrients 2023; 15:3856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra S, Mohanty D. Psychobiotics: a new approach for treating mental illness? Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 2017; 59:1230&#x2013;1236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett E, Ross RP, O&#x2019;Toole PW, Fitzgerald GF, Stanton C. &#x3b3;-Aminobutyric- acid production by culturable bacteria from the human intestine. J Appl Microbiol 2012; 113:411&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selhub EM, Logan AC, Bested AC. Fermented foods, microbiota, and mental health: ancient practice meets nutritional psychiatry. J Physiol Anthropol 2014; 33:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkasheh GZ, Kashani-Poor M, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi P, Jafari P, Akbasi M, Taghizadeh M, et al. Clinical and metabolic response to probiotic administration in patients with major depressive disorder: a randomized, double blind, placebo-controlled trial. Nutrition 2016; 32:315&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinan TG, Stanton C, Cryan JF. Psychobiotics: a novel class of psychotropic. Biol Psychiatry 2013; 74:720&#x2013;726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G, Ades AE, Ioannidis JP. Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol 2011; 64:163&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaimani A, Higgins JPT, Mavridis D, Spyridonos P, Salanti G. Graphical tools for network meta-analysis in STATA. PLoS One 2013; 8:e76654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S, Hutton B, Clifford T, Coyle D, Grima D, Wells G, Cameron C. A Microsoft-Excel based tool for running and critically appraising network meta-analyses an overview and application of NetMetaXL. Syst Rev 2014; 3:110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokkas T, Gisbert JP, Niv Y, O&#x2019;Morain C. The association between Helicobacter pylori infection and inflammatory bowel disease based on meta-analysis. United European Gastroenterol J 2015; 3:539&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med 2015; 162:777&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhan MA, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Murad MH, Li T, Brignardello-Petersen R, Singh JA, et al.; GRADE Working Group. A GRADE Working Group approach for rating the quality of treatment effect estimates from network meta-analysis. BMJ 2008; 336:924&#x2013;926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokkas T, Gisbert JP, Gasbarrini A, Hold GL, Tilg H, Malfertheiner P, et al. A network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials exploring the role of fecal microbiota transplantation in recurrent Clostridium difficile infection. United European Gastroenterol J 2019; 7:1051&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick DL, Drossman DA, Frederick IO, Dicesare J, Puder KL. Quality of life in persons with irritable bowel syndrome (development and validation of a new measure). Dig Dis Sci 1998; 43:400&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand 1983; 67:361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjelland I, Dahl AA, Haug TT. The validity of the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale. An updated literature reviews. J Psychosom Res 2002; 52:69&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis CY, Morris J, Whorwell PJ. The irritable bowel severity scoring system: a simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 1997; 11:395&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dam NT, Earleywine M. Validation of the Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale &#x2013; Revised (CESD-R): pragmatic depression assessment in the general population. Psychiatry Res 2011; 186:128&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams EA, Stimpson J, Wang D, Plummer S, Garaiova I, Barker ME, Corfe BM. Clinical trial: a multistrain probiotic preparation significantly reduces symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome in a double-blind placebo-controlled study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2009; 29:97&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simr&#xe9;n M, Ohman L, Olsson J, Svensson U, Ohlson K, Posserud I, Strid H. Clinical trial: the effects of a fermented milk containing three probiotic bacteria in patients with irritable bowel syndrome &#x2013; a randomized, double-blind, controlled study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2010; 31:218&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CH, Jo SY, Park HJ, Chang SK, Byeon J-S, Myung S-J. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multicenter trial of Saccharomyces boulardii in irritable bowel syndrome: effect on quality of life. J Clin Gastroenterol 2011; 45:679&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ki Cha B, Mun Jung S, Hwan Choi C, Song ID, Lee HW, Kim HJ, et al. The effect of a multispecies probiotic mixture on the symptoms and fecal microbiota in diarrhea-dominant irritable bowel syndrome. a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Gastroenterol 2012; 46:220&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begtrup LM, de Muckadell OB, Kjeldsen J, Christensen RD, Jarb&#xf8;l DE. Long-term treatment with probiotics in primary care patients with irritable bowel syndrome &#x2013; a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Scand J Gastroenterol 2013; 48:1127&#x2013;1135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LM, McCahon D, Holder R, Wilson S, Hobbs FDR. A randomised controlled trial of a probiotic &#x2018;functional food&#x2019; in the management of irritable bowel syndrome. BMC Gastroenterol 2013; 13:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shavakhi A, Minakari M, Farzamnia S, Peykar MS, Taghipour G, Tayebi A, et al. The effects of multi-strain probiotic compound on symptoms and quality-of-life in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Adv Biomed Res 2014; 3:140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenzo-Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga V, Llop E, Su&#xe1;rez C, &#xc1;lvarez B, Abreu L, Espadaler J, Serra J. I.31, a new combination of probiotics, improves irritable bowel syndrome-related quality of life. World J Gastroenterol 2014; 20:8709&#x2013;8716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisson G, Ayis S, Sherwood RA, Bjarnason I. Randomised clinical trial: a liquid multi-strain probiotic vs. placebo in the irritable bowel syndrome &#x2013; a 12-week double blind study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2014; 40:51&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson C, Blaauw R, Fredericks E, Visser J, Roux S. Randomized clinical trial: effect of Lactobacillus plantarum 299 v on symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome. Nutrition 2014; 30:1151&#x2013;1157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CH, Kwon JG, Kim SK, Myung SJ, Park KS, So CI, et al. Efficacy of combination therapy with probiotics and mosapride in patients with IBS without diarrhea: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, phase II trial. Neurogastroenterol Motil 2015; 27:705&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thijssen AY, Clemens CH, Vankerckhoven V, Goossens H, Jonkers DMAE, Masclee AAM. Efficacy of Lactobacillus casei Shirota for patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2016; 28:8&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong RK, Yang C, Song GH, Wong J, Ho K-Y. Melatonin regulation as a possible mechanism for probiotic (VSL#3) in irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized double-blinded placebo study. Dig Dis Sci 2015; 60:186&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyra A, Hillila M, Huttunen T, M&#xe4;nnikk&#xf6; S, Taalikka M, Tennil&#xe4; J, et al. Irritable bowel syndrome symptom severity improves equally with probiotic and placebo. World J Gastroenterol 2016; 22:10631&#x2013;10642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto-Sanchez MI, Hall GB, Ghajar K, Nardelli A, Bolino C, Lau JT, et al. Probiotic Bifidobacterium longum NCC3001 reduces depression scores and alters brain activity: a pilot study in patients with irritable bowel syndrome. Gastroenterology 2017; 153:448&#x2013;459.e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishaque SM, Khosruzzaman SM, Ahmed DS, Sah MP. Randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial of a multi-strain probiotic formulation (Bio-Kult&#xae;) in the management of diarrhea predominant irritable bowel syndrome. BMC Gastroenterol 2018; 18:71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun YY, Li M, Li YY, Li L-X, Zhai W-Z, Wang P, et al. The effect of Clostridium butyricum on symptoms and fecal microbiota in diarrhea-dominant irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Sci Rep 2018; 8:2964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston K, Krumian R, Hattner J, de Montigny D, Stewart M, Gaddam S. Lactobacillus acidophilus CL1285, Lactobacillus casei LBC80R and Lactobacillus rhamnosus CLR2 improve quality-of-life and IBS symptoms: a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled study. Benef Microbes 2018; 9:697&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francavilla R, Piccolo M, Francavilla A, Polimero L, Semerato F, Cristofori F, et al. Clinical and microbiological effect of a multispecies probiotic supplementation in celiac patients with persistent IBS-type symptoms: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter trial. J Clin Gastroenterol 2019; 53:e117&#x2013;e125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Yu X, Yu L, Tian F, Zhao J, Zhang H, et al. Lactobacillus plantarum CCFM8610 alleviates irritable bowel syndrome and prevents gut microbiota dysbiosis: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, pilot clinical trial. Engineering 2021; 7:376&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martoni CJ, Srivastava S, Leyer GJ. Lactobacillus acidophilus DDS-1 and Bifidobacterium lactis UABla-12 improve abdominal pain severity and symptomology in irritable bowel syndrome: randomized controlled trial. Nutrients 2020; 12:363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skrzyd&#x142;o-Radomanska BS, Prozorow-Kr&#xf3;l B, Cicho&#x17c;-Lach H, Majsiak E, Bier&#x142;a JB, Kanarek E, et al. The effectiveness and safety of multi-strain probiotic preparation in patients with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome: a randomized controlled study. Nutrients 2021; 13:756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourey M, Decherf A, Jeanne JF, Cl&#xe9;ment-Ziza M, Grisoni ML, Machuron F, et al. Saccharomyces cerevisiae I-3856 in irritable bowel syndrome with predominant constipation. World J Gastroenterol 2022; 28:2509&#x2013;2522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkawi M, Raja Ali RAR, Wahab AW, Abdul Rathi ND, Mokhtar NM. A randomized, double&#x2011;blinded, placebo&#x2011;controlled clinical trial on Lactobacillus&#x2011;containing cultured milk drink as adjuvant therapy for depression in irritable bowel syndrome. Sci Rep 2024; 14:9478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastavaa S, Basaka U, Naghibib M, Vijayakumar V, Parihar R, Patel J, et al. A randomized double-blind, placebo-controlled trial to evaluate the safety and efficacy of live Bifidobacterium longum CECT 7347 (ES1) and heat-treated Bifidobacterium longum CECT 7347 (HT-ES1) in participants with diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Gut Microbes 2024; 16:2338322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashashati M, Rezaei N, Shafieyoun A, McKernan DP, Chang L, &#xd6;hman L, et al. Cytokin imbalance in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurogastroenterol Motil 2014; 26:1036&#x2013;1048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haroon E, Raison CL, Miller AH. Psychoneuroimmunology meets neuropsycho-pharmacology: translational implications of the impact of inflammation on behavior. Neuropsychopharmacology 2012; 37:137&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40908534</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>First Real-World Evidence of an AI-Enhanced Digital Collaborative Care Model to Improve IBS Symptoms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70144</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70144</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.70144</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Health systems struggle to deliver guideline-recommended multidisciplinary care to patients with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). Digital collaborative care models (DCCMs) that integrate technology with experienced providers offer a promising solution for improving IBS management. We aimed to evaluate whether a novel DCCM improved clinical outcomes in IBS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective, longitudinal uncontrolled single-arm study design was used to assess the Ayble Health program. Participants were recruited online via social media, clinic, or employer. Data were prospectively collected from 202 participants (78% female; 78% white) with active IBS symptoms at baseline (&#x2265;&#x2009;75 on the IBS symptom severity scale (IBS-SSS)) and completed at least one follow-up symptom survey. All participants engaged in at least one care pathway: (1) a multidisciplinary care team, (2) a nutrition program with a personalized elimination diet, and (3) a brain-gut behavioral therapy (BGBT) program. Each pathway was supported by AI algorithms trained on a large, multimodal GI dataset to identify and communicate key trends in patient-reported outcomes, further personalizing care plans.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 202 participants, 197 (98%) participated in the nutrition pathway, 152 (75%) the BGBT pathway, and 156 (77%) the care team pathway. The majority of participants (62%) enrolled in all three pathways. Participants experienced a 140-point decrease in IBS-SSS, on average, with 86% experiencing a &#x2265;&#x2009;50-point reduction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The novel DCCM successfully delivered evidence-based care to participants with active IBS symptoms, with clinically significant, sustained symptom relief. Randomized clinical trials are recommended to assess cost and treatment efficacy compared to standard of care approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lupe</LastName><ForeName>Stephen E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4285-6216</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olson</LastName><ForeName>Joseph M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9414-1941</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ayble Health, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamp</LastName><ForeName>Kendra</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7753-3564</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heitkemper</LastName><ForeName>Margaret</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2938-1842</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pathipati</LastName><ForeName>Mythili P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3580-7974</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Palo Alto Medical Foundation, Palo Alto, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simons</LastName><ForeName>Madison L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5042-2725</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Jordan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ayble Health, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jactel</LastName><ForeName>Samuel N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ayble Health, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Regueiro</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7681-8111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lembo</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4479-1188</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taft</LastName><ForeName>Tiffany H</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4670-2441</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Rome Foundation, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain&#x2013;gut behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">collaborative care model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40908534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.70144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>A. D. Sperber, D. Dumitrascu, S. Fukudo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Global Prevalence of IBS in Adults Remains Elusive due to the Heterogeneity of Studies: A Rome Foundation Working Team Literature Review,&#x201d; Gut 66, no. 6 (2017): 1075&#x2013;1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. J. Black and A. C. Ford, &#x201c;Global Burden of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Trends, Predictions and Risk Factors,&#x201d; Nature Reviews. Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 17, no. 8 (2020): 473&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. J. Black, E. R. Thakur, L. A. Houghton, E. M. M. Quigley, P. Moayyedi, and A. C. Ford, &#x201c;Efficacy of Psychological Therapies for Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Systematic Review and Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Gut 69, no. 8 (2020): 1441&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. S. van Lanen, A. de Bree, and A. Greyling, &#x201c;Efficacy of a Low&#x2010;FODMAP Diet in Adult Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; European Journal of Nutrition 60, no. 6 (2021): 3505&#x2013;3522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. E. Lacy, M. Pimentel, D. M. Brenner, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;ACG Clinical Guideline: Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 116, no. 1 (2021): 17&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. D. Chey, J. G. Hashash, L. Manning, and L. Chang, &#x201c;AGA Clinical Practice Update on the Role of Diet in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Expert Review,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 162, no. 6 (2022): 1737&#x2013;1745.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Basnayake, M. A. Kamm, A. Stanley, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Long&#x2010;Term Outcome of Multidisciplinary Versus Standard Gastroenterologist Care for Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders: A Randomized Trial,&#x201d; Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology 20, no. 9 (2022): 2102&#x2013;2111.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Scarlata, S. Eswaran, J. R. Baker, and W. D. Chey, &#x201c;Utilization of Dietitians in the Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome by Members of the American College of Gastroenterology,&#x201d; Official Journal of the American College of Gastroenterology | ACG 117, no. 6 (2022): 923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. J. Arizmendi, M. R. Craven, P. Martinez&#x2010;Camblor, L. K. Tormey, and J. K. Salwen&#x2010;Deremer, &#x201c;Engagement in GI Behavioral Health Is Associated With Reduced Portal Messages, Phone Calls, and ED Visits,&#x201d; Digestive Diseases and Sciences 69, no. 6 (2024): 1939&#x2013;1947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Luo, R. E. Dixon, B. J. Shah, and L. A. Keefer, &#x201c;Gastroenterology Trainees' Attitudes and Knowledge Towards Patients With Disorders of Gut&#x2010;Brain Interaction,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 34, no. 11 (2022): e14410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. G. David, E. Sejkora, H. K. Michel, and L. Mackner, &#x201c;Pediatric GI Health Care Professionals' Perceptions of and Engagement With Psychosocial Providers in Pediatric IBD Care,&#x201d; JPGN Reports 4, no. 2 (2023): e305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Shaver, &#x201c;The State of Telehealth Before and After the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic,&#x201d; Primary Care Clinics in Office Practice 49, no. 4 (2022): 517&#x2013;530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ipsos, &#x201c;MDVIP/Ipsos Poll Shows Americans Are Struggling With the Healthcare System | Ipsos [Internet],&#x201d; (2024), accessed November 21, 2024, https://www.ipsos.com/en&#x2010;us/mdvipipsos&#x2010;poll&#x2010;shows&#x2010;americans&#x2010;are&#x2010;struggling&#x2010;healthcare&#x2010;system.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Dimidi, K. Belogianni, K. Whelan, and M. C. E. Lomer, &#x201c;Gut Symptoms During FODMAP Restriction and Symptom Response to Food Challenges During FODMAP Reintroduction: A Real&#x2010;World Evaluation in 21,462 Participants Using a Mobile Application,&#x201d; Nutrients 15, no. 12 (2023): 2683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. M. Brenner, A. M. Ladewski, and S. W. Kinsinger, &#x201c;Development and Current State of Digital Therapeutics for Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology 22, no. 2 (2024): 222&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. P. Pathipati, L. L. Scott, A. C. Griser, and K. Staller, &#x201c;Real&#x2010;World Outcomes for a Digital Prescription Mobile Application for Adults With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 36, no. 7 (2024): e14811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Menear, A. Girard, M. Dugas, M. Gervais, M. Gilbert, and M. P. Gagnon, &#x201c;Personalized Care Planning and Shared Decision Making in Collaborative Care Programs for Depression and Anxiety Disorders: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; PLoS One 17, no. 6 (2022): e0268649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Kappelin, A. C. Carlsson, and C. Wachtler, &#x201c;Specific Content for Collaborative Care: A Systematic Review of Collaborative Care Interventions for Patients With Multimorbidity Involving Depression and/or Anxiety in Primary Care,&#x201d; Family Practice 39, no. 4 (2022): 725&#x2013;734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Click and M. Regueiro, &#x201c;The Inflammatory Bowel Disease Medical Home: From Patients to Populations,&#x201d; Inflammatory Bowel Diseases 25, no. 12 (2019): 1881&#x2013;1885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. N. Jactel, J. M. Olson, K. Y. Wolin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Efficacy of a Digital Personalized Elimination Diet for the Self&#x2010;Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Comorbid Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; Clinical and Translational Gastroenterology 14, no. 1 (2023): e00545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. J. Kamp, K. R. Weaver, L. B. Sherwin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of a Comprehensive Self&#x2010;Management Intervention on Extraintestinal Symptoms Among Patients With IBS,&#x201d; Journal of Psychosomatic Research 126 (2019): 109821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Y. Francis, J. Morris, and P. J. Whorwell, &#x201c;The Irritable Bowel Severity Scoring System: A Simple Method of Monitoring Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Its Progress,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 11, no. 2 (1997): 395&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>JASP&#x2014;Free and User&#x2010;Friendly Statistical Software [Internet], &#x201c;JASP&#x2014;A Fresh Way to Do Statistics,&#x201d; accessed November 22, 2024, https://jasp&#x2010;stats.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. T. E. Richardson, &#x201c;Eta Squared and Partial Eta Squared as Measures of Effect Size in Educational Research,&#x201d; Educational Research Review 6, no. 2 (2011): 135&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Singh, G. A. Kennedy, and I. Stupans, &#x201c;Does the Modality Used in Health Coaching Matter? A Systematic Review of Health Coaching Outcomes,&#x201d; Patient Preference and Adherence 14 (2020): 1477&#x2013;1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Kivel&#xe4;, S. Elo, H. Kyng&#xe4;s, and M. K&#xe4;&#xe4;ri&#xe4;inen, &#x201c;The Effects of Health Coaching on Adult Patients With Chronic Diseases: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Patient Education and Counseling 97, no. 2 (2014): 147&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. D. Chey, L. Keefer, K. Whelan, and P. R. Gibson, &#x201c;Behavioral and Diet Therapies in Integrated Care for Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 160, no. 1 (2021): 47&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. M. Staudacher, C. J. Black, S. B. Teasdale, A. Mikocka&#x2010;Walus, and L. Keefer, &#x201c;Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Mental Health Comorbidity&#x2014;Approach to Multidisciplinary Management,&#x201d; Nature Reviews. Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 20, no. 9 (2023): 582&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">40904246</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-698X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Median arcuate ligament syndrome: challenges, comorbidities, and controversies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>447</StartPage><EndPage>451</EndPage><MedlinePgn>447-451</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MOP.0000000000001503</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Median arcuate ligament syndrome (MALS) is understood to be a condition where compression of the celiac artery by the median arcuate ligament (MAL) may lead to symptoms of postprandial or exercise-induced abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, oral aversion, and weight loss. This review summarizes recent literature on pediatric MALS while highlighting the challenges, comorbidities, and controversies encountered in this condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The pathophysiologic mechanism by which MALS leads to pain is currently unknown. Several overlapping conditions are described in MALS, including mental health comorbidities to autonomic disorders such as orthostatic intolerance, POTS, or Ehlers-Danlos syndrome. Comorbid gastrointestinal conditions may include gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), and gastroparesis. This overlap makes it difficult to distinguish the cause of broad symptoms patients may experience. MALS remains a complex and controversial topic with particular challenges in consensus diagnostic criteria, normative values in children, symptom definition or correlation, patient selection, predictive outcomes, or long-term follow-up data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with MALS deserve a comprehensive multidisciplinary team to address their health. There is also a desperate need for collaborative research including randomized control trials in adults and a multicenter patient registry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mostamand</LastName><ForeName>Shikib</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition, Stanford University School of Medicine and Stanford Children's Health, Palo Alto, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9000850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-8703</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074742" MajorTopicYN="Y">Median Arcuate Ligament Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Orthostatic Intolerance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004535" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015746" MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009325" MajorTopicYN="N">Nausea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014839" MajorTopicYN="N">Vomiting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003967" MajorTopicYN="N">Diarrhea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">celiac artery compression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric abdominal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric median arcuate ligament syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40904246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOP.0000000000001503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00008480-202510000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>King S, Chambers CT, Huguet A, et al. The epidemiology of chronic pain in children and adolescents revisited: a systematic review. Pain 2011; 152:2729&#x2013;2738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers CT, Dol J, Tutelman PR, et al. The prevalence of chronic pain in children and adolescents: a systematic review update and meta-analysis. Pain 2024; 165:2215&#x2013;2234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harjola P-T, Lahtiharju A. Celiac axis syndrome: abdominal angina caused by external compression of the celiac artery. Am J Surg 1968; 115:864&#x2013;869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EN, Lamb K, Relles D, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome-review of this rare disease. JAMA Surg 2016; 151:471&#x2013;477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter SR, Bernstein EF. The anatomic basis for respiratory variation in median arcuate ligament compression of the celiac artery. Surgery 1973; 73:381&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terlouw LG, Moelker A, Abrahamsen J, et al. European guidelines on chronic mesenteric ischaemia&#x2013;joint United European Gastroenterology, European Association for Gastroenterology, Endoscopy and Nutrition, European Society of Gastrointestinal and Abdominal Radiology, Netherlands Association of Hepatogastroenterologists, Hellenic Society of Gastroenterology, Cardiovascular and Interventional Radiological Society of Europe, and Dutch Mesenteric Ischemia Study group clinical guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of patients with chronic mesenteric ischaemia. United Eur Gastroenterol J 2020; 8:371&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak GZ, Speaker C, Anderson K, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome in the pediatric population. J Pediatr Surg 2013; 48:2261&#x2013;2270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelly CL, Mak GZ. Median arcuate ligament syndrome&#x2013;current state of management. Semin Pediatr Surg 2021; 30:151129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber H, Loizides A, Peer S, Gruber I. Ultrasound of the median arcuate ligament syndrome: a new approach to diagnosis. Med Ultrason 2012; 14:5&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Hayek KM, Titus J, Bui A, et al. Laparoscopic median arcuate ligament release: are we improving symptoms? J Am Coll Surg 2013; 216:272&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultan S, Hynes N, Elsafty N, Tawfick W. Eight years experience in the management of median arcuate ligament syndrome by decompression, celiac ganglion sympathectomy, and selective revascularization. Vasc Endovasc Surg 2013; 47:614&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts B, Pevsner R, Alkhoury F. Robotic approach for median arcuate ligament release in pediatrics. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A 2020; 30:92&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall R, Langridge B, Onida S, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome. J Vasc Surg 2020; 71:2170&#x2013;2176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moak JP, Ramwell C, Fabian R, et al. Median arcuate ligament syndrome with orthostatic intolerance: intermediate-term outcomes following surgical intervention. J Pediatr 2021; 231:141&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower KS, McCarthy CC, Vyasa P, et al. Celiac plexus block: a diagnostic tool for neurogenic median arcuate ligament syndrome. Pain Pract 2025; 25:e13403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shnayder-Adams MM, Masotti M, Sanogo ML. Clinical outcomes after median arcuate ligament release in patients responsive to celiac plexus block. J Vasc Interv Radiol 2024; 35:558&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak GZ, Lucchetti AR, Drossos T, et al. Pediatric chronic abdominal pain and median arcuate ligament syndrome: a review and psychosocial comparison. Pediatr Ann 2016; 45:e257&#x2013;e264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeCicco J, Raja F, Ganesan S, El-Hayek K. First description of a histopathologic grading system and relationship to outcomes after robotic median arcuate ligament release with celiac ganglionectomy and lymphadenectomy. Surgery 2024; 175:822&#x2013;832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeCicco J, Raja F, Ganesan S, et al. Pediatric outcomes after robotic median arcuate ligament release, celiac ganglionectomy, and lymphadenectomy. J Pediatr Surg 2024; 59:161664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakavand B, Burns RC, Centner A, Casas-Melley A. Median arcuate ligament syndrome in children: a single-center experience. Cureus 2024; 16:e57184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiles-Shields C, Osos S, Heilbrun A, et al. Targeting coping to improve surgical outcomes in pediatric patients with median arcuate ligament syndrome: feasibility study. Front Psychol 2021; 12:695435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiles-Shields C, Skelly CL, Mak GZ, et al. Psychological factors and outcomes in the surgical treatment of pediatric patients with median arcuate ligament syndrome. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2018; 66:866&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelly CL, Stiles-Shields C, Mak GZ, et al. The impact of psychiatric comorbidities on patient-reported surgical outcomes in adults treated for the median arcuate ligament syndrome. J Vasc Surg 2018; 68:1414&#x2013;1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JE, Kang M, Jeong OS, Rhee PL. A median arcuate ligament syndrome could be re-termed as a nutcracker celiac ganglion abdominal pain syndrome. J Neurogastroenterol Motil 2023; 29:200&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholbach T. Celiac artery compression syndrome in children, adolescents, and young adults: clinical and color duplex sonographic features in a series of 59 cases. J Ultrasound Med 2006; 25:299&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park CM, Chung JW, Kim HB, et al. Celiac axis stenosis: incidence and etiologies in asymptomatic individuals. Korean J Radiol 2001; 2:8&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskan O, Kaya E, Gungoren FZ, Erol C. Compression of the celiac artery by the median arcuate ligament: multidetector computed tomography findings and characteristics. Can Assoc Radiol J 2015; 66:272&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petnys A, Puech-Le&#xe3;o P, Zerati AE, et al. Prevalence of signs of celiac axis compression by the median arcuate ligament on computed tomography angiography in asymptomatic patients. J Vasc Surg 2018; 68:1782&#x2013;1787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazan V, Qu W, Al-Natour M, et al. Celiac artery compression syndrome: a radiological finding without clinical symptoms? Vascular 2013; 21:293&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner HH, Kemprud E. A clinicoanatomical study of the arcuate ligament of the diaphragm. Arch Surg 1971; 103:600&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metz FM, Blauw JT, Brusse-Keizer M, et al. Systematic review of the efficacy of treatment for median arcuate ligament syndrome. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 2022; 64:720&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce DD, Antiel RM, Oderich G, et al. Pediatric median arcuate ligament syndrome: surgical outcomes and quality of life. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A 2014; 24:104&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnasamy K, Sanghavi R. Median arcuate ligament syndrome: the past and the future. Gastroenterol Clin North Am 2025; 54:589&#x2013;595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen J, Gordon M, Chogle A, et al. ESPGHAN/NASPGHAN guidelines for treatment of irritable bowel syndrome and functional abdominal pain-not otherwise specified in children aged 4-18&#x200a;years. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr 2025; 81:442&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40891151</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-650X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>18</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food &amp; function</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Funct</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety, tolerability, and preliminary effects of cricket chitin for adults with IBS: a double-blind randomized crossover pilot trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7434</StartPage><EndPage>7454</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7434-7454</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5fo01540e</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) is a gastrointestinal disorder affecting around 11% of the global population. Increased production of inflammatory mediators and altered gut microbiota are common with IBS, and evidence suggests these factors are integral to IBS pathophysiology. Prebiotic dietary fiber interventions are being investigated to improve functional gastrointestinal symptoms by remediating gut microbiota and reducing intestinal inflammation. <i>Objective</i>: To investigate the safety and tolerability of a unique and sustainable fiber source, cricket-derived chitin, in a sample of adults (<i>n</i> = 18) diagnosed with IBS, and to gather preliminary data regarding IBS symptoms, inflammatory biomarkers, and gut microbiota to power future randomized, controlled trials. <i>Methods</i>: In this randomized, double-blind, 2 &#xd7; 2 crossover pilot intervention, participants consumed cacao patties containing either 4 grams of cricket-derived chitin (<i>n</i> = 10) or a maltodextrin comparator (<i>n</i> = 8) daily for 30 days, followed by a 14 day washout period and additional 30 day intervention period where participants engaged in in the opposite intervention group. The primary outcome of safety and tolerability (<i>e.g.</i>, adverse events monitoring, physiologic and metabolic biomarkers, quality of life) and secondary outcomes (<i>e.g.</i>, inflammatory biomarkers, gastrointestinal symptoms, stool consistency, and gut microbiota) were assessed before and after each intervention. <i>Results</i>: All safety and tolerability criteria were met. Additionally, while participants reported improved GI symptoms following both treatments (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05), the relationship was more pronounced following the chitin intervention (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01); on average, the chitin treatment resulted in a significantly greater reduction in serum TNF-alpha than the comparator group by 47.41% (95% CI: -90.37, -4.44; <i>p</i>-value = 0.0350). Both interventions resulted in differentially abundant microbial taxa. <i>Conclusions</i>: Results suggest that while both chitin and cacao may be safe and tolerable in individuals with IBS and support symptom management, the chitin additive may provide an additional benefit for lowering inflammatory cytokines. This trial is registered on Clinicaltrials.gov (NCT06397924) and funded by a Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station grant.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vita</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra Adorno</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5126-0601</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teo</LastName><ForeName>Shihning</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murphy</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khandaker</LastName><ForeName>Afsana Mim</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6045-6200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hart</LastName><ForeName>Rania A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathews</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analytical Resources Core, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>John W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaparro</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Analytical Resources Core, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aquilino</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dinsmore</LastName><ForeName>Isaac</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7611-208X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Yuren</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stull</LastName><ForeName>Valerie J</ForeName><Initials>VJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sustainability and the Global Environment, University of, Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53726, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weir</LastName><ForeName>Tiffany L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5423-7140</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Human Nutrition, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523, USA. tiffany.weir@colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06397924</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Food Funct</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549033</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2042-6496</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1398-61-4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002686">Chitin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D056692">Prebiotics</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004043">Dietary Fiber</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002686" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chitin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006135" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gryllidae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056692" MajorTopicYN="N">Prebiotics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004043" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Fiber</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40891151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5fo01540e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40851355</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Randomized Waitlist-Controlled Trial of a Positive Psychology Intervention for Irritable Bowel Syndrome: The WISH Proof-of-Concept Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70146</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.70146</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Though greater positive psychological well-being (PPWB) is associated with both improved physical and mental health in irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), it has not yet been explored as a primary target of brain-gut behavior therapies (BGBTs). Accordingly, we developed a novel, 9-week, phone-delivered BGBT to cultivate PPWB in IBS, and examined its feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary effects in a randomized waitlist-controlled proof-of-concept trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-two adults with IBS meeting Rome IV criteria were randomized, stratified by gender and IBS subtype, to the intervention (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;12) or waitlist-control (WLC; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10) groups. Participants completed specific positive psychology (PP) activities and phone sessions weekly with an interventionist. Intervention feasibility was assessed by the proportion of completed sessions, and acceptability by weekly ease/utility ratings. Exploratory psychological and health-related self-report measures were collected pre- and post-intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Participants (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;22; ages 19-79; 55% female) completed 85% of sessions, above our a priori feasibility threshold of 65%. The intervention was rated as easy to complete (mean&#x2009;=&#x2009;7.2/10, 95% CI: [6.70, 7.75]) and subjectively helpful (mean&#x2009;=&#x2009;7.6/10, 95% CI: [7.14, 8.01]). Of the 18 participants who completed the intervention, 11 (61%) no longer met criteria for IBS post-intervention. Compared to the WLC, the intervention led to promising but nonsignificant improvements in exploratory clinical outcomes including IBS symptom severity, IBS health-related quality of life, and resilience, with effect sizes ranging from 0.1 to 0.7.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND INFERENCES" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This 9-week, phone-delivered intervention targeting greater PPWB in IBS was feasible, well-accepted, and associated with promising improvements in key IBS-related outcomes, highlighting the need for further testing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madva</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth N</ForeName><Initials>EN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurointestinal Health, Gastroenterology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huffman</LastName><ForeName>Jeff C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Crystal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harnedy</LastName><ForeName>Lauren E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franklin</LastName><ForeName>Tesiya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>M Tim</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burton-Murray</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2059-3256</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurointestinal Health, Gastroenterology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Healy</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staller</LastName><ForeName>Kyle</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4925-4290</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurointestinal Health, Gastroenterology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartels</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Mongan Institute, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Braden</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neurointestinal Health, Gastroenterology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keefer</LastName><ForeName>Laurie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, Gastroenterology, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Celano</LastName><ForeName>Christopher M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01HL155301</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01HL133149</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Harvard Medical School</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23DK120945</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23DK131334</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23DK138875</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01DK121003</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01DK112193</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional gastrointestinal disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">positive psychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological resilience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychosomatic medicine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40851355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.70146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>A. C. Ford, A. D. Sperber, M. Corsetti, and M. Camilleri, &#x201c;Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Lancet 396, no. 10263 (2020): 1675&#x2013;1688, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(20)31548&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USCBTCRf United States Census Bureau: 2020 Census, https://www.census.gov/programs&#x2010;surveys/decennial&#x2010;census/decade/2020/2020&#x2010;census&#x2010;main.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Enck, Q. Aziz, G. Barbara, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Nature Reviews. Disease Primers 2 (2016): 16014, https://doi.org/10.1038/nrdp.2016.14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Person and L. Keefer, &#x201c;Psychological Comorbidity in Gastrointestinal Diseases: Update on the Brain&#x2010;Gut&#x2010;Microbiome Axis,&#x201d; Progress in Neuro&#x2010;Psychopharmacology &amp; Biological Psychiatry 107 (2021): 110209, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2020.110209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. B. Blanchard and L. Scharff, &#x201c;Psychosocial Aspects of Assessment and Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in Adults and Recurrent Abdominal Pain in Children,&#x201d; Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 70, no. 3 (2002): 725&#x2013;738, https://doi.org/10.1037//0022&#x2010;006x.70.3.725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Cash, S. Sullivan, and V. Barghout, &#x201c;Total Costs of IBS: Employer and Managed Care Perspective,&#x201d; American Journal of Managed Care 11, no. 1 Suppl (2005): S7&#x2013;S16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. M. Gralnek, R. D. Hays, A. Kilbourne, B. Naliboff, and E. A. Mayer, &#x201c;The Impact of Irritable Bowel Syndrome on Health&#x2010;Related Quality of Life,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 119, no. 3 (2000): 654&#x2013;660, https://doi.org/10.1053/gast.2000.16484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. N. Madva, L. E. Harnedy, R. M. Longley, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Positive Psychological Well&#x2010;Being: A Novel Concept for Improving Symptoms, Quality of Life, and Health Behaviors in Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 35 (2023): e14531, https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.14531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. J. Schmulson and D. A. Drossman, &#x201c;What Is New in Rome IV,&#x201d; Journal of Neurogastroenterology and Motility 23, no. 2 (2017): 151&#x2013;163, https://doi.org/10.5056/jnm16214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Camilleri, &#x201c;Diagnosis and Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Review,&#x201d; JAMA 325, no. 9 (2021): 865&#x2013;877, https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2020.22532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Keefer, S. K. Ballou, D. A. Drossman, G. Ringstrom, S. Elsenbruch, and B. Ljotsson, &#x201c;A Rome Working Team Report on Brain&#x2010;Gut Behavior Therapies for Disorders of Gut&#x2010;Brain Interaction,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 162, no. 1 (2022): 300&#x2013;315, https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2021.09.015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Wu, &#x201c;Psychological Co&#x2010;Morbidity in Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders: Epidemiology, Mechanisms and Management,&#x201d; Journal of Neurogastroenterology and Motility 18, no. 1 (2012): 13&#x2013;18, https://doi.org/10.5056/jnm.2012.18.1.13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Elsenbruch, C. Rosenberger, P. Enck, M. Forsting, M. Schedlowski, and E. R. Gizewski, &#x201c;Affective Disturbances Modulate the Neural Processing of Visceral Pain Stimuli in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: An fMRI Study,&#x201d; Gut 59, no. 4 (2010): 489&#x2013;495, https://doi.org/10.1136/gut.2008.175000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Van Oudenhove, M. D. Crowell, D. A. Drossman, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Biopsychosocial Aspects of Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 150, no. 6 (2016): 1355&#x2013;1367.e2. S0016&#x2010;5085(16)00218&#x2010;3, https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2016.02.027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. K. Zia, A. Lenhart, P. L. Yang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Risk Factors for Abdominal Pain Disorders of Gut&#x2010;Brain Interaction in Adults and Children: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 163 (2022): 995&#x2013;1023, https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2022.06.028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. S. Palsson and S. Ballou, &#x201c;Hypnosis and Cognitive Behavioral Therapies for the Management of Gastrointestinal Disorders,&#x201d; Current Gastroenterology Reports 22, no. 7 (2020): 31, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11894&#x2010;020&#x2010;00769&#x2010;z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. E. Kazdin, &#x201c;Addressing the Treatment Gap: A Key Challenge for Extending Evidence&#x2010;Based Psychosocial Interventions,&#x201d; Behaviour Research and Therapy 88 (2017): 7&#x2013;18, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brat.2016.06.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Sinagra, C. Romano, and M. Cottone, &#x201c;Psychopharmacological Treatment and Psychological Interventions in Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Gastroenterology Research and Practice 2012 (2012): 486067, https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/486067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Hutton, &#x201c;Issues to Consider in Cognitive&#x2010;Behavioural Therapy for Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; European Journal of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 20, no. 4 (2008): 249&#x2013;251, https://doi.org/10.1097/MEG.0b013e3282f25185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Keefer, &#x201c;Behavioural Medicine and Gastrointestinal Disorders: The Promise of Positive Psychology,&#x201d; Nature Reviews. Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 15, no. 6 (2018): 378&#x2013;386, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41575&#x2010;018&#x2010;0001&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Feingold, H. B. Murray, and L. Keefer, &#x201c;Recent Advances in Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Digestive Disorders and the Role of Applied Positive Psychology Across the Spectrum of GI Care,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Gastroenterology 53, no. 7 (2019): 477&#x2013;485, https://doi.org/10.1097/MCG.0000000000001234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. D. Kubzansky, J. C. Huffman, J. K. Boehm, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Positive Psychological Well&#x2010;Being and Cardiovascular Disease: JACC Health Promotion Series,&#x201d; Journal of the American College of Cardiology 72, no. 12 (2018): 1382&#x2013;1396, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2018.07.042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. N. Madva, M. Sadlonova, L. E. Harnedy, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Positive Psychological Well&#x2010;Being and Clinical Characteristics in IBS: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; General Hospital Psychiatry 81 (2023): 1&#x2013;14, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2023.01.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Chakhssi, J. T. Kraiss, M. Sommers&#x2010;Spijkerman, and E. T. Bohlmeijer, &#x201c;The Effect of Positive Psychology Interventions on Well&#x2010;Being and Distress in Clinical Samples With Psychiatric or Somatic Disorders: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; BMC Psychiatry 18, no. 1 (2018): 211, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888&#x2010;018&#x2010;1739&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Bolier, M. Haverman, G. J. Westerhof, H. Riper, F. Smit, and E. Bohlmeijer, &#x201c;Positive Psychology Interventions: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Randomized Controlled Studies,&#x201d; BMC Public Health 13 (2013): 119, https://doi.org/10.1186/1471&#x2010;2458&#x2010;13&#x2010;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Farhadi, D. Banton, and L. Keefer, &#x201c;Connecting Our Gut Feeling and How Our Gut Feels: The Role of Well&#x2010;Being Attributes in Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Neurogastroenterology and Motility 24, no. 2 (2018): 289&#x2013;298, https://doi.org/10.5056/jnm17117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Shahdadi, A. Balouchi, and A. Shaykh, &#x201c;Comparison of Resilience and Psychological Wellbeing in Women With Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Normal Women,&#x201d; Materia Socio&#x2010;medica 29, no. 2 (2017): 105&#x2013;108, https://doi.org/10.5455/msm.2017.29.105&#x2010;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. X. Z. Quek, E. X. L. Loo, A. Demutska, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Impact of the Coronavirus Disease 2019 Pandemic on Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology 36, no. 8 (2021): 2187&#x2013;2197, https://doi.org/10.1111/jgh.15466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. H. Park, B. D. Naliboff, W. Shih, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Resilience Is Decreased in Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Associated With Symptoms and Cortisol Response,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 30, no. 1 (2018): 1&#x2013;9, https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.13155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. H. Parker, B. D. Naliboff, W. Shih, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Role of Resilience in Irritable Bowel Syndrome, Other Chronic Gastrointestinal Conditions, and the General Population,&#x201d; Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology 19 (2020): 2541&#x2013;2550, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cgh.2020.08.043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Dabek&#x2010;Drobny, T. Mach, and M. Zwolinska&#x2010;Wcislo, &#x201c;Effect of Selected Personality Traits and Stress on Symptoms of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Folia Medica Cracoviensia 60, no. 2 (2020): 29&#x2013;41, https://doi.org/10.24425/fmc.2020.135011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. C. Voci and K. M. Cramer, &#x201c;Gender&#x2010;Related Traits, Quality of Life, and Psychological Adjustment Among Women With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Quality of Life Research 18, no. 9 (2009): 1169&#x2013;1176, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136&#x2010;009&#x2010;9532&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Endo, T. Shoji, S. Fukudo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Features of Adolescent Irritable Bowel Syndrome in Japan,&#x201d; Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology 26, no. Suppl 3 (2011): 106&#x2013;109, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440&#x2010;1746.2011.06637.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Selvi and O. Bozo, &#x201c;Group Comparison of Individuals With and Without Irritable Bowel Syndrome in Terms of Psychological and Lifestyle&#x2010;Related Factors,&#x201d; Dusunen Adam the Journal of Psychiatry and Neurological Sciences 1, no. 35 (2022): 13&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Sibelli, T. Chalder, H. Everitt, J. Chilcot, and R. Moss&#x2010;Morris, &#x201c;Positive and Negative Affect Mediate the Bidirectional Relationship Between Emotional Processing and Symptom Severity and Impact in Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Psychosomatic Research 105 (2018): 1&#x2013;13, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2017.11.016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ben&#x2010;Ezra, Y. Hamama&#x2010;Raz, S. Palgi, and Y. Palgi, &#x201c;Cognitive Appraisal and Psychological Distress Among Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Israel Journal of Psychiatry and Related Sciences 52, no. 1 (2015): 54&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Torkzadeh, M. Danesh, L. Mirbagher, H. Daghaghzadeh, and M. H. Emami, &#x201c;Relations Between Coping Skills, Symptom Severity, Psychological Symptoms, and Quality of Life in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; International Journal of Preventive Medicine 10 (2019): 72, https://doi.org/10.4103/ijpvm.IJPVM_464_17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. H. Taft, L. Keefer, C. Artz, J. Bratten, and M. P. Jones, &#x201c;Perceptions of Illness Stigma in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Quality of Life Research 20, no. 9 (2011): 1391&#x2013;1399, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136&#x2010;011&#x2010;9883&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Melchior, E. Colomier, I. A. Trindade, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Factors of Importance for Disease&#x2010;Specific Quality of Life,&#x201d; United European Gastroenterology Journal 10 (2022): 754&#x2013;764, https://doi.org/10.1002/ueg2.12277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. DuBois, O. V. Lopez, E. E. Beale, B. C. Healy, J. K. Boehm, and J. C. Huffman, &#x201c;Relationships Between Positive Psychological Constructs and Health Outcomes in Patients With Cardiovascular Disease: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of Cardiology 195 (2015): 265&#x2013;280, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2015.05.121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Rozanski, C. Bavishi, L. D. Kubzansky, and R. Cohen, &#x201c;Association of Optimism With Cardiovascular Events and All&#x2010;Cause Mortality: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; JAMA Network Open 2, no. 9 (2019): e1912200, https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.12200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. N. Levine, B. E. Cohen, Y. Commodore&#x2010;Mensah, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Psychological Health, Well&#x2010;Being, and the Mind&#x2010;Heart&#x2010;Body Connection: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association,&#x201d; Circulation 143, no. 10 (2021): e763&#x2013;e783, https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, E. H. Feig, R. A. Millstein, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Usefulness of a Positive Psychology&#x2010;Motivational Interviewing Intervention to Promote Positive Affect and Physical Activity After an Acute Coronary Syndrome,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 123, no. 12 (2019): 1906&#x2013;1914, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.03.023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, J. Golden, C. N. Massey, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Positive Psychology&#x2010;Motivational Interviewing Intervention to Promote Positive Affect and Physical Activity in Type 2 Diabetes: The BEHOLD&#x2010;8 Controlled Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Psychosomatic Medicine 82, no. 7 (2020): 641&#x2013;649, https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0000000000000840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Celano, M. E. Freedman, E. E. Beale, F. Gomez&#x2010;Bernal, and J. C. Huffman, &#x201c;A Positive Psychology Intervention to Promote Health Behaviors in Heart Failure: A Proof&#x2010;of&#x2010;Concept Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease 206, no. 10 (2018): 800&#x2013;808, https://doi.org/10.1097/NMD.0000000000000883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Celano, J. Zambrano, L. Harnedy, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Novel Health Behaviour Intervention to Promote Adherence in Kidney Failure,&#x201d; Journal of Renal Care 49 (2022): 24&#x2013;34, https://doi.org/10.1111/jorc.12435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. L. Amonoo, A. El&#x2010;Jawahri, C. M. Celano, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Positive Psychology Intervention to Promote Health Outcomes in Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation: The PATH Proof&#x2010;of&#x2010;Concept Trial,&#x201d; Bone Marrow Transplantation 56, no. 9 (2021): 2276&#x2013;2279, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41409&#x2010;021&#x2010;01296&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. H. Feig, L. E. Harnedy, A. N. Thorndike, C. Psaros, B. C. Healy, and J. C. Huffman, &#x201c;A Positive Emotion&#x2010;Focused Intervention to Increase Physical Activity After Bariatric Surgery: Protocol for a Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; JMIR Research Protocols 11, no. 10 (2022): e39856, https://doi.org/10.2196/39856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. A. Millstein, A. N. Thorndike, S. Kim, E. R. Park, and J. C. Huffman, &#x201c;A Community&#x2010;Based Positive Psychology Group Intervention to Promote Physical Activity Among People With Metabolic Syndrome: Proof of Concept Results to Inform a Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial Protocol,&#x201d; Contemporary Clinical Trials Communications 19 (2020): 100626, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conctc.2020.100626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Muller, K. J. Gertz, I. R. Molton, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of a Tailored Positive Psychology Intervention on Well&#x2010;Being and Pain in Individuals With Chronic Pain and a Physical Disability: A Feasibility Trial,&#x201d; Clinical Journal of Pain 32, no. 1 (2016): 32&#x2013;44, https://doi.org/10.1097/AJP.0000000000000225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. A. Emmons and M. E. McCullough, &#x201c;Counting Blessings Versus Burdens: An Experimental Investigation of Gratitude and Subjective Well&#x2010;Being in Daily Life,&#x201d; Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 84, no. 2 (2003): 377&#x2013;389, https://doi.org/10.1037//0022&#x2010;3514.84.2.377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. E. Seligman, T. A. Steen, N. Park, and C. Peterson, &#x201c;Positive Psychology Progress: Empirical Validation of Interventions,&#x201d; American Psychologist 60, no. 5 (2005): 410&#x2013;421, https://doi.org/10.1037/0003&#x2010;066X.60.5.410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. P. N. Peterson and M. E. P. Seligman, &#x201c;Orientations to Happiness and Life Satisfaction: The Full Life Versus the Empty Life,&#x201d; Journal of Happiness Studies 6, no. 1 (2005): 25&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Hooker, K. S. Masters, K. M. Vagnini, and C. L. Rush, &#x201c;Engaging in Personally Meaningful Activities Is Associated With Meaning Salience and Psychological Well&#x2010;Being,&#x201d; Journal of Positive Psychology 15, no. 6 (2019): 821&#x2013;831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, R. A. Millstein, C. A. Mastromauro, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Positive Psychology Intervention for Patients With an Acute Coronary Syndrome: Treatment Development and Proof&#x2010;of&#x2010;Concept Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Happiness Studies 17, no. 5 (2016): 1985&#x2013;2006, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10902&#x2010;015&#x2010;9681&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, C. M. DuBois, R. A. Millstein, C. M. Celano, and D. Wexler, &#x201c;Positive Psychological Interventions for Patients With Type 2 Diabetes: Rationale, Theoretical Model, and Intervention Development,&#x201d; Journal of Diabetes Research 2015 (2015): 428349, https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/428349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. E. Freedman, B. C. Healy, J. C. Huffman, T. Chitnis, H. L. Weiner, and B. I. Glanz, &#x201c;An At&#x2010;Home Positive Psychology Intervention for Individuals With Multiple Sclerosis: A Phase 1 Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; International Journal of Multiple Sclerosis Care 23, no. 3 (2021): 128&#x2013;134, https://doi.org/10.7224/1537&#x2010;2073.2020&#x2010;020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Czajkowski, L. H. Powell, N. Adler, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;From Ideas to Efficacy: The ORBIT Model for Developing Behavioral Treatments for Chronic Diseases,&#x201d; Health Psychology 34, no. 10 (2015): 971&#x2013;982, https://doi.org/10.1037/hea0000161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. S. Onken, K. M. Carroll, V. Shoham, B. N. Cuthbert, and M. Riddle, &#x201c;Reenvisioning Clinical Science: Unifying the Discipline to Improve the Public Health,&#x201d; Clinical Psychological Science: A Journal of the Association for Psychological Science 2, no. 1 (2014): 22&#x2013;34, https://doi.org/10.1177/2167702613497932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Burton&#x2010;Murray, L. Guadagnoli, K. Kamp, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Review Article: Rome Foundation Working Team Report: Consensus Statement on the Design and Conduct of Behavioural Clinical Trials for Disorders of Gut&#x2010;Brain Interaction,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 61, no. 5 (2025): 787&#x2013;802, https://doi.org/10.1111/apt.18482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. A. Drossman, &#x201c;Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders: History, Pathophysiology, Clinical Features and Rome IV,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 150 (2016): S0016&#x2010;5085(16)00223&#x2010;7, https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2016.02.032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Callahan, F. W. Unverzagt, S. L. Hui, A. J. Perkins, and H. C. Hendrie, &#x201c;Six&#x2010;Item Screener to Identify Cognitive Impairment Among Potential Subjects for Clinical Research,&#x201d; Medical Care 40, no. 9 (2002): 771&#x2013;781, https://doi.org/10.1097/00005650&#x2010;200209000&#x2010;00007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. R. Pinninti, H. Madison, E. Musser, and D. Rissmiller, &#x201c;MINI International Neuropsychiatric Schedule: Clinical Utility and Patient Acceptance,&#x201d; European Psychiatry 18, no. 7 (2003): 361&#x2013;364, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eurpsy.2003.03.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Nalichowski, D. Keogh, H. C. Chueh, and S. N. Murphy, &#x201c;Calculating the Benefits of a Research Patient Data Repository,&#x201d; AMIA Annual Symposium Proceedings/AMIA Symposium 2006 (2006): 1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. S. Palsson, W. E. Whitehead, M. A. van Tilburg, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Rome IV Diagnostic Questionnaires and Tables for Investigators and Clinicians,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 150 (2016): S0016&#x2010;5085(16)00180&#x2010;3, https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2016.02.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. van Kessel, D. Teunissen, and T. Lagro&#x2010;Janssen, &#x201c;Sex&#x2010;Gender Differences in the Effectiveness of Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of General Medicine 14 (2021): 867&#x2013;884, https://doi.org/10.2147/IJGM.S291964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Windgassen, R. Moss&#x2010;Morris, H. Everitt, A. Sibelli, K. Goldsmith, and T. Chalder, &#x201c;Cognitive and Behavioral Differences Between Subtypes in Refractory Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Behavior Therapy 50, no. 3 (2019): 594&#x2013;607, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.beth.2018.09.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. T. Moskowitz, A. W. Carrico, L. G. Duncan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Randomized Controlled Trial of a Positive Affect Intervention for People Newly Diagnosed With HIV,&#x201d; Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 85, no. 5 (2017): 409&#x2013;423, https://doi.org/10.1037/ccp0000188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Rowland and O. S. Curry, &#x201c;A Range of Kindness Activities Boost Happiness,&#x201d; Journal of Social Psychology 159, no. 3 (2019): 340&#x2013;343, https://doi.org/10.1080/00224545.2018.1469461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. M. Sheldon and S. Lyubomirsky, &#x201c;How to Increase and Sustain Positive Emotion: The Effects of Expressing Gratitude and Visualizing Best Possible Selves,&#x201d; Journal of Positive Psychology 1, no. 2 (2006): 73&#x2013;82, https://doi.org/10.1080/17439760500510676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, J. Golden, C. N. Massey, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Positive Psychology&#x2010;Motivational Interviewing Program to Promote Physical Activity in Type 2 Diabetes: The BEHOLD&#x2010;16 Pilot Randomized Trial,&#x201d; General Hospital Psychiatry 68 (2021): 65&#x2013;73, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2020.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, R. A. Millstein, C. M. Celano, B. C. Healy, E. R. Park, and L. M. Collins, &#x201c;Developing a Psychological&#x2010;Behavioral Intervention in Cardiac Patients Using the Multiphase Optimization Strategy: Lessons Learned From the Field,&#x201d; Annals of Behavioral Medicine 54, no. 3 (2020): 151&#x2013;163, https://doi.org/10.1093/abm/kaz035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Celano, M. E. Freedman, L. E. Harnedy, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Feasibility and Preliminary Efficacy of a Positive Psychology&#x2010;Based Intervention to Promote Health Behaviors in Heart Failure: The REACH for Health Study,&#x201d; Journal of Psychosomatic Research 139 (2020): 110285, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2020.110285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. L. Amonoo, E. Daskalakis, E. D. Wolfe, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Positive Psychology Intervention in Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation Survivors (PATH): A Pilot Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Journal of the National Comprehensive Cancer Network 22, no. 2D (2024): e237117, https://doi.org/10.6004/jnccn.2023.7117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. DuBois, R. A. Millstein, C. M. Celano, D. J. Wexler, and J. C. Huffman, &#x201c;Feasibility and Acceptability of a Positive Psychological Intervention for Patients With Type 2 Diabetes,&#x201d; Primary Care Companion for CNS Disorders 18, no. 3 (2016): e1&#x2013;e8, https://doi.org/10.4088/PCC.15m01902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. L. Fredrickson, &#x201c;The Role of Positive Emotions in Positive Psychology. The Broaden&#x2010;And&#x2010;Build Theory of Positive Emotions,&#x201d; American Psychologist 56, no. 3 (2001): 218&#x2013;226, https://doi.org/10.1037//0003&#x2010;066x.56.3.218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Celano, A. M. Albanese, R. A. Millstein, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Optimizing a Positive Psychology Intervention to Promote Health Behaviors After an Acute Coronary Syndrome: The Positive Emotions After Acute Coronary Events III (PEACE&#x2010;III) Randomized Factorial Trial,&#x201d; Psychosomatic Medicine 80, no. 6 (2018): 526&#x2013;534, https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0000000000000584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Watson, L. A. Clark, and A. Tellegen, &#x201c;Development and Validation of Brief Measures of Positive and Negative Affect: The PANAS Scales,&#x201d; Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 54, no. 6 (1988): 1063&#x2013;1070, https://doi.org/10.1037//0022&#x2010;3514.54.6.1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. F. Scheier, C. S. Carver, and M. W. Bridges, &#x201c;Distinguishing Optimism From Neuroticism (and Trait Anxiety, Self&#x2010;Mastery, and Self&#x2010;Esteem): A Reevaluation of the Life Orientation Test,&#x201d; Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 67, no. 6 (1994): 1063&#x2013;1078, https://doi.org/10.1037//0022&#x2010;3514.67.6.1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Bjelland, A. A. Dahl, T. T. Haug, and D. Neckelmann, &#x201c;The Validity of the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale. An Updated Literature Review,&#x201d; Journal of Psychosomatic Research 52, no. 2 (2002): 69&#x2013;77, https://doi.org/10.1016/s0022&#x2010;3999(01)00296&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Labus, R. Bolus, L. Chang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Visceral Sensitivity Index: Development and Validation of a Gastrointestinal Symptom&#x2010;Specific Anxiety Scale,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 20, no. 1 (2004): 89&#x2013;97, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2036.2004.02007.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. W. Smith, J. Dalen, K. Wiggins, E. Tooley, P. Christopher, and J. Bernard, &#x201c;The Brief Resilience Scale: Assessing the Ability to Bounce Back,&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Medicine 15, no. 3 (2008): 194&#x2013;200, https://doi.org/10.1080/10705500802222972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. J. Sullivan, S. Bishop, and J. Pivik, &#x201c;The Pain Catastrophizing Scale: Development and Validation,&#x201d; Psychological Assessment 7, no. 4 (1995): 524&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Cohen, T. Kamarck, and R. Mermelstein, &#x201c;A Global Measure of Perceived Stress,&#x201d; Journal of Health and Social Behavior 24, no. 4 (1983): 385&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. L. Patrick, D. A. Drossman, I. O. Frederick, J. DiCesare, and K. L. Puder, &#x201c;Quality of Life in Persons With Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Development and Validation of a New Measure,&#x201d; Digestive Diseases and Sciences 43, no. 2 (1998): 400&#x2013;411, https://doi.org/10.1023/a:1018831127942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Y. Francis, J. Morris, and P. J. Whorwell, &#x201c;The Irritable Bowel Severity Scoring System: A Simple Method of Monitoring Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Its Progress,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 11, no. 2 (1997): 395&#x2013;402, https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365&#x2010;2036.1997.142318000.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. L. Cain, T. L. Conway, M. A. Adams, L. E. Husak, and J. F. Sallis, &#x201c;Comparison of Older and Newer Generations of ActiGraph Accelerometers With the Normal Filter and the Low Frequency Extension,&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 10 (2013): 51, https://doi.org/10.1186/1479&#x2010;5868&#x2010;10&#x2010;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. F. Zickgraf and J. M. Ellis, &#x201c;Initial Validation of the Nine Item Avoidant/Restrictive Food Intake Disorder Screen (NIAS): A Measure of Three Restrictive Eating Patterns,&#x201d; Appetite 123 (2018): 32&#x2013;42, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.appet.2017.11.111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cohen, &#x201c;A Power Primer,&#x201d; Psychological Bulletin 112, no. 1 (1992): 155&#x2013;159, https://doi.org/10.1037//0033&#x2010;2909.112.1.155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Glaesmer, W. Rief, A. Martin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Psychometric Properties and Population&#x2010;Based Norms of the Life Orientation Test Revised (LOT&#x2010;R),&#x201d; British Journal of Health Psychology 17, no. 2 (2012): 432&#x2013;445, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2044&#x2010;8287.2011.02046.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Schou&#x2010;Bredal, T. Heir, L. Skogstad, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Population&#x2010;Based Norms of the Life Orientation Test&#x2010;Revised (LOT&#x2010;R),&#x201d; International Journal of Clinical and Health Psychology 17, no. 3 (2017): 216&#x2013;224, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijchp.2017.07.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. R. Crawford and J. D. Henry, &#x201c;The Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS): Construct Validity, Measurement Properties and Normative Data in a Large Non&#x2010;Clinical Sample,&#x201d; British Journal of Clinical Psychology 43, no. Pt 3 (2004): 245&#x2013;265, https://doi.org/10.1348/0144665031752934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. A. Everitt, S. Landau, G. O'Reilly, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Assessing Telephone&#x2010;Delivered Cognitive&#x2010;Behavioural Therapy (CBT) and Web&#x2010;Delivered CBT Versus Treatment as Usual in Irritable Bowel Syndrome (ACTIB): A Multicentre Randomised Trial,&#x201d; Gut 68, no. 9 (2019): 1613&#x2013;1623, https://doi.org/10.1136/gutjnl&#x2010;2018&#x2010;317805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. S. Carver, M. F. Scheier, and S. C. Segerstrom, &#x201c;Optimism,&#x201d; Clinical Psychology Review 30, no. 7 (2010): 879&#x2013;889, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2010.01.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Huffman, S. Legler, R. A. Millstein, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Does Timeframe Adjustment of the Life Orientation Test&#x2010;Revised Assess Optimism as a State?: Data From the PEACE&#x2010;III Trial in Patients With Heart Disease,&#x201d; Journal of Positive Psychology 14, no. 6 (2019): 799&#x2013;806, https://doi.org/10.1080/17439760.2019.1579355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Labus, E. A. Mayer, L. Chang, R. Bolus, and B. D. Naliboff, &#x201c;The Central Role of Gastrointestinal&#x2010;Specific Anxiety in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Further Validation of the Visceral Sensitivity Index,&#x201d; Psychosomatic Medicine 69, no. 1 (2007): 89&#x2013;98, https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0b013e31802e2f24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Jerndal, G. Ringstrom, P. Agerforz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Gastrointestinal&#x2010;Specific Anxiety: An Important Factor for Severity of GI Symptoms and Quality of Life in IBS,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 22, no. 6 (2010): 646&#x2010;e179, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2982.2010.01493.x.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40786128</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2397-9070</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JGH open : an open access journal of gastroenterology and hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JGH Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Double-Blind 8-Week Trial on the Efficacy of A Proprietary Kiwifruit Extract on Constipation-Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70250</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70250</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70250</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jgh3.70250</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Green kiwifruit (<i>Actinidia deliciosa</i> <i>var Hayward</i>) extract improves constipation. This study aimed to determine its efficacy in patients with constipation-predominant irritable bowel syndrome (IBS-C).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A randomized, multicenter, double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled trial was conducted in 186 IBS-C patients (Rome III criteria). Patients received either placebo or kiwifruit extract (575&#x2009;mg twice daily for 4&#x2009;weeks, followed by 575&#x2009;mg daily for 4&#x2009;weeks). Outcomes included measures of bowel movement frequency, Bristol Stool Scores, and abdominal pain and related measures (100&#x2009;mm visual analog scale). The primary efficacy end point was the combined improvement of the number of complete spontaneous bowel movements and reduction of weekly average abdominal pain symptom score by at least 30% for at least half of the weeks during treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">On kiwifruit extract, the proportion of subjects with increased frequency of spontaneous bowel movements (54% vs. 36%, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.012), improved Bristol Stool Score (87 vs. 73%, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.014), and abdominal pain (74% vs. 59%, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.023) was greater than in controls. However, no difference was observed in the combined two-variable primary end point (24% vs. 26%; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.798). In post hoc analyses of 49 subjects with severe pain (&#x2265;&#x2009;50&#x2009;mm), kiwifruit extract improved the primary end point (33% vs. 8%, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.028) and normalized or maintained normal bowel actions with kiwifruit extract (44% vs. 24%, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In patients with IBS-C, kiwifruit extract improves bowel habits and abdominal pain. The predefined end point for the whole study population was not met because the 30% or greater improvement of pain only occurred in patients with more pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Australian Clinical Trial Research Network (ACTRN 12613001222730).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). JGH Open published by Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology Foundation and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holtmann</LastName><ForeName>Gerald</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0206-2358</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology Princess Alexandra Hospital Brisbane Queensland Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine University of Queensland Brisbane Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talley</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2537-3092</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Medicine University of Newcastle Newcastle Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nandurkar</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Health Clinical School Monash University Melbourne Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology Eastern Health Melbourne Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibson</LastName><ForeName>Peter R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9108-1712</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Health Clinical School Monash University Melbourne Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology School of Translational Medicine, Monash University and Alfred Health Melbourne Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>JGH Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101730833</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2397-9070</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">constipation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kiwifruit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>G.H.: Advisory board member for Australian Biotherapeutics, Glutagen, Bayer; received research support from Bayer, Abbott, Pfizer, Janssen, Takeda, Allergan. He serves on the Boards of the West Moreton Hospital and Health Service (WMHHS), Queensland, UQ Healthcare, Brisbane, and the Gastro&#x2010;Liga, Germany, and is Chair of the WMHHS Board Quality and Safety Committee. He has a patent for the Brisbane aseptic biopsy device and serves as Editor of the Gastro&#x2010;Liga Newsletter. N.J.T.: GutSee Ltd. (consulting microbiome, 2025), Brown University &amp; Agency for Health Care Research and Quality (fiber and laxation) (2024), Biocodex (FD diagnostic tool) (present), Microba (consulting microbiome, 2025), Comvita Manuka Honey (FD trial consulting) (2025), BluMaiden (2025) outside the submitted work. In addition, Dr. Talley has a patent Nepean Dyspepsia Index (NDI) 1998, a patent Licensing Questionnaires Talley Bowel Disease Questionnaire licensed to Mayo/Talley, &#x201c;Diagnostic marker for functional gastrointestinal disorders&#x201d; Australian Provisional Patent Application 2&#x2009;021&#x2009;901&#x2009;692, &#x201c;Methods and compositions for treating age&#x2010;related neurodegenerative disease associated with dysbiosis&#x201d; US Patent Application No. 63/537725. S.N.: Speaker Honoraria with Falk Pharma. P.R.G.: consultant or advisory board member for Anatara, Atmo Biosciences, Topas, and Comvita; research grants for investigator&#x2010;driven studies from Atmo Biosciences and Mindset Health, and speaker honoraria from Dr. Falk Pharma and Mindset Health Pty Ltd. Shareholder in Atmo Biosciences.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40786128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12335029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jgh3.70250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JGH370250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sperber A. D., Bangdiwala S. I., Drossman D. A., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Worldwide Prevalence and Burden of Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders. Results of Rome Foundation Global Study,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 160, no. 1 (2021): 99&#x2013;114.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes P. A., Harrington A. M., Castro J., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Sensory Neuro&#x2010;Immune Interactions Differ Between Irritable Bowel Syndrome Subtypes,&#x201d; Gut 62, no. 10 (2013): 1456&#x2013;1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22767422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikocka&#x2010;Walus A., Turnbull D., Moulding N., Wilson I., Andrews J. M., and Holtmann G., &#x201c;Psychological Comorbidity and Complexity of Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Clinically Diagnosed Irritable Bowel Syndrome Patients,&#x201d; Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology 23, no. 7 Pt 1 (2008): 1137&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18070012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talley N. J., Holtmann G., and Walker M. M., &#x201c;Therapeutic Strategies for Functional Dyspepsia and Irritable Bowel Syndrome Based on Pathophysiology,&#x201d; Journal of Gastroenterology 50, no. 6 (2015): 601&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25917563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L., Sultan S., Lembo A., Verne G. N., Smalley W., and Heidelbaugh J. J., &#x201c;AGA Clinical Practice Guideline on the Pharmacological Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Constipation,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 163, no. 1 (2022): 118&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35738724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sendzischew Shane M. A., Ruddy J., Cline M., Rosenbaum D. P., Edelstein S., and Moshiree B., &#x201c;Review of the Patient Burden and Therapeutic Landscape of Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Constipation in the United States,&#x201d; Clinical and Experimental Gastroenterology 17 (2024): 227&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11303673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39114809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eltorki M., Leong R., and Ratcliffe E. M., &#x201c;Kiwifruit and Kiwifruit Extracts for Treatment of Constipation: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Canadian Journal of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 2022 (2022): 7596920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9560827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gearry R., Fukudo S., Barbara G., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Consumption of 2 Green Kiwifruits Daily Improves Constipation and Abdominal Comfort &#x2010; Results of an International Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 118, no. 6 (2023): 1058&#x2013;1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10226473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36537785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson&#x2010;Smith V., Dellschaft N., Ansell J., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mechanisms Underlying Effects of Kiwifruit on Intestinal Function Shown by MRI in Healthy Volunteers,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 49, no. 6 (2019): 759&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6590324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30706488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick D. L., Drossman D. A., Frederick I. O., DiCesare J., and Puder K. L., &#x201c;Quality of Life in Persons With Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Development and Validation of a New Measure,&#x201d; Digestive Diseases and Sciences 43, no. 2 (1998): 400&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9512138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHorney C. A., J. E. Ware, Jr. , and Raczek A. E., &#x201c;The MOS 36&#x2010;Item Short&#x2010;Form Health Survey (SF&#x2010;36): II. Psychometric and Clinical Tests of Validity in Measuring Physical and Mental Health Constructs,&#x201d; Medical Care 31, no. 3 (1993): 247&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8450681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis C. Y., Morris J., and Whorwell P. J., &#x201c;The Irritable Bowel Severity Scoring System: A Simple Method of Monitoring Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Its Progress,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 11, no. 2 (1997): 395&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9146781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lembo A. J., Lacy B. E., Zuckerman M. J., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Eluxadoline for Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Diarrhea,&#x201d; New England Journal of Medicine 374, no. 3 (2016): 242&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26789872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chey W. D., Lembo A. J., Lavins B. J., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Linaclotide for Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Constipation: A 26&#x2010;Week, Randomized, Double&#x2010;Blind, Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Trial to Evaluate Efficacy and Safety,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 107, no. 11 (2012): 1702&#x2013;1712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22986437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wensaas K. A., Hanevik K., Hausken T., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Postinfectious and Sporadic Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders Have Different Prevalences and Rates of Overlap: Results From a Controlled Cohort Study 3&#x2009;Years After Acute Giardiasis,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 28, no. 10 (2016): 1561&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrigues V., Mearin F., Badia X., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Change Over Time of Bowel Habits in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Prospective, Observational, 1&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up Study (RITMO Study),&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 25 (2007): 323&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17217445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caballero N., Benslaiman B., Ansell J., and Serra J., &#x201c;The Effect of Green Kiwifruit on Gas Transit and Tolerance in Healthy Humans,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 32, no. 9 (2020): e13874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32431019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So D., Gibson P. R., Muir J. G., and Yao C. K., &#x201c;Dietary Fibres and IBS: Translating Functional Characteristics to Clinical Value in the Era of Personalised Medicine,&#x201d; Gut 70, no. 12 (2021): 2383&#x2013;2394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Carnachan S., Bootten T., Mishra s., Monro J., and Sims I., &#x201c;Effects of Simulated Digestion In&#xa0;Vitro on Cell Wall Polysaccharides From Kiwifruit (<i>Actinidia</i> spp.),&#x201d; Food Chemistry
133 (2012): 132&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkar S. G., Rosendale D., Paturi G., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;In Vitro Utilization of Gold and Green Kiwifruit Oligosaccharides by Human Gut Microbial Populations,&#x201d; Plant Foods for Human Nutrition 67, no. 3 (2012): 200&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22576129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Lee Y. K., Low K. Y., Siah K., Drummond L. M., and Gwee K. A., &#x201c;Kiwifruit (
<i>Actinidia deliciosa</i>
) Changes Intestinal Microbial Profile,&#x201d; Microbial Ecology in Health and Disease
23 (2012): 23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3747767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23990838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Blatchford P., Stoklosinski H., Eady S., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Consumption of Kiwifruit Capsules Increases <i>Faecalibacterium prausnitzii</i> Abundance in Functionally Constipated Individuals: A Randomised Controlled Human Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Nutritional Science
6 (2017): e52.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5672330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29152256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goya&#x2010;Jorge E., Bondue P., Gonza I., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Butyrogenic, Bifidogenic and Slight Anti&#x2010;Inflammatory Effects of a Green Kiwifruit Powder (Kiwi FFG) in a Human Gastrointestinal Model Simulating Mild Constipation,&#x201d; Food Research International 173, no. Pt 2 (2023): 113348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37803696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S. and Rao S. S., &#x201c;Pharmacologic Management of Chronic Constipation,&#x201d; Gastroenterology Clinics of North America 39, no. 3 (2010): 509&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20951915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udani J. K. and Bloom D. W., &#x201c;Effects of Kivia Powder on Gut Health in Patients With Occasional Constipation: A Randomized, Double&#x2010;Blind, Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Study,&#x201d; Nutrition Journal 12 (2013): 78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3706267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23758673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C. C., Lin Y. T., Lu Y. T., Liu Y. S., and Liu J. F., &#x201c;Kiwifruit Improves Bowel Function in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Constipation,&#x201d; Asia Pacific Journal of Clinical Nutrition 19, no. 4 (2010): 451&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21147704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan A. O., Leung G., Tong T., and Wong N. Y., &#x201c;Increasing Dietary Fiber Intake in Terms of Kiwifruit Improves Constipation in Chinese Patients,&#x201d; World Journal of Gastroenterology 13, no. 35 (2007): 4771&#x2013;4775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4611199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17729399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paturi G., Butts C. A., Bentley&#x2010;Hewitt K. L., and Ansell J., &#x201c;Influence of Green and Gold Kiwifruit on Indices of Large Bowel Function in Healthy Rats,&#x201d; Journal of Food Science 79, no. 8 (2014): H1611&#x2013;H1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25048562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur L., Rutherford S., Drummond L., and Moughan P., &#x201c;Actinidin Enhances Protein Digestion in the Small Intestine as Assessed Using an In&#xa0;Vitro Digestion Model,&#x201d; Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 58, no. 8 (2010): 5074&#x2013;5080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20232891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Montoya C., Rutherford S., Olson T., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Actinidin From Kiwifruit (<i>Actinidia deliciosa</i> cv. Hayward) Increases the Digestion and Rate of Gastric Empying of Meat Proteins in the Growing Pig,&#x201d; British Journal of Nutrition
111, no. 6 (2014): 957&#x2013;967.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24252432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boland M., &#x201c;Kiwifruit Proteins and Enzymes: Actinidin and Other Significant Proteins,&#x201d; in Advances in Food and Nutrition Research, vol. 68 (Elsevier, 2013), 59&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23394982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40765115</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-277X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human nutrition and dietetics : the official journal of the British Dietetic Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Nutr Diet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a Low FODMAP Diet in Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Patient Experiences: A Mixed Methods Systematic Literature Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70106</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70106</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70106</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jhn.70106</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A low FODMAP diet reduces symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), but its impact on inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is less established. This systematic review aimed to: (1) assess the effect of a low FODMAP diet in IBD and (2) understand patient experiences when implementing the low FODMAP diet.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Four databases (Medline, Embase, CINAHL and CENTRAL) were systematically searched. RCTs evaluating a low FODMAP diet in IBD on disease activity, inflammatory markers, gastrointestinal symptoms, and quality of life (QoL), and qualitative studies reporting patient experiences of low FODMAP interventions (in either IBS or IBD), were included. Outcome data were meta-analysed as standardised mean differences or odds ratios. Qualitative data underwent content analysis using the Health Belief Model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Five RCTs (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;224) and two qualitative studies (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;30 IBS patients, no studies in IBD) were included. Compared with controls, there was no effect of a low FODMAP diet on disease activity (Crohn's disease: SMD -0.33; -0.77, 0.11; ulcerative colitis: SMD -0.31; -0.78, 0.15) or faecal calprotectin (SMD -0.20; -0.49, 0.09), but lower severity of global IBS symptoms (SMD -0.56; -0.90, 0.23) and higher QoL scores (SMD 0.43; 0.05, 0.81) at end of intervention. Patients with IBS described implementation as burdensome (Severity, Barriers), inadequate professional support (Susceptibility) and found it difficult to interpret information (Susceptibility, Barriers). Meal plans and recipes (Cue to action and Self-efficacy) gained through dietitian-led information sessions were valued (Benefits).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A low FODMAP diet does not impact IBD disease activity and inflammation markers, but leads to improved gastrointestinal symptoms compared with controls. The diet should be considered for improving functional gastrointestinal symptoms, but not an IBD treatment. There are minimal studies about patient experiences implementing the low FODMAP diet, all in IBS. Future research should assess patient experiences of low FODMAP diet implementation, specific to IBD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROTOCOL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">PROSPERO CRD42023480762, Open Science Framework.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Dietetic Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ville</LastName><ForeName>Aubane</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-7701-3309</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences &amp; Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McRae</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences &amp; Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nomchong</LastName><ForeName>Jiayen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences &amp; Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reidlinger</LastName><ForeName>Dianne P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9993-8239</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences &amp; Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davidson</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences &amp; Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Evidence-Based Healthcare, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staudacher</LastName><ForeName>Heidi M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food &amp; Mood Centre, The Institute for Mental and Physical Health and Clinical Translation, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albarqouni</LastName><ForeName>Loai</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences &amp; Medicine, Bond University, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Evidence-Based Healthcare, Robina, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>The authors received no specific funding for this work.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Nutr Diet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904840</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0952-3871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050528" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, Carbohydrate-Restricted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="N">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092622" MajorTopicYN="N">FODMAP Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Crohn's disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FODMAP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RCT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory bowel disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ulcerative colitis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40765115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12326053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.70106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Centers for Disease Control and Prevention
, &#x201c;People With IBD Have More Chronic Disease,&#x201d; Updated April 15, 2022, https://www.cdc.gov/ibd/features/IBD-more-chronic-diseases.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A., Yassin N., Marley A., et al., &#x201c;Crossing Barriers: The Burden of Inflammatory Bowel Disease Across Western Europe,&#x201d; Therapeutic Advances in Gastroenterology 16 (2023): 17562848231218615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10748558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38144422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman M., Nutrition in Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) (MDPI&#x2014;Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan G. G., &#x201c;The Global Burden of IBD: From 2015 to 2025,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 12, no. 12 (2015): 720&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26323879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox S. R., Clarke H., O'Keeffe M., et al., &#x201c;Nutrient, Fibre, and FODMAP Intakes and Food&#x2010;Related Quality of Life in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease, and Their Relationship With Gastrointestinal Symptoms of Differing Aetiologies,&#x201d; Journal of Crohn's and Colitis 15, no. 12 (2021): 2041&#x2013;2053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8684455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Li Z., Liu S., and Zhang D., &#x201c;Global, Regional and National Burden of Inflammatory Bowel Disease in 204 Countries and Territories From 1990 to 2019: A Systematic Analysis Based on the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019,&#x201d; BMJ Open 13, no. 3 (2023): e065186&#x2010;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36977543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major G., Pritchard S., Murray K., et al., &#x201c;Colon Hypersensitivity to Distension, Rather Than Excessive Gas Production, Produces Carbohydrate&#x2010;Related Symptoms in Individuals With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 152, no. 1 (2017): 124&#x2013;133.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27746233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black C. J., Staudacher H. M., and Ford A. C., &#x201c;Efficacy of a Low FODMAP Diet in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: Systematic Review and Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Gut 71, no. 6 (2022): 1117&#x2013;1126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34376515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbrass K. M., Costantino S. J., Gracie D. J., and Ford A. C., &#x201c;Prevalence of Irritable Bowel Syndrome&#x2010;Type Symptoms in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease in Remission: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Lancet Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 5, no. 12 (2020): 1053&#x2013;1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb C. A., Kennedy N. A., Raine T., et al., &#x201c;British Society of Gastroenterology Consensus Guidelines on the Management of Inflammatory Bowel Disease in Adults,&#x201d; supplement, Gut 68, no. S3 (2019): s1&#x2013;s106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6872448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox S. R., Prince A. C., Myers C. E., et al., &#x201c;Fermentable Carbohydrates [FODMAPS] Exacerbate Functional Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease: A Randomised, Double&#x2010;Blind, Placebo&#x2010;Controlled, Cross&#x2010;Over, Re&#x2010;Challenge Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Crohn's and Colitis 11, no. 12 (2017): 1420&#x2013;1429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28525543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prince A. C., Myers C. E., Joyce T., Irving P., Lomer M., and Whelan K., &#x201c;Fermentable Carbohydrate Restriction (Low FODMAP Diet) in Clinical Practice Improves Functional Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; Inflammatory Bowel Diseases 22, no. 5 (2016): 1129&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26914438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischoff S. C., Bager P., Escher J., et al., &#x201c;ESPEN Guideline on Clinical Nutrition in Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; Clinical Nutrition 42, no. 3 (2023): 352&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36739756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashash J. G., Elkins J., Lewis J. D., and Binion D. G., &#x201c;AGA Clinical Practice Update on Diet and Nutritional Therapies in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease: Expert Review,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 166, no. 3 (2024): 521&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38276922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomer M. C. E., Wilson B., and Wall C. L., &#x201c;British Dietetic Association Consensus Guidelines on the Nutritional Assessment and Dietary Management of Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics 36, no. 1 (2023): 336&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10084145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35735908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Z., Yi J., and Liu X., &#x201c;A Low&#x2010;FODMAP Diet Provides Benefits for Functional Gastrointestinal Symptoms but not for Improving Stool Consistency and Mucosal Inflammation in IBD: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Nutrients 14, no. 10 (2022): 2072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9146862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35631213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell H., Porter J., Gibson P. R., Barrett J., and Garg M., &#x201c;Review Article: Implementation of a Diet Low in FODMAPs for Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome&#x2014;Directions for Future Research,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 49, no. 2 (2019): 124&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30589971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher H. M., Ralph F. S. E., Irving P. M., Whelan K., and Lomer M. C. E., &#x201c;Nutrient Intake, Diet Quality, and Diet Diversity in Irritable Bowel Syndrome and the Impact of the Low FODMAP Diet,&#x201d; Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics 120, no. 4 (2020): 535&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31029650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott N., Aziz I., Rej A., and Surendran Sanders D., &#x201c;How Patients With IBS Use Low FODMAP Dietary Information Provided by General Practitioners and Gastroenterologists: A Qualitative Study,&#x201d; Nutrients 11, no. 6 (2019): 1313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6627590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31212668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So D., Loughman A., and Staudacher H. M., &#x201c;Effects of a Low FODMAP Diet on the Colonic Microbiome in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Systematic Review With Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 116, no. 4 (2022): 943&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9535515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35728042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswaran S., Dolan R. D., Ball S. C., Jackson K., and Chey W., &#x201c;The Impact of a 4&#x2010;Week Low&#x2010;FODMAP and mNICE Diet on Nutrient Intake in a Sample of US Adults With Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Diarrhea,&#x201d; Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics 120, no. 4 (2020): 641&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelan K., Martin L. D., Staudacher H. M., and Lomer M. C. E., &#x201c;The Low FODMAP Diet in the Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: An Evidence&#x2010;Based Review of FODMAP Restriction, Reintroduction and Personalisation in Clinical Practice,&#x201d; Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics 31, no. 2 (2018): 239&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29336079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson B., Cox S. R., and Whelan K., &#x201c;Challenges of the Low FODMAP Diet for Managing Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Approaches to Their Minimisation and Mitigation,&#x201d; Proceedings of the Nutrition Society 80, no. 1 (2021): 19&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32468985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J. P. T., Thomas J., Chandler J., et al., Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions (2nd ed. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Incorporated, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M. J., McKenzie J. E., Bossuyt P. M., et al., &#x201c;The PRISMA 2020 Statement: An Updated Guideline for Reporting Systematic Reviews,&#x201d; BMJ 372 (2021): n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark J. M., Sanders S., Carter M., et al., &#x201c;Improving the Translation of Search Strategies Using the Polyglot Search Translator: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Journal of the Medical Library Association 108, no. 2 (2020): 195&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32256231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark J., Glasziou P., Del Mar C., Bannach&#x2010;Brown A., Stehlik P., and Scott A. M., &#x201c;A Full Systematic Review Was Completed in 2 Weeks Using Automation Tools: A Case Study,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 121 (2020): 81&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32004673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne J. A. C., Savovi&#x107; J., Page M. J., et al., &#x201c;RoB 2: A Revised Tool for Assessing Risk of Bias in Randomised Trials,&#x201d; BMJ 366 (2019): l4898&#x2010;l.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santesso N., Glenton C., Dahm P., et al., &#x201c;GRADE Guidelines 26: Informative Statements to Communicate the Findings of Systematic Reviews of Interventions,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 119 (2020): 126&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Q. N., Gonzalez&#x2010;Reyes A., and Pluye P., &#x201c;Improving the Usefulness of a Tool for Appraising the Quality of Qualitative, Quantitative and Mixed Methods Studies, the Mixed Methods Appraisal Tool (MMAT),&#x201d; Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice 24, no. 3 (2018): 459&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29464873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
VassarStats
, &#x201c;Website for Statistical Computation,&#x201d; http://www.vassarstats.net/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan X., Wang W., Liu J., and Tong T., &#x201c;Estimating the Sample Mean and Standard Deviation From the Sample Size, Median, Range and/or Interquartile Range,&#x201d; BMC Medical Research Methodology 14, no. 1 (2014): 135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25524443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Rohatgi A., &#x201c;WebPlotDigitizer 2024 [4.7],&#x201d; https://automeris.io/WebPlotDigitizer.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Costa B. R., Rutjes A. W., Johnston B. C., et al., &#x201c;Methods to Convert Continuous Outcomes Into Odds Ratios of Treatment Response and Numbers Needed to Treat: Meta&#x2010;Epidemiological Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Epidemiology 41, no. 5 (2012): 1445&#x2013;1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23045205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock I. M., Strecher V. J., and Becker M. H., &#x201c;Social Learning Theory and the Health Belief Model,&#x201d; Health Education Quarterly 15, no. 2 (1988): 175&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3378902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodini G., Zanella C., Crespi M., et al., &#x201c;A Randomized, 6&#x2010;wk Trial of a Low FODMAP Diet in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; Nutrition 67&#x2013;68 (2019): 110542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31470260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox S. R., Lindsay J. O., Fromentin S., et al., &#x201c;Effects of Low FODMAP Diet on Symptoms, Fecal Microbiome, and Markers of Inflammation in Patients With Quiescent Inflammatory Bowel Disease in a Randomized Trial,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 158, no. 1 (2020): 176&#x2013;188.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31586453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halmos E. P., Christophersen C. T., Bird A. R., Shepherd S. J., Muir J. G., and Gibson P. R., &#x201c;Consistent Prebiotic Effect on Gut Microbiota With Altered FODMAP Intake in Patients With Crohn's Disease: A Randomised, Controlled Cross&#x2010;Over Trial of Well&#x2010;Defined Diets,&#x201d; Clinical and Translational Gastroenterology 7, no. 4 (2016): e164&#x2010;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27077959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melgaard D., S&#xf8;rensen J., Riis J., et al., &#x201c;Efficacy of FODMAP Elimination and Subsequent Blinded Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Provocations in a Randomised Controlled Study in Patients With Ulcerative Colitis in Remission and Symptoms of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Feasibility Study,&#x201d; Nutrients 14, no. 6 (2022): 1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen N., Ankersen D. V., Felding M., et al., &#x201c;Low&#x2010;FODMAP Diet Reduces Irritable Bowel Symptoms in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; World Journal of Gastroenterology 23, no. 18 (2017): 3356&#x2013;3366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5434443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28566897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan D., Skidmore P., O'Brien L., Watson S., and Gearry R., &#x201c;A Feasibility Study Investigating the Impact of a Dietitian&#x2010;Led Low in Fermentable Oligosaccharide, Disaccharide, Monosaccharide and Polyols Diet Group Education Programme With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; New Zealand Medical Journal 133, no. 1522 (2020): 42&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32994615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milajerdi A., Sadeghi O., Siadat S. D., et al., &#x201c;A Randomized Controlled Trial Investigating the Effect of a Diet Low in Fermentable Oligosaccharides, Disaccharides, Monosaccharides, and Polyols on the Intestinal Microbiome and Inflammation in Patients With Ulcerative Colitis: Study Protocol for a Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Trials 21, no. 1 (2020): 201&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7029518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monash University (AU) , Monash Univeristy Low FODMAP Diet App, 3.1.1 ed. (Monash University, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capili B., Anastasi J. K., and Chang M., &#x201c;Addressing the Role of Food in Irritable Bowel Syndrome Symptom Management,&#x201d; Journal for Nurse Practitioners 12, no. 5 (2016): 324&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4944381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27429601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher H. M. and Whelan K., &#x201c;The Low FODMAP Diet: Recent Advances in Understanding Its Mechanisms and Efficacy in IBS,&#x201d; Gut 66, no. 8 (2017): 1517&#x2013;1527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28592442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariaee A., Koentgen S., Wardill H. R., et al., &#x201c;Prebiotic Selection Influencing Inflammatory Bowel Disease Treatment Outcomes: A Review of the Preclinical and Clinical Evidence,&#x201d; eGastroenterology 2, no. 2 (2024): e100055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11731074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39944472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voisin A., Mahmood R., Jeanson T. L., Bernstein C., Armstrong H., et al., &#x201c;DOP03 Unfermented &#x3b2;&#x2010;fructan Fibres Can Induce Gut Inflammation and Tumorigenesis in Select Inflammatory Bowel Disease Patients Mediated by Gut Microbiota,&#x201d; Journal of Crohn's and Colitis 17, no. Suppl_1 (2023): i60&#x2010;i1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H., Rowland I., and Yaqoob P., &#x201c;Comparative Effects of Six Probiotic Strains on Immune Function In Vitro,&#x201d; British Journal of Nutrition 108, no. 3 (2012): 459&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22054064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sokol H., Pigneur B., Watterlot L., et al., &#x201c;
<i>Faecalibacterium prausnitzii</i> Is an Anti&#x2010;Inflammatory Commensal Bacterium Identified by Gut Microbiota Analysis of Crohn Disease Patients,&#x201d; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences &#x2010; PNAS
105, no. 43 (2008): 16731&#x2013;16736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2575488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18936492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson P. R., &#x201c;Use of the Low&#x2010;FODMAP Diet in Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; supplement, Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology 32, no. S1 (2017): 40&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28244679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick J. A., Melton S. L., Yao C. K., Gibson P. R., and Halmos E. P., &#x201c;Dietary Management of Adults With IBD&#x2014;The Emerging Role of Dietary Therapy,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 19, no. 10 (2022): 652&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35577903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner R. M., Bird S. M., and Higgins J. P. T., &#x201c;The Impact of Study Size on Meta&#x2010;Analyses: Examination of Underpowered Studies in Cochrane Reviews,&#x201d; PLoS One 8, no. 3 (2013): e59202&#x2010;e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3609745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23544056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40728847</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9766</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2025 Jul-Aug 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gastroenterology nursing : the official journal of the Society of Gastroenterology Nurses and Associates</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gastroenterol Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Progressive Muscle Relaxation Exercises on Symptom Severity and Quality of Life in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>271</StartPage><EndPage>279</EndPage><MedlinePgn>271-279</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SGA.0000000000000879</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study was conducted to evaluate the effects of progressive muscle relaxation exercises on symptom severity and quality of life in patients with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). This randomized controlled trial was conducted with a total of 57 IBS patients (28 in an intervention group and 29 in a control group) who were consulted in the gastroenterology outpatient clinic of Erzurum City Hospital in Erzuerum, Turkey. The patients in the intervention group performed progressive muscle relaxation every day for 6&#xa0;weeks at home, while the control group did not receive any treatment. The patient information form, IBS Symptom Severity Scores, and IBS Quality of Life Scale were used to collect data. The mean IBS symptom severity score of the patients who performed progressive muscle relaxation was significantly lower compared to that of the control group (p &lt;&#xa0;.001). The mean IBS Quality of Life score of the patients in the intervention group was significantly higher than that of the control group (p &lt;&#xa0;.050). Progressive muscle relaxation reduced the severity of IBS symptoms and improved quality of life. Based on these results, it is recommended that patients with IBS perform progressive muscle relaxation exercises to achieve significant improvements in their symptoms and quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Society of Gastroenterology Nurses and Associates.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arslan</LastName><ForeName>Eylem</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>About the authors: Eylem Arslan,MSc, RN, Erzurum City Hospital, Eye-Algology Clinic, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emine Kiyak, PhD, Faculty of Nursing, Ataturk University, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiyak</LastName><ForeName>Emine</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>About the authors: Eylem Arslan,MSc, RN, Erzurum City Hospital, Eye-Algology Clinic, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emine Kiyak, PhD, Faculty of Nursing, Ataturk University, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Gastroenterol Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8915377</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1042-895X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009126" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Relaxation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014421" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Turkey</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012064" MajorTopicYN="Y">Relaxation Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article. The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40728847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SGA.0000000000000879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001610-202507000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abuelazm M., Muhammad S., &amp; Gamal M. (2022). The effect of vitamin D supplementation on the severity of symptoms and the quality of life in irritable bowel syndrome patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutrients, 14(13), 2618. doi:10.3390/nu14132618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14132618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Hasbi H., Chayati N., &amp; Makiyah S. N. N. (2020). Progressive muscle relaxation to reduces chronic pain in hemodialysis patient. Medisains, 17(3), 62&#x2013;66. doi:10.30595/medisains.v17i3.5823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30595/medisains.v17i3.5823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasi J. K., Capili B., &amp; Chang M. (2013). Managing irritable bowel syndrome. American Journal of Nursing, 113(7), 42&#x2013;52. doi:10.1097/01.Naj.0000431911.65473.35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.Naj.0000431911.65473.35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard E. B., Greene B., Scharff L., &amp; Schwarz-McMorris S. P. (1993). Relaxation training as a treatment for irritable bowel syndrome. Biofeedback and Self-Regulation, 18(3), 125&#x2013;132. doi:10.1007/bf00999789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf00999789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetto S., Fagoonee S., Battaglia E., Grassini M., Saracco G. M., &amp; Pellicano R. (2021). Recent advances in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Polish Archives of Internal Medicine, 131(7-8), 709&#x2013;715. doi:10.20452/pamw.16067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20452/pamw.16067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremner H. (2013). Nurse-led hypnotherapy: An innovative approach to irritable bowel syndrome. Complementary Therapies in Clinical Practice, 19(3), 147&#x2013;152. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2013.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2013.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buyukozturk S. (2014). Sosyal bilimler i&#xe7;in veri analizi el kitab&#x131; (Manual of data analysis for social sciences). Ankara, Turkey: Pegem Akademi Yay&#x131;nlar&#x131;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain K. C., Headstrom P., &amp; Jarrett M. E. (2006). Abdominal pain impacts quality of life in women with irritable bowel syndrome. American Journal of Gastroenterology, 101(1), 124&#x2013;132. doi:10.1111/j.1572-0241.2006.00404.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1572-0241.2006.00404.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M. (2018). Management options for irritable bowel syndrome. Mayo Clinic Proceedings, 93(12), 1858&#x2013;1872. doi:10.1016/j.mayocp.2018.04.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mayocp.2018.04.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canakis A., Haroon M., &amp; Weber H. C. (2020). Irritable bowel syndrome and gut microbiota. Current Opinion in Endocrinology &amp; Diabetes and Obesity, 27(1), 28&#x2013;35. doi:10.1097/med.0000000000000523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/med.0000000000000523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. (1988). Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences (2nd ed.). Routledge. doi:10.4324/9780203771587</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhusein A. M. &amp; Fadlalmola H. A. (2022). Efficacy of fecal microbiota transplantation in irritable bowel syndrome patients: An updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology Nursing, 45(1), 11&#x2013;20. doi:10.1097/sga.0000000000000652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/sga.0000000000000652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrukh A. (2022). Measurement of pain and related symptoms in irritable bowel syndrome: The use of validated pain measurement tools. Gastrointestinal Disorders, 4(1), 22&#x2013;29. doi:10.3390/gidisord4010004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gidisord4010004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford A. C., Sperber A. D., Corsetti M., &amp; Camilleri M. (2020). Irritable bowel syndrome. The Lancet, 396(10263), 1675&#x2013;1688. doi:10.1016/s0140-6736(20)31548-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(20)31548-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis C. Y., Morris J., &amp; Whorwell P. J. (1997). The irritable bowel severity scoring system: A simple method of monitoring irritable bowel syndrome and its progress. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics, 11(2), 395&#x2013;402. doi:10.1046/j.1365-2036.1997.142318000.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2036.1997.142318000.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guven G. K. &amp; Kiyak E. (2020). Assessment of quality of life in irritable bowel syndrome patients. Archives of Health Science and Research, 7(2), 146&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Psychology. (2016, March 23). Progressive muscle relaxation technique [Video]. Youtube. https://youtu.be/Ov_S4-TNtIc?feature=shared</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya Y. D. (2019). Irritable bowel syndrome. The Journal of Turkish Family Physician, 10(4), 205&#x2013;213. doi:10.15511/tjtfp.19.00405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15511/tjtfp.19.00405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellow J. E. &amp; Phillips S. F. (1987). Altered small bowel motility in irritable bowel syndrome is correlated with symptoms. Gastroenterology, 92(6), 1885&#x2013;1893. doi:10.1016/0016-5085(87)90620-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-5085(87)90620-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilic S. P., Ovayolu N., &amp; Koruk M. (2017). Irritabl barsak sendromlu hastalarda yasam kalitesi (quality of life in patients with irritable bowel syndrome). Izmir Katip Celebi Universitesi Saglik Bilimleri Fakultesi Dergisi, 2(2), 27&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo B., Bhasin M., &amp; Jacquart J. (2015). Genomic and clinical effects associated with a relaxation response mind-body intervention in patients with irritable bowel syndrome and inflammatory bowel disease. PLoS One, 10(4), e0123861. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0123861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0123861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwekkeboom K. L. &amp; Gretarsdottir E. (2006). Systematic review of relaxation interventions for pain. Journal of Nursing Scholarship, 38(3), 269&#x2013;277. doi:10.1111/j.1547-5069.2006.00113.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1547-5069.2006.00113.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labus J., Gupta A., &amp; Gill H. K. (2013). Randomised clinical trial: Symptoms of the irritable bowel syndrome are improved by a psycho-education group intervention. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics, 37(3), 304&#x2013;315. doi:10.1111/apt.12171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apt.12171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCallie M. S., Blum C. M., &amp; Hood C. J. (2006). Progressive muscle relaxation. Journal of Human Behavior in the Social Environment, 13(3), 51&#x2013;66. doi:10.1300/J137v13n03_04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1300/J137v13n03_04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B., Keller A., M&#xfc;ller B., W&#xf6;hlbier H. G., &amp; Kropp P. (2018). Progressive muscle relaxation according to Jacobson for migraine prophylaxis: Clinical effectiveness and mode of action. Der Schmerz, 32(4), 250&#x2013;258. doi:10.1007/s00482-018-0305-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00482-018-0305-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neff D. F. &amp; Blanchard E. B. (1987). A multi-component treatment for irritable bowel syndrome. Behavior Therapy, 18(1), 70&#x2013;83. doi:10.1016/S0005-7894(87)80052-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0005-7894(87)80052-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelkowska D. D. (2020). Treating irritable bowel syndrome through an interdisciplinary approach. Annals of Gastroenterology, 33(1), 1&#x2013;8. doi:10.20524/aog.2019.0441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20524/aog.2019.0441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlar K&#x131;l&#x131;c S., K&#x131;l&#x131;c N., Sevinc S., &amp; Demirel C. (2020). A qualitative study of the experiences of complementary and alternative medicine use in patients with IBS-C. Holistic Nursing Practice, 34(3), 171&#x2013;179. doi:10.1097/hnp.0000000000000383</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/hnp.0000000000000383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick D., Drossman D., Frederick I., Dicesare j., Puder K. (1998). Quality of life in persons with irritable bowel syndrome: Development and validation of a new measure.. Digestive Diseases &amp; Sciences, 11, 400&#x2013;411. doi:10.1023/A:101883112794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:101883112794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur E. R., Holmes H. J., &amp; Lockhart N. A. (2017). Emotional awareness and expression training improves irritable bowel syndrome: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Neurogastroenterology and Motility, 29(12), 1&#x2013;9. doi:10.1111/nmo.13143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.13143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Veek P. P., van Rood Y. R., &amp; Masclee A. A. (2007). Clinical trial: Short- and long-term benefit of relaxation training for irritable bowel syndrome. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics, 26(6), 943&#x2013;952. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2036.2007.03437.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2036.2007.03437.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dulmen A. M., Fennis J. F., &amp; Bleijenberg G. (1996). Cognitive-behavioral group therapy for irritable bowel syndrome: Effects and long-term follow-up. Psychosomatic Medicine, 58(5), 508&#x2013;514. doi:10.1097/00006842-199609000-00013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006842-199609000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Wang F., Fan F., Sedas A. C., &amp; Wang J. (2017). Mind-body interventions for irritable bowel syndrome patients in the Chinese population: A systematic review and meta-analysis. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine, 24(2), 191&#x2013;204. doi:10.1007/s12529-016-9589-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12529-016-9589-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildiz E. &amp; Acaro&#x11f;lu R. (2022). The effect of massage and progressive relaxation exercises on pain intensity and menstrual symptoms in students with primary dysmenorrhea: A randomized controlled trial. Holistic Nursing Practice, 36(5), 284&#x2013;294. doi:10.1097/hnp.0000000000000541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/hnp.0000000000000541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz B. &amp; Akbulut G. (2018). Irritabl bagirsak sendromuna guncel bakis (irritable bowel syndrome: Up to date). Beslenme Ve Diyet Dergisi, 46(3), 276&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40712106</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of the Enterosorbent Silicolgel in Irritable Bowel Syndrome, IBS-D and IBS-M: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Multi-Center Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70118</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70118</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.70118</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a common gastrointestinal disorder significantly reducing quality of life. Silicolgel, a colloidal silicic acid enterosorbent, acts locally in the gut. This double-blind, placebo-controlled trial investigated its safety and efficacy in IBS-D and IBS-M, subtypes affecting over 60% of IBS sufferers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">After 2&#x2009;weeks of screening, patients were randomized into 4&#x2009;weeks of treatment, followed by a no-medication phase to assess return of symptoms. Patients recorded bowel habits, abdominal pain, QoL, and global symptoms using weekly questionnaires and daily diaries. Primary outcome was a &#x2265;&#x2009;50 point reduction in IBS Severity Scoring System (IBS SSS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">From 139 adults with ROME IV IBS-D or IBS-M, 120 were randomized and all completed screening and treatment phases (silicolgel n&#x2009;=&#x2009;60, placebo n&#x2009;=&#x2009;60). After 4&#x2009;weeks' treatment: 91.67% (ITT) achieved the primary outcome in the silicolgel group versus 20.00% for placebo (relative risk (RR)&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.58, 95% CI 2.74-7.65, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Mean IBS SSS for silicolgel reduced to 92.75 [62.68], -162.87 versus 257.58 [74.94] +3.17 for the placebo group (U&#x2009;=&#x2009;210.5, r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.76, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Silicolgel also improved bowel habit, abdominal pain, distension, flatulence, and QoL. IBS-D and IBS-M patients showed the same improvements. Adverse events were similar in both groups, with no serious events attributable to silicolgel or placebo. Onset of action was rapid; after 2&#x2009;weeks, 85.0% on silicolgel achieved the primary outcome versus 11.7% on placebo (significant difference).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Silicolgel is safe and effective in IBS-D and IBS-M, providing an alternative to the limited treatments currently available.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuzminska</LastName><ForeName>O</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chernivtsi Hospital of Emergency Medical Care, Chernivtsi, Ukraine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vitkovska</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Head of the Gastroenterology Department, TOV "GASTROTSENTR", Kyiv, Ukraine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuvaiskov</LastName><ForeName>Yurii</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Writer, Verum Clinical Study LLC, Kyiv, Ukraine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hatton</LastName><ForeName>Chris G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-6959-2653</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FW Medical Ltd, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>FW Medical Ltd and Delta Medical LLC</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rome IV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">double&#x2010;blind</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterosorbent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">placebo&#x2010;controlled study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized clinical trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">silicolgel</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40712106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.70118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>D. H. Vasant, P. A. Paine, C. J. Black, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;British Society of Gastroenterology Guidelines on the Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Gut 70, no. 7 (2021): 1214&#x2013;1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. M. Lovell and A. C. Ford, &#x201c;Global Prevalence of and Risk Factors for Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology 10, no. 7 (2012): 712&#x2013;721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. S. Palsson, W. Whitehead, H. T&#xf6;rnblom, A. D. Sperber, and M. Simren, &#x201c;Prevalence of Rome IV Functional Bowel Disorders Among Adults in the United States, Canada, and the United Kingdom,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 158, no. 5 (2020): 1262&#x2013;1273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Mearin, B. E. Lacy, L. Chang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Bowel Disorders,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 150, no. 6 (2016): 1393&#x2013;1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. D. Sperber, S. I. Bangdiwala, D. A. Drossman, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Worldwide Prevalence and Burden of Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders, Results of Rome Foundation Global Study,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 160, no. 1 (2021): 99&#x2013;114.e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Erdrich, J. A. Hawrelak, S. P. Myers, and J. E. Harnett, &#x201c;A Systematic Review of the Association Between Fibromyalgia and Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders,&#x201d; Therapeutic Advances in Gastroenterology 13 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Zamani, S. Alizadeh&#x2010;Tabari, and V. Zamani, &#x201c;Systematic Review With Meta&#x2010;Analysis: The Prevalence of Anxiety and Depression in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 50, no. 2 (2019): 132&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Berman, B. D. Naliboff, B. Suyenobu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Reduced Brainstem Inhibition During Anticipated Pelvic Visceral Pain Correlates With Enhanced Brain Response to the Visceral Stimulus in Women With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Neuroscience 28, no. 2 (2008): 349&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. M. Lovell and A. C. Ford, &#x201c;Prevalence of Gastro&#x2010;Esophageal Reflux&#x2010;Type Symptoms in Individuals With Irritable Bowel Syndrome in the Community: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 107, no. 12 (2012): 1793&#x2013;1802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Piacentino, R. Cantarini, M. Alfonsi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Psychopathological Features of Irritable Bowel Syndrome Patients With and Without Functional Dyspepsia: A Cross Sectional Study,&#x201d; BMC Gastroenterology 11 (2011): 94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. E. Lakhan and A. Kirchgessner, &#x201c;Gut Inflammation in Chronic Fatigue Syndrome,&#x201d; Nutrition &amp; Metabolism (London) 7 (2010): 79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Patel, P. Bercik, D. G. Morgan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Irritable Bowel Syndrome Is Significantly Associated With Somatization in 840 Patients, Which May Drive Bloating,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 41, no. 5 (2015): 449&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Ballou and L. Keefer, &#x201c;The Impact of Irritable Bowel Syndrome on Daily Functioning: Characterizing and Understanding Daily Consequences of IBS,&#x201d; Neurogastroenterology and Motility 29, no. 4 (2017), https://doi.org/10.1111/nmo.12982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Society of Intestinal Research, &#x201c;IBS Global Impact Report 2018,&#x201d; 2017, accessed September 14, 2024, https://badgut.org/ibs&#x2010;global&#x2010;impact&#x2010;report&#x2010;2018/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;. Fr&#xe4;ndemark, H. T&#xf6;rnblom, S. Jakobsson, and M. Simr&#xe9;n, &#x201c;Work Productivity and Activity Impairment in Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS): A Multifaceted Problem,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 113, no. 10 (2018): 1540&#x2013;1549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Singh, K. Staller, K. Barshop, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome&#x2010;Diarrhea Have Lower Disease&#x2010;Specific Quality of Life Than Irritable Bowel Syndrome&#x2010;Constipation,&#x201d; World Journal of Gastroenterology 21, no. 26 (2015): 8103&#x2013;8109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. E. Flacco, L. Manzoli, R. De Giorgio, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Costs of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in European Countries With Universal Healthcare Coverage: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; European Review for Medical and Pharmacological Sciences 23, no. 7 (2019): 2986&#x2013;3000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. C. Goodoory, C. E. Ng, C. J. Black, and A. C. Ford, &#x201c;Direct Healthcare Costs of Rome IV or Rome III&#x2010;Defined Irritable Bowel Syndrome in the United Kingdom,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 56, no. 1 (2022): 110&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. J. Black and A. C. Ford, &#x201c;Best Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Frontline Gastroenterology 12, no. 4 (2020): 303&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Society of Intestinal Research, &#x201c;Gastrointestinal Society 2016 Survey Results: Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS),&#x201d; accessed September 14, 2024, https://badgut.org/wp&#x2010;content/uploads/IBS&#x2010;Survey&#x2010;Results&#x2010;2016.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Y. Chang, C. L. Lu, C. Y. Chen, and J. C. Luo, &#x201c;Efficacy of Dioctahedral Smectite in Treating Patients of Diarrhea&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology 22, no. 12 (2007): 2266&#x2013;2272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. F. Tack, P. B. Miner, Jr., L. Fischer, and M. S. Harris, &#x201c;Randomized Clinical Trial: The Safety and Efficacy of AST&#x2010;120 in Non&#x2010;Constipating Irritable Bowel Syndrome&#x2014;A Double&#x2010;Blind, Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Study,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 34, no. 8 (2011): 868&#x2013;877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. A. Howell, A. Kemppinen, V. Allgar, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Double&#x2010;Blinded Randomized Placebo&#x2010;Controlled Trial of Enterosgel (Polymethylsiloxane Polyhydrate) for the Treatment of IBS With Diarrhea (IBS&#x2010;D),&#x201d; Gut 71, no. 12 (2022): 2430&#x2013;2438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. D. Park, R. Spector, M. J. Goldberg, and G. F. Johnson, &#x201c;Expanded Role of Charcoal Therapy in the Poisoned and Overdosed Patient,&#x201d; Archives of Internal Medicine 146, no. 5 (1986): 969&#x2013;973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. A. Guss, &#x201c;Emergency Medicine: Activated Charcoal&#x2010;The First&#x2010;Line Agent in Cases of Overdose,&#x201d; Western Journal of Medicine 151, no. 1 (1989): 63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Uehleke, M. Ortiz, and R. Stange, &#x201c;Silicea Gastrointestinal Gel Improves Gastrointestinal Disorders: A Non&#x2010;Controlled, Pilot Clinical Study,&#x201d; Gastroenterology Research and Practice 2012 (2012): 750750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Swinyard and M. Pathak, &#x201c;Surface Acting Drugs,&#x201d; in The Pharmacological Basis of Therapeutics, 6th ed. (Macmillan, 1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Kachel and H. Ruppin, &#x201c;Akute Diarroe: Diagnostik Und Therapie,&#x201d; Deutsche Apotheker&#x2010;Zeitung 122, no. 31 (1982): 1604&#x2013;1610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. G. Rateau, G. Morgant, M. T. Droy&#x2010;Priot, and J. L. Parier, &#x201c;A Histological, Enzymatic and Water&#x2010;Electrolyte Study of the Action of Smectite, a Mucoprotective Clay, on Experimental Infectious Diarrhea in the Rabbit,&#x201d; Current Medical Research and Opinion 8, no. 4 (1982): 233&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wagner, &#x201c;Kolloidales Siliciumdioxid Bei Colitis Ulcerosa Und Morbus Crohn &#x2010; Eine Therapeutische Alternative Zur Herk&#xf6;mmlichen Behandlung,&#x201d; Die Therapiewoche 32 (1982): 6185&#x2013;6190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. A. Howell, S. V. Mikhalovsky, E. N. Markaryan, and A. V. Khovanov, &#x201c;Investigation of the Adsorption Capacity of the Enterosorbent Enterosgel for a Range of Bacterial Toxins, Bile Acids and Pharmaceutical Drugs,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 9, no. 1 (2019): 5629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. A. Howell, E. Markaryan, V. Allgar, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Enterosgel for the Treatment of Adults With Acute Diarrhea in a Primary Care Setting: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; BMJ Open Gastroenterology 6, no. 1 (2019): e000287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FW Medical Ltd, &#x201c;Silicolgel for Gastrointestinal Disorders,&#x201d; accessed September 14, 2024, https://www.silicol.co.uk/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Crawford, R. Taylor, D. Young, and C. G. Hatton, &#x201c;Efficacy of the Enterosorbent SilicolGel in Adults With Irritable Bowel Syndrome Subtypes IBS&#x2010;D or Mixed: Observational Open&#x2010;Label Study,&#x201d; Gastroenterology Research and Practice 2023 (2023): 3432763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Y. Francis, J. Morris, and P. J. Whorwell, &#x201c;The Irritable Bowel Severity Scoring System: A Simple Method of Monitoring Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Its Progress,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 11, no. 2 (1997): 395&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency, &#x201c;Evaluation of Medicinal Products for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome&#x2014;Scientific Guideline,&#x201d; 2014, accessed September 14, 2024, https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/evaluation&#x2010;medicinal&#x2010;products&#x2010;treatment&#x2010;irritable&#x2010;bowel&#x2010;syndrome&#x2010;scientific&#x2010;guideline.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The European Parliament and the Council of the European Union, &#x201c;Medical Devices Regulation EU2017\745 (Medical Devices),&#x201d; accessed September 14, 2024, https://eur&#x2010;lex.europa.eu/legal&#x2010;content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32017R0745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Lembo, J. M. Kelley, J. Nee, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Open&#x2010;Label Placebo vs Double&#x2010;Blind Placebo for Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Pain 162, no. 9 (2021): 2428&#x2013;2435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Rangan, S. Ballou, A. Shin, M. Camilleri, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center GI Motility Working Group, and A. Lembo, &#x201c;Use of Treatments for Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Patient Satisfaction Based on the IBS in America Survey,&#x201d; Gastroenterology 158, no. 3 (2020): 786&#x2013;788.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Dionne, A. C. Ford, Y. Yuan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis Evaluating the Efficacy of a Gluten&#x2010;Free Diet and a Low FODMAPs Diet in Treating Symptoms of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 113, no. 9 (2018): 1290&#x2013;1300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. C. Ford, P. Moayyedi, W. D. Chey, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;American College of Gastroenterology Monograph on Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 113, no. Suppl 2 (2018): 1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. A. Gorard, G. W. Libby, and M. J. Farthing, &#x201c;Influence of Antidepressants on Whole Gut and Orocaecal Transit Times in Health and Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 8, no. 2 (1994): 159&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. W. Min and P. L. Rhee, &#x201c;The Clinical Potential of Ramosetron in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Diarrhea (IBS&#x2010;D),&#x201d; Therapeutic Advances in Gastroenterology 8, no. 3 (2015): 136&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. J. Black, N. E. Burr, M. Camilleri, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Efficacy of Pharmacological Therapies in Patients With IBS With Diarrhea or Mixed Stool Pattern: Systematic Review and Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Gut 69, no. 1 (2020): 74&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Garsed, J. Chernova, M. Hastings, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Randomized Trial of Ondansetron for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome With Diarrhea,&#x201d; Gut 63, no. 10 (2014): 1617&#x2013;1625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. E. Lacy, W. D. Chey, B. D. Cash, A. J. Lembo, L. S. Dove, and P. S. Covington, &#x201c;Eluxadoline Efficacy in IBS&#x2010;D Patients Who Report Prior Loperamide Use,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 112, no. 6 (2017): 924&#x2013;932.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle><PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40706614</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2468-1253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The lancet. Gastroenterology &amp; hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of gluten and wheat on symptoms and behaviours in adults with irritable bowel syndrome: a single-centre, randomised, double-blind, sham-controlled crossover trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>794</StartPage><EndPage>805</EndPage><MedlinePgn>794-805</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2468-1253(25)00090-1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2468-1253(25)00090-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Many patients with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) believe gluten or wheat triggers their symptoms. We compared symptomatic responses to wheat and gluten with gluten-free sham challenge in patients with IBS who previously perceived benefit from a gluten-free diet.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted this randomised, double-blind, sham-controlled crossover study at McMaster University Medical Centre, ON, Canada. Eligible participants were adults aged 18 years or older who met Rome IV criteria for IBS and had previously self-reported improvement on a gluten-free diet, which was implemented for at least 3 weeks before enrolment. Eligible participants were randomly assigned (1:1:1:1:1:1) to receive one of six sequences of wheat, gluten, and sham (containing gluten and wheat free flour) in three periods of 7 days, separated by 14-day washout periods. Randomisation was done using the randomizeBE package in R and the cereal bars were designed to have the same appearance, taste, and smell to maintain blinding. The primary outcome was worsening of IBS symptoms of at least 50 points on the IBS Symptom Severity Score (IBS-SSS) after dietary challenges. Outcome and safety analyses were done in all patients who completed all three challenges. This trial was registered with ClinicalTrials.gov, NCT03664531.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between Nov 15, 2018, and June 19, 2023, we assessed 101 people for eligibility. 72 people were excluded due to ineligibility (n=15), refusing screening (n=42), and refusing participation (n=15). 29 participants were enrolled and randomly assigned to wheat-gluten-sham (n=5), wheat-sham-gluten (n=5), gluten-wheat-sham (n=5), gluten-sham-wheat (n=5), sham-wheat-gluten (n=5), and sham-gluten-wheat (n=4). One participant in the wheat-sham-gluten group completed the first challenge but withdrew without providing a reason. In the 28 patients completing the study, there were no statistically significant differences in the proportion of participants with a worsening of IBS-SSS of at least 50 points after wheat (11 [39%] of 28 participants, risk difference vs sham 0&#xb7;11; 95% CI -0&#xb7;16 to 0&#xb7;35) or gluten (ten participants [36%], 0&#xb7;07; -0&#xb7;19 to 0&#xb7;32) versus sham (eight participants [29%]). Adverse events were reported in 26 (93%) of 28 patients after wheat, 26 patients (93%) after gluten, and 26 patients (93%) after sham. Study emergent adverse events were similar between challenges (five [18%] of 28 participants after wheat, five [18%] after gluten, and seven [25%] after sham). No patients reported severe adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">IBS patients with self-perceived gluten sensitivity reacted similarly to gluten, wheat, and sham challenges. These findings suggest that expectations played a major role in symptom generation, and that only some of these patients could benefit from gluten or wheat restriction. Identifying this subset of patients while destigmatising wheat and gluten in the remaining ones should be considered for effective management of patients with IBS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Canadian Digestive Health Foundation, Society for the Study of Celiac Disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seiler</LastName><ForeName>Caroline Larissa</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rueda</LastName><ForeName>Gaston Horacio</ForeName><Initials>GH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miranda</LastName><ForeName>Pedro Miguel</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nardelli</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borojevic</LastName><ForeName>Rajka</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hann</LastName><ForeName>Amber</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahmani</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Souza</LastName><ForeName>Russell</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Population Health Research Institute, Hamilton Health Sciences, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caminero</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Curella</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Translational Immunology and Research Center for Immune Therapy, Medical Center, Johannes-Gutenberg-University, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neerukonda</LastName><ForeName>Manjusha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Translational Immunology and Research Center for Immune Therapy, Medical Center, Johannes-Gutenberg-University, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanner</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastrointestinal Diseases Research Unit, Kingston Health Science Centre, Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuppan</LastName><ForeName>Detlef</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Translational Immunology and Research Center for Immune Therapy, Medical Center, Johannes-Gutenberg-University, Mainz, Germany; Division of Gastroenterology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moayyedi</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collins</LastName><ForeName>Stephen Michael</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verdu</LastName><ForeName>Elena Francisca</ForeName><Initials>EF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto-Sanchez</LastName><ForeName>Maria Ines</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bercik</LastName><ForeName>Premysl</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Farncombe Family Digestive Health Research Institute, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada. Electronic address: bercikp@mcmaster.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT03664531</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101690683</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8002-80-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005983">Glutens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005983" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glutens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Triticum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055050" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, Gluten-Free</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests MIP-S received honoraria from Takeda for consulting and research funding from ProventBio and Takeda; payment from Celiac Disease Foundation (for speaking), SCOPE (for speaking), and Pharmacists Compendium (for writing); and was on the professional advisory board for Celiac Canada, all unrelated to this paper. RDS consulted and provided data analysis support for Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre and was an independent director for the Helderleigh Foundation, a committee member for the Nutrition Science Advisory Committee for Health Canada, a member of the Scientific Advisory Committee on Nutrition Subgroup on the Framework for the Evaluation of Evidence for Public Health England, and an external resource person for WHO, unrelated to this paper. DS received consulting fees and travel or conference support from Falk Pharma, Sanofi, and Takeda; participated in advisory boards for Boehringer-Ingelheim, Vedanta, and Tillots; and has stock options in Northsea Therapeutics, unrelated to this paper. DS was chair of the scientific advisory board for the German Celiac Society, unrelated to this paper. PB was a consultant and received grant support from Nestec Switzerland, unrelated to this paper. The other authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40706614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(25)00090-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2468-1253(25)00090-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>