<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40801411</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Outcomes of Multiarterial Versus Single Arterial Grafting in Patients with Reduced Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction Undergoing Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ischemic cardiomyopathy with reduced left ventricular ejection fraction presents considerable outcome-related challenges, even with the development of surgical revascularization. Coronary artery bypass grafting continues to be a key therapy, yet the best grafting technique, single arterial grafting (SAG) versus multiarterial grafting (MAG) for patients with reduced EF, is uncertain. This systematic review and meta-analysis aims to assess the comparative outcomes of MAG versus SAG in this high-risk group. Fourteen cohort studies consisting of 19,976 patients were studied, with 10,306 receiving MAG and 9670 receiving SAG. The primary outcomes are 5-year overall survival, cardiac death, and in-hospital mortality, while secondary outcomes include major adverse cardiovascular events, perioperative myocardial infarction, repeat revascularization, atrial fibrillation, postoperative dialysis, stroke, intensive care unit/hospital stay, and sternal wound infection. MAG was notably related to improved 5-year survival [odds ratio (OR), 1.50; 95% confidence interval (CI), 1.32-1.70; P &lt; 0.00001] and reduced in-hospital mortality (OR, 0.66; 95% CI, 0.55-0.79; P &lt; 0.00001). While cardiac mortality was not statistically significant, secondary outcomes were generally similar between groups. Sensitivity analyses validated the robustness of findings, and Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation assessments confirmed moderate to high certainty of evidence. No considerable publication bias was noted. Despite the lack of randomized controlled trials, this review underscores the improved survival of MAG without increased perioperative risk in patients with left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;50%. These outcomes indicate that MAG may be suitable in select cases, though further randomized studies are required to confirm these results and guide optimized decision-making.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javed</LastName><ForeName>Javeria</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Jinnah Sindh Medical University, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bacha</LastName><ForeName>Zaryab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fida</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sajjad</LastName><ForeName>Fatima</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rath</LastName><ForeName>Shree</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Bhubaneswar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afridi</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alam</LastName><ForeName>Umama</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henna</LastName><ForeName>Fathimathul</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Dubai Medical College for Girls, Dubai, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noor</LastName><ForeName>Hamna</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Khyber Medical College, Peshawar Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naintara</LastName><ForeName>Fnu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Wellspan Health York Hospital, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery bypass grafting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemic cardiomyopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">left ventricular ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiarterial grafting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">single arterial grafting</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40801411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Christiansen MN, K&#xf8;ber L, Weeke P, et al. Age-specific trends in incidence, mortality, and comorbidities of heart failure in Denmark, 1995 to 2012. Circulation. 2017;135:1214&#x2013;1223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones NR, Roalfe AK, Adoki I, et al. Survival of patients with chronic heart failure in the community: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Heart Fail. 2019;21:1306&#x2013;1325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun LY, Gaudino M, Chen RJ, et al. Long-term outcomes in patients with severely reduced left ventricular ejection fraction undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention vs coronary artery bypass grafting [published correction appears in JAMA Cardiol. 2020 Jun 1;5(6):732. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1655.]. JAMA Cardiol. 2020;5:631&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, et al.; ACC/AHA Joint Committee Members. 2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association joint committee on clinical practice guidelines [published correction appears in Circulation. 2022 May 3;145(18):e1033. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001073.] [published correction appears in Circulation. 2022 Sep 27;146(13):e185. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001097.] [published correction appears in Circulation. 2023 Apr 4;147(14):e674. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001142.]. Circulation. 2022;145:e895&#x2013;e1032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al.; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure [published correction appears in Eur Heart J. 2021 Dec 21;42(48):4901. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehab670.]. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Zhu Q, Lu L, et al. Comparison of multiple arterial grafts vs. single arterial graft in coronary artery bypass surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2025;12:1555242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda M, Niinami H, Morita K, et al. Long-term results following off-pump coronary-artery bypass grafting in left ventricular dysfunction. Heart Vessels. 2024;39:571&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Chen W, Zhao Y, et al. Multiple arterial conduits for multi-vessel coronary artery bypass grafting in patients with mild to moderate left ventricular systolic dysfunction: a multicenter retrospective study. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2021;16:123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Bai S, Zhang J, et al. Multiple arterial grafts do not increase perioperative or short- to medium-term risks of postoperative MACE in patients with impaired left ventricular function: 3-year follow-up results. J South Med Uni. 2025;45:239&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Bloom JE, Chan W, et al. Survival outcomes after multiple vs single arterial grafting among patients with reduced ejection fraction. JAMA Netw Open. 2025;8:e254508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane Training. Available from: https://training.cochrane.org/handbook. Accessed Jan 11, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. Available from: https://www.bmj.com/content/372/bmj.n71. Accessed Jan 11, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galbut DL, Kurlansky PA, Traad EA, et al. Bilateral internal thoracic artery grafting improves long-term survival in patients with reduced ejection fraction: a propensity-matched study with 30-year follow-up. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2012;143:844&#x2013;853.e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi S, Kalavrouziotis D, Cresce G, et al. Bilateral internal thoracic artery use in patients with low ejection fraction: is there any additional long-term benefit? Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2014;46:425&#x2013;31; discussion 431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwann TA, Al-Shaar L, Tranbaugh RF, et al. Multi versus single arterial coronary bypass graft surgery across the ejection fraction spectrum. Ann Thorac Surg. 2015;100:810&#x2013;7; discussion 817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popovic B, Maureira P, Juilliere Y, et al. Bilateral vs unilateral internal mammary revascularization in patients with left ventricular dysfunction. World J Cardiol. 2017;9:339&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong TH, Ha YJ, Jeong DS, et al. Graft strategy for coronary artery bypass grafting in patients with severe left ventricular dysfunction [published correction appears in Korean J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2019 Jun;52(3):189. doi: 10.5090/kjtcs.2019.52.3.189.]. Korean J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2019;52:16&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farkash A, Pevni D, Mohr R, et al. Single versus bilateral internal thoracic artery grafting in patients with low ejection fraction. Medicine (Baltim). 2020;99:e22842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kainuma S, Toda K, Daimon T, et al.; Osaka Cardiovascular Surgery Research (OSCAR) Group. Bilateral internal thoracic artery grafting improves survival for severe left ventricular dysfunction and diabetes. Circ J. 2021;85:1991&#x2013;2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronai T, Abraham D, Erez E, et al. The impact of multiarterial grafting in patients with left ventricular dysfunction. Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2024;70:40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hachiro K, Takashima N, Kamiya K, et al. Multiple arterial grafting in patients with low left ventricular ejection fraction. Circ J. 2025;CJ-24:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute. Available from: https://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epidemiology/oxford.asp. Accessed Jan 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santesso N, Carrasco-Labra A, Langendam M, et al. Improving GRADE evidence tables part 3: detailed guidance for explanatory footnotes supports creating and understanding GRADE certainty in the evidence judgments. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016;74:28&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao SC, Kuo LT, Huang YT, et al. Using Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) to rate the certainty of evidence of study outcomes from systematic reviews: a quick tutorial. Dermatol Sin. 2023;41:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials. 1986;7:177&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, et al. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo M, Tomizawa Y, Nishida H. Bilateral versus unilateral internal mammary revascularization in patients with diabetes. Circulation. 2003;108:1343&#x2013;1349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velazquez EJ, Lee KL, Deja MA, et al.; STICH Investigators. Coronary-artery bypass surgery in patients with left ventricular dysfunction. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:1607&#x2013;1616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeling WB, Williams ML, Slaughter MS, et al. Off-pump and on-pump coronary revascularization in patients with low ejection fraction: a report from the society of thoracic surgeons national database. Ann Thorac Surg. 2013;96:83&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardi P, Pellegrino A, Scafuri A, et al. Long-term outcome of coronary artery bypass grafting in patients with left ventricular dysfunction. Ann Thorac Surg. 2009;87:1401&#x2013;1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman S, Zadina K, Moritz T, et al.; VA Cooperative Study Group #207/297/364. Long-term patency of saphenous vein and left internal mammary artery grafts after coronary artery bypass surgery: results from a Department of Veterans Affairs cooperative study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;44:2149&#x2013;2156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lytle BW, Loop FD, Cosgrove DM, et al. Long-term (5 to 12 years) serial studies of internal mammary artery and saphenous vein coronary bypass grafts. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 1985;89:248&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth JA, Cukingnan RA, Brown BG, et al. Factors influencing patency of saphenous vein grafts. Ann Thorac Surg. 1979;28:176&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward PA, Yap CH, Shi WY, et al. Does the addition of a radial artery graft improve survival after higher risk coronary artery bypass grafting? A propensity-score analysis of a multicentre database. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2013;44:497&#x2013;504; discussion 504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golla MSG, Hajouli S, Ludhwani D. Heart Failure and Ejection Fraction. [Updated 2024 May 5]. In: StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025 Jan-. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK553115/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapira OM, Idais I, Aviel G. The best conduits, by the best surgeons, for the best outcomes. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;74:1286&#x2013;1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboul-Hassan SS, Hirnle G, Perek B, et al.; KROK Investigators. Single versus multiple arterial coronary artery bypass grafting in men and women: results from Polish National Registry of Cardiac Surgery Procedures. Int J Surg. 2024;110:2234&#x2013;2242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruka E, Dagenais F, Mohammadi S, et al. Bilateral mammary artery grafting increases postoperative mediastinitis without survival benefit in obese patients. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2016;50:1188&#x2013;1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Q, Huang K, Lin S, et al. Impact of multiarterial versus single arterial coronary bypass graft surgery on postoperative atrial fibrillation. Am J Cardiol. 2025;234:30&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>