<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40964547</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of Functional Outcomes of Cemented Bipolar Hemiarthroplasty Versus Uncemented Total Hip Arthroplasty for Displaced Femoral Neck Fractures in Patients Over 60 Years: A Prospective Randomized Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e90255</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e90255</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e90255</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.90255</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Displaced femoral neck fractures in elderly patients pose significant challenges due to osteoporosis and comorbidities. Apart from Internal Fixation, which is reserved for non-osteoporotic young patients, bipolar hemiarthroplasty (BHA) and total hip arthroplasty (THA) are common surgical options, but optimal management remains debated. Objective To compare the functional outcomes, surgical parameters, and complications of cemented BHA versus uncemented THA in patients over 60 years with displaced femoral neck fractures. Methods In this prospective randomized study, 40 patients (mean age, 66.7 years) with displaced femoral neck fractures were allocated to either uncemented THA (group 1, n=20) or cemented BHA (group 2, n=20). Outcomes were assessed using the Harris Hip Score (HHS) at 14 days, one, three, six, and 12 months postoperatively. Secondary outcomes included surgical duration, blood loss, weight-bearing initiation, and complications. Results THA demonstrated significantly higher HHS at 14 days (21.40 vs 20.05, p=0.03) and three months (64.55 vs 59.60, p=0.001), but no significant differences were noted at six and 12 months. BHA was associated with shorter surgical duration (75.0 vs 96.25 minutes, p&lt;0.001) and less blood loss (307.65 vs 357.50 mL, p&lt;0.001). No significant differences were found in weight-bearing initiation or complication rates, including infection, dislocation, or reoperation. Conclusion Both THA and BHA yield comparable long-term functional outcomes in elderly patients with displaced femoral neck fractures. THA offers superior early functional recovery, while BHA is advantageous for shorter surgical time and reduced blood loss. Treatment should be individualized based on patient factors and surgical expertise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Prasad et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prasad</LastName><ForeName>Brejesh</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Employees State Insurance Corporation (ESIC) Medical College, Faridabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Jasbir</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Employees State Insurance Corporation (ESIC) Medical College, Faridabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Krishan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Employees State Insurance Corporation (ESIC) Medical College, Faridabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bipolar hemiarthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">femoral neck fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">harris hip score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total hip arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee of ESIC Medical College and Hospital, Faridabad issued approval 134 X/11/13/2023 - IEC/DHR/47. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40964547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12436082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.90255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Changes in hip fracture epidemiology: redistribution between ages, genders and fracture types. L&#xf6;fman O, Berglund K, Larsson L, Toss G. Osteoporos Int. 2002;13:18&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11878451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment and outcome of femoral neck fractures: an analysis of 2418 patients admitted from their own homes. Holmberg S, Kalen R, Thorngren KG. https://journals.lww.com/clinorthop/abstract/1987/05000/treatment_and_outcome_of_femoral_neck_fractures_an.7.aspx Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1987;216:42&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3568494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The societal burden of osteoporosis. Becker DJ, Kilgore ML, Morrisey MA. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2010;12:186&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20425518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical management of hip fractures: an evidence-based review of the literature. I: femoral neck fractures. Miyamoto RG, Kaplan KM, Levine BR, Egol KA, Zuckerman JD. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2008;16:596&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18832603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early outcome of hemiarthroplasty using cemented bipolar prosthesis in fracture lower femur in elderly: a study of 50 cases. Patel KK, Moraday N, Gawatre P, Deasal TV. Int J Orthop Sci. 2017;3:303&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The functional outcome in patients treated with THA with acute fracture neck of femur in patients aged above 60 years using Harris hip score. Hiranya Kumar S, Mahesh Kumar Reddy V, Gowtham G, Abhinav Gandra. Int J Orthop Sci. 2019;5:1138&#x2013;1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychometric assessment of modified Harris Hip Score for femoral neck fracture in Indian population. Vishwanathan K, Pathan SK, Makadia RC, Chaudhary CB. Indian J Orthop. 2020;54:87&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32952915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictors of functional outcome following femoral neck fractures treated with an arthroplasty: limitations of the Harris hip score. Reuling EM, Sierevelt IN, van den Bekerom MP, et al. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2012;132:249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3261383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22113433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The self-locking metal hip prosthesis. Moore AT. https://journals.lww.com/jbjsjournal/abstract/1957/39040/the_self_locking_metal_hip_prosthesis.5.aspx. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1957;39:811&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13438939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traumatic arthritis of the hip after dislocation and acetabular fractures: treatment by mold arthroplasty. Harris WH. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1969;51:737&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5783851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomised controlled trial comparing bipolar hemiarthroplasty with total hip replacement for displaced intracapsular fractures of the femoral neck in elderly patients. Blomfeldt R, T&#xf6;rnkvist H, Eriksson K, S&#xf6;derqvist A, Ponzer S, Tidermark J. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2007;89:160&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17322427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized comparison of reduction and fixation, bipolar hemiarthroplasty, and total hip arthroplasty. Treatment of displaced intracapsular hip fractures in healthy older patients. Keating JF, Grant A, Masson M, Scott NW, Forbes JF. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2006;88:249&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16452734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prospective randomized clinical trial comparing hemiarthroplasty to total hip arthroplasty in the treatment of displaced femoral neck fractures: winner of the Dorr Award. Macaulay W, Nellans KW, Garvin KL, Iorio R, Healy WL, Rosenwasser MP. J Arthroplasty. 2008;23:2&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18722297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomechanics of femoral neck fractures and implications for fixation. Augat P, Bliven E, Hackl S. J Orthop Trauma. 2019;33:0&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30540669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation interventions for persons with hip fracture and cognitive impairment: A scoping review. Cadel L, Kuluski K, Wodchis WP, Thavorn K, Guilcher SJ. PLoS One. 2022;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9377630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quality of life following hip fractures: results from the Norwegian hip fracture register. Gjertsen JE, Baste V, Fevang JM, Furnes O, Enges&#xe6;ter LB. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2016;17:265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4936302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Better early outcome with enhanced recovery total hip arthroplasty (ERAS-THA) versus conventional setup in randomized clinical trial (RCT) G&#xf6;tz J, Maderbacher G, Leiss F, et al. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;144:439&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10774173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37552325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing complications and costs of total hip arthroplasty and hemiarthroplasty for femoral neck fractures: a propensity score-matched, population-based study. Ravi B, Pincus D, Khan H, Wasserstein D, Jenkinson R, Kreder HJ. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2019;101:572&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30946190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of bipolar hemiarthroplasty and total hip arthroplasty for displaced femoral neck fractures in the healthy elderly: a meta-analysis. Wang F, Zhang H, Zhang Z, Ma C, Feng X. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2015;16:229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4552391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthroplasties (with and without bone cement) for proximal femoral fractures in adults. Parker MJ, Rajan D. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2001;27:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11686994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dual-mobility acetabular components in primary total hip arthroplasty do not increase the risk of complication compared to conventional articulations: a matched cohort comparative analysis. Khaliq M, Jenkins N, Van Duren B, Palan J, Pandit H, Jain S. Arthroplast Today. 2024;26:101332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38433873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Total hip replacement and hemiarthroplasty in mobile, independent patients with a displaced intracapsular fracture of the femoral neck: a seven- to ten-year follow-up report of a prospective randomised controlled trial. Avery PP, Baker RP, Walton MJ, Rooker JC, Squires B, Gargan MF, Bannister GC. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2011;93:1045&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21768626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>