<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40986486</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-7080</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Postmyocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture: optimizing surgical timing and repair.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HCO.0000000000001256</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This review summarizes the most recent literature regarding the surgical management of postmyocardial infarction (MI) ventricular septal rupture and the optimal timing and performance of the operation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There are conflicting data surrounding the optimal timing of surgical intervention for post-MI ventricular septal rupture. Patients often present in hemodynamic compromise which limits the ability to delay their intervention. A lack of randomized control trials mandates reliance on retrospective cohort studies that have a selection bias in favor of delayed surgery due to unstable patients requiring emergent intervention. Similarly, mechanical circulatory support may be associated with poorer outcomes in part due to selection bias. There is a trend towards better prognosis in patients with lower preoperative lactate and lower vasopressor requirements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A diagnosis of a post-MI ventricular septal rupture carries a poor prognosis. Without surgical intervention, the likelihood of 1-year survival is very low. Percutaneous treatment options have limited success, and the gold standard remains surgical intervention. Surgical timing is often dictated by patients being hemodynamically unstable and requiring emergent surgery. When a patient can have delayed intervention, there is a trend towards better outcomes. Optimized hemodynamics, metabolic parameters, and initial medical management are associated with improved outcomes. Mechanical circulatory support is of benefit in sicker patients if it can assist with preoperative optimization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goubran</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiac Surgery, University of Ottawa Heart Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Issa</LastName><ForeName>Hugo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarizia</LastName><ForeName>Nadia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Vincent</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruel</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8608087</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0268-4705</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute coronary syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemic heart disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventricular septal defect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventricular septal rupture</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40986486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCO.0000000000001256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001573-990000000-00233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>de Grandsaigne HT, Bouisset F, Porterie J, et al. Incidence, management, and prognosis of postischaemic ventricular septal defect: insights from a 12-year tertiary centre experience. Front Cardiovasc Med 2022; 9:1066308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu W, Wu L, Ma X, et al. Outcomes of surgical repair of anterior or posterior ventricular septal rupture after myocardial infarction. Cardiovasc Diagn Ther 2022; 12:177&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Liu H, Yang P, et al. Current understanding of timing of surgical repair for ventricular septal rupture following acute myocardial infarction. Cardiol Cardiac Surg 2024; 149:618&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts JD, So DYF, Lambert AS, Ruel M. Successful surgical repair of ventricular. Can J Cardiol 2011; 27:868.e5&#x2013;868.e7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matteucci M, Ronco D, Corazzari C, et al. Surgical repair of postinfarction ventricular septal rupture: systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Thorac Surg 2021; 112:326&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen MM, Zhao DXM. Percutaneous post-myocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture closure: a review. Struct Heart 2018; 2:122&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlotter F, de Waha S, Eitel I, et al. Interventional postmyocardial infarction ventricular septal defect closure: a systematic review of current evidence. Euro Interv 2016; 12:94&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Wang C, Du X, et al. Percutaneous closure vs. surgical repair for postinfarction ventricular septal rupture: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brazi J Cardiovasc Surg 2023; 38:e20220417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, xio L-L, Liu C, et al. Clinical characteristics and contemporary prognosis of ventricular septal rupture complicating acute myocardial infarction: a single-center experience. Front Cardiovasc Med 2021; 8:679148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundblad R, Abdelnoor M. Surgery of postinfarction ventricular septal rupture: The effect of David infarct exclusion versus Daggett direct septal closure on early and late outcomes. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg Aquir Cardiovasc Dis 2014; 148:2736&#x2013;2742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, O&#x2019;Donoghue M, Ruel M, et al. 2025 ACC/AHA/ACEP/NAEMSP/SCAI guideline for the management of patients with acute coronary syndromes: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines,&#x201d;. Circulation 2025; 151: 771&#x2013;862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moros D, Maigrot J, Tong M, et al. Temporary microaxial transvalvular left ventricular assist device for postmyocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture: bridging a paradigm shift. JTCVS Tech 2024; 28:97&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rob D, &#x160;punda R, Lindner J, et al. A rationale for early extracorporeal membrane oxygenation in patients with postinfarction ventricular septal rupture complicated by cardiogenic shock. Eur J Heart Fail 2017; 19:97&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronco D, Ariza-Sol&#xe9; A, Kowalewski M, et al. The current clinical practice for management of postinfarction ventricular septal rupture: a European survey. Eur Heart J Open 2023; 3:oead091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua K, Peng Z, Yang X. Long-term survival and risk factors for post-infarction ventricular septal rupture. Heart Lung Circ 2021; 30:978&#x2013;985.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>