<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40968746</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2055-5822</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ESC heart failure</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ESC Heart Fail</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SGLT2 inhibitors for the prevention and treatment of heart failure: A scientific statement of the HFA and the HFAI.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ehf2.15408</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the 2021 European Society of Cardiology (ESC) heart failure (HF) guidelines, sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors were recommended for the prevention of HF in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and for the treatment of HF with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF). Further trials showed efficacy of empagliflozin and dapagliflozin in patients with HF with preserved ejection fraction (HFpEF). These results prompted a broadened recommendation for the SGLT2 inhibitors dapagliflozin or empagliflozin across the whole left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) spectrum in the 2023 Focused Update of the ESC HF guidelines and in other international guidelines. In SOLOIST-WHF and EMPULSE, sotagliflozin (enrolling only patients with T2DM) and empagliflozin, respectively, were beneficial when initiated at the end or soon after an episode of decompensated HF. Based on these results and on the early appearance of their beneficial effects, the administration of SGLT2 inhibitors should start early in patients hospitalized for acute HF. Analyses after study drug withdrawal in randomized clinical trials have shown that their benefits may decline rapidly after discontinuation, and thus, persistence of treatment is advised. In EMPACT-MI, empagliflozin did not reduce the primary outcome of cardiovascular (CV) death/HF hospitalization but reduced first/recurrent HF hospitalizations. Potential benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors in further specific conditions (i.e., cardiac amyloidosis, grown-up congenital heart disease and paediatric patients with HF) have been reported in observational studies but need confirmation from prospective trials. This scientific statement summarizes current evidence regarding the effects of SGLT2 inhibitors for the prevention and treatment of HF.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). ESC Heart Failure published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Cardiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metra</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology. ASST Spedali Civili di Brescia and Department of Medical and Surgical Specialties, Radiological Sciences, and Public Health, University of Brescia, Brescia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomasoni</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology. ASST Spedali Civili di Brescia and Department of Medical and Surgical Specialties, Radiological Sciences, and Public Health, University of Brescia, Brescia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Science and Education, S&#xf6;dersjukhuset, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adamo</LastName><ForeName>Marianna</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology. ASST Spedali Civili di Brescia and Department of Medical and Surgical Specialties, Radiological Sciences, and Public Health, University of Brescia, Brescia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amir</LastName><ForeName>Offer</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Hadassah Medical Center, Faculty of Medicine, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anker</LastName><ForeName>Stefan D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology (CVK) of German Heart Center Charit&#xe9;, German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK) partner site Berlin, Charit&#xe9;-Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayes-Genis</LastName><ForeName>Antoni</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart Institute, Hospital Universitari Germans Trias i Pujol, Badalona, CIBERCV, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boehm</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Klinik f&#xfc;r Innere Medizin III, Universit&#xe4;tsklinikum des Saarlandes, Saarland University, Homburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Butler</LastName><ForeName>Javed</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor Scott &amp; White Research Institute, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Mississippi, Jackson, Mississippi, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chioncel</LastName><ForeName>Ovidiu</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Institute for Cardiovascular Diseases 'Prof. C.C. Iliescu', University of Medicine Carol Davila, Bucharest, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filippatos</LastName><ForeName>Gerasimos</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gustafsson</LastName><ForeName>Finn</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The Heart Centre, Rigshospitalet, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jankowska</LastName><ForeName>Ewa A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Heart Diseases, Wroc&#x142;aw Medical University, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaski</LastName><ForeName>Juan Carlos</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular and Clinical Sciences Research Institute, St George's University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moura</LastName><ForeName>Brenda</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investiga&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Tecnologias e Servi&#xe7;os de Sa&#xfa;de, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Servi&#xe7;o de Cardiologia, Hospital das For&#xe7;as Armadas-P&#xf3;lo do Porto, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petrie</LastName><ForeName>Mark C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ponikowski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Heart Diseases, Wroc&#x142;aw Medical University, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Wroc&#x142;aw Medical University, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rakisheva</LastName><ForeName>Amina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Scientific Institution of Cardiology and Internal Diseases, Almaty, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ristic</LastName><ForeName>Arsen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roubille</LastName><ForeName>Francois</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhyMedExp, Universit&#xe9; de Montpellier, INSERM, CNRS, Cardiology Department, CHU de Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Savarese</LastName><ForeName>Gianluigi</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Science and Education, S&#xf6;dersjukhuset, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seferovic</LastName><ForeName>Petar</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Serbian Academy of Sciences and Arts, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Meer</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volterrani</LastName><ForeName>Maurizio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences, Centre for Clinical and Basic Research, IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coats</LastName><ForeName>Andrew J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart Research Institute, Newtown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chopra</LastName><ForeName>Vijay K</ForeName><Initials>VK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Medanta, Gurgaon, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosano</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences and Promotion of Quality of Life, San Raffaele Open University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS San Raffaele, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>ESC Heart Fail</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101669191</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-5822</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GDMT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SGLT2 inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40968746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ehf2.15408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ponikowski P, Voors AA, Anker SD, Bueno H, Cleland JG, Coats AJ, et al. 2016 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure: The Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute and Chronic Heart Failure of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Developed with the special contribution of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur J Heart Fail 2016;18:891&#x2010;975. doi:10.1002/ejhf.592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray JJV, Solomon SD, Inzucchi SE, Kober L, Kosiborod MN, Martinez FA, et al. Dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. N Engl J Med 2019;381:1995&#x2010;2008. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1911303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, Pocock SJ, Carson P, et al. Cardiovascular and renal outcomes with empagliflozin in heart failure. N Engl J Med 2020;383:1413&#x2010;1424. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2022190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald M, Virani S, Chan M, Ducharme A, Ezekowitz JA, Giannetti N, et al. CCS/CHFS heart failure guidelines update: Defining a new pharmacologic standard of care for heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. Can J Cardiol 2021;37:531&#x2010;546. doi:10.1016/j.cjca.2021.01.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Authors/Task Force Members, McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, Gardner RS, Baumbach A, et al. 2021 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure: Developed by the Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute and Chronic Heart Failure of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). With the special contribution of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:4&#x2010;131. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2333</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, Allen LA, Byun JJ, Colvin MM, et al. 2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation 2022;145:e895&#x2010;e1032. doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, Ferreira JP, Bocchi E, Bohm M, et al. Empagliflozin in heart failure with a preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med 2021;385:1451&#x2010;1461. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2107038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, McMurray JJV, Claggett B, de Boer RA, DeMets D, Hernandez AF, et al. Dapagliflozin in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med 2022;387:1089&#x2010;1098. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2206286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, Gardner RS, Baumbach A, Bohm M, et al. 2023 focused update of the 2021 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure: Developed by the Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute and Chronic Heart Failure of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) with the special contribution of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J 2023;44:3627&#x2010;3639. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad195</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkovic V, Jardine MJ, Neal B, Bompoint S, Heerspink HJL, Charytan DM, et al. Canagliflozin and renal outcomes in type 2 diabetes and nephropathy. N Engl J Med 2019;380:2295&#x2010;2306. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1811744</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heerspink HJL, Stefansson BV, Correa&#x2010;Rotter R, Chertow GM, Greene T, Hou FF, et al. Dapagliflozin in patients with chronic kidney disease. N Engl J Med 2020;383:1436&#x2010;1446. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2024816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt DL, Szarek M, Pitt B, Cannon CP, Leiter LA, McGuire DK, et al. Sotagliflozin in patients with diabetes and chronic kidney disease. N Engl J Med 2021;384:129&#x2010;139. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2030186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The EMPA&#x2010;KIDNEY Collaborative Group, Herrington WG, Staplin N, Wanner C, Green JB, Hauske SJ, et al. Empagliflozin in patients with chronic kidney disease. N Engl J Med 2023;388:117&#x2010;127. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2204233</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Nuffield Department of Population Health Renal Studies Group, SGLT2 inhibitor Meta&#x2010;Analysis Cardio&#x2010;Renal Trialists' Consortium. Impact of diabetes on the effects of sodium glucose co&#x2010;transporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors on kidney outcomes: Collaborative meta&#x2010;analysis of large placebo&#x2010;controlled trials. Lancet 2022;400:1788&#x2010;1801. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(22)02074&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrominski JW, Solomon SD, Vaduganathan M. Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction therapy: Combining sodium&#x2010;glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibitors and glucagon&#x2010;like peptide&#x2010;1 receptor agonists. Eur Heart J 2024;45:2748&#x2010;2751. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neal B, Perkovic V, Mahaffey KW, de Zeeuw D, Fulcher G, Erondu N, et al. Canagliflozin and cardiovascular and renal events in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2017;377:644&#x2010;657. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1611925</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiviott SD, Raz I, Bonaca MP, Mosenzon O, Kato ET, Cahn A, et al. Dapagliflozin and cardiovascular outcomes in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2019;380:347&#x2010;357. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1812389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannon CP, Pratley R, Dagogo&#x2010;Jack S, Mancuso J, Huyck S, Masiukiewicz U, et al. Cardiovascular outcomes with ertugliflozin in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2020;383:1425&#x2010;1435. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2004967</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelniker TA, Wiviott SD, Raz I, Im K, Goodrich EL, Bonaca MP, et al. SGLT2 inhibitors for primary and secondary prevention of cardiovascular and renal outcomes in type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of cardiovascular outcome trials. Lancet 2019;393:31&#x2010;39. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(18)32590&#x2010;X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braunwald E. Gliflozins in the management of cardiovascular disease. N Engl J Med 2022;386:2024&#x2010;2034. doi:10.1056/NEJMra2115011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire DK, Shih WJ, Cosentino F, Charbonnel B, Cherney DZI, Dagogo&#x2010;Jack S, et al. Association of SGLT2 inhibitors with cardiovascular and kidney outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes: A meta&#x2010;analysis. JAMA Cardiol 2021;6:148&#x2010;158. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2020.4511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman MS, Siddiqi TJ, Anker SD, Bakris GL, Bhatt DL, Filippatos G, et al. Effect of SGLT2 inhibitors on cardiovascular outcomes across various patient populations. J Am Coll Cardiol 2023;81:2377&#x2010;2387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SM, Kang YM, Im K, Neuen BL, Anker SD, Bhatt DL, et al. Sodium&#x2010;glucose cotransporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors and major adverse cardiovascular outcomes: A SMART&#x2010;C collaborative meta&#x2010;analysis. Circulation 2024;149:1789&#x2010;1801. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnesen K, Heide&#x2010;Jorgensen U, Christensen DH, Lash TL, Hennessy S, Matthews A, et al. Comparative cardiovascular effectiveness of empagliflozin versus dapagliflozin in adults with treated type 2 diabetes: A target trial emulation. Circulation 2024;150:1401&#x2010;1411. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068613</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelniker TA, Morrow DA, Mosenzon O, Goodrich EL, Jarolim P, Murphy SA, et al. Relationship between baseline cardiac biomarkers and cardiovascular death or hospitalization for heart failure with and without sodium&#x2013;glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibitor therapy in DECLARE&#x2010;TIMI 58. Eur J Heart Fail 2021;23:1026&#x2010;1036. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinman B, Wanner C, Lachin JM, Fitchett D, Bluhmki E, Hantel S, et al. Empagliflozin, cardiovascular outcomes, and mortality in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2015;373:2117&#x2010;2128. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1504720</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx N, Federici M, Schutt K, Muller&#x2010;Wieland D, Ajjan RA, Antunes MJ, et al. 2023 ESC guidelines for the management of cardiovascular disease in patients with diabetes: Developed by the Task Force on the Management of Cardiovascular Disease in Patients with Diabetes of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J 2023;44:4043&#x2010;4140. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitt B, Bhatt DL, Metra M. Does SGLT1 inhibition add to the benefits of SGLT2 inhibition in the prevention and treatment of heart failure? Eur Heart J 2022;43:4754&#x2010;4757. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehac417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitt B, Bhatt DL. Does SGLT1 inhibition add benefit to SGLT2 inhibition in type 2 diabetes? Circulation 2021;144:4&#x2010;6. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.054442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kottgen A, Russell SD, Loehr LR, Crainiceanu CM, Rosamond WD, Chang PP, et al. Reduced kidney function as a risk factor for incident heart failure: The Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities (ARIC) study. J Am Soc Nephrol 2007;18:1307&#x2010;1315. doi:10.1681/ASN.2006101159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uijl A, Koudstaal S, Direk K, Denaxas S, Groenwold RHH, Banerjee A, et al. Risk factors for incident heart failure in age&#x2010; and sex&#x2010;specific strata: A population&#x2010;based cohort using linked electronic health records. Eur J Heart Fail 2019;21:1197&#x2010;1206. doi:10.1002/ejhf.1350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray JJV, Wheeler DC, Stefansson BV, Jongs N, Postmus D, Correa&#x2010;Rotter R, et al. Effects of dapagliflozin in patients with kidney disease, with and without heart failure. JACC Heart Fail 2021;9:807&#x2010;820. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2021.06.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarraju A, Bakris G, Cannon CP, Cherney D, Damaraju CV, Figtree GA, et al. Cardiovascular effects of canagliflozin in relation to renal function and albuminuria. J Am Coll Cardiol 2022;80:1721&#x2010;1731. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2022.08.772</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Cannon CP, Jardine MJ, Heerspink HJL, Arnott C, Neuen BL, et al. Effects of canagliflozin on total heart failure events across the kidney function spectrum: Participant&#x2010;level pooled analysis from the CANVAS Program and CREDENCE trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2024;26:1967&#x2010;1975. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3292</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Januzzi JL, Mohebi R, Liu Y, Sattar N, Heerspink HJL, Tefera E, et al. Cardiorenal biomarkers, canagliflozin, and outcomes in diabetic kidney disease: The CREDENCE trial. Circulation 2023;148:651&#x2010;660. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065251</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMPA&#x2010;KIDNEY Collaborative Group, Herrington WG, Staplin N, Agrawal N, Wanner C, Green JB, et al. Long&#x2010;term effects of empagliflozin in patients with chronic kidney disease. N Engl J Med 2025;392:777&#x2010;787. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2409183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Anker SD, Filippatos G, Usman MS, Ferreira JP, Zannad F, et al. Sodium glucose co&#x2010;transporter inhibitors and heart failure outcomes across different patient populations. Eur Heart J 2021;42:4887&#x2010;4890. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehab704</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James S, Erlinge D, Storey RF, McGuire DK, de Belder M, Eriksson N, et al. Dapagliflozin in myocardial infarction without diabetes or heart failure. NEJM Evid 2024;3:EVIDoa2300286. doi:10.1056/EVIDoa2300286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez AF, Udell JA, Jones WS, Anker SD, Petrie MC, Harrington J, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on heart failure outcomes after acute myocardial infarction: Insights from the EMPACT&#x2010;MI trial. Circulation 2024;149:1627&#x2010;1638. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington J, Udell JA, Jones WS, Anker SD, Bhatt DL, Petrie MC, et al. Baseline characteristics of patients enrolled in the EMPACT&#x2010;MI trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1708&#x2010;1715. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Jones WS, Udell JA, Anker SD, Petrie MC, Harrington J, et al. Empagliflozin after acute myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 2024;390:1455&#x2010;1466. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2314051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carberry J, Petrie MC, Lee MMY, Stanley B, Brooksbank KJM, Campbell RT, et al. Empagliflozin to prevent worsening of left ventricular volumes and systolic function after myocardial infarction (EMPRESS&#x2010;MI). Eur J Heart Fail 2024;27:566&#x2010;576. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos GS, Jamal W, Salsali A, Schnee J, et al. Evaluation of the effects of sodium&#x2010;glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibition with empagliflozin on morbidity and mortality in patients with chronic heart failure and a preserved ejection fraction: Rationale for and design of the EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2019;21:1279&#x2010;1287. doi:10.1002/ejhf.1596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Butler J, Zannad F, Filippatos G, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on worsening heart failure events in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction: EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial. Circulation 2021;144:1284&#x2010;1294. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.056824</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker SD, Siddiqi TJ, Filippatos G, Zannad F, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, et al. Outcomes with empagliflozin in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction using DELIVER&#x2010;like endpoint definitions. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:1400&#x2010;1405. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon SD, de Boer RA, DeMets D, Hernandez AF, Inzucchi SE, Kosiborod MN, et al. Dapagliflozin in heart failure with preserved and mildly reduced ejection fraction: Rationale and design of the DELIVER trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2021;23:1217&#x2010;1225. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatur S, Vaduganathan M, Claggett B, Vardeny O, Desai AS, Jhund PS, et al. Dapagliflozin and diuretic utilization in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: The DELIVER trial. Eur Heart J 2023;44:2930&#x2010;2943. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Jhund PS, Docherty KF, Diez M, Petrie MC, Verma S, et al. Effects of dapagliflozin on symptoms, function, and quality of life in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: Results from the DAPA&#x2010;HF trial. Circulation 2020;141:90&#x2010;99. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.044138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Anker SD, Filippatos G, Khan MS, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, et al. Empagliflozin and health&#x2010;related quality of life outcomes in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: The EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced trial. Eur Heart J 2021;42:1203&#x2010;1212. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa1007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Cleland JGF, Bauersachs J. Great Debate: SGLT2 inhibitors should be first&#x2010;line treatment in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. Eur Heart J 2024;45:2186&#x2010;2196. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zannad F, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, et al. SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: A meta&#x2010;analysis of the EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced and DAPA&#x2010;HF trials. Lancet 2020;396:819&#x2010;829. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(20)31824&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt B, Ahmad T, Alexander KM, Baker WL, Bosak K, Breathett K, et al. Heart failure epidemiology and outcomes statistics: A report of the Heart Failure Society of America. J Card Fail 2023;29:1412&#x2010;1451. doi:10.1016/j.cardfail.2023.07.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland JGF. Nature and magnitude of the benefits of dapagliflozin and empagliflozin for heart failure. Circulation 2024;149:839&#x2010;842. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt DL, Szarek M, Steg PG, Cannon CP, Leiter LA, McGuire DK, et al. Sotagliflozin in patients with diabetes and recent worsening heart failure. N Engl J Med 2021;384:117&#x2010;128. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2030183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippatos G, Anker SD, Butler J, Farmakis D, Ferreira JP, Gollop ND, et al. Effects of empagliflozin on cardiovascular and renal outcomes in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction according to age: A secondary analysis of EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:2297&#x2010;2304. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2707</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker SD, Khan MS, Butler J, Ofstad AP, Peil B, Pfarr E, et al. Weight change and clinical outcomes in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: Insights from EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:117&#x2010;127. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2728</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AS, Jhund PS, Claggett BL, Vaduganathan M, Miao ZM, Kondo T, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin on cause&#x2010;specific mortality in patients with heart failure across the spectrum of ejection fraction: A participant&#x2010;level pooled analysis of DAPA&#x2010;HF and DELIVER. JAMA Cardiol 2022;7:1227&#x2010;1234. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2022.3736</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira JP, Zannad F, Butler J, Filippatos G, Pocock S, Iwata T, et al. Recency of heart failure hospitalization, outcomes, and the effect of empagliflozin: An EMPEROR&#x2010;Pooled analysis. JACC Heart Fail 2023;11:702&#x2010;712. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2023.01.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Hegde SM, Pabon M, Kulac IJ, et al. Sex differences in characteristics, outcomes, and treatment response with dapagliflozin across the range of ejection fraction in patients with heart failure: Insights from DAPA&#x2010;HF and DELIVER. Circulation 2023;147:624&#x2010;634. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.062832</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt JH, Kondo T, Yang M, Jhund PS, Docherty KF, Vaduganathan M, et al. Heart failure, peripheral artery disease, and dapagliflozin: A patient&#x2010;level meta&#x2010;analysis of DAPA&#x2010;HF and DELIVER. Eur Heart J 2023;44:2170&#x2010;2183. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhingra NK, Verma S, Butler J, Anker SD, Ferreira JP, Filippatos G, et al. Efficacy and safety of empagliflozin according to background diuretic use in HFrEF: Post&#x2010;hoc analysis of EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced. JACC Heart Fail 2024;12:35&#x2010;46. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2023.06.036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt JH, Lu H, Kondo T, Bachus E, de Boer RA, Inzucchi SE, et al. Heart failure, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: Insights from DELIVER. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:2078&#x2010;2090. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt JH, Docherty KF, Claggett BL, Desai AS, Fang JC, Petersson M, et al. Dapagliflozin in Black and White patients with heart failure across the ejection fraction spectrum. JACC Heart Fail 2023;11:375&#x2010;388. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2022.11.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figtree GA, Radholm K, Barrett TD, Perkovic V, Mahaffey KW, de Zeeuw D, et al. Effects of canagliflozin on heart failure outcomes associated with preserved and reduced ejection fraction in type 2 diabetes mellitus: Results from the CANVAS Program. Circulation 2019;139:2591&#x2010;2593. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.040057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato ET, Silverman MG, Mosenzon O, Zelniker TA, Cahn A, Furtado RHM, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin on heart failure and mortality in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Circulation 2019;139:2528&#x2010;2536. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.040130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham JW, Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Kulac IJ, Desai AS, Jhund PS, et al. Dapagliflozin in patients recently hospitalized with heart failure and mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. J Am Coll Cardiol 2022;80:1302&#x2010;1310. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2022.07.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inzucchi SE, Claggett BL, Vaduganathan M, Desai AS, Jhund PS, de Boer RA, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction by baseline glycaemic status (DELIVER): A subgroup analysis from an international, multicentre, double&#x2010;blind, randomised, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2022;10:869&#x2010;881. doi:10.1016/S2213&#x2010;8587(22)00308&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Jering KS, Borleffs CJW, de Boer RA, Claggett BL, Desai AS, et al. Patient characteristics, outcomes, and effects of dapagliflozin according to the duration of heart failure: A prespecified analysis of the DELIVER trial. Circulation 2023;147:1067&#x2010;1078. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.062918</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Docherty KF, Claggett BL, Jhund PS, de Boer RA, Hernandez AF, et al. SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with heart failure: A comprehensive meta&#x2010;analysis of five randomised controlled trials. Lancet 2022;400:757&#x2010;767. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(22)01429&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardeny O, Fang JC, Desai AS, Jhund PS, Claggett B, Vaduganathan M, et al. Dapagliflozin in heart failure with improved ejection fraction: A prespecified analysis of the DELIVER trial. Nat Med 2022;28:2504&#x2010;2511. doi:10.1038/s41591&#x2010;022&#x2010;02102&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pabon M, Claggett BL, Wang X, Miao ZM, Chatur S, Bhatt AS, et al. Influence of background medical therapy on efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure with improved ejection fraction in the DELIVER trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1663&#x2010;1670. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma S, Dhingra NK, Butler J, Anker SD, Ferreira JP, Filippatos G, et al. Empagliflozin in the treatment of heart failure with reduced ejection fraction in addition to background therapies and therapeutic combinations (EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced): A post&#x2010;hoc analysis of a randomised, double&#x2010;blind trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2022;10:35&#x2010;45. doi:10.1016/S2213&#x2010;8587(21)00292&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Butt JH, Kondo T, Jering KS, Docherty KF, Jhund PS, et al. Dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced and preserved ejection fraction treated with a mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist or sacubitril/valsartan. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:2307&#x2010;2319. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metra M, Tomasoni D, Adamo M, Bayes&#x2010;Genis A, Filippatos G, Abdelhamid M, et al. Worsening of chronic heart failure: Definition, epidemiology, management and prevention. A clinical consensus statement by the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:776&#x2010;791. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2874</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biegus J, Cotter G, Davison BA, Metra M, Pagnesi M, Ponikowski P. Diuretic de&#x2010;escalation in response to HF therapy: Are we closer to reduced reliance on diuretics? JACC Heart Fail 2025;13:846&#x2010;854. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2025.03.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AM, Dewan P, Anand IS, Belohlavek J, Bengtsson O, de Boer RA, et al. Dapagliflozin and diuretic use in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction in DAPA&#x2010;HF. Circulation 2020;142:1040&#x2010;1054. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047077</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Bhatt AS, Claggett BL, Vaduganathan M, Kulac IJ, Lam CSP, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin on health status in patients with preserved or mildly reduced ejection fraction. J Am Coll Cardiol 2023;81:460&#x2010;473. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2022.11.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi TJ, Anker SD, Filippatos G, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, Bohm M, et al. Health status across major subgroups of patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1623&#x2010;1631. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2831</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassif ME, Windsor SL, Gosch K, Borlaug BA, Husain M, Inzucchi SE, et al. Dapagliflozin improves heart failure symptoms and physical limitations across the full range of ejection fraction: Pooled patient&#x2010;level analysis from DEFINE&#x2010;HF and PRESERVED&#x2010;HF trials. Circ Heart Fail 2023;16:e009837. doi:10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.122.009837</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta K, Spertus JA, Birmingham M, Gosch KL, Husain M, Kitzman DW, et al. Racial differences in quality of life in patients with heart failure treated with sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors: A patient&#x2010;level meta&#x2010;analysis of the CHIEF&#x2010;HF, DEFINE&#x2010;HF, and PRESERVED&#x2010;HF trials. Circulation 2023;148:220&#x2010;228. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.063263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Packer M, Filippatos G, Ferreira JP, Zeller C, Schnee J, et al. Effect of empagliflozin in patients with heart failure across the spectrum of left ventricular ejection fraction. Eur Heart J 2022;43:416&#x2010;426. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehab798</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oriecuia C, Tomasoni D, Sala I, Bonfioli GB, Adamo M, Gussago C, et al. Sodium glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibitors and quality of life in patients with heart failure: A comprehensive systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Pharmacother 2024;10:147&#x2010;157. doi:10.1093/ehjcvp/pvad088</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Khan MS, Mori C, Filippatos GS, Ponikowski P, Comin&#x2010;Colet J, et al. Minimal clinically important difference in quality of life scores for patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. Eur J Heart Fail 2020;22:999&#x2010;1005. doi:10.1002/ejhf.1810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Usman MS, Gandotra C, Salman A, Farb A, Thompson AM, et al. Patient&#x2010;reported outcomes as end points in heart failure trials. Circulation 2025;151:1111&#x2010;1125. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metra M, Tomasoni D, Adamo M, Anker SD, Bayes&#x2010;Genis A, von Bardeleben RS, et al. Evidence generation and implementation of transcatheter interventions for atrioventricular valvular heart disease in heart failure: Current status and future directions. Circulation 2025;151:1342&#x2010;1363. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070411</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray JJV, Docherty KF, de Boer RA, Hammarstedt A, Kitzman DW, Kosiborod MN, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin versus placebo on symptoms and 6&#x2010;minute walk distance in patients with heart failure: The DETERMINE randomized clinical trials. Circulation 2024;149:825&#x2010;838. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis GD, Gosch K, Cohen LP, Nassif ME, Windsor SL, Borlaug BA, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin on 6&#x2010;minute walk distance in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: PRESERVED&#x2010;HF. Circ Heart Fail 2023;16:e010633. doi:10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.123.010633</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borlaug BA, Reddy YNV, Braun A, Sorimachi H, Omar M, Popovic D, et al. Cardiac and metabolic effects of dapagliflozin in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: The CAMEO&#x2010;DAPA trial. Circulation 2023;148:834&#x2010;844. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tada A, Burkhoff D, Naser JA, Harada T, Pourmussa B, Reddy YNV, et al. Dapagliflozin enhances arterial and venous compliance during exercise in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: Insights from the CAMEO&#x2010;DAPA trial. Circulation 2024;150:997&#x2010;1009. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068788</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi S, Reddy YNV, Jensen MD, Smith JR, Borlaug BA. Dapagliflozin and ventilatory control during exercise in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: The CAMEO&#x2010;DAPA trial. Eur Heart J 2025;46:1554&#x2010;1556. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omar M, Jensen J, Frederiksen PH, Kistorp C, Videbaek L, Poulsen MK, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on hemodynamics in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. J Am Coll Cardiol 2020;76:2740&#x2010;2751. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2020.10.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassif ME, Qintar M, Windsor SL, Jermyn R, Shavelle DM, Tang F, et al. Empagliflozin effects on pulmonary artery pressure in patients with heart failure: Results from the EMBRACE&#x2010;HF trial. Circulation 2021;143:1673&#x2010;1686. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.052503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Butler J, Zeller C, Pocock SJ, Brueckmann M, Ferreira JP, et al. Blinded withdrawal of long&#x2010;term randomized treatment with empagliflozin or placebo in patients with heart failure. Circulation 2023;148:1011&#x2010;1022. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasoni D, Vitale C, Guidetti F, Benson L, Braunschweig F, Dahlstrom U, et al. The role of multimorbidity in patients with heart failure across the left ventricular ejection fraction spectrum: Data from the Swedish Heart Failure Registry. Eur J Heart Fail 2024;26:854&#x2010;868. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conrad N, Judge A, Tran J, Mohseni H, Hedgecott D, Crespillo AP, et al. Temporal trends and patterns in heart failure incidence: A population&#x2010;based study of 4 million individuals. Lancet 2018;391:572&#x2010;580. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(17)32520&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peikert A, Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Kulac IJ, Litwin S, Zile M, et al. Near&#x2010;universal prevalence of central adiposity in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: The PARAGON&#x2010;HF trial. Eur Heart J 2025;46:2372&#x2010;2390. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamson C, Kondo T, Jhund PS, de Boer RA, Cabrera Honorio JW, Claggett B, et al. Dapagliflozin for heart failure according to body mass index: The DELIVER trial. Eur Heart J 2022;43:4406&#x2010;4417. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehac481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattar N, Butler J, Lee MMY, Harrington J, Sharma A, Zannad F, et al. Body mass index and cardiorenal outcomes in the EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial: Principal findings and meta&#x2010;analysis with the DELIVER trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2024;26:900&#x2010;909. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MJ, Eriksson JW. Emerging role of SGLT&#x2010;2 inhibitors for the treatment of obesity. Drugs 2019;79:219&#x2010;230. doi:10.1007/s40265&#x2010;019&#x2010;1057&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Petrie MC, Borlaug BA, Butler J, Davies MJ, Hovingh GK, et al. Semaglutide in patients with obesity&#x2010;related heart failure and type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2024;390:1394&#x2010;1407. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2313917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Abildstrom SZ, Borlaug BA, Butler J, Rasmussen S, Davies M, et al. Semaglutide in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. N Engl J Med 2023;389:1069&#x2010;1084. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2306963</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Kramer CM, Borlaug BA. Tirzepatide for heart failure and obesity. Reply. N Engl J Med 2025;392:1661&#x2010;1662. doi:10.1056/NEJMc2502743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuen BL, Fletcher RA, Heath L, Perkovic A, Vaduganathan M, Badve SV, et al. Cardiovascular, kidney, and safety outcomes with GLP&#x2010;1 receptor agonists alone and in combination with SGLT2 inhibitors in type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Circulation 2024;150:1781&#x2010;1790. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kario K, Ferdinand KC, Vongpatanasin W. Are SGLT2 inhibitors new hypertension drugs? Circulation 2021;143:1750&#x2010;1753. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.053709</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye N, Jardine MJ, Oshima M, Hockham C, Heerspink HJL, Agarwal R, et al. Blood pressure effects of canagliflozin and clinical outcomes in type 2 diabetes and chronic kidney disease: Insights from the CREDENCE trial. Circulation 2021;143:1735&#x2010;1749. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.048740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrominski JW, Vaduganathan M, Selvaraj S, Claggett BL, Miao ZM, Desai AS, et al. Dapagliflozin and apparent treatment&#x2010;resistant hypertension in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: The DELIVER trial. Circulation 2023;148:1945&#x2010;1957. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065254</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm M, Butler J, Coats A, Lauder L, Mahfoud F, Filippatos G, et al. Empagliflozin in resistant hypertension and heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: The EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial. Eur Heart J 2025;46:1304&#x2010;1317. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serenelli M, Bohm M, Inzucchi SE, Kober L, Kosiborod MN, Martinez FA, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin according to baseline systolic blood pressure in the Dapagliflozin and Prevention of Adverse Outcomes in Heart Failure trial (DAPA&#x2010;HF). Eur Heart J 2020;41:3402&#x2010;3418. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm M, Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, et al. Empagliflozin improves cardiovascular and renal outcomes in heart failure irrespective of systolic blood pressure. J Am Coll Cardiol 2021;78:1337&#x2010;1348. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2021.07.049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraj S, Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Miao ZM, Fang JC, Vardeny O, et al. Blood pressure and dapagliflozin in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: DELIVER. JACC Heart Fail 2023;11:76&#x2010;89. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2022.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhm M, Anker S, Mahfoud F, Lauder L, Filippatos G, Ferreira JP, et al. Empagliflozin, irrespective of blood pressure, improves outcomes in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: The EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial. Eur Heart J 2023;44:396&#x2010;407. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehac693</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosano GMC, Moura B, Metra M, Bohm M, Bauersachs J, Ben Gal T, et al. Patient profiling in heart failure for tailoring medical therapy. A consensus document of the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology. Eur J Heart Fail 2021;23:872&#x2010;881. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasoni D, Fonarow GC, Adamo M, Anker SD, Butler J, Coats AJS, et al. Sodium&#x2013;glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibitors as an early, first&#x2010;line therapy in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:431&#x2010;441. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skouri H, Girerd N, Monzo L, Petrie MC, Bohm M, Adamo M, et al. Clinical management and therapeutic optimization of patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction and low blood pressure. A clinical consensus statement of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur J Heart Fail 2025;27:707&#x2010;722. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Ferreira JP, Zannad F, Pocock SJ, Filippatos G, Pfarr E, et al. Cardiac and kidney benefits of empagliflozin in heart failure across the spectrum of kidney function: Insights from the EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1337&#x2010;1348. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2857</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Causland FR, Claggett BL, Vaduganathan M, Desai AS, Jhund P, de Boer RA, et al. Dapagliflozin and kidney outcomes in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: A prespecified analysis of the DELIVER randomized clinical trial. JAMA Cardiol 2023;8:56&#x2010;65. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2022.4210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zannad F, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, Zeller C, Anker SD, Butler J, et al. Cardiac and kidney benefits of empagliflozin in heart failure across the spectrum of kidney function: Insights from EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced. Circulation 2021;143:310&#x2010;321. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.051685</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhund PS, Solomon SD, Docherty KF, Heerspink HJL, Anand IS, Bohm M, et al. Efficacy of dapagliflozin on renal function and outcomes in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: Results of DAPA&#x2010;HF. Circulation 2021;143:298&#x2010;309. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.050391</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler J, Packer M, Siddiqi TJ, Bohm M, Brueckmann M, Januzzi JL, et al. Efficacy of empagliflozin in patients with heart failure across kidney risk categories. J Am Coll Cardiol 2023;81:1902&#x2010;1914. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.03.390</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee M, Maisnam I, Pal R, Mukhopadhyay S. Mineralocorticoid receptor antagonists with sodium&#x2013;glucose co&#x2010;transporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors in heart failure: A meta&#x2010;analysis. Eur Heart J 2023;44:3686&#x2010;3696. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad522</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira JP, Zannad F, Pocock SJ, Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G, et al. Interplay of mineralocorticoid receptor antagonists and empagliflozin in heart failure: EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced. J Am Coll Cardiol 2021;77:1397&#x2010;1407. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2021.01.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zannad F, Ferreira JP, Gregson J, Kraus BJ, Mattheus M, Hauske SJ, et al. Early changes in estimated glomerular filtration rate post&#x2010;initiation of empagliflozin in EMPEROR&#x2010;Reduced. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:1829&#x2010;1839. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2578</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamson C, Docherty KF, Heerspink HJL, de Boer RA, Damman K, Inzucchi SE, et al. Initial decline (dip) in estimated glomerular filtration rate after initiation of dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: Insights from DAPA&#x2010;HF. Circulation 2022;146:438&#x2010;449. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.058910</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatur S, Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Mc Causland FR, Desai AS, Jhund PS, et al. Dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure and deterioration in renal function. J Am Coll Cardiol 2023;82:1854&#x2010;1863. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.08.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm M, Butler J, Krawczyk M, Mahfoud F, Haring B, Filippatos G, et al. Liver tests, cardiovascular outcomes and effects of empagliflozin in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction: The EMPEROR&#x2010;Preserved trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1375&#x2010;1383. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2922</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty KF, Jhund PS, Bengtsson O, DeMets DL, Inzucchi SE, Kober L, et al. Effect of dapagliflozin in DAPA&#x2010;HF according to background glucose&#x2010;lowering therapy. Diabetes Care 2020;43:2878&#x2010;2881. doi:10.2337/dc20&#x2010;1402</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao VN, Murray E, Butler J, Cooper LB, Cox ZL, Fiuzat M, et al. In&#x2010;hospital initiation of sodium&#x2010;glucose cotransporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors for heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. J Am Coll Cardiol 2021;78:2004&#x2010;2012. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2021.08.064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metra M, Adamo M, Tomasoni D, Mebazaa A, Bayes&#x2010;Genis A, Abdelhamid M, et al. Pre&#x2010;discharge and early post&#x2010;discharge management of patients hospitalized for acute heart failure: A scientific statement by the Heart Failure Association of the ESC. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1115&#x2010;1131. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2888</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatur S, Cunningham JW, Vaduganathan M, Mc Causland FR, Claggett BL, Desai AS, et al. Renal and blood pressure effects of dapagliflozin in recently hospitalized patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: Insights from the DELIVER trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1170&#x2010;1175. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitt B, Bhatt DL, Szarek M, Cannon CP, Leiter LA, McGuire DK, et al. Effect of sotagliflozin on early mortality and heart failure&#x2010;related events: A post hoc analysis of SOLOIST&#x2010;WHF. JACC Heart Fail 2023;11:879&#x2010;889. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2023.05.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voors AA, Angermann CE, Teerlink JR, Collins SP, Kosiborod M, Biegus J, et al. The SGLT2 inhibitor empagliflozin in patients hospitalized for acute heart failure: A multinational randomized trial. Nat Med 2022;28:568&#x2010;574. doi:10.1038/s41591&#x2010;021&#x2010;01659&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Angermann CE, Collins SP, Teerlink JR, Ponikowski P, Biegus J, et al. Effects of empagliflozin on symptoms, physical limitations, and quality of life in patients hospitalized for acute heart failure: Results from the EMPULSE trial. Circulation 2022;146:279&#x2010;288. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.059725</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damman K, Beusekamp JC, Boorsma EM, Swart HP, Smilde TDJ, Elvan A, et al. Randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled, multicentre pilot study on the effects of empagliflozin on clinical outcomes in patients with acute decompensated heart failure (EMPA&#x2010;RESPONSE&#x2010;AHF). Eur J Heart Fail 2020;22:713&#x2010;722. doi:10.1002/ejhf.1713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Butler J. Similarities and distinctions between acetazolamide and sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in patients with acute heart failure: Key insights into ADVOR and EMPULSE. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1537&#x2010;1543. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze PC, Bogoviku J, Westphal J, Aftanski P, Haertel F, Grund S, et al. Effects of early empagliflozin initiation on diuresis and kidney function in patients with acute decompensated heart failure (EMPAG&#x2010;HF). Circulation 2022;146:289&#x2010;298. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.059038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biegus J, Voors AA, Collins SP, Kosiborod MN, Teerlink JR, Angermann CE, et al. Impact of empagliflozin on decongestion in acute heart failure: The EMPULSE trial. Eur Heart J 2023;44:41&#x2010;50. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehac530</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biegus J, Fudim M, Salah HM, Heerspink HJL, Voors AA, Ponikowski P. Sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors in heart failure: Potential decongestive mechanisms and current clinical studies. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1526&#x2010;1536. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2967</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin M, Rao VS, Ivey&#x2010;Miranda J, Fleming J, Mahoney D, Maulion C, et al. Empagliflozin in heart failure: Diuretic and cardiorenal effects. Circulation 2020;142:1028&#x2010;1039. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.045691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marton A, Saffari SE, Rauh M, Sun RN, Nagel AM, Linz P, et al. Water conservation overrides osmotic diuresis during SGLT2 inhibition in patients with heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024;83:1386&#x2010;1398. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Wilcox CS, Testani JM. Critical analysis of the effects of SGLT2 inhibitors on renal tubular sodium, water and chloride homeostasis and their role in influencing heart failure outcomes. Circulation 2023;148:354&#x2010;372. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.064346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs Andersen C, Omar M, Glenthoj A, El Fassi D, Moller HJ, Lindholm Kurtzhals JA, et al. Effects of empagliflozin on erythropoiesis in heart failure: Data from the Empire HF trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:226&#x2010;234. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2735</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox ZL, Collins SP, Hernandez GA, McRae AT 3rd, Davidson BT, Adams K, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with acute heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024;83:1295&#x2010;1306. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deniau B, Costanzo MR, Sliwa K, Asakage A, Mullens W, Mebazaa A. Acute heart failure: Current pharmacological treatment and perspectives. Eur Heart J 2023;44:4634&#x2010;4649. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad617</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeoh SE, Osmanska J, Petrie MC, Brooksbank KJM, Clark AL, Docherty KF, et al. Dapagliflozin vs. metolazone in heart failure resistant to loop diuretics. Eur Heart J 2023;44:2966&#x2010;2977. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CY, Shah BR, Sharma A, Sheng Y, Liu PP, Kopp A, et al. Timing of sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor initiation and post&#x2010;discharge outcomes in acute heart failure with diabetes: A population&#x2010;based cohort study. Eur J Heart Fail 2025;27:307&#x2010;316. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3464</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki S, Yamada T, Watanabe T, Morita T, Furukawa Y, Kawasaki M, et al. Effect of empagliflozin as an add&#x2010;on therapy on decongestion and renal function in patients with diabetes hospitalized for acute decompensated heart failure: A prospective randomized controlled study. Circ Heart Fail 2021;14:e007048. doi:10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.120.007048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi Y, Matsue Y, Nogi K, Onitsuka K, Okumura T, Hoshino M, et al. Early treatment with a sodium&#x2010;glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibitor in high&#x2010;risk patients with acute heart failure: Rationale for and design of the EMPA&#x2010;AHF trial. Am Heart J 2023;257:85&#x2010;92. doi:10.1016/j.ahj.2022.12.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amat&#x2010;Santos IJ, Sanchez&#x2010;Luna JP, Abu&#x2010;Assi E, Melendo&#x2010;Viu M, Cruz&#x2010;Gonzalez I, Nombela&#x2010;Franco L, et al. Rationale and design of the Dapagliflozin after Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation (DapaTAVI) randomized trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2022;24:581&#x2010;588. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2370</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raposeiras&#x2010;Roubin S, Amat&#x2010;Santos IJ, Rossello X, Gonzalez Ferreiro R, Gonzalez Bermudez I, Lopez Otero D, et al. Dapagliflozin in patients undergoing transcatheter aortic&#x2010;valve implantation. N Engl J Med 2025;392:1396&#x2010;1405. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2500366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porcari A, Cappelli F, Nitsche C, Tomasoni D, Sinigiani G, Longhi S, et al. SGLT2 inhibitor therapy in patients with transthyretin amyloid cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024;83:2411&#x2010;2422. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.03.429</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang FM, Teruya S, Weinsaft A, Cuomo M, Santos AM, Nalbandian A, et al. Sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors for transthyretin amyloid cardiomyopathy: Analyses of short&#x2010;term efficacy and safety. Eur J Heart Fail 2024;26:938&#x2010;947. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newland DM, Law YM, Albers EL, Friedland&#x2010;Little JM, Ahmed H, Kemna MS, et al. Early clinical experience with dapagliflozin in children with heart failure. Pediatr Cardiol 2023;44:146&#x2010;152. doi:10.1007/s00246&#x2010;022&#x2010;02983&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neijenhuis RML, Nederend M, Jongbloed MRM, Kies P, Rotmans JI, Vliegen HW, et al. The potential of sodium&#x2010;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors for the treatment of systemic right ventricular failure in adults with congenital heart disease. Front Cardiovasc Med 2023;10:1093201. doi:10.3389/fcvm.2023.1093201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowie MR, Fisher M. SGLT2 inhibitors: Mechanisms of cardiovascular benefit beyond glycaemic control. Nat Rev Cardiol 2020;17:761&#x2010;772. doi:10.1038/s41569&#x2010;020&#x2010;0406&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis. Circulation 2022;146:1383&#x2010;1405. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.061732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega&#x2010;Paz L, Cristobal H, Ortiz&#x2010;Perez JT, Garcia de Frutos P, Mendieta G, Sandoval E, et al. Direct actions of dapagliflozin and interactions with LCZ696 and spironolactone on cardiac fibroblasts of patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. ESC Heart Fail 2023;10:453&#x2010;464. doi:10.1002/ehf2.14186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M. SGLT2 inhibitors: Role in protective reprogramming of cardiac nutrient transport and metabolism. Nat Rev Cardiol 2023;20:443&#x2010;462. doi:10.1038/s41569&#x2010;022&#x2010;00824&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsurada K, Nandi SS, Sharma NM, Patel KP. Enhanced expression and function of renal SGLT2 (sodium&#x2010;glucose cotransporter 2) in heart failure: Role of renal nerves. Circ Heart Fail 2021;14:e008365. doi:10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.121.008365</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual&#x2010;Figal DA, Zamorano JL, Domingo M, Morillas H, Nunez J, Cobo Marcos M, et al. Impact of dapagliflozin on cardiac remodelling in patients with chronic heart failure: The DAPA&#x2010;MODA study. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1352&#x2010;1360. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omar M, Jensen J, Ali M, Frederiksen PH, Kistorp C, Videbaek L, et al. Associations of empagliflozin with left ventricular volumes, mass, and function in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: A substudy of the Empire HF randomized clinical trial. JAMA Cardiol 2021;6:836&#x2010;840. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2020.6827</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogoviku J, Nguyen TD, Westphal JG, Aftanski P, Moebius&#x2010;Winkler S, Haertel F, et al. Acute effects of empagliflozin on left atrial and ventricular filling parameters using echocardiography&#x2014;A subanalysis of the EMPAG&#x2010;HF trial. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Pharmacother 2025;11:190&#x2010;197. doi:10.1093/ehjcvp/pvaf003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MMY, Brooksbank KJM, Wetherall K, Mangion K, Roditi G, Campbell RT, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on left ventricular volumes in patients with type 2 diabetes, or prediabetes, and heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (SUGAR&#x2010;DM&#x2010;HF). Circulation 2021;143:516&#x2010;525. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.052186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos&#x2010;Gallego CG, Vargas&#x2010;Delgado AP, Requena&#x2010;Ibanez JA, Garcia&#x2010;Ropero A, Mancini D, Pinney S, et al. Randomized trial of empagliflozin in nondiabetic patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. J Am Coll Cardiol 2021;77:243&#x2010;255. doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2020.11.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connelly KA, Mazer CD, Puar P, Teoh H, Wang CH, Mason T, et al. Empagliflozin and left ventricular remodeling in people without diabetes: Primary results of the EMPA&#x2010;HEART 2 CardioLink&#x2010;7 randomized clinical trial. Circulation 2023;147:284&#x2010;295. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.062769</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman MS, Januzzi JL, Anker SD, Salman A, Parikh PB, Adamo M, et al. The effect of sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors on left cardiac remodelling in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: Systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Eur J Heart Fail 2024;26:373&#x2010;382. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zannad F, Ferreira JP, Butler J, Filippatos G, Januzzi JL, Sumin M, et al. Effect of empagliflozin on circulating proteomics in heart failure: Mechanistic insights into the EMPEROR programme. Eur Heart J 2022;43:4991&#x2010;5002. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehac495</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty KF, Welsh P, Verma S, De Boer RA, O'Meara E, Bengtsson O, et al. Iron deficiency in heart failure and effect of dapagliflozin: Findings from DAPA&#x2010;HF. Circulation 2022;146:980&#x2010;994. doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.060511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hundertmark MJ, Adler A, Antoniades C, Coleman R, Griffin JL, Holman RR, et al. Assessment of cardiac energy metabolism, function, and physiology in patients with heart failure taking empagliflozin: The randomized, controlled EMPA&#x2010;VISION trial. Circulation 2023;147:1654&#x2010;1669. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.062021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M. Autophagy stimulation and intracellular sodium reduction as mediators of the cardioprotective effect of sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors. Eur J Heart Fail 2020;22:618&#x2010;628. doi:10.1002/ejhf.1732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan M, Claggett BL, Jhund P, de Boer RA, Hernandez AF, Inzucchi SE, et al. Time to clinical benefit of dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction: A prespecified secondary analysis of the DELIVER randomized clinical trial. JAMA Cardiol 2022;7:1259&#x2010;1263. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2022.3750</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tromp J, Ponikowski P, Salsali A, Angermann CE, Biegus J, Blatchford J, et al. Sodium&#x2013;glucose co&#x2010;transporter 2 inhibition in patients hospitalized for acute decompensated heart failure: Rationale for and design of the EMPULSE trial. Eur J Heart Fail 2021;23:826&#x2010;834. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhund PS, Kondo T, Butt JH, Docherty KF, Claggett BL, Desai AS, et al. Dapagliflozin across the range of ejection fraction in patients with heart failure: A patient&#x2010;level, pooled meta&#x2010;analysis of DAPA&#x2010;HF and DELIVER. Nat Med 2022;28:1956&#x2010;1964. doi:10.1038/s41591&#x2010;022&#x2010;01971&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland JGF. Home&#x2010;time is good, but feeling well is better. Patient&#x2010;journey and quality home&#x2010;time as end points in heart failure trials and registries. Circ Heart Fail 2024;17:e012263. doi:10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.124.012263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada T, Shojima N, Noma H, Yamauchi T, Kadowaki T. Sodium&#x2010;glucose co&#x2010;transporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors as add&#x2010;on therapy to insulin for type 1 diabetes mellitus: Systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Obes Metab 2018;20:1755&#x2010;1761. doi:10.1111/dom.13260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattah H, Vallon V. The potential role of SGLT2 inhibitors in the treatment of type 1 diabetes mellitus. Drugs 2018;78:717&#x2010;726. doi:10.1007/s40265&#x2010;018&#x2010;0901&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorvaldsen T, Ferrannini G, Mellbin L, Benson L, Cosentino F, McMurray JJV, et al. Eligibility for dapagliflozin and empagliflozin in a real&#x2010;world heart failure population. J Card Fail 2022;28:1050&#x2010;1062. doi:10.1016/j.cardfail.2022.04.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talha KM, Butler J, Greene SJ, Aggarwal R, Anker SD, Claggett BL, et al. Potential global impact of sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors in heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:999&#x2010;1009. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2864</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talha KM, Butler J, Greene SJ, Aggarwal R, Anker SD, Claggett BL, et al. Population&#x2010;level implications of sodium&#x2010;glucose cotransporter&#x2010;2 inhibitors for heart failure with preserved ejection fraction in the US. JAMA Cardiol 2023;8:66&#x2010;73. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2022.4348</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savarese G, Kishi T, Vardeny O, Adamsson Eryd S, Bodegard J, Lund LH, et al. Heart failure drug treatment&#x2014;Inertia, titration, and discontinuation: A multinational observational study (EVOLUTION HF). JACC Heart Fail 2023;11:1&#x2010;14. doi:10.1016/j.jchf.2022.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolfo D, Lund LH, Benson L, Lindberg F, Ferrannini G, Dahlstrom U, et al. Real&#x2010;world use of sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: Data from the Swedish Heart Failure Registry. Eur J Heart Fail 2023;25:1648&#x2010;1658. doi:10.1002/ejhf.2971</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savarese G, Lindberg F, Cannata A, Chioncel O, Stolfo D, Musella F, et al. How to tackle therapeutic inertia in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. A scientific statement of the Heart Failure Association of the ESC. Eur J Heart Fail 2024;26:1278&#x2010;1297. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3295</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidetti F, Giraldo CIS, Shchendrygina A, Kida K, Niederseer D, Basic C, et al. Differences in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction management between care providers: An international survey. Eur J Heart Fail 2025;27:198&#x2010;208. doi:10.1002/ejhf.3416</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>