<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40909368</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2766-4651</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of healthy eating and active living</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Healthy Eat Act Living</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The PARCS Pilot Study Randomized Controlled Trial: Feasibility and Acceptability of a Park-Based Exercise Program Led by Peer Specialists for Peers with Serious Mental Illness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>146</StartPage><EndPage>160</EndPage><MedlinePgn>146-160</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Adults with serious mental illness (SMI) die decades early, mostly from heart disease. Few park-based exercise interventions have been tested, none focused on SMI. The study (NCT05293587) tested a 6-week exercise intervention (INT; 45 min park-based exercise led by a certified peer specialist (CPS) 3 days/week) vs. waitlist control (WAIT), as part of an existing peer support program for adults with SMI in Georgia. Eighteen peers (44&#xb1;15 yrs, 28% female, 72% Black, 17% Hispanic, 33% with diabetes) were randomized (6 INT, 12 WAIT). One CPS was trained to lead exercise sessions, supported by a certified fitness instructor at each session. 10 sessions were conducted in each cohort, up to 2 per week. Transportation was provided as part of peer services. INT peers attended 69&#xb1;22% of sessions. INT peers attended 100% of sessions when they were present at the peer support program, except for one peer on 2 occasions (improper footwear, medication side effect). Peers were highly satisfied with the park sessions and highly motivated to participate. The CPS who led the sessions expressed satisfaction. While not significant, compared to baseline, INT peers had slightly improved fitness, hemodynamics, and depression symptoms, and social support for exercise at post. The park-based CPS-led exercise program for peers with SMI seems acceptable and relatively feasible. Further work will replicate these pilot findings, assess health outcomes and optimize feasibility and scalability to existing mental health services.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; JHEAL, 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Catherine L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2942-8233</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bell</LastName><ForeName>Heather</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Serenity Behavioral Health System, Augusta, Georgia, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrews</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Kansas State University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stewart</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Seixas Soares</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiser</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rico Martinez</LastName><ForeName>Esmeralda J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Kansas State University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frazier</LastName><ForeName>Brittany</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Prevention Institute, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McEvoy</LastName><ForeName>Joseph P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatry and Health Behavior, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Besenyi</LastName><ForeName>Gina M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4538-9510</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Kansas State University, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Healthy Eat Act Living</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918300979906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2766-4651</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Black/African American</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feasibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">park</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serious mental illness</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40909368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12408091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jheal-5-2-146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alegr&#xed;a M, Wong Y, Mulvaney-Day N, Nillni A, Proctor E, Nickel M, Jones L, Green B, Koegel P, Wright A. Community-based partnered research: new directions in mental health services research. Ethnicity and Disease. 2011;21(3 0 1):S1..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3653438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22352075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association. The Burden of Diabetes in Georgia (State Diabetes Fact Sheets) 2024.  
 https://diabetes.org/sites/default/files/2024-03/adv_2024_state_fact_georgia.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschbrenner KA, Naslund JA, Shevenell M, Kinney E, Bartels SJ. A Pilot Study of a Peer-Group Lifestyle Intervention Enhanced With mHealth Technology and Social Media for Adults With Serious Mental Illness. The journal of nervous and mental disease. 2016;204(6):483&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4887192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27233056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschbrenner KA, Naslund JA, Shevenell M, Mueser KT, Bartels SJ. Feasibility of Behavioral Weight Loss Treatment Enhanced with Peer Support and Mobile Health Technology for Individuals with Serious Mental Illness. Psychiatr Q. 2016;87(3):401&#x2013;415. doi: 10.1007/s11126-015-9395-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11126-015-9395-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4929042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26462674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahorik AL, Satre DD, Kline-Simon AH, Weisner CM, Campbell CI. Serious mental illness and medical comorbidities: Findings from an integrated health care system. Journal of Psychosomatic Research. 2017;100:35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28789791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social foundations of thought and action: A social cognitive theory. Prentice-Hall, Inc; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Health promotion by social cognitive means. Health Educ Behav. 2004;31(2):143&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1177/1090198104263660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1090198104263660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15090118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Guide for constructing self-efficacy scales. In: Pajares F, Urdan T, editors. Self-efficacy beliefs of adolescents. 5. Information Age Publishing; 2006. pp. 307&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedimo-Rung AL, Mowen AJ, Cohen DA. The significance of parks to physical activity and public health: A conceptual model. American Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2005;28(2 Suppl 2):159&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2004.10.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2004.10.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15694524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besenyi GM, Bramwell RC, Heinrich KM, Mailey EL, McEvoy JP, Davis CL. A qualitative exploration of park-based physical activity in adults with serious mental illness: Insights from peers and peer counselors. Mental Health and Physical Activity. 2022;23:100466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besenyi GM, Fair M, Hughey SM, Kaczynski AT, Powers A, Dunlap E. LGPH Team. Park Hop: Pilot Evaluation of an Inter-Agency Collaboration to Promote Park Awareness, Visitation, and Physical Activity in Greenville County, SC. Journal of Park and Recreation Administration. 2015;33(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besenyi GM, Kaczynski AT, Stanis SAW, Bergstrom RD, Lightner JS, Hipp JA. Planning for health: A community-based spatial analysis of park availability and chronic disease across the lifespan. Health &amp; place. 2014;27:102&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24594836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird VJ, Le Boutillier C, Leamy M, Williams J, Bradstreet S, Slade M. Evaluating the feasibility of complex interventions in mental health services: standardised measure and reporting guidelines. The British Journal of Psychiatry. 2014;204(4):316&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24311549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Behavioral Health Statistics and Quality. Behavioral health trends in the United States: Results from the 2014 National Survey on Drug Use and Health. 2015.  Retrieved 6/23/2025 from  https://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/NSDUH-FRR1-2014/NSDUH-FRR1-2014.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CK, Hayes RD, Perera G, Broadbent MT, Fernandes AC, Lee WE, Hotopf M, Stewart R. Life expectancy at birth for people with serious mental illness and other major disorders from a secondary mental health care case register in London. PLoS One. 2011;6(5):e19590. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0019590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0019590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21611123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman S, Spetz J, Blash L, Chan K, Kogle V. Case Study of Peer Providers in the Behavioral Health Workforce: Georgia. San Francisco, CA:: UCSF Health Workforce Research Center on Long-Term Care alth Workforce Research Center on Long-Term Care; 2015.  Retrieved 6/23/2025 from  https://healthworkforce.ucsf.edu/sites/healthworkforce.ucsf.edu/files/Case_Study_of_Peer_Providers_in_the_Behavioral_Health_Workforce_Georgia_0.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen DA, Han B, Derose KP, Williamson S, Marsh T, McKenzie TL. Physical activity in parks: A randomized controlled trial using community engagement. American Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2013;45(5):590&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4091686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24139772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd ed. Erlbaum; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Colton CW, Manderscheid RW.

Congruencies in increased mortality rates, years of potential life lost, and causes of death among public mental health clients in eight states. 






Prev Chronic Dis. 2006;3(2):A42. 
 https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16539783
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1563985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16539783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sjostrom M, Bauman AE, Booth ML, Ainsworth BE, Pratt M, Ekelund U, Yngve A, Sallis JF, Oja P. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(8):1381&#x2013;1395. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000078924.61453.FB.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000078924.61453.FB</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham GB. Development of the Physical Activity Class Satisfaction Questionnaire (PACSQ) Measurement in Physical Education and Exercise Science. 2007;11(3):161&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1080/10913670701326443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10913670701326443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das-Munshi J, Ashworth M, Dewey ME, Gaughran F, Hull S, Morgan C, Nazroo J, Petersen I, Schofield P, Stewart R, Thornicroft G, Prince MJ. Type 2 diabetes mellitus in people with severe mental illness: inequalities by ethnicity and age. Cross-sectional analysis of 588:408 records from the UK. Diabet Med. 2017;34(7):916&#x2013;924. doi: 10.1111/dme.13298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.13298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5484374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27973692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Hert M, Detraux J, Van Winkel R, Yu W, Correll CU. Metabolic and cardiovascular adverse effects associated with antipsychotic drugs. Nature Reviews Endocrinology. 2012;8(2):114&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22009159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Druss BG, Singh M, von Esenwein SA, Glick GE, Tapscott S, Tucker SJ, Lally CA, Sterling EW. Peer-Led Self-Management of General Medical Conditions for Patients With Serious Mental Illnesses: A Randomized Trial. Psychiatr Serv. 2018;69(5):529&#x2013;535. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.201700352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.201700352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Druss BG, Zhao L, Silke A, Bona JR, Fricks L, Jenkins-Tucker S, Sterling E, DiClemente R, Lorig K. The Health and Recovery Peer (HARP) Program: a peer-led intervention to improve medical self-management for persons with serious mental illness. Schizophrenia Research. 2010;118(1):264&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20185272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Druss BG, Zhao L, Von Esenwein S, Morrato EH, Marcus SC. Understanding excess mortality in persons with mental illness: 17-year follow up of a nationally representative US survey. Medical care. 2011;49(6):599&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21577183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firth J, Cotter J, Elliott R, French P, Yung A. A systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise interventions in schizophrenia patients. Psychological medicine. 2015;45(07):1343&#x2013;1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25650668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firth J, Cotter J, Elliott R, French P, Yung AR. A systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise interventions in schizophrenia patients. Psychol Med. 2015;45(7):1343&#x2013;1361. doi: 10.1017/S0033291714003110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291714003110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25650668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goff DC, Sullivan LM, McEvoy JP, Meyer JM, Nasrallah HA, Daumit GL, Lamberti S, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Stroup TS, Davis S. A comparison of ten-year cardiac risk estimates in schizophrenia patients from the CATIE study and matched controls. Schizophrenia Research. 2005;80(1):45&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16198088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goff DC, Sullivan LM, McEvoy JP, Meyer JM, Nasrallah HA, Daumit GL, Lamberti S, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Stroup TS, Davis S, Lieberman JA. A comparison of ten-year cardiac risk estimates in schizophrenia patients from the CATIE study and matched controls. Schizophr Res. 2005;80(1):45&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2005.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2005.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16198088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman ML, Pincus HA, Mangurian C. Schizophrenia. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(6):583&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc1915943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc1915943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32023392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman ML, Spaeth-Rublee B, Pincus HA. The Case for Severe Mental Illness as a Disparities Category. Psychiatr Serv. 2018;69(6):726&#x2013;728. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.201700138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.201700138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5984130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29446331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heath GW, Parra DC, Sarmiento OL, Andersen LB, Owen N, Goenka S, Montes F, Brownson RC. Group LPASW. Evidence-based intervention in physical activity: lessons from around the world. The lancet. 2012;380(9838):272&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4978123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaczynski AT, Henderson K. Environmental correlates of physical activity: A review of evidence about parks and recreation. Leisure sciences. 2007;29(Journal Article):315&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1080/01490400701394865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01490400701394865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel AA, Ford PB, Kaczynski AT. Disparities in park availability, features, and characteristics by social determinants of health within a US&#x2013;Mexico border urban area. Preventive Medicine. 2014;69:S111&#x2013;S113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25451326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman L, Kuhn W, Stevens Manser S. Peer Specialist Training and Certification Programs: A National Overview. University of Texas at Austin; 2016.  
 http://sites.utexas.edu/mental-health-institute/files/2017/01/Peer-Specialist-Training-and-Certification-Programs-A-National-Overview-2016-Update-1.5.17.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Strine TW, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, Berry JT, Mokdad AH. The PHQ-8 as a measure of current depression in the general population. J Affect Disord. 2009;114(1&#x2013;3):163&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2008.06.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2008.06.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18752852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee PH, Macfarlane DJ, Lam TH, Stewart SM. Validity of the International Physical Activity Questionnaire Short Form (IPAQ-SF): a systematic review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2011;8:115. doi: 10.1186/1479-5868-8-115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5868-8-115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3214824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22018588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas J, van Dillen SM, Verheij RA, Groenewegen PP. Social contacts as a possible mechanism behind the relation between green space and health. Health &amp; place. 2009;15(2):586&#x2013;595. doi: 10.1016/j.healthplace.2008.09.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthplace.2008.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19022699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas J, Verheij RA, de Vries S, Spreeuwenberg P, Schellevis FG, Groenewegen PP. Morbidity is related to a green living environment. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health. 2009;63(12):967&#x2013;973. doi: 10.1136/jech.2008.079038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech.2008.079038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangurian C, Newcomer JW, Modlin C, Schillinger D. Diabetes and Cardiovascular Care Among People with Severe Mental Illness: A Literature Review. Journal of general internal medicine. 2016;31(9):1083&#x2013;1091. doi: 10.1007/s11606-016-3712-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-016-3712-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4978675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27149967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangurian CV, Schillinger D, Newcomer JW, Vittinghoff E, Essock SM, Zhu Z, Dyer WT, Schmittdiel JA. Diabetes and Prediabetes Prevalence by Race and Ethnicity Among People With Severe Mental Illness. Diabetes Care. 2018;41(7):e119&#x2013;e120. doi: 10.2337/dc18-0425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc18-0425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6014538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29898903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEvoy JP, Meyer JM, Goff DC, Nasrallah HA, Davis SM, Sullivan L, Meltzer HY, Hsiao J, Stroup TS, Lieberman JA. Prevalence of the metabolic syndrome in patients with schizophrenia: baseline results from the Clinical Antipsychotic Trials of Intervention Effectiveness (CATIE) schizophrenia trial and comparison with national estimates from NHANES III. Schizophrenia Research. 2005;80(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16137860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamee L, Mead G, MacGillivray S, Lawrie SM. Schizophrenia, poor physical health and physical activity: evidence-based interventions are required to reduce major health inequalities. The British Journal of Psychiatry. 2013;203(4):239&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24085733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Mental Health. Mental illness.  Retrieved 1/17/2025 from  https://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/statistics/mental-illness.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute on Aging. NIH Stage Model for Behavioral Intervention Development.  Retrieved 6/23/2025 from  https://www.nia.nih.gov/research/dbsr/nih-stage-model-behavioral-intervention-development.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onken L. Implementation science at the National Institute on Aging the principles of it. Public Policy &amp; Aging Report. 2022;32(1):39&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peebles SA, Mabe PA, Davidson L, Fricks L, Buckley PF, Fenley G. Recovery and systems transformation for schizophrenia. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 2007;30(3):567&#x2013;583. doi: 10.1016/j.psc.2007.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psc.2007.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17720037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy KL, Troiano RP, Ballard RM, Carlson SA, Fulton JE, Galuska DA, George SM, Olson RD. The Physical Activity Guidelines for Americans. JAMA. 2018;320(19):2020&#x2013;2028. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.14854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2018.14854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9582631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30418471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnick B, Jenkins LS. Testing the reliability and validity of the Self-Efficacy for Exercise scale. Nurs Res. 2000;49(3):154&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1097/00006199-200005000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006199-200005000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10882320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson CR, Faulkner G, McDevitt J, Skrinar GS, Hutchinson DS, Piette JD. Integrating physical activity into mental health services for persons with serious mental illness. Psychiatr Serv. 2005;56(3):324&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.56.3.324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.56.3.324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson CR, Faulkner G, McDevitt J, Skrinar GS, Hutchinson DS, Piette JD. Integrating physical activity into mental health services for persons with serious mental illness. Psychiatric services. 2005 2005 Mar;56(3):324&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.56.3.324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.56.3.324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rico Martinez E, Free K, Robertson M, Davis CL, Besenyi GM.Feasibility and sustainability of the PARCS Pilot intervention with mental health services: Feedback from administrators [Poster]. 45th Annual Society of Behavioral Medicine Conference; Philadelphia. 2024. Mar, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum S, Tiedemann A, Sherrington C, Curtis J, Ward PB. Physical activity interventions for people with mental illness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. The Journal of clinical psychiatry. 2014;75(9):1,478&#x2013;974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24813261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum S, Tiedemann A, Sherrington C, Curtis J, Ward PB. Physical activity interventions for people with mental illness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Psychiatry. 2014;75(9):964&#x2013;974. doi: 10.4088/JCP.13r08765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.13r08765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24813261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum S, Tiedemann A, Ward PB, Curtis J, Sherrington C. Physical activity interventions: an essential component in recovery from mental illness. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2015;49(24):1544&#x2013;1545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25807153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis J.Scoring of scales Memo to Users of Social Support Surveys for Diet and Exercise Behaviors. 1996.  Retrieved 5/29/2024 from  https://www.drjimsallis.com/social-support-for-diet-and-exercise.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis JF, Grossman RM, Pinski RB, Patterson TL, Nader PR. The development of scales to measure social support for diet and exercise behaviors. Prev Med. 1987;16(6):825&#x2013;836. doi: 10.1016/0091-7435(87)90022-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-7435(87)90022-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3432232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. SAMHSA &#x2019;s Working Definition of Recovery. (PEP12-RECDEF) 2012.  Retrieved 6/23/2025 from  https://library.samhsa.gov/product/samhsas-working-definition-recovery/pep12-recdef.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson Coon J, Boddy K, Stein K, Whear R, Barton J, Depledge MH. Does participating in physical activity in outdoor natural environments have a greater effect on physical and mental wellbeing than physical activity indoors? A systematic review. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2011;45(5):1761&#x2013;1772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21291246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg AE, Maas J, Verheij RA, Groenewegen PP. Green space as a buffer between stressful life events and health. Social Science and Medicine. 2010;70(8):1203&#x2013;1210. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2010.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2010.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20163905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vancampfort D, Stubbs B, Ward PB, Teasdale S, Rosenbaum S. Integrating physical activity as medicine in the care of people with severe mental illness. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry. 2015;49(8):681&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26041791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villeneuve PJ, Jerrett M, Su JG, Burnett RT, Chen H, Wheeler AJ, Goldberg MS. A cohort study relating urban green space with mortality in Ontario, Canada [Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov&#x2019;t] Environmental Research. 2012;115:51&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2012.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2012.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward MC, White DT, Druss BG. A meta-review of lifestyle interventions for cardiovascular risk factors in the general medical population: lessons for individuals with serious mental illness. The Journal of clinical psychiatry. 2015;76(4):477&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25919840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells K, Miranda J, Bruce ML, Alegria M, Wallerstein N. Bridging community intervention and mental health services research. American Journal of Psychiatry. 2004 2004 Jun;161(6):955&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.161.6.955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.161.6.955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15169681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler K, Razani N, Bashir Z.Park Prescriptions in Practice: The community driven way. 2014.  [Accessed 6/23/2025].  at  https://activelivingresearch.org/sites/activelivingresearch.org/files/2014_ParksTrails_Wheeler-Razani.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitfield GP, Riebe D, Magal M, Liguori G. Applying the ACSM Preparticipation Screening Algorithm to U.S. Adults: National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2001&#x2013;2004. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(10):2056&#x2013;2063. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28557860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcox S, Sharpe PA, Hutto BE, Granner ML. Psychometric properties of the self-efficacy for exercise questionnaire in a diverse sample of men and women. Journal of Physical Activity and Health. 2005;2(3):285&#x2013;297. doi: 10.1123/JPAH.2.3.285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/JPAH.2.3.285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>