<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40190543</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1729-0503</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>African health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Afr Health Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Meta analysis of clinical efficacy of acupoint application in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>351</StartPage><EndPage>361</EndPage><MedlinePgn>351-361</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4314/ahs.v24i4.44</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The clinical efficacy of acupoint application in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) was evaluated by Meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Computer searched Chinese and English databases for the randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and quasi-randomized controlled trials (CCTs) of TCM external therapy, acupoint application, TCM external application, navel sticking and their combination therapy in the treatment of IBS. The search period is from the establishment of the database to December 2022. The literature was screened independently by 2 researchers according to the standard of nano-ranking, and the data of the other 5 researchers were proofread, screened and extracted. After that, the bias risk of the included study was evaluated, and the data were analysed by RevMan 5.4. software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">(1) A total of 1842 patients, were included in 25 randomized controlled trials, including the acupoint application treatment group (n=928) and conventional therapy control group (n = 914).(2) The quality of the literature method shows that there are 5 high-quality literatures with a score of 4-7, 20 low-quality literatures with a score of 1-3 and few high-quality literatures;(3) In terms of effectiveness, compared with the western medicine control group, the total odds ratio OR [95 % CI] of the total effective rate of the acupoint application treatment group was 4.77 [3.68, 6.20], and the difference was statistically significant (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Shenque, Zhongwan, Pishu and Zusanli are the most commonly used.(4) In terms of literature bias, 2 studies used envelopes to hide, which belonged to "low risk"; 9 studies were blindly implemented and evaluated as "unclear"; and 6 studies were rated as "high risk" because cases fell off but were not reported. The funnel plot shows that the study is scatter symmetrical, the probability of publication bias is small, and the conclusion is reliable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Acupoint application can improve the effective clinical rate of IBS with fewer adverse reactions, better patient compliance and fewer adverse reactions, but it still needs to be confirmed by high-quality multicenter, large sample randomized controlled trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wang Q et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qingbo</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Lili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Junhong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Baoxia</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qiong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yike</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The first affiliated Hospital of Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zongqing</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Acupuncture and Massage, Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450018.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Shuangshuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Acupuncture and Massage, Henan University of traditional Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, 450018.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Uganda</Country><MedlineTA>Afr Health Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101149451</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1680-6905</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015669" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acupuncture Points</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015670" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acupuncture Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008516" MajorTopicYN="N">Medicine, Chinese Traditional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acupoint application</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">constipation type</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diarrhea type</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed-type</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40190543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11970189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ahs.v24i4.44</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jAFHS.v24.i4.pg351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Consensus opinion on the combined diagnosis and treatment of irritable bowel syndrome in Chinese and Western medicine. Chinese Journal of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine. 2011;31.05:587&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21812255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Erying, Zhou Jiawei, Chu Haiyun, Lu Sijia, Yang Yanjie. Advances in Epidemiology and pathogenic factors of irritable bowel syndrome [J] Public health in China. 2021;04:764&#x2013;768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI Xiaoqing, CHANG Min, XU Dong, FANG Xiucai. Analysis of the current status of epidemiological investigation of irritable bowel syndrome in China[J] Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology. 2013;22(08):734&#x2013;739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Wen Y, Wei Y, Liang X, Ma X, Zhang B, Tang X. External therapy of traditional Chinese medicine for treating irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022 Aug 9;9:940328. Doi: 10.3389/fmed.2022.940328. PMID: 36017012; PMCID: PMC9396246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9396246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36017012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S, Li FG, Kang JY, Li HW, Guo SHJ. A reticulated Meta-analysis of the efficacy of six acupuncture therapies in the treatment of diarrheal irritable bowel syndrome[J] Journal of Yunnan College of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020;43(04):53&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>YAN Dongxiao. Curative Effect Observation of Acupoint Application in Treating Diarrhea - type irritable bowel syndrome [J] Chinese Journal of Anorectal Diseases. 2021;01:53&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Duoxi, Guo Kuikui, Tan Jie, Huang Guilan, Li Shuai, Jiang Quanrui, Xie Jiao, Xie Hui, Zhang Zhiqi, Chen Ying, Peng Liang. Meta analysis of clinical study on acupuncture treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [J] Chinese acupuncture. 2017;08:907&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29231356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHANG Sha, WANG Wen, LI Zhe, CAO Liang, WANG Zongren, SHEN Shuwen. Systematic review of acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome [J] Journal of Hunan University of Chinese Medicine. 2017;09:1002&#x2013;1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wi&#x119;cek M, Panufnik P, Kaniewska M, Lewandowski K, Rydzewska G. Low-FODMAP Diet for the Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in Remission of IBD. Nutrients. 2022 Oct 29;14(21):4562. Doi: 10.3390/nu14214562. PMID: 36364824; PMCID: PMC9658010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9658010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36364824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Zhongting. Clinical study on acupoint application of Jianpi Wenshen Babu in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [D] Beijing University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>JI Chunyan, LI Bingshi, YAN Quanyun, LI Juju, LU Weimin. Clinical observation of 50 cases of diarrhea-type irritable bowel syndrome guided by meridian injection theory[J] Herald of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2021;02:56&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Jianyu. Observation on the therapeutic effect of Xu's prescription for suppressing the liver and invigorating the spleen combined with acupoint application on IBS-D with liver depression and spleen deficiency syndrome and its effect on the quality of life [D] Nanjing University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHOU Tao, TAN Haicheng, YANG Zhongting, WANG Hong, ZHAO Xiaodan, JIAO Yuntao, CHEN Lin, ZHANG Lihong, WU Chen, NIU Kemin. Clinical Observation on Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome with Spleen and Kidney Yang Deficiency by Acupuncture point sticker Therapy [J] Chinese Journal of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020;11:5858&#x2013;5862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Shujin. Clinical observation of traditional Chinese medicine combined with acupoint application in the treatment of IBS-D spleen and stomach weakness syndrome [D] Guangzhou University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Jianwen. Clinical observation of acupuncture combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [J] Electronic Journal of Cardiovascular Diseases with Integrated traditional Chinese and Western Medicine. 2020;26:153&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Yueqin, Zhan Daowei, Luo Kaitao, Shi Xiaowen. A randomized controlled study of acupuncture combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [J] Shanghai Journal of Acupuncture. 2017;06:684&#x2013;687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Xinzhi. Observation on the clinical efficacy of timing Sanfu patch in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [D] Hubei University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Wanting. Clinical observation of acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome with spleen and kidney yang deficiency and its effect on intestinal flora [D] Nanjing University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan Yanhe. Acupuncture point sticker and Acupuncture Treatment of Diarrhea Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome Clinical Controlled Observation [D] Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Yueping, Li Xuejun. Clinical observation of acupoint application combined with modified Gegen Qinlian decoction in the treatment of spleen-stomach dampheat syndrome of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [J] Journal of Anhui University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2021;06:49&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Daowei. Annual Meeting Proceedings. Zhejiang Acupuncture Association 2016 Academic; 2016. A randomized controlled trial of acupuncture combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome [C] pp. 95&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Menglin. Clinical observation of warming the middle and tonifying deficiency combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome (spleen-kidney yang deficiency) [D] Jiangxi University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Yuanyuan. Observation on the clinical efficacy of warming spleen and hot election bag in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome (spleen and stomach weakness syndrome) [D] Chengdu University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Defeng, Chu Xin, Wang Zongqin, Liu Ruihan, Xiao Qianxiu, Dai Li, Zhang Yan, Yang Zhihui. Observation on the effect of Wenpi paste on irritable bowel syndrome with spleen and kidney yang deficiency diarrhea [J] Sichuan Chinese medicine. 2020;09:217&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Beiyan. Clinical observation of Tongxieyao prescription combined with Shenque acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome with liver depression and spleen deficiency syndrome [D] Hunan University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LIANG Bi-qi, LU Yu-xia, SUN Ling-jun, SU Qiang. Clinical observation and nursing of Shengjiang Powder in the Treatment of Diarrhea Type IBS [J] Journal of Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2013;02:175&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HUA Hanbing. Clinical observation of Maziren Pill combined with acupoint application in the treatment of constipation irritable bowel syndrome [D] Liaoning University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Songhua, Xu Baocai, Qiu Genxiang, Wang Xiaomin, Dong Hongli, Chen Wei. Clinical study on Lei's purging dysentery accumulation method combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome (spleen-stomach damp-heat syndrome) [J] Emergency of traditional Chinese medicine. 2018;10:17371739&#x2013;17371743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI Lin. Clinical Observation of Jianpi Shugan Acupuncture point sticker Combined with Modified Tongxie Yaofang in the Treatment of Diarrhea-predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome [D] Beijing University of Chinese Medicine. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Shihong, Wei Xiaona. Clinical observation of Huazhuo mixture combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea of irritable bowel syndrome [J] Hubei Journal of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2010;05:52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Hao, Niu Yue, Huang Qian, Yang Zhengming, Yang Li. Fiery needle combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome with spleen deficiency and dampness syndrome: a randomized controlled trial [J] Chinese acupuncture. 2021;09:984&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Xiong. Clinical study of Ding Ai umbilical paste pill combined with Jiawei Zisheng granule in the treatment of IBS-D [D] Guangxi University of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Binghan. Observation on the clinical efficacy of electroacupuncture combined with acupoint application in the treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome [D] Jianghan University; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Qing. Clinical observation of Shenqi Zhuyao decoction combined with acupoint application of traditional Chinese medicine in the treatment of diarrhea of spleen and kidney yang deficiency type [D] Heilongjiang University of traditional Chinese Medicine. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastrointestinal functional Disease Cooperation Group of Gastroenterology Branch of Chinese Medical Association, Gastrointestinal Dynamics Group of Gastroenterology Branch of Chinese Medical Association, author. Consensus of Chinese irritable bowel syndrome experts in 2020 [J] Chinese Journal of digestion. 2020;12:803&#x2013;818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Longde, Zhang Ping, Ren Peipei, Liu Junhong, Wang Miaolei, Niu Yuanyuan, Jin Sansheng, Li Zhengju. Research progress on pathogenesis and treatment of diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome [J] 2022;01:16&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng QX, Soh AYS, Loke W, Venkatanarayanan N, Lim DY, Yeo WS. Systematic review with meta-analysis: The association between post-traumatic stress disorder and irritable bowel syndrome. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019 Jan;34(1):68&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1111/jgh.14446. Epub 2018 Sep 10. PMID: 30144372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30144372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Kaibo, Li Xian, Zhang Lupeng, Li Yingxiao, Li Chen. Research status of traditional Chinese and western medicine on diarrhea irritable bowel syndrome [J] Chinese Journal of Integrated traditional Chinese and Western Medicine digestion. 2021;04:298&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>