<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40900649</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-7080</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Complete revascularization with percutaneous coronary intervention for acute coronary syndromes presenting with multivessel disease.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HCO.0000000000001250</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Complete revascularization (CR) by percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) in acute coronary syndromes with multivessel coronary artery disease (CAD) was previously contraindicated in the absence of cardiogenic shock or high-risk ischemia. Over the last decade, CR has been a focus of recent clinical investigation and practice evolution due to high-quality evidence supporting hard cardiovascular outcome benefit, contributing to a reversal in international guidelines. This review provides concise syntheses of contemporary and emerging randomized evidence underpinning current strategies and unresolved questions regarding patient selection, timing of CR and guidance modalities for the identification and treatment of nonculprit lesions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The randomized evidence base supporting CR with PCI for acute coronary syndromes (ACS) and multivessel CAD has increased recently with large-scale trials comparing immediate versus staged CR and physiology-guided versus angiography-guided CR, including reports of longer-term comparative outcomes. Enough events have recently accrued to enable demonstration of all-cause mortality benefits with CR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Contemporary randomized data increasingly support CR with PCI in haemodynamically stable patients. However, ACS type, timing of intervention and method of evaluation still necessitate individualized shared clinical decision-making, and further trials are required to validate the optimal PCI strategies by which to achieve CR in the correct populations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reddy</LastName><ForeName>Rohin K</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart and Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Population Health, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bernstein</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howard</LastName><ForeName>James P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart and Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Yousif</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, University of California, San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8608087</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0268-4705</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complete revascularization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fractional flow reserve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intracoronary imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40900649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCO.0000000000001250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001573-990000000-00230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The top 10 causes of death. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/the-top-10-causes-of-death [Accessed May 22, 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task Force on the management of ST-segment elevation acute myocardial infarction of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC), Steg PG, James SK, et al.. ESC Guidelines for the management of acute myocardial infarction in patients presenting with ST-segment elevation. Eur Heart J 2012; 33:2569&#x2013;2619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Gara PT, Kushner FG, Ascheim DD, et al. 2013&#x200a;ACCF/AHA guideline for the management of ST-elevation myocardial infarction: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. Circulation 2013; 127:e362&#x2013;e425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized trial of preventive angioplasty in myocardial infarction. https://pubmed-ncbi-nlm-nih-gov.iclibezp1.cc.ic.ac.uk/23991625/ [Accessed May 28, 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engstr&#xd8;m T, Kelb&#xe6;k H, Helqvist S, et al. Complete revascularisation versus treatment of the culprit lesion only in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction and multivessel disease (DANAMI-3&#x2014;PRIMULTI): an open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2015; 386:665&#x2013;671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>10-Year Outcome of Complete or Infarct-Artery-Only Revascularization in STEMI with Multivessel Disease (DANAMI-3-PRIMULTI). https://pubmed-ncbi-nlm-nih-gov.iclibezp1.cc.ic.ac.uk/40392668/ [Accessed June 3, 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smits PC, Abdel-Wahab M, Neumann FJ, et al. Fractional flow reserve-guided multivessel angioplasty in myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 2017; 376:1234&#x2013;1244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiele H, Akin I, Sandri M, et al. PCI strategies in patients with acute myocardial infarction and cardiogenic shock. N Engl J Med 2017; 377:2419&#x2013;2432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiele H, Desch S. CULPRIT-SHOCK (Culprit Lesion Only PCI Versus Multivessel Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in Cardiogenic Shock): implications on guideline recommendations. Circulation 2018; 137:1314&#x2013;1316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complete Revascularization with Multivessel PCI for Myocardial Infarction. https://pubmed-ncbi-nlm-nih-gov.iclibezp1.cc.ic.ac.uk/31475795/ [Accessed June 1, 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy RK, Howard JP, Jamil Y, et al. Percutaneous coronary revascularization strategies after myocardial infarction: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024; 84:276&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne RA, Rossello X, Coughlan JJ, et al. 2023 ESC Guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes. Eur Heart J 2023; 44:3720&#x2013;3826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao SV, O&#x2019;Donoghue ML, Ruel M, et al. 2025&#x200a;ACC/AHA/ACEP/NAEMSP/SCAI Guideline for the Management of Patients With Acute Coronary Syndromes: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation 2025; 151:e771&#x2013;e862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchini E, Basile M, Bianchini F, et al. Multivessel revascularization in non-ST segment elevation acute coronary syndromes: A systematic review and meta-analysis of 182,798 patients. Int J Cardiol 2024; 413:132392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biscaglia S, Guiducci V, Escaned J, et al. Complete or culprit-only PCI in older patients with myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:889&#x2013;898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocco M, Campo G, Guiducci V, et al. Complete vs culprit-only revascularization in older patients with myocardial infarction with or without ST-segment elevation. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024; 84:2014&#x2013;2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad Y, Reddy RK, Mehta SR. Myocardial infarction and multivessel disease: completing the story. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024; 84:2023&#x2013;2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerensky RA, Wade M, Deedwania P, et al. Veterans Affairs Non-Q-Wave Infarction Stategies in-Hospital (VANQWISH) Trial Investigators. Revisiting the culprit lesion in non-Q-wave myocardial infarction. Results from the VANQWISH trial angiographic core laboratory. J Am Coll Cardiol 2002; 39:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraler S, Mueller C, Libby P, Bhatt DL. Acute coronary syndromes: mechanisms, challenges, and new opportunities. Eur Heart J 2025; ehaf289 doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2020 ESC Guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes in patients presenting without persistent ST-segment elevation. https://pubmed-ncbi-nlm-nih-gov.iclibezp1.cc.ic.ac.uk/32860058/ [Accessed June 2, 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahed AC, Jang IK. Plaque erosion and acute coronary syndromes: phenotype, molecular characteristics and future directions. Nat Rev Cardiol 2021; 18:724&#x2013;734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niccoli G, Montone RA, Di Vito L, et al. Plaque rupture and intact fibrous cap assessed by optical coherence tomography portend different outcomes in patients with acute coronary syndrome. Eur Heart J 2015; 36:1377&#x2013;1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonetsu T, Lee T, Murai T, et al. Plaque morphologies and the clinical prognosis of acute coronary syndrome caused by lesions with intact fibrous cap diagnosed by optical coherence tomography. Int J Cardiol 2016; 203:766&#x2013;774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pustjens TFS, Streukens B, Vainer J, et al. Design and rationale of ischaemia-driven complete revascularisation versus usual care in patients with non-ST-elevation myocardial infarction and multivessel coronary disease: the South Limburg Myocardial Infarction (SLIM) trial. Neth Heart J 2020; 28:75&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feistritzer HJ, Jobs A, Zeymer U, et al. Complete revascularization versus culprit-lesion only PCI in patients with NSTEMI and multivessel disease &#x2013; design and rationale of the randomized COMPLETE-NSTEMI trial. Am Heart J 2025; 287:94&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politi L, Sgura F, Rossi R, et al. A randomised trial of target-vessel versus multivessel revascularisation in ST-elevation myocardial infarction: major adverse cardiac events during long-term follow-up. Heart 2010; 96:662&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardella G, Lucisano L, Garbo R, et al. Single-staged compared with multi-staged PCI in multivessel NSTEMI patients: the SMILE Trial. J Am Coll Cardiol 2016; 67:264&#x2013;272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diletti R, den Dekker WK, Bennett J, et al. Immediate versus staged complete revascularisation in patients presenting with acute coronary syndrome and multivessel coronary disease (BIOVASC): a prospective, open-label, noninferiority, randomised trial. Lancet 2023; 401:1172&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;hli BE, Varbella F, Linke A, et al. Timing of complete revascularization with multivessel PCI for myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:1368&#x2013;1379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MC, Ahn JH, Hyun DY, et al. Timing of fractional flow reserve-guided complete revascularization in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction with multivessel disease: rationale and design of the OPTION-STEMI trial. Am Heart J 2024; 273:35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uren NG, Crake T, Lefroy DC, et al. Reduced coronary vasodilator function in infarcted and normal myocardium after myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 1994; 331:222&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragosta M, Powers ER, Samady H, et al. Relationship between extent of residual myocardial viability and coronary flow reserve in patients with recent myocardial infarction. Am Heart J 2001; 141:456&#x2013;462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntalianis A, Sels JW, Davidavicius G, et al. Fractional flow reserve for the assessment of nonculprit coronary artery stenoses in patients with acute myocardial infarction. JACC Cardiovasc Interv 2010; 3:1274&#x2013;1281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layland J, Carrick D, McEntegart M, et al. Vasodilatory capacity of the coronary microcirculation is preserved in selected patients with non-ST-segment-elevation myocardial infarction. Circ Cardiovasc Interv 2013; 6:231&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sels JWEM, Tonino PAL, Siebert U, et al. Fractional flow reserve in unstable angina and non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction experience from the FAME (Fractional flow reserve versus Angiography for Multivessel Evaluation) study. JACC Cardiovasc Interv 2011; 4:1183&#x2013;1189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puymirat E, Cayla G, Simon T, et al. FLOWER-MI Study Investigators. Three-year outcomes with fractional flow reserve-guided or angiography-guided multivessel percutaneous coronary intervention for myocardial infarction. Circ Cardiovasc Interv 2024; 17:e013913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JM, Kim HK, Park KH, et al. Fractional flow reserve versus angiography-guided strategy in acute myocardial infarction with multivessel disease: a randomized trial. Eur Heart J 2023; 44:473&#x2013;484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hm F, Mogensen B, Engstr&#xf8;m T, et al. FFR-guided complete or culprit-only PCI in patients with myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 2024; 390:1481&#x2013;1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xd8;nborg J, Engstr&#xd8;m T, Kelb&#xe6;k H, et al. Fractional flow reserve-guided complete revascularization improves the prognosis in patients with ST-segment-elevation myocardial infarction and severe nonculprit disease: a DANAMI 3-PRIMULTI substudy (Primary PCI in Patients With ST-Elevation Myocardial Infarction and Multivessel Disease: Treatment of Culprit Lesion Only or Complete Revascularization). Circ Cardiovasc Interv 2017; 10:e004460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinilla-Echeverri N, Mehta SR, Wang J, et al. Nonculprit lesion plaque morphology in patients with ST-segment-elevation myocardial infarction: results from the COMPLETE trial optical coherence tomography substudys. Circ Cardiovasc Interv 2020; 13:e008768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone GW, Maehara A, Lansky AJ, et al. A prospective natural-history study of coronary atherosclerosis. N Engl J Med 2011; 364:226&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>