<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40875648</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing ensemble machine learning models for accurate liver disease prediction in healthcare.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0330899</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0330899</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0330899</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0330899</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Liver disease encompasses a range of conditions affecting the liver, including hepatitis, cirrhosis, fatty liver, and liver cancer. It can be caused by infections, alcohol abuse, obesity, or genetic factors, and it often progresses silently until advanced stages. Early detection and lifestyle adjustments are essential for effective management and to prevent severe liver damage. This study explores the application of machine learning (ML) techniques to predict liver disease, leveraging a dataset to compare the performance of several ensemble classifiers. The algorithms include the Random Forrest Classifier, Ada Boost Classifier, and Gradient Boosting Classifier. After a series of feature extraction and selection, hyperparameter tuning by Randomized Search CV and GridSearchCV, we aimed to determine the best model for liver disease prediction in terms of accuracy, precision, recall, and F1-score. The results showed that the Random Forest Classifier, optimized with GridSearchCV, achieved the highest accuracy at just over 85.17%. The considerations presented in this classifier can be considered for potential use as a precise diagnostic tool for liver disease diagnostics as these measurements indicate that this classifier works balanced with precision at 0.85 for both the presence and absence of the given disease as well as recall of 0.81 for its presence and 0.87 for its absence and F1-measure of 0.83 and 0.85 respectively. There were also relatively high performances of AdaBoost Classifier and Gradient Boosting Classifier, though none of the classifiers outperformed Random Forest Classifier significantly. The research has shown the potential of ensemble ML techniques, especially in the diagnosis of medical conditions, including liver diseases which, if diagnosed early, are critical. The results add evidence regarding the applicability of the ML models in clinical practices with the potential to improve diagnostic activities and consequently the outcomes of patients. Future studies will build on these models, testing them on larger and more diverse sets of data, including aspects of deep learning, and apply the research to other disease domains. The work presented in this research offers a starting point for carrying out innovations with ML in the sphere of healthcare to progress the methods of diagnosing diseases and treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 El Atifi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Atifi</LastName><ForeName>W</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7130-0241</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hassan First University of Settat, High Institute of Health Sciences, Laboratory of Sciences and Health Technologies, Settat, Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiotherapy, Hospital Center Ibn Rochd, Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, University Hassan II, Casablanca, Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Rhazouani</LastName><ForeName>O</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hassan First University of Settat, High Institute of Health Sciences, Laboratory of Sciences and Health Technologies, Settat, Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Fida Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Qurtuba University of Science and Information Technology, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sekkat</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-1530-4837</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hassan First University of Settat, High Institute of Health Sciences, Laboratory of Sciences and Health Technologies, Settat, Morocco.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008107" MajorTopicYN="Y">Liver Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>NO authors have competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40875648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12393716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0330899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-09517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arbain R. Analyzing data mining techniques for liver disease prediction on imbalanced datasets. Int J Data Sci Machine Learn. 2022;2(02):5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhupathi D, Tan CL, Tirumula SS, Ray SK. Liver disease detection using machine learning techniques. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assegie TA, Subhashni R, Kumar NK, Manivannan JP, Duraisamy P, Engidaye MF. Random forest and support vector machine based hybrid liver disease detection. Bulletin of Electrical Engineering and Informatics. 2022;11(3):1650&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shylaja DS, Karunya M, Oliviya J. Accuracy Prediction using Machine Learning Techniques for Indian Patient Liver Disease. In: 2023 International Conference on Computational Intelligence and Sustainable Engineering Solutions (CISES), 2023:614&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1109/cises58720.2023.10183617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/cises58720.2023.10183617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta K, Jiwani N, Afreen N, Divyarani D. Liver disease prediction using machine learning classification techniques. In: 2022 IEEE 11th International Conference on Communication Systems and Network Technologies (CSNT), 2022:221&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straw I, Wu H. Investigating for bias in healthcare algorithms: a sex-stratified analysis of supervised machine learning models in liver disease prediction. BMJ Health Care Inform. 2022;29(1):e100457. doi: 10.1136/bmjhci-2021-100457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjhci-2021-100457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9039354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam D, Chapiro J, Paradis V, Seraphin TP, Kather JN. Artificial intelligence in liver diseases: Improving diagnostics, prognostics and response prediction. JHEP Rep. 2022;4(4):100443. doi: 10.1016/j.jhepr.2022.100443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhepr.2022.100443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8867112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35243281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazal TM, Rehman AU, Saleem M, Ahmad M, Ahmad S, Mehmood F. Intelligent model to predict early liver disease using machine learning technique. In: 2022 International Conference on Business Analytics for Technology and Security (ICBATS), 2022. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalal S, Onyema EM, Malik A. Hybrid XGBoost model with hyperparameter tuning for prediction of liver disease with better accuracy. World J Gastroenterol. 2022;28(46):6551&#x2013;63. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v28.i46.6551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v28.i46.6551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9782838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36569269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons M, Rivera-Esteban J, Ma MM, Davyduke T, Delamarre A, Hermabessi&#xe8;re P, et al. Point-of-care noninvasive prediction of liver-related events in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology. 2024;22(8):1637&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37573987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin R, Yasmin R, Ruhi S, Rahman MH, Reza MS. Prediction of chronic liver disease patients using integrated projection based statistical feature extraction with machine learning algorithms. Informatics in Medicine Unlocked. 2023;36:101155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aswini J, Yamini B, Venkata Ramana K, Jegan Amarnath J. An efficient liver disease prediction using mask-regional convolutional neural network and pelican optimization algorithm. IETE Journal of Research. 2024;70(2):1985&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gidener T, Yin M, Dierkhising RA, Allen AM, Ehman RL, Venkatesh SK. Magnetic resonance elastography for prediction of long-term progression and outcome in chronic liver disease: A retrospective study. Hepatology. 2022;75(2):379&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1002/hep.32151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.32151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8766880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34510513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, M&#xe9;ric G, Havulinna AS, Teo SM, &#xc5;berg F, Ruuskanen M, et al. Early prediction of incident liver disease using conventional risk factors and gut-microbiome-augmented gradient boosting. Cell Metab. 2022;34(5):719&#x2013;730.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2022.03.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2022.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9097589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altaf I, Butt MA, Zaman M. Disease detection and prediction using the liver function test data: A review of machine learning algorithms. In: International Conference on Innovative Computing and Communications: Proceedings of ICICC 2021, Volume 2, 2022:785&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Md AQ, Kulkarni S, Joshua CJ, Vaichole T, Mohan S, Iwendi C. Enhanced Preprocessing Approach Using Ensemble Machine Learning Algorithms for Detecting Liver Disease. Biomedicines. 2023;11(2):581. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines11020581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11020581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9953600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36831118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;berg F, Byrne CD, Pirola CJ, M&#xe4;nnist&#xf6; V, Sookoian S. Alcohol consumption and metabolic syndrome: Clinical and epidemiological impact on liver disease. J Hepatol. 2023;78(1):191&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1016/j.jhep.2022.08.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2022.08.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36063967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan RA, Luo Y, Wu F-X. Machine learning based liver disease diagnosis: A systematic review. Neurocomputing. 2022;468:492&#x2013;509. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2021.08.138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2021.08.138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu L, Thiele M, Geyer PE, Rasmussen DN, Webel HE, Santos A, et al. Noninvasive proteomic biomarkers for alcohol-related liver disease. Nat Med. 2022;28(6):1277&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01850-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01850-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9205783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35654907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X, Lv F, He X, Zhao Y, Liu Y, Zu J, et al. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on liver disease-related mortality rates in the United States. J Hepatol. 2023;78(1):16&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1016/j.jhep.2022.07.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2022.07.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9611810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35988691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy DT, Kavya G, Anusha L, Shashank M, Adithya M. Disease prediction using machine learning. International Journal of Information Technology and Computer Engineering. 2024;12(1):319&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali AMAA. A comprehensive review of liver disease prediction using big and artificial intelligence. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trebicka J, Gu W, de Ledinghen V, Aub&#xe9; C, Krag A, Praktiknjo M, et al. Two-dimensional shear wave elastography predicts survival in advanced chronic liver disease. Gut. 2022;71(2):402&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2020-323419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2020-323419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash NN, Rajesh V, Namakhwa DL, Pande SD, Ahammad SH. A DenseNet CNN-based liver lesion prediction and classification for future medical diagnosis. Sci Afr. 2023;20:e01629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X-L, Jiang L-S, Wu C-S, Pan L-Y, Lou Z-Q, Peng C-T, et al. The role of fibrosis index FIB-4 in predicting liver fibrosis stage and clinical prognosis: A diagnostic or screening tool? J Formos Med Assoc. 2022;121(2):454&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/j.jfma.2021.07.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfma.2021.07.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34325952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doghish AS, Elballal MS, Elazazy O, Elesawy AE, Elrebehy MA, Shahin RK, et al. The role of miRNAs in liver diseases: Potential therapeutic and clinical applications. Pathol Res Pract. 2023;243:154375. doi: 10.1016/j.prp.2023.154375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prp.2023.154375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36801506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyoda H, Johnson PJ. The ALBI score: From liver function in patients with HCC to a general measure of liver function. JHEP Rep. 2022;4(10):100557. doi: 10.1016/j.jhepr.2022.100557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhepr.2022.100557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9482109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36124124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe4;rber G, Marx J, Scherag A, Saqer I, Diab M, Sponholz C, et al. Risk stratification for isolated tricuspid valve surgery assisted using the Model for End-Stage Liver Disease score. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2023;166(5):1433&#x2013;1441.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.jtcvs.2021.11.102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcvs.2021.11.102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semmler G, Meyer EL, Kozbial K, Schwabl P, Hametner-Schreil S, Zanetto A, et al. HCC risk stratification after cure of hepatitis C in patients with compensated advanced chronic liver disease. J Hepatol. 2022;76(4):812&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.jhep.2021.11.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2021.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34871626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn JC, Connell A, Simonetto DA, Hughes C, Shah VH. Application of Artificial Intelligence for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Liver Diseases. Hepatology. 2021;73(6):2546&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1002/hep.31603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.31603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33098140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JI, Lee HW, Lee KS, Lee HS, Park J-Y. Effects of Statin Use on the Development and Progression of Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: A Nationwide Nested Case-Control Study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116(1):116&#x2013;24. doi: 10.14309/ajg.0000000000000845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000000845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33027082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajmera V, Kim BK, Yang K, Majzoub AM, Nayfeh T, Tamaki N, et al. Liver Stiffness on Magnetic Resonance Elastography and the MEFIB Index and Liver-Related Outcomes in Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Individual Participants. Gastroenterology. 2022;163(4):1079&#x2013;1089.e5. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2022.06.073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2022.06.073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9509452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35788349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menardi G, Torelli N. Training and assessing classification rules with imbalanced data. Data Min Knowl Disc. 2012;28(1):92&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1007/s10618-012-0295-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10618-012-0295-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seva A, Rao ST, Sireesha M. Prediction of liver disease with random forest classifier through SMOTE-ENN balancing. In 2024 IEEE 13th International Conference on Communication Systems and Network Technologies (CSNT). IEEE. 2024: 928&#x2013;933</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlMustafa KM, Katrib J. Evaluating Machine Learning Classifiers for Predicting Liver Disease Outcomes. In 2024 International Conference on Decision Aid Sciences and Applications (DASA). IEEE. 2024:1&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theerthagiri P. Liver disease classification using histogram-based gradient boosting classification tree with feature selection algorithm. Biomedical Signal Processing and Control. 2025;100:107102.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>