<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40673957</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coronary Sinus Reducer in Refractory Angina: A Targeted Approach to Microvascular Ischemia and Symptom Relief.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001001</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Refractory angina remains a therapeutic challenge in patients with advanced coronary artery disease who are not amenable to further revascularization and remain symptomatic despite optimal medical therapy. The coronary sinus reducer (CSR) is a novel, device-based therapy that aims to alleviate angina by increasing coronary sinus pressure and redistributing blood flow toward ischemic myocardial territories, particularly in the subendocardial region. This article reviews current evidence on the comparative effectiveness of CSR relative to established pharmacologic and interventional therapies, with a focus on its potential role in patients with microvascular versus macrovascular ischemia. Data from randomized trials and real-world registries demonstrate significant symptomatic improvement and favorable safety outcomes in the majority of CSR-treated patients, though nonresponder rates remain between 15% and 30%. Emerging evidence suggests CSR may be particularly effective in patients with microvascular dysfunction, such as those with angina and no obstructive coronary artery disease. However, long-term efficacy, ideal patient selection criteria, and mechanistic underpinnings remain areas of ongoing investigation. Current and upcoming trials such as COSIRA-II (CSR for Treatment of RA) and REMEDY-PILOT (Reducing microvascular dysfunction in patients with angina, ischaemia, and unobstructed coronary arteries- a pilot study) aim to address these uncertainties. CSR represents a promising addition to the therapeutic landscape for refractory angina, particularly in complex or no-option cases, pending further clinical validation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Hadrian Hoang-Vu</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Hackensack University Medical Center, Palisades Medical Center, North Bergen, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thu</LastName><ForeName>Audrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Touro College of Osteopathic Medicine, New York, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Twayana</LastName><ForeName>Anu Radha</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center at Permian Basin, Odessa, TX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuertes</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Hackensack University Medical Center, Palisades Medical Center, North Bergen, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Hackensack University Medical Center, Palisades Medical Center, North Bergen, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basta</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Hackensack University Medical Center, Palisades Medical Center, North Bergen, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>James</LastName><ForeName>Maggie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Hackensack University Medical Center, Palisades Medical Center, North Bergen, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Krutagni Adwait</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Internal Medicine, Hackensack University Medical Center, Palisades Medical Center, North Bergen, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frishman</LastName><ForeName>William H</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aronow</LastName><ForeName>Wilbert S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Cardiology and Medicine, Westchester Medical Center and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ANOCA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COSIRA trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary sinus pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary sinus reducer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">device-based therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microvascular dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonobstructive ischemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">refractory angina</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subendocardial perfusion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40673957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lantz R, Quesada O, Mattingly G, et al. Contemporary management of refractory angina. Interv Cardiol Clin. 2022;11:279&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley C, Berry C. Definition and epidemiology of coronary microvascular disease. J Nucl Cardiol. 2022;29:1763&#x2013;1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies A, Fox K, Galassi AR, et al. Management of refractory angina: an update. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:269&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virani SS, Newby LK, Arnold SV, et al.; Writing Committee Members. 2023 AHA/ACC/ACCP/ASPC/NLA/PCNA guideline for the management of patients with chronic coronary disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;82:833&#x2013;955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masi S, Rizzoni D, Taddei S, et al. Assessment and pathophysiology of microvascular disease: recent progress and clinical implications. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:2590&#x2013;2604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Buono MG, Montone RA, Camilli M, et al. Coronary microvascular dysfunction across the spectrum of cardiovascular diseases. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;78:1352&#x2013;1371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houben AJHM, Martens RJH, Stehouwer CDA. Assessing microvascular function in humans from a chronic disease perspective. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2017;28:3461&#x2013;3472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheye S, Jolic&#x153;ur EM, Behan MW, et al. Efficacy of a device to narrow the coronary sinus in refractory angina. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:519&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzanis G, Khokhar AA, Ponticelli F, et al. Coronary sinus size and ischemia improvement after reducer implantation; &#x201c;one size to fit them all?&#x201d;. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2021;98:E365&#x2013;E369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theofilis P, Oikonomou E, Sagris M, et al. Novel concepts in the management of angina in coronary artery disease. Curr Pharm Des. 2023;29:1825&#x2013;1834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochstadt A, Itach T, Merdler I, et al. Effectiveness of coronary sinus reducer for treatment of refractory angina: a meta-analysis. Can J Cardiol. 2022;38:376&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponticelli F, Khokhar AA, Leenders G, et al. Safety and efficacy of coronary sinus narrowing in chronic refractory angina: insights from the RESOURCE study. Int J Cardiol. 2021;337:29&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah SS, Teague SD, Lu JC, et al. Imaging of the coronary sinus: normal anatomy and congenital abnormalities. Radiographics. 2012;32:991&#x2013;1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loukas M, Bilinsky S, Bilinsky E, et al. Cardiac veins: a review of the literature. Clin Anat. 2009;22:129&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun C, Pan Y, Wang H, et al. Assessment of the coronary venous system using 256-Slice computed tomography. PLoS One. 2014;9:e104246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noheria A, Desimone CV, Lachman N, et al. Anatomy of the coronary sinus and epicardial coronary venous system in 620 hearts: an electrophysiology perspective. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2013;24:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib A, Lachman N, Christensen KN, et al. The anatomy of the coronary sinus venous system for the cardiac electrophysiologist. Europace. 2009;11:v15&#x2013;v21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortale JR, Gabriel EA, Iost C, et al. The anatomy of the coronary sinus and its tributaries. Surg Radiol Anat. 2001;23:15&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmaasarany S, Ferrett C, Firth A, et al. The coronary sinus conduit function: anatomical study (relationship to adjacent structures). Europace. 2005;7:475&#x2013;481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn RT, Abraham T, Adams MS, et al. Guidelines for performing a comprehensive transesophageal echocardiographic examination: recommendations from the American Society of Echocardiography and the Society of Cardiovascular Anesthesiologists. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2013;26:921&#x2013;964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Cruz IA, Shala MB, Johns C. Echocardiography of the coronary sinus in adults. Clin Cardiol. 2000;23:149&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Cruz IA, Shirwany A. Update on echocardiography of coronary sinus anatomy and physiology. Echocardiogr. 2003;20:87&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantin B, Rouleau JR. Myocardial tissue pressure and blood flow during coronary sinus pressure modulation in anesthetized dogs. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1992;73:2184&#x2013;2191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saremi F, Thonar B, Sarlaty T, et al. Posterior interatrial muscular connection between the coronary sinus and left atrium: anatomic and functional study of the coronary sinus with multidetector CT. Radiology. 2011;260:671&#x2013;679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konigstein M, Giannini F, Banai S. The Reducer device in patients with angina pectoris: mechanisms, indications, and perspectives. Eur Heart J. 2018;39:925&#x2013;933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheye S, van de Hoef TP, de Silva R, et al.; REDUCER-I Study Investigators. Coronary sinus narrowing for treating refractory angina. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2024;17:2908&#x2013;2918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Fan L, Choy JS, et al. Mechanisms of coronary sinus reducer for treatment of myocardial ischemia: in silico study. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2024;136:1157&#x2013;1169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tryon D, Corban MT, Alkhouli M, et al. Coronary sinus reducer improves angina, quality of life, and coronary flow reserve in microvascular dysfunction. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2024;17:2893&#x2013;2904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebaldi M, Campo G, Ugo F, et al. Coronary sinus narrowing improves coronary microcirculation function in patients with refractory angina: a multicenter prospective INROAD study. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2024;17:e013481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng K, Alpendurada F, Bucciarelli-Ducci C, et al. Segmental redistribution of myocardial blood flow after coronary sinus reducer implantation demonstrated by quantitative perfusion cardiovascular magnetic resonance. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2025;27:101868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmisano A, Giannini F, Rancoita P, et al. Feature tracking and mapping analysis of myocardial response to improved perfusion reserve in patients with refractory angina treated by coronary sinus Reducer implantation: a CMR study. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;37:291&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Amico G, Giannini F, Massussi M, et al. Usefulness of coronary sinus reducer implantation for the treatment of chronic refractory angina pectoris. Am J Cardiol. 2021;139:22&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin AM, Khan U, Khlidj Y, et al. Efficacy and safety of coronary sinus reducer for refractory angina: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Coron Artery Dis. 2025;36:337&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallone G, Baldetti L, Angelini F, et al. The placebo effect on symptoms, quality of life, and functional outcomes in patients with angina pectoris: a meta-analysis of randomized placebo-controlled trials. Can J Cardiol. 2022;38:113&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen TPJ, Konst RE, Elias-Smale SE, et al. Assessing microvascular dysfunction in angina with unobstructed coronary arteries. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;78:1471&#x2013;1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehan R, Yong A, Ng M, et al. Coronary microvascular dysfunction: a review of recent progress and clinical implications. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1111721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pompei G, Ganzorig N, Kotanidis CP, et al. Novel diagnostic approaches and management of coronary microvascular dysfunction. Am J Prev Cardiol. 2024;19:100712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullrich H, Hammer P, Olschewski M, et al. Coronary venous pressure and microvascular hemodynamics in patients with microvascular angina. JAMA Cardiol. 2023;8:979&#x2013;983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramik J, Mariathas M, Felekos I. Coronary microvascular dysfunction and vasospastic angina&#x2014;pathophysiology, diagnosis and management strategies. J Clin Med. 2025;14:1128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smilowitz NR, Toleva O, Chieffo A, et al. Coronary microvascular disease in contemporary clinical practice. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2023;16:e012568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira Reis J, Br&#xed;zido C, Madeira S, et al. Coronary sinus reducer device for the treatment of refractory angina: a multicenter initial experience. Rev Port Cardiol. 2023;42:413&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldetti L, Colombo A, Banai S, et al. Coronary sinus reducer non-responders: insights and perspectives. EuroIntervention. 2018;13:1667&#x2013;1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson NP, Kirkeeide RL, Gould KL. Coronary anatomy to predict physiology. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2013;6:817&#x2013;832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#x142;odarczak S, Rola P, Jastrz&#x119;bski A, et al. Safety and effectiveness of coronary sinus reducer in the therapy of refractory angina pectoris-mid-term results of the real-life cohort. J Clin Med. 2024;13:4413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng K, Rajabali H, Tan S-T, et al. Procedural factors influencing successful coronary sinus reducer implantation for refractory angina: a single-centre experience. Cardiovasc Revasc Med. 2024; 00747-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng K, Hill JM, de Silva R. Coronary sinus reducer therapy for refractory angina and its role in modern interventional practice: a contemporary review. Interv Cardiol. 2024;19:e11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannini F, Tzanis G, Ponticelli F, et al. Technical aspects in coronary sinus reducer implantation. EuroIntervention. 2020;15:1269&#x2013;1277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zivelonghi C, Verheye S. The coronary sinus reducer - clinical evidence and new perspectives on an emerging tool in the treatment of refractory angina. Heart Int. 2020;14:29&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konigstein M, Ponticelli F, Zivelonghi C, et al. Long&#x2010;term outcomes of patients undergoing coronary sinus reducer implantation &#x2010; A multicenter study. Clin Cardiol. 2021;44:424&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannini F, Baldetti L, Ponticelli F, et al. Coronary sinus reducer implantation for the treatment of chronic refractory angina. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2018;11:784&#x2013;792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banai S, Ben Muvhar S, Parikh KH, et al. Coronary sinus reducer stent for the treatment of chronic refractory angina pectoris. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;49:1783&#x2013;1789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzanis G, Palmisano A, Gallone G, et al. The impact of the coronary sinus reducer upon left ventricular function in patients with refractory angina pectoris. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2020;95:1104&#x2013;1108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz Y, Grosman-Rimon L, Levy Y, et al. The coronary sinus reducer stent for the treatment of refractory angina pectoris: from the conception of innovation to clinical application. Cardiol Rev. 2024;32:448&#x2013;452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrak M, &#x17d;lahti&#x10d; T, Starc V, et al. The impact of coronary sinus reducer on arrhythmic properties in patients with refractory angina. Rev Cardiovasc Med. 2023;24:368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Asan O. Role of artificial intelligence in patient safety outcomes: systematic literature review. JMIR Med Inform. 2020;8:e18599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan X, Bao H, Si Y, et al. Spinal cord stimulation for refractory angina pectoris. Clin J Pain. 2017;33:543&#x2013;551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Liu X, Wang X, et al. Efficacy of enhanced external counterpulsation in patients with chronic refractory angina on Canadian Cardiovascular Society (CCS) angina class. Medicine (Baltimore). 2015;94:e2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen KB, Dowling RD, DelRossi AJ, et al. Transmyocardial laser revascularization combined with coronary artery bypass grafting: a multicenter, blinded, prospective, randomized, controlled trial. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2000;119:540&#x2013;549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abawi M, Nijhoff F, Stella PR, et al. Safety and efficacy of a device to narrow the coronary sinus for the treatment of refractory angina: a single-centre real-world experience. Neth Heart J. 2016;24:544&#x2013;551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley MJ, Rajkumar CA, Ahmed-Jushuf F, et al. Coronary sinus reducer for the treatment of refractory angina (ORBITA-COSMIC): a randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet (London, England). 2024;403:1543&#x2013;1553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnan E, Cioffi GM, Bossard M, et al. Treatment of microvascular angina with the coronary sinus reducer: a first experience. Eur Heart J. 2023;44:e365&#x2013;e369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai W, Xu X, Ji H, et al. Evaluation of the anatomical variations of the coronary venous system in patients with coronary artery calcification using 256-slice computed tomography. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0242216.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>