<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40963157</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparing Fractional Flow Reserve Versus Intravascular Ultrasound for Percutaneous Coronary Intervention Guidance: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001046</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Assessing lesion severity and optimizing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) are crucial for improving long-term outcomes in patients with coronary artery disease. Both strategies offer advantages over angiography alone; however, direct comparisons for revascularization decision-making are limited. This study evaluates and compares outcomes of FFR versus intravascular ultrasound (IVUS)-guided PCI strategies. We searched PubMed, Cochrane Central, and ScienceDirect from inception till April 2025. Data for various outcomes were extracted after computing the random-effect model and risk ratio (RR) with a 95% confidence interval (CI). The quality assessment of the included randomized controlled trials and observational studies was conducted using the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2 (ROB-2) and the Newcastle-Ottawa Scale, respectively. Publication bias was assessed visually through funnel plots and statistically through Egger's regression test. We included 5 studies comparing FFR and IVUS in 4714 patients undergoing PCI. The FFR and IVUS groups demonstrated comparable results across all endpoints including major adverse cardiovascular events (RR: 1.05; 95% CI: 0.84-1.30; P = 0.68), all-cause mortality (RR: 0.84; 95% CI: 0.50-1.39; P = 0.49), cardiac death (RR: 1.05; 95% CI: 0.59-1.87; P = 0.87), nonfatal myocardial infarction (RR: 1.31; 95% CI: 0.70-2.44; P = 0.40), and target vessel revascularization (RR: 1.20; 95% CI: 0.78-1.84; P = 0.40). The FFR (either hyperemic or angiography-driven) and IVUS groups showed comparable clinical outcomes in PCI for intermediate coronary lesions. However, FFR adds value with enhanced cost-efficiency and a physiology-driven approach that avoids unnecessary interventions. Selection should depend on patient factors, operator expertise, and institutional resources.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheema</LastName><ForeName>Ameer Haider</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the University of Texas Southwestern, Dallas, TX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waseem</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Hassan</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Allama Iqbal Medical College, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ul Abideen</LastName><ForeName>Zain</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoaib</LastName><ForeName>Areeba</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dow Medical College, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waheed</LastName><ForeName>Aiman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rawalpindi Medical University and Allied Hospitals, Rawalpindi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasheed</LastName><ForeName>Sanan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rawalpindi Medical University and Allied Hospitals, Rawalpindi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dilawar</LastName><ForeName>Esha</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Services Institute of Medical Sciences, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thada</LastName><ForeName>Pawan Kumar</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sotang Primary Hospital, Solukhumbu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary lesions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fractional flow reserve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravascular ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosures: The authors have no conflicts of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40963157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nissen SE, Yock P. Intravascular ultrasound: novel pathophysiological insights and current clinical applications. Circulation. 2001;103:604&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijls NHJ, Bruyne B, Peels K, et al. Measurement of fractional flow reserve to assess the functional severity of coronary-artery stenoses. N Engl J Med. 1996;334:1703&#x2013;1708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonino PA, De Bruyne B, Pijls NH, et al.; FAME Study Investigators. Fractional flow reserve versus angiography for guiding percutaneous coronary intervention. N Engl J Med. 2009;360:213&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Bruyne B, Pijls NH, Kalesan B, et al.; FAME 2 Trial Investigators. Fractional flow reserve-guided PCI versus medical therapy in stable coronary disease. N Engl J Med. 2012;367:991&#x2013;1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mintz GS, Nissen SE, Anderson WD, et al. American College of Cardiology Clinical Expert consensus document on standards for acquisition, measurement and reporting of Intravascular Ultrasound Studies (IVUS). a report of the American College of Cardiology Task Force on Clinical Expert Consensus Documents. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2001;37:1478&#x2013;1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SJ, Kim BK, Shin DH, et al.; IVUS-XPL Investigators. Effect of intravascular ultrasound-guided vs angiography-guided everolimus-eluting stent implantation: the IVUS-XPL randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2015;314:2155&#x2013;2163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgendy IY, Mahmoud AN, Elgendy AY, et al. Outcomes with intravascular ultrasound-guided stent implantation: a meta-analysis of randomized trials in the era of drug-eluting stents. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2016;9:e003700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Gao X, Kan J, et al. Intravascular ultrasound versus angiography-guided drug-eluting stent implantation: the ULTIMATE trial. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:3126&#x2013;3137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al.; PRISMA Group. Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6:e1000097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions 2019:1&#x2013;694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiavo JH. PROSPERO: an international register of systematic review protocols. Med Ref Serv Q. 2019;38:171&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25:603&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21:1539&#x2013;1558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Torre Hernandez JM, L&#xf3;pez-Palop R, Garcia Camarero T, et al. Clinical outcomes after intravascular ultrasound and fractional flow reserve assessment of intermediate coronary lesions. Propensity score matching of large cohorts from two institutions with a differential approach. EuroIntervention. 2013;9:824&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Zhang J, Yang S, et al.; FLAVOUR II Study Group. Angiography-derived fractional flow reserve versus intravascular ultrasound to guide percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with coronary artery disease (FLAVOUR II): a multicentre, randomised, non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2025;405:1491&#x2013;1504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo B-K, Hu X, Kang J, et al.; FLAVOUR Investigators. Fractional flow reserve or intravascular ultrasonography to guide PCI. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:779&#x2013;789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam C-W, Yoon H-J, Cho Y-K, et al. Outcomes of percutaneous coronary intervention in intermediate coronary artery disease: fractional flow reserve&#x2013;guided versus intravascular ultrasound&#x2013;guided. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2010;3:812&#x2013;817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo H, Liu Q, Zhang Z, et al. [Outcomes of percutaneous coronary intervention for intermediate coronary artery disease guided by intravascular ultrasound or fractional flow reserve]. Nan Fang Yi Ke Da Xue Xue Bao. 2014;34:704&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FLAVOUR II. Novel AI-Powered Imaging Technique Noninferior to IVUS in PCI. American College of Cardiology. Available from: https://www.acc.org/Latest-in-Cardiology/Journal-Scans/2025/03/24/16/30/sun-10am-flavourii-acc-2025. Accessed May 15, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhang Y, Xu Y, et al. Fractional flow reserve versus intravascular imaging to guide decision-making for percutaneous coronary intervention in intermediate lesions: a meta-analysis. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2023;102:1198&#x2013;1209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neleman T, van Zandvoort LJC, Tovar Forero MN, et al. FFR-guided PCI optimization directed by high-definition IVUS versus standard of care: the FFR REACT trial. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2022;15:1595&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuno T, Kiyohara Y, Maehara A, et al. Comparison of intravascular imaging, functional, or angiographically guided coronary intervention. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;82:2167&#x2013;2176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann FJ, Sousa-Uva M, Ahlsson A, et al.; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2018 ESC/EACTS Guidelines on myocardial revascularization. Eur Heart J. 2019;40:87&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SW, Kang J, Zhang J, et al. Fractional flow reserve- and intravascular ultrasound-guided strategies for intermediate coronary stenosis and low lesion complexity in patients with or without diabetes: a post hoc analysis of the randomised FLAVOUR trial. EuroIntervention. 2025;21:e183&#x2013;e192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding D, Zhang J, Wu P, et al. Prognostic value of postpercutaneous coronary intervention Murray-law-based quantitative flow ratio: post hoc analysis from FLAVOUR Trial. JACC Asia. 2025;5:59&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zandvoort LJC, Ali Z, Kern M, et al. Improving PCI outcomes using postprocedural physiology and intravascular imaging. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2021;14:2415&#x2013;2430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida M. Novel applications of the hybrid IVUS-OCT imaging system. JACC Asia. 2025;5:242&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada K, Ikeda K, Honda Y. Enhancing PCI outcomes with postprocedural Murray law-based quantitative flow ratio. JACC Asia. 2025;5:71&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>