<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40920457</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0844</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of heart failure</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Heart Fail</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The CONDUCT-AF trial: Rationale and design of a prospective, randomized, multicentre study comparing conduction system and biventricular pacing in patients undergoing atrioventricular node ablation for heart failure with atrial fibrillation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ejhf.70013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">There is a lack of data from randomized clinical trials comparing treatment outcomes between conduction system pacing (CSP) modalities and biventricular pacing (BVP) in symptomatic patients with refractory atrial fibrillation (AF) scheduled for atrioventricular node ablation (AVNA). The CONDUCT-AF investigates whether CSP is non-inferior to BVP in improving left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) and clinical outcomes in heart failure (HF) patients with symptomatic AF undergoing AVNA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study is an investigator-initiated, prospective, randomized, multicentre clinical trial conducted across 10 European centres, enrolling 82 patients with symptomatic AF, HF with reduced LVEF, and narrow QRS. Participants will be randomized 1:1 to CSP or BVP with subsequent AVNA and followed for at least 24&#x2009;months. The primary endpoint is the change in LVEF after 6&#x2009;months. Secondary endpoints will include time to the first occurrence of worsening HF or cardiovascular death and its individual components, total number of HF hospitalizations, change in quality of life, N-terminal pro-B-type natriuretic peptide, 6-min walk test distance, and safety outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The CONDUCT-AF trial will provide critical insights into the optimal pacing modality for patients with HF and refractory AF undergoing AVNA. Recruitment is expected to conclude in 2025, with the first study results anticipated in 2026.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). European Journal of Heart Failure published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Cardiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ivanovski</LastName><ForeName>Maja</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Ljubljana, Faculty of Medicine, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mrak</LastName><ForeName>Miha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Me&#x17e;nar</LastName><ForeName>Anja Zupan</ForeName><Initials>AZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jan</LastName><ForeName>Matev&#x17e;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pestrea</LastName><ForeName>Catalin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Interventional Cardiology, Brasov County Emergency Clinical Hospital, Brasov, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brusich</LastName><ForeName>Sandro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Cardiovascular Diseases, Clinical Hospital Centre Rijeka, Rijeka, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Rijeka, Department of Internal Medicine, Medical Faculty, Rijeka, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogyi</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central-Hospital of Northern Pest - Military Hospital, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Semmelweis University, Centre for Translational Medicine, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhont</LastName><ForeName>Sebastiaan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Ziekenhuis Oost-Limburg A.V., Genk, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hasselt University, Faculty of Medicine and Life Sciences, Diepenbeek, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juri&#x161;i&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Zrinka</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Center Split, Split, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Traykov</LastName><ForeName>Vassil</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Invasive Electrophysiology, Clinic of Cardiology, Acibadem City Clinic Tokuda University Hospital, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nikoli&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Borka Pezo</ForeName><Initials>BP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mullens</LastName><ForeName>Wilfried</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Ziekenhuis Oost-Limburg A.V., Genk, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hasselt University, Faculty of Medicine and Life Sciences, Diepenbeek, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x17d;i&#x17e;ek</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5029-3989</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department, University Medical Centre Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Ljubljana, Faculty of Medicine, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Heart Fail</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887595</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1388-9842</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atrioventricular node ablation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biventricular pacing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Conduction system pacing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart failure</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40920457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.70013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Shoureshi P, Tan AY, Koneru J, Ellenbogen KA, Kaszala K, Huizar JF. Arrhythmia&#x2010;induced cardiomyopathy: JACC state&#x2010;of&#x2010;the&#x2010;art review. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024;83:2214&#x2013;2232. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.03.416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung R, Burri H. Role of conduction system pacing in ablate and pace strategies for atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J Suppl 2023;25:G56&#x2013;G62. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartjsupp/suad119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joza J, Burri H, Andrade JG, Linz D, Ellenbogen KA, Vernooy K. Atrioventricular node ablation for atrial fibrillation in the era of conduction system pacing. Eur Heart J 2024;45:4887&#x2013;4901. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae656</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naito M, David D, Michelson EL, Schaffenburg M, Dreifus LS. The hemodynamic consequences of cardiac arrhythmias: Evaluation of the relative roles of abnormal atrioventricular sequencing, irregularity of ventricular rhythm and atrial fibrillation in a canine model. Am Heart J 1983;106:284&#x2013;291. https://doi.org/10.1016/0002&#x2010;8703(83)90194&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling LH, Khammy O, Byrne M, Amirahmadi F, Foster A, Li G, et al. Irregular rhythm adversely influences calcium handling in ventricular myocardium: Implications for the interaction between heart failure and atrial fibrillation. Circ Heart Fail 2012;5:786&#x2013;793. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.112.968321</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daoud EG, Weiss R, Bahu M, Knight BP, Bogun F, Goyal R, et al. Effect of an irregular ventricular rhythm on cardiac output. Am J Cardiol 1996;78:1433&#x2013;1436. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0002&#x2010;9149(97)89297&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohns C, Fox H, Marrouche NF, Crijns HJGM, Costard&#x2010;Jaeckle A, Bergau L, et al.; CASTLE HTx Investigators. Catheter ablation in end&#x2010;stage heart failure with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med 2023;389:1380&#x2013;1389. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2306037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brachmann J, Sohns C, Andresen D, Siebels J, Sehner S, Boersma L, et al. Atrial fibrillation burden and clinical outcomes in heart failure: The CASTLE&#x2010;AF trial. JACC Clin Electrophysiol 2021;7:594&#x2013;603. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacep.2020.11.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer DL, Mark DB, Robb RA, Monahan KH, Bahnson TD, Poole JE, et al.; CABANA Investigators. Effect of catheter ablation vs antiarrhythmic drug therapy on mortality, stroke, bleeding, and cardiac arrest among patients with atrial fibrillation: The CABANA randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2019;321:1261&#x2013;1274. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2019.0693</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gelder IC, Rienstra M, Bunting KV, Casado&#x2010;Arroyo R, Caso V, Crijns HJGM, et al.; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2024 ESC Guidelines for the management of atrial fibrillation developed in collaboration with the European Association for Cardio&#x2010;Thoracic Surgery (EACTS). Eur Heart J 2024;45:3314&#x2013;3414. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joglar JA, Chung MK, Armbruster AL, Benjamin EJ, Chyou JY, Cronin EM, et al. 2023 ACC/AHA/ACCP/HRS guideline for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation: A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation 2024;149:e1&#x2013;e156. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calkins H, Reynolds MR, Spector P, Sondhi M, Xu Y, Martin A, et al. Treatment of atrial fibrillation with antiarrhythmic drugs or radiofrequency ablation: Two systematic literature reviews and meta&#x2010;analyses. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol 2009;2:349&#x2013;361. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCEP.108.824789</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan ES, Rienstra M, Wiesfeld AC, Schoonderwoerd BA, Hobbel HH, Van Gelder IC. Long&#x2010;term outcome of the atrioventricular node ablation and pacemaker implantation for symptomatic refractory atrial fibrillation. Europace 2008;10:412&#x2013;418. https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/eun020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Fang T, Cheng Z. Comparison of the efficacy and safety endpoints of five therapies for atrial fibrillation: A network meta&#x2010;analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med 2022;9:853149. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2022.853149</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee NA, Upadhyay GA, Ellenbogen KA, McAlister FA, Choudhry NK, Singh JP. Atrioventricular nodal ablation in atrial fibrillation: A meta&#x2010;analysis and systematic review. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol 2012;5:68&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCEP.111.967810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernooy K, Dijkman B, Cheriex EC, Prinzen FW, Crijns HJ. Ventricular remodeling during long&#x2010;term right ventricular pacing following His bundle ablation. Am J Cardiol 2006;97:1223&#x2013;1227. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjcard.2005.11.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brignole M, Pokushalov E, Pentimalli F, Palmisano P, Chieffo E, Occhetta E, et al.; APAF&#x2010;CRT Investigators. A randomized controlled trial of atrioventricular junction ablation and cardiac resynchronization therapy in patients with permanent atrial fibrillation and narrow QRS. Eur Heart J 2018;39:3999&#x2013;4008. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehy555</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brignole M, Pentimalli F, Palmisano P, Landolina M, Quartieri F, Occhetta E, et al.; APAF&#x2010;CRT Trial Investigators. AV junction ablation and cardiac resynchronization for patients with permanent atrial fibrillation and narrow QRS: The APAF&#x2010;CRT mortality trial. Eur Heart J 2021;42:4731&#x2013;4739. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehab569</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruschitzka F, Abraham WT, Singh JP, Bax JJ, Borer JS, Brugada J, et al.; EchoCRT Study Group. Cardiac&#x2010;resynchronization therapy in heart failure with a narrow QRS complex. N Engl J Med 2013;369:1395&#x2013;1405. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1306687</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Su L, Wu S, Xu L, Xiao F, Zhou X, et al. Benefits of permanent His bundle pacing combined with atrioventricular node ablation in atrial fibrillation patients with heart failure with both preserved and reduced left ventricular ejection fraction. J Am Heart Assoc 2017;6:e005309. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.116.005309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillai A, Kolominsky J, Koneru JN, Kron J, Shepard RK, Kalahasty G, et al. Atrioventricular junction ablation in patients with conduction system pacing leads: A comparison of His&#x2010;bundle vs left bundle branch area pacing leads. Heart Rhythm 2022;19:1116&#x2013;1123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2022.03.1222</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert J, Kovacsovics A, Brito R, Masson N, Burri H. Mid&#x2010;term performance of His bundle pacing and usefulness of backup leads. Europace 2024;26:euae168. https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euae168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x17d;i&#x17e;ek D, Antoli&#x10d; B, Me&#x17e;nar AZ, Zavrl&#x2010;D&#x17e;ananovi&#x107; D, Jan M, &#x160;tublar J, et al. Biventricular versus His bundle pacing after atrioventricular node ablation in heart failure patients with narrow QRS. Acta Cardiol 2022;77:222&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.1080/00015385.2021.1903196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanovski M, Mrak M, Me&#x17e;nar AZ, &#x17d;i&#x17e;ek D. Biventricular versus conduction system pacing after atrioventricular node ablation in heart failure patients with atrial fibrillation. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis 2022;9:209. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcdd9070209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glikson M, Nielsen JC, Kronborg MB, Michowitz Y, Auricchio A, Barbash IM, et al.; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2021 ESC Guidelines on cardiac pacing and cardiac resynchronization therapy. Eur Heart J 2021;42:3427&#x2013;3520. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehab364</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burri H, Jastrzebski M, Cano &#xd3;, &#x10c;urila K, de Pooter J, Huang W, et al. EHRA clinical consensus statement on conduction system pacing implantation: Endorsed by the Asia Pacific Heart Rhythm Society (APHRS), Canadian Heart Rhythm Society (CHRS), and Latin American Heart Rhythm Society (LAHRS). Europace 2023;25:1208&#x2013;1236. https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euad043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Badano LP, Mor&#x2010;Avi V, Afilalo J, Armstrong A, Ernande L, et al. Recommendations for cardiac chamber quantification by echocardiography in adults: An update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging 2015;16:233&#x2013;270. https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjci/jev014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Wang S, Su L, Fu G, Su Y, Chen K, et al. His&#x2010;bundle pacing vs biventricular pacing following atrioventricular nodal ablation in patients with atrial fibrillation and reduced ejection fraction: A multicenter, randomized, crossover study&#xa0;&#x2013;&#xa0;the ALTERNATIVE&#x2010;AF trial. Heart Rhythm 2022;19:1948&#x2013;1955. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2022.07.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Shi J, Zhang Y, Ge X, Zhang X, Fan W, et al. Comparative cost analysis of implanting devices in different cardiac resynchronization therapeutic strategies. Clin Cardiol 2023;46:1227&#x2013;1233. https://doi.org/10.1002/clc.24107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay JCK, Lim ETS, Wong TJ, Feng JJ, Ching CK, Tan BY. Right bundle branch activation during left bundle branch pacing: Marginal gains in left bundle branch pacing&#x2010;optimized cardiac resynchronization therapy and the effects of atrioventricular delay dynamic optimization. Heart Rhythm Case Rep 2023;10:191&#x2013;197. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrcr.2023.12.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai M, Wu S, Wang S, Zheng R, Jiang L, Lian L, et al. Left bundle branch pacing postatrioventricular junction ablation for atrial fibrillation: Propensity score matching with His bundle pacing. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol 2022;15:e010926. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCEP.122.010926</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>