<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40959231</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-2766</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Exploratory research in clinical and social pharmacy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing holistic patient care of black individuals diagnosed with HIV and comorbid chronic conditions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100607</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100607</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100607</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.rcsop.2025.100607</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pharmacists can play a crucial role in delivering the holistic care model. Research suggests that HIV-positive African American patients particularly benefit from this approach compared to other communities. Typically, pharmacists in community pharmacy settings are limited in their access to a patient's medical record, preventing holistic care delivery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study addressed the impact of access to medical records on a holistic patient care approach among pharmacists engaged in medication therapy management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This was a sub-analysis of a randomized controlled trial of the impact of community pharmacist access to medical records during MTM for African Americans diagnosed with HIV and multimorbidity with hypertension (HTN) and/or type 2 diabetes mellitus (DM). A random sample was selected of 30 participants (15 in the intervention arm with access to medical records and 15 in the control arm) who completed at least seven study visits between 2019 and 2021. A quantitative content analysis of the study pharmacist visit notes was conducted to identify themes of pharmacist interventions. The percentages of the theme's repetitions were compared across study groups using the Fisher exact test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Thirteen themes were extracted from the pharmacists' visit notes. The intervention group demonstrated a higher repetition of themes concerning any disease, medicine, exercise/weight/diet, sexual, sleeping, smoking, alcohol/marijuana, vaccination, will/power of attorney, food/ housing, and depression/stress. Themes related to career goals and recommending consultation with a provider were repeated more in the control group. The two study groups had statistically significant differences in the percentages of repetition of seven themes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Access to medical records enables pharmacists to focus more on mental health, lifestyle, and social determinants of health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleming</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Economics and Policy, Chapman University School of Pharmacy, Harry and Diane Rinker Health Science Campus, 9401 Jeronimo Road, Irvine, CA 92618-1908, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nedjat</LastName><ForeName>Saharnaz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery, University of California, Irvine, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schommer</LastName><ForeName>Jon C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Care &amp; Health Systems, University of Minnesota College of Pharmacy, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hodge</LastName><ForeName>Crystal K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of North Texas Health Science Center System College of Pharmacy, Fort Worth, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918266300706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2667-2766</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AIDS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Holistic patient care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacists</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40959231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12433802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rcsop.2025.100607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-2766(25)00048-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Navickas R., Petric V.K., Feigl A.B., Seychell M. Multimorbidity: what do we know? What should we do? J Comorb. 2016;6:4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5556462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29090166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinnott C., Mc Hugh S., Browne J., Bradley C. GPs&#x2019; perspectives on the management of patients with multimorbidity: systematic review and synthesis of qualitative research. BMJ Open. 2013;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3773648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24038011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodger A.J., Lodwick R., Schechter M., et al. Mortality in well controlled HIV in the continuous antiretroviral therapy arms of the SMART and ESPRIT trials compared with the general population. Aids. 2013;27:973&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23698063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Dakkak I., Patel S., McCann E., Gadkari A., Prajapati G., Maiese E.M. The impact of specific HIV treatment-related adverse events on adherence to antiretroviral therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. AIDS Care. 2013;25:400&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3613968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22908886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paisible A.L., Chang C.C., So-Armah K.A., et al. HIV infection, cardiovascular disease risk factor profile, and risk for acute myocardial infarction. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2015;68:209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25588033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Neyman S.M., Davis K., Zohoori N., Broughton K.S., Moore C.E., Miketinas D. Racial disparities and prevalence of cardiovascular disease risk factors, cardiometabolic risk factors, and cardiovascular health metrics among US adults: NHANES 2011-2018. Sci Rep. 2022;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9663590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36376533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magodoro I.M., Okello S., Dungeni M., Castle A.C., Mureyani S., Danaei G. Association between HIV and prevalent hypertension and diabetes mellitus in South Africa: analysis of a nationally representative cross-sectional survey. Int J Infect Dis. 2022;121:217&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9337715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35597557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera A.S., Rusie L., Plank M., et al. Association of Cumulative Viral Load with the incidence of hypertension and diabetes in people with HIV. Hypertension. 2022;79:e135&#x2013;e142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9673163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36378919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazen R.J., Halbur D., Mills B., Kirkham H.S., Hou J. Evaluation of medication therapy issues, resolutions, and adherence among persons with HIV in the pharmacist-led patient-centered HIV care model. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2021;88:96&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34034304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horace A.E. Pharmacists&#x2019; research contributions in the fight against HIV/AIDs. AIDS Res Treat. 2012;2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23193465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamanzadeh V., Jasemi M., Valizadeh L., Keogh B., Taleghani F. Effective factors in providing holistic care: a qualitative study. Indian J Palliat Care. 2015;21:214&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26009677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler L., Zona S., Patel A.A., Brittle C., Shea L. How can pharmacists better support patients with chronic diseases? The patient perspective. J Am Pharm Assoc. 2003;2023 1776-1784.e1773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37696490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturrock A., Bissett S.M., Carrozzo M., et al. Qualitative interview study exploring the early identification and referral of patients with suspected head and neck cancer by community pharmacists in England. BMJ Open. 2023;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36882255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qudah B., Thakur T., Chewning B. Factors influencing patient participation in medication counseling at the community pharmacy: a systematic review. Res Soc Adm Pharm. 2021;17:1863&#x2013;1876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33766505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch S., Moles R., Viardot A., Deweerd P., Daly S., Lee K. Connecting the dots of care: a pilot study linking aboriginal and/or Torres Strait islander peoples with diabetes care in hospital, using hospital pharmacists. Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10641541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renet S., Chaumais M.C., Gallant-Dewavrin M., et al. Knowledge exchange between patient and pharmacist: a mixed methods study to explore the role of pharmacists in patient education and counseling in asthma and pulmonary arterial hypertension. Ann Pharm Fr. 2023;81:53&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35738438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoro O., Odedina F.T. Improving medication adherence in African-American women living with HIV/AIDS: leveraging the provider role and peer involvement. AIDS Care. 2016;28:179&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26278429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siaw M.Y.L., Ko Y., Malone D.C., et al. Impact of pharmacist-involved collaborative care on the clinical, humanistic and cost outcomes of high-risk patients with type 2 diabetes (IMPACT): a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2017;42:475&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28449205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara K.P., O&#x2019;Reilly S.L., Dunbar J.A., et al. A pilot study evaluating multiple risk factor interventions by community pharmacists to prevent cardiovascular disease: the PAART CVD pilot project. Ann Pharmacother. 2012;46:183&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai A.L., Carretta H., Beitsch L.M., Watson L., Munn J., Mehriary S. Medication therapy management programs: promises and pitfalls. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2014;20:1162&#x2013;1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10441009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25443511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brummel A.R., Soliman A.M., Carlson A.M., de Oliveira D.R. Optimal diabetes care outcomes following face-to-face medication therapy management services. Popul Health Manage. 2013;16:28&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23113628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marupuru S., Roether A., Guimond A.J., Stanley C., Pesqueira T., Axon D.R. A systematic review of clinical outcomes from pharmacist provided medication therapy management (MTM) among patients with diabetes, hypertension, or dyslipidemia. Healthcare (Basel) 2022:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9318817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35885734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planas L.G., Crosby K.M., Mitchell K.D., Farmer K.C. Evaluation of a hypertension medication therapy management program in patients with diabetes. J Am Pharm Assoc. 2003;2009(49):164&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd K.K., Hou J.G., Bush T., et al. Adherence and viral suppression among participants of the patient-centered human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) care model project: a collaboration between community-based pharmacists and HIV clinical providers. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;70:789&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6821576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd K.K., Hardnett F., Clay P.G., et al. Retention in HIV care among participants in the patient-centered HIV care model: a collaboration between community-based pharmacists and primary medical providers. AIDS Patient Care STDs. 2019;33:58&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6379900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30648888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Pharmacists Association Medication therapy management in pharmacy practice: core elements of an MTM service model (version 2.0) J Am Pharm Assoc. 2003;2008(48):341&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas E.I., Dupotey N.M., De Loof H. Comprehensive medication management services with a holistic point of view, a scoping review. Pharmacy (Basel) 2023:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9964776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36827675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gernant S.A., Zillich A.J., Snyder M.E. Access to medical records&#x2019; impact on community pharmacist-delivered medication therapy management: a pilot from the medication safety research network of Indiana (Rx-SafeNet) J Pharm Pract. 2018;31:642&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29017421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe K., Scacco J.M. The international encyclopedia of communication research methods. 2017. Content analysis, quantitative; pp. 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedoose L. SocioCultural Research Consultants, LLC; Los Angeles, CA: 2021. Dedoose Version 9.0. 17, Cloud Application for Managing, Analyzing, and Presenting Qualitative and Mixed Method Research Data.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braveman P., Gottlieb L. The social determinants of health: it&#x2019;s time to consider the causes of the causes. Public Health Rep. 2014;129(suppl 2):19&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24385661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoro O.N., DeVuyst-Miller S.A., MacDonald D.A., et al. Integrating social determinants into pharmacotherapy courses: a case-based learning approach. Curr Pharm Teach Learn. 2022;14:1438&#x2013;1447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36154989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder M.E., Adeoye-Olatunde O.A., Gernant S.A., et al. A user-centered evaluation of medication therapy management alerts for community pharmacists: recommendations to improve usability and usefulness. Res Soc Adm Pharm. 2021;17:1433&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9178508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipman A.G., Deffenbaugh J.H., Jr. Improving patient care by using medical records to transmit medication orders. Hosp Formul. 1989;24 653&#x2013;655, 658, 663&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10296354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agomo C., Udoh A., Kpokiri E., Osuku-Opio J. Community pharmacists&#x2019; contribution to public health: assessing the global evidence base. Clin Pharm. 2018;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motlohi N.F., Wiafe E., Mensah K.B., Padayachee N., Petrus R., Bangalee V. A systematic review of the role of community pharmacists in the prevention and control of cardiovascular diseases: the perceptions of patients. Syst Rev. 2023;12:160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10500864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37705090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Ansari W., Stock C. Explaining the gender difference in self-rated health among university students in Egypt. Women Health. 2016;56:731&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26886289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen J.T., Andersen J.S., Tj&#xf8;nneland A., Andersen Z.J. Determinants related to gender differences in general practice utilization: Danish diet, Cancer and health cohort. Scand J Prim Health Care. 2016;34:240&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27421064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Hunt K., Nazareth I., Freemantle N., Petersen I. Do men consult less than women? An analysis of routinely collected UK general practice data. BMJ Open. 2013;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3753483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertakis K.D., Azari R., Helms L.J., Callahan E.J., Robbins J.A. Gender differences in the utilization of health care services. J Fam Pract. 2000;49:147&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10718692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redondo-Sendino A., Guallar-Castill&#xf3;n P., Banegas J.R., Rodr&#xed;guez-Artalejo F. Gender differences in the utilization of health-care services among the older adult population of Spain. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1525176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16780576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikka N., DeLong A., Kamano J., et al. Sex differences in health status, healthcare utilization, and costs among individuals with elevated blood pressure: the LARK study from Western Kenya. BMC Public Health. 2021;21:948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akosionu O., Virnig B., Call K.T., Yuan J.M., Chanthanouvong S., Nguyen R.H. The impact of gender differences in attitudes and beliefs concerning HBV vaccination and screening in the Lao community. J Immigr Minor Health. 2016;18:277&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25612922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelbrecht M.C., Kigozi N.G., Heunis J.C. Factors associated with limited vaccine literacy: lessons learnt from COVID-19. Vaccines (Basel) 2022:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9229188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35746473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flor L.S., Friedman J., Spencer C.N., et al. Quantifying the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on gender equality on health, social, and economic indicators: a comprehensive review of data from march, 2020, to September, 2021. Lancet. 2022;399:2381&#x2013;2397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8890763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlassoff C. Gender differences in determinants and consequences of health and illness. J Health Popul Nutr. 2007;25:47&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3013263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17615903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conover C.J., Arno P., Weaver M., Ang A., Ettner S.L. Income and employment of people living with combined HIV/AIDS, chronic mental illness, and substance abuse disorders. J Ment Health Policy Econ. 2006;9:71&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17007485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>