<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40841644</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of mobile application-based education on illness perception in patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1097</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1097</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1097</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-025-03759-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Illness perception (IP) significantly influences recovery and self-care in patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), particularly in managing post-intervention complications. Although effective education is acknowledged as a way to enhance IP, using novel technologies such as mobile apps in this area has received less attention. This study aimed to evaluate the impact of education delivered through mobile apps on IP in patients undergoing PCI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS">A randomized controlled trial was conducted with 110 patients undergoing PCI at Shahid Rajaee Hospital in Karaj, Iran, in 2023. Patients were enrolled consecutively and assigned through block randomization to either an intervention group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;55) or a control group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;55). The intervention group received educational content derived from the five dimensions of Leventhal&#x2019;s Common-Sense Model of Illness Perception through a mobile app. The control group received routine hospital care. Data were collected using a demographic characteristics form and the Illness Perception Questionnaire-Brief (IPQ-B) at baseline and four weeks after the intervention. The collected data were analyzed with SPSS version 21, using descriptive and inferential statistical tests. Statistical significance was established at <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">The two groups were homogeneous regarding age, gender, body mass index, occupation, education level, smoking status, family history of coronary artery disease, presence of stents, underlying diseases, and balloon angioplasty (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The results indicated no significant differences between the experimental and control groups regarding IP mean score and the median scores of its dimensions (consequences, timeline, control, treatment, identity, concerns about the illness, emotional responses, and concerns about IP) at baseline (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). A statistically significant improvement in IP score and its dimensions was observed in the intervention group compared to the control group (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). More specifically, the experimental group displayed a significantly lower mean score of IP and median scores of its dimensions than the control group after the intervention (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Mobile app-based education can enhance IP in patients undergoing PCI. Thus, these findings support the integration of mobile apps into routine nursing care to enhance IP in patients undergoing PCI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION">The study was registered with the Iranian Registry of Clinical Trials (IRCT) with the following details:</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION CODE">IRCT20110912007529N27.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION DATE">January 23, 2023.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salavati</LastName><ForeName>Khatereh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6980-3221</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Faculty of Nursing, Gonabad University of Medical Sciences, Gonabad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rejeh</LastName><ForeName>Nahid</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6916-6514</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Faculty of Nursing &amp; Midwifery, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rohani</LastName><ForeName>Farhad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2269-3843</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Health and Psychiatric Nursing, Faculty of Nursing, Gonabad University of Medical Sciences, Gonabad, Iran. f.rohani96@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Illness perception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobile app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol was approved by the ethics committee of Shahed University with the ethics code IR.SHAHED.REC.1401.102. The present study was conducted in accordance with the revised Declaration of Helsinki, which outlines ethical principles guiding physicians and other researchers in medical studies involving human subjects. All participants were informed of the voluntary nature of their participation, the commitment to confidentiality and anonymity of their data, and their right to withdraw at any time without consequences. Informed consent forms were signed by all participants (both control and intervention groups) prior to data collection. Moreover, the study&#x2019;s purpose, their role, and their rights were explicated to them. Only those who agreed to participate signed the consent form voluntarily. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40841644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12372300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-03759-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-025-03759-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nissa N, Jamwal S, Neshat M. A technical comparative heart disease prediction framework using boosting ensemble techniques. Computation. 2024;12(1):15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi MSS, Khadem Vatan K. Determine the burden of myocardial infarction. Tehran Uni Med J. 2019;7(3):208&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamali A, Yavari S, Yazdi B. Prophylactic effect of Amiodarone and in combination with vitamin C in reducing atrial fibrillation after coronary artery bypass. Eur J Transl Myol. 2021;31(3):8991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahjehan RD, Bhutta BS. Coronary artery disease.2024 December 2, 2024. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK564304/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark AMHL, Vandermeer B, McAlister FA. Meta-analysis: secondary prevention programs for patients with coronary artery disease. Annals Inter Med. 2005;143(39):659&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16263889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M, Mehta P, Reddy Reddivari AK. Percutaneous Coronary Intervention. 2023 December 15, 2024. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK556123/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan SQ, Ludman PF. Percutaneous coronary intervention. Medicine. 2022;50(7):437&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taglieri NBA, Bacchi Reggiani ML, D&#x2019;Angelo EC, Ghetti G, Bruno M, Palmerini T, Rapezzi C, Gali&#xe8; N, Saia F. Impact of coronary bypass or stenting on mortality and myocardial infarction in stable coronary artery disease. Int J Cardio. 2020;321:73&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32037130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darvishpour AJPN, Salari A, Taleshan Nejad M, Barari F. Comparing the quality of life in patients with cardiovascular diseases before and after coronary angioplasty. J Mazandaran Uni Med Sci. 2016;26(137):206&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salgado R, Paulo N, Zufferey A, Bucher CO. Patient&#x2019;s learning needs and self-efficacy level after percutaneous coronary intervention: A descriptive study. J Clin Nurs. 2023:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36823713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grace SLKS, Brooks D, Arthur H, Scholely P, Suskin N, et al. Illness perceptions among cardiac patients: relation to depressive symptomatology and sex. J Psychosom Res. 2005;59(3):153&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16198188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeineb Z, Jemmali S, Rekik S, Boussaid S, Rahmouni S, Zouaoui K, et al. POS1568-Pare the brief-illness perception questionnaire: a method for assessing the cognitive representation of rheumatic disease. Ann Rheum Dis. 2022;81:1130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger MS, Orbell S. A meta-analytic review of the common-sense model of illness representations. Psychol Health. 2003;18(2):141&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent E, Wilkes C, Koschwanez H, Weinman J, Norton S, Petrie KJ. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the brief illness perception questionnaire. Psychol Health. 2015;30(11):1361&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26181764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cucciniello M, Petracca F, Ciani O, Tarricone R. Development features and study characteristics of mobile health apps in the management of chronic conditions: a systematic review of randomised trials. NPJ Digit Med. 2021;4(1):144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8492762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salavati K, Rejeh N, Rohani F, Nayeri AD. The effect of education through a mobile application on self-care behavior in patients undergoing percutaneous coronary: A randomized clinical trial. Nurs Pract Today. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umeh CA, Reddy M, Dubey A, Yousuf M, Chaudhuri S, Shah S. Home telemonitoring in heart failure patients and the effect of study design on outcome: A literature review. J Telemed Telecare. 2024;30(1):44&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34369171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad Nur KRCT, Kritpracha C. Illness perception and cardiovascular health behaviors in persons with ischemic heart disease: a literature review. GSTF J Nurs Heal Care. 2017;4(2):18&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thagizadeh A, Ghahramanian A, Zamanzadeh V, Aslanabadi N, Onyeka TC, Ramazanzadeh N. Illness perception and cardiovascular risk factors in patients with myocardial infarction undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention in Iran. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2022;22(1):245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9161526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35655125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achmad BF, Setiyarini S, Sutono S, Rasyid F, Fitriawan AS, Kafil RF. Association between illness perception and anxiety undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with acute coronary syndrome: A pilot study. Open Access Macedonian J Med Sci. 2023;11:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sararoudi RMM, Maracy M, Pishghadam E, Kheirabadi G. Efficacy of illness perception focused intervention on quality of life, anxiety, and depression in patients with myocardial infarction. J Res Med Sci. 2017;21(1):125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5348829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28331511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker AL, Peeters G, Morello RT, Norman R, Ayton D, Lefkovits J, et al. Symptoms and feelings valued by patients after a percutaneous coronary intervention: a discrete-choice experiment to inform development of a new patient-reported outcome. BMJ Open. 2018;8(10):e023141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6196865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30341131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari ARL, Ashouri A, Moaddab F, Zaersabet F, Nourisaeed A. Medication adherence and its related factors in patients undergoing coronary artery angioplasty. J Caring Sci. 2018;7(4):213&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6311628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang YH, Lai FC, Chang CC, Wan HT. Effects of a skill demonstration video delivered by smartphone on facilitating nursing students&#x2019;s skill competencies and self-confidence: A randomized controlled trial study. Nurse Educ Today. 2019;66:63&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29677580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu LL, Hsiang HC, Tseng YH, Huang SY, Hsieh SI. Nursing students&#x2019; experiences of using a smart phone application for a physical assessment course: A qualitative study. Japan J Nurs Science: JJNS. 2019;16(2):115&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29947101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okolo CA, Babawarun O, Arowoogun JO, Adeniyi AO, Chidi R. The role of mobile health applications in improving patient engagement and health outcomes: A critical review. Int J Sci Res Archive. 2024;11(1):2566&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang A, Cristol D. Handbook of mobile teaching and learning. Springer Berlin; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts W, Lyson H, Speer C, Tovar E, Paz E, Zimlichman E. Cost savings and improved clinical outcomes from a mobile health cardiovascular disease Self-Management program. Value in health. the journal of the International Society for Pharmacoeconomics and Outcomes Research; 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39954854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Gong Y, Zheng B, Fan F, Yi T, Zheng Y, Huo Y. Effects on adherence to a mobile app&#x2013;based self-management digital therapeutics among patients with coronary heart disease: pilot randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2022;10(2):e32251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8889473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajami STF. Features and application of wearable biosensors in medical care. J Res Med Sci. 2015;20(12):1208&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4766830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26958058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Shorey S, Seah B, Chan WX, Tam WWS, Wang W. The effectiveness of psychological interventions on self-care, psychological and health outcomes in patients with chronic heart failure-A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. 2018;78:16&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Hopewell S, Schulz KF, Montori V, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Devereaux PJ et al. CONSORT 2010 explanation and elaboration: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMJ. 2010;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2844943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20332511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negarandeh R, Zolfaghari M, Bashi N, Kiarsi M. Evaluating the effect of monitoring through telephone (tele-monitoring) on self-care behaviors and readmission of patients with heart failure after discharge. Appl Clin Inf. 2019;10(02):261&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6469982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30995686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent E, Petrie KJ, Main J, Weinman J. The brief illness perception questionnaire. J Psychosom Res. 2006;60(6):631&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16731240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ataee EHM, Dalvandi A, Bakhshandeh H. Effect of self-care education on quality of life among patients with permanent pacemaker. Iran J Cardio Nurs. 2013;1(4):40&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheriansararoodi RT. The relationship between myocardial infarction and cognitive schemas from myocardial infarction. J Health Psychol. 2009;6(6):29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masaeli N, Bagherian R, Kheirabadi G, Khedri A, Mahaki B. Psychometric properties of the Persian version of the brief illness perception questionnaire in chronic diseases. J Res Rehabil Sci. 2018;14(6):332&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Cobo C, Bernal-Jim&#xe9;nez M&#xc1;, Calle G, Gheorghe LL, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Barrios A, Ca&#xf1;adas D, et al. Efficacy of a mobile health app (eMOTIVA) regarding compliance with cardiac rehabilitation guidelines in patients with coronary artery disease: randomized controlled clinical trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2024;12:e55421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11310647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39052330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi YJ, Liu Y, Jiang TT, Zhang HR, Shi TY. Effects of multidisciplinary exercise management on patients after percutaneous coronary intervention: A randomized controlled study. Int J Nurs Sci. 2022;9(3):286&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9305004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Zhao Y, Wu Y. Effectiveness of mobile health applications on clinical outcomes and health behaviors in patients with coronary heart disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Sci. 2024;11(2):258&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38707688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khani Jeihooni, Fereidouni A, Afzali Harsini Z, Kavi P, Haghshenas E, Akbari H. Effect of educational program on nursing section lifestyle of myocardial infarction patients in Iranian population. J Clin Diagnos Res. 2018;12(9):6&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikkhah Beydokhti, Basiri Moghadam E, Sajjadi K, Basiri Moghadam M. A comparison of the effect of multimedia and telephone education on illness perception in patients with myocardial infarction after discharge: A randomized clinical trial. Hayat J. 2023;29(1):8&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsworthy MAFW, Thygesen H, Aldersley MA, Rowe IA, Jones RL. Patient Understanding of liver cirrhosis and improvement using multimedia education. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2017;8(3):214&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5502237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28706622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taqfaghodi BMB, Sadeghi R, Tol A, Yakanejad MS. The effect of educational intervention on the nutritional knowledge, illness perception and dietary adherence in middle-aged women with hypertension: application of the transtheoretical model. J School Public Health Inst Public Health Res. 2022;19(4):433&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahardika IMR, Widyandari NMAS. The effectiveness of leaflet and video educational media through Whatsapp toward the knowledge of type 2 DM patients. Babali Nurs Res. 2023;4(1):43&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu. T, Wang J, Lin HL, Lee HF, Lin CT, Chieh LY, et al. Multimedia-assisted instruction on pain assessment learning of new nurses: a quasi-experimental study. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6398238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sin NL. The protective role of positive well-being in cardiovascular disease: review of current evidence, mechanisms, and clinical implications. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2016;18:106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5060088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27612475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoseinzadeh T, Paryad E, Asiri S, Kazem Nezhad Leili E. Relationship between perception of illness and general self-efficacy in coronary artery disease patients. J Holist Nurs Midwifery. 2012;22(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafi Ghezeljeh T, Davoudi M, Vakilian F. The impact of using a smartphone-based application on medication adherence in people with heart failure. Nurs Midwifery J. 2019;17(6):494&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitsiou S, Gerber BS, Kansal MM, Buchholz SW, Chen J, Ruppar T, et al. Patient-centered mobile health technology intervention to improve self-care in patients with chronic heart failure: protocol for a feasibility randomized controlled trial. Contemp Clin Trials. 2021;106:106433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33991686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhane-Medina NZ, Castillo-May&#xe9;n R, Luque B, Rubio SJ, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Domingo T, Cuadrado E, Tabernero C. A brief mHealth-Based psychological intervention in emotion regulation to promote positive subjective Well-Being in cardiovascular disease patients: A Non-Randomized controlled trial. Healthcare. 2022;10(9):1640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9498759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36141252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salavati K, Rejeh N, Rohani F, Nayeri AD. The effect of education through a mobile application on self-care behavior in patients undergoing percutaneous coronary: A randomized clinical trial. Nurs Pract Today. 2024;11(3):272&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes ACM, Coelho T, Prata R, Maciel J. Impact of a brief psychological intervention on lifestyle, risk factors and disease knowledge during phase i of cardiac rehabilitation after acute coronary syndrome. Rev Port Cardiol Engl. 2019;38:361&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanju&#xe1;n PM, P&#xe9;rez-Garc&#xed;a T, Berm&#xfa;dez AM, Arranz J, Castro H. A. A randomised trial of a positive intervention to promote well-being in cardiac patients. Appl Psychol Health Well-Being. 2016;8:64&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26876425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clays EPP, Lu&#x161;trek M, Pioggia G, Derboven J, Vrana M, et al. Proof-of-concept trial results of the heartman mobile personal health system for self-management in congestive heart failure. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):5663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33707523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wonggom PNP, Clark RA, Barry T, Burdeniuk C, Nesbitt K, et al. Effectiveness of an avatar educational application for improving heart failure patients&#x2019; knowledge and self-care behaviors: a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Adv Nurs. 2020;76(9):2401&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32395836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmaderer MSSL, Loecker C, Lier L, Lundgren SW, Wichman C, et al. Mobile health self-management interventions for patients with heart failure: a pilot study. J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2021;1(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10199463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34369914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koehler F, Koehler K, Deckwart O, Prescher S, Wegscheider K, Kirwan B-A, et al. Efficacy of telemedical interventional management in patients with heart failure (TIM-HF2): a randomised, controlled, parallel-group, unmasked trial. Lancet. 2018;392(10152):1047&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>