<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40980629</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1735-9066</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Sep-Oct</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Iranian journal of nursing and midwifery research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Ankle-brachial Index in Patients with Type 2 Diabetes: A Randomized Clinical Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>732</StartPage><EndPage>738</EndPage><MedlinePgn>732-738</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_174_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Vitamin D deficiency in patients with type 2 diabetes (T2D) is recognized as a risk factor for developing vascular complications and poor disease control. This study aimed to determine the effect of vitamin D supplementation on ankle-brachial index (ABI) in patients with T2D.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This two-group clinical trial was conducted among 56 patients with T2D. Participants were recruited through sampling conducted in the diabetes clinic of Velayat Hospital in Qazvin, Iran. They were allocated to the intervention and control groups using a simple blocked randomization method. The intervention group received an oral dose of 1000 IU/day of vitamin D. Data were collected using a checklist that included demographic information, laboratory measurements, and ABI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After the intervention, the score in the intervention group (ABI &lt; 0.9: t<sub>32</sub> = 4.082, <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001) was significantly different from the control group (ABI &#x2265; 1.3: t<sub>20</sub> = -2.711, <i>p</i> = 0.013). After the intervention, significant differences were also observed regarding the mean ranges of vitamin D (t<sub>54</sub> = 10.07, <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001), fasting blood glucose (FBG) (t<sub>54</sub> = -2.97, <i>p</i> = 0.004), 2-hour post-prandial blood glucose (2hpp) (t<sub>54</sub> = -2.55, <i>p</i> = 0.013), and hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) (t<sub>54</sub> = -3.02, <i>p</i> = 0.004) between the two groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results of this study revealed that a daily intake of 1000 IU of vitamin D significantly improved the ABI, serum concentration of vitamin D, FBG, and HbA1c in patients with T2D. These findings suggest that vitamin D supplementation may be considered an effective approach for preventing arterial diseases and improving blood sugar control.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Iranian Journal of Nursing and Midwifery Research.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yekefallah</LastName><ForeName>Leili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Social Determinants of Health Research Center, School of Nursing and Midwifery, Qazvin University of Medical Sciences, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jalalpour</LastName><ForeName>Azadeh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Metabolic Diseases Research Center, School of Medicine, Qazvin University of Medical Sciences, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aghakhanbeigi</LastName><ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Student Research Committee, School of Nursing and Midwifery, Qazvin University of Medical Sciences, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Namdar</LastName><ForeName>Peyman</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, School of Medicine, Qazvin University of Medical Sciences, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mafi</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing , Non-communicable Diseases Research Center, Research Institute for Prevention of Non-communicable Diseases, Qazvin University of Medical Sciences, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101558775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1735-9066</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ankle-brachial index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral arterial disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin D</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Nothing to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40980629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12445898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_174_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJNMR-30-732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hossain MJ, Al-Mamun M, Islam MR. Diabetes mellitus, the fastest growing global public health concern: Early detection should be focused. Health Sci Rep. 2024;7:e2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10958528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker K, Apelqvist J, Lipsky BA, Van Netten JJ International Working Group on the Diabetic Foot. The 2015 IWGDF guidance documents on prevention and management of foot problems in diabetes: Development of an evidence-based global consensus. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2016;32((Suppl 1)):2&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26409930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghani A, Korozhdehi H, Khalilzadeh SH, Fallahzadeh H, Rahmanian V. Prevalence of diabetes and its correlates among Iranian adults: Results of the first phase of Shahedieh cohort study. Health Sci Rep. 2023;6:e1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37021014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Wang W, Liu J, Xie M, Liu Q, Li S. Vascular complications of diabetes: A narrative review. Medicine (Baltimore) 2023;102:e35285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10553000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37800828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansour A, Mousa M, Abdelmannan D, Tay G, Hassoun A, Alsafar H. Microvascular and macrovascular complications of type 2 diabetes mellitus: Exome wide association analyses. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2023;14:1143067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10076756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37033211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abugoukh TM, Al Sharaby A, Elshaikh AO, Joda M, Madni A, Ahmed I, et al. Does vitamin D have a role in diabetes? Cureus. 2022;14:e30432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36407246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Md Isa Z, Amsah N, Ahmad N. The impact of vitamin D deficiency and insufficiency on the outcome of type 2 diabetes mellitus patients: A systematic review. Nutrients. 2023;15:2310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10223393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37242192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia J, Tao X, Tian Z, Liu J, Ye X, Zhan Y. Vitamin D receptor deficiency increases systolic blood pressure by upregulating the renin-angiotensin system and autophagy. Exp Ther Med. 2022;23:314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35369533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghozali NM, Giribabu N, Salleh N. Mechanisms linking vitamin D deficiency to impaired metabolism: An overview. Int J Endocrinol. 2022;2022:6453882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9293580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35859985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Kumar S, Biswas K, Jyoti A, Tripathi A. Vitamin D status in peripheral vascular diseases: A longitudinal prospective study. Asian J Med Sci. 2022;13:113&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartore G, Caprino R, Ragazzi E, Bianchi L, Lapolla A, Piarulli F. The ankle-brachial index for assessing the prevalence of peripheral artery disease and cardiovascular risk in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2023;33:560&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donohue CM, Adler JV, Bolton LL. Peripheral arterial disease screening and diagnostic practice: A scoping review. Int Wound J. 2020;17:32&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7948585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31680419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford F, Welch K, Andras A, Chappell FM. Ankle brachial index for the diagnosis of lower limb peripheral arterial disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;9:CD010680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6457627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27623758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav A, Sawant V, Singh Bedi V, Yadav K. Dyslipidemia and peripheral arterial disease. Indian Heart J. 2024;76((Suppl 1)):S86&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11019313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38224837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leelathanalerk A, Piankarnka N, Srimongkon P, Chanasopon S, Phumart P, Paktipat P, et al. Quality of life and utility of patients with peripheral artery disease (PAD): A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2024;14:28823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11582567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39572676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King RW, Canonico ME, Bonaca MP, Hess CN. Management of peripheral arterial disease: Lifestyle modifications and medical therapies. J Soc Cardiovasc Angiogr Interv. 2022;1:100513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11307706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39132343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider F, Ghafoor H, Hassan OF, Farooqui K, Bel Khair AO, Shoaib F. Vitamin D and cardiovascular diseases: An update. Cureus. 2023;15:e49734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10757591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apivatthakakul A, Jaruvongvanich S, Upala S, Jaruvongvanich V. Association between serum vitamin D levels and retinal vascular occlusion: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Cureus. 2024;16:e64356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11316675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39130960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazidi M, Karimi E, Rezaie P, Vatanparast H. The impact of vitamin D supplement intake on vascular endothelial function;a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Food Nutr Res. 2017;61:1273574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor PN, Davies JS. A review of the growing risk of vitamin D toxicity from inappropriate practice. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2018;84:1121&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5980613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29498758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade JM, Grandoff PG, Schneider ST. Vitamin D intake and factors associated with self-reported vitamin D deficiency among US adults: A 2021 cross-sectional study. Front Nutr. 2022;9:899300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35634404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guirguis-Blake JM, Evans CV, Redmond N, Lin JS. Screening for peripheral artery disease using the ankle-brachial index: Updated evidence report and systematic review for the US preventive services task force. JAMA. 2018;320:184&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29998343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;ceres-Farf&#xe1;n L, Moreno-Loaiza M, Cubas WS. Ankle-brachial index: More than a diagnostic test? Arch Peru Cardiol Cir Cardiovasc. 2021;2:254&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10506545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37727667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depczynski B, Young T, White C. A high ankle-brachial index is associated with obesity and low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in patients with diabetes. J Clin Transl Endocrinol. 2018;11:7&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29725581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou W, Ye SD. Relationship between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and lower extremity arterial disease in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients and the analysis of the intervention of vitamin D. J Diabetes Res. 2015;2015:815949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4397474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25922846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anandabaskar N, Selvarajan S, Dkhar SA, Kamalanathan SK, Tamilarasu K, Bobby Z. Effect of vitamin D supplementation on vascular functions and oxidative stress in type 2 diabetic patients with vitamin D deficiency. Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2017;21:555&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28670540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momeni A, Mirhosseini M, Kabiri M, Kheiri S. Effect of vitamin D on proteinuria in type 2 diabetic patients. J Nephropathol. 2017;6:10&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5106877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28042548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemieux P, Weisnagel SJ, Caron AZ, Julien AS, Morisset AS, Carreau AM, et al. Effects of 6-month vitamin D supplementation on insulin sensitivity and secretion: A randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Eur J Endocrinol. 2019;181:287&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31344685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salih YA, Rasool MT, Ahmed IH, Mohammed AA. Impact of vitamin D level on glycemic control in diabetes mellitus type 2 in Duhok. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2021;64:102208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7988274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33786167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safarpour P, Vafa MR, Amiri F, Janani L, Noorbakhsh M, Rajabpour Nikoo E, et al. A double blind randomized clinical trial to investigate the effect of vitamin D supplementation on metabolic and hepato-renal markers in type 2 diabetes and obesity. Med J Islam Repub Iran. 2018;32:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6108264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30159285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahmand MA, Daneshzad E, Fung TT, Zahidi F, Muhammadi M, Bellissimo N, et al. What is the impact of vitamin D supplementation on glycemic control in people with type-2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trails. BMC Endocr Disord. 2023;23:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9841647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirhosseini N, Vatanparast H, Mazidi M, Kimball SM. Vitamin D supplementation, glycemic control, and insulin resistance in prediabetics: A meta-analysis. J Endocr Soc. 2018;2:687&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6016617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29951596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>