<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40934467</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tadalafil for Treatment of Pulmonary Hypertension: Mechanisms, Evidence, and Emerging Perspectives.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001036</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH), a subset of pulmonary hypertension (PH), remains a progressive and debilitating disease marked by vascular remodeling and elevated pulmonary vascular resistance. Tadalafil, a phosphodiesterase type 5 inhibitor (PDE-5i), plays a central role in the nitric oxide-cyclic guanosine monophosphate pathway, enhancing vasodilation and reducing right ventricular afterload. Compared with sildenafil, tadalafil offers the advantages of once-daily dosing, a longer half-life, and favorable tolerability. A randomized controlled trial and its long-term extension demonstrated significant improvements in 6-minute walk distance, functional class, and hemodynamic parameters in patients with PAH, with sustained efficacy and an acceptable safety profile over time. Current international guidelines recommend tadalafil both as monotherapy and in combination regimens, particularly with endothelin receptor antagonists like ambrisentan, for World Health Organization functional class (WHO-FC) II or III PAH patients. Beyond PAH, tadalafil's therapeutic potential in WHO Group 2 PH, especially in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction, has been investigated with mixed results. While preclinical models suggest benefits in left ventricular function and remodeling, the PASSION (Tadalafil for treatment of combined postcapillary and precapillary pulmonary hypertension in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction) trial in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction with combined post- and precapillary PH failed to demonstrate clinical benefit. These findings underscore the need for additional studies to define tadalafil's role outside Group 1 PH and to better stratify patients who may benefit through biomarker- or phenotype-guided approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elattar</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, Westchester Medical Center, and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basha</LastName><ForeName>Nabel Rajab</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, Westchester Medical Center, and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salem</LastName><ForeName>Amr</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Westchester Medical Center, and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdulfattah</LastName><ForeName>Ammar Y</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, State University of New York Downstate Medical Center, Brooklyn, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taha</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frishman</LastName><ForeName>William H</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, Westchester Medical Center, and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aronow</LastName><ForeName>Wilbert S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Cardiology and Medicine, Westchester Medical Center and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lanier</LastName><ForeName>Gregg M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Cardiology and Medicine, Westchester Medical Center and New York Medical College, Valhalla, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure with preserved ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nitric oxide pathway</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phosphodiesterase type 5 inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary arterial hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tadalafil</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40934467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000001036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kovacs G, Bartolome S, Denton CP, et al. Definition, classification and diagnosis of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2024;64:2401324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper MM, Humbert M, Souza R, et al. A global view of pulmonary hypertension. Lancet Respir Med. 2016;4:306&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang M, Hart CM, Kempker JA, et al. Pulmonary hypertension mortality trends in United States 1999-2019. Ann Epidemiol. 2022;75:47&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh H, Agarwal L, Jani C, et al. Pulmonary hypertension associated mortality in the United States from 2003 to 2020: an observational analysis of time trends and disparities. J Thorac Dis. 2023;15:3256&#x2013;3272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Humbert M, Vachiery JL, et al. 2015 ESC/ERS Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension: the joint task force for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Respiratory Society (ERS): endorsed by: Association for European Paediatric and Congenital Cardiology (AEPC), International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT) [published correction appears in Eur Respir J. 2015 Dec;46(6):1855-6. doi: 10.1183/13993003.51032-2015.]. Eur Respir J. 2015;46:903&#x2013;975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, Ghofrani HA. The molecular targets of approved treatments for pulmonary arterial hypertension. Thorax. 2016;71:73&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White RJ, Jerjes-Sanchez C, Bohns Meyer GM, et al.; FREEDOM-EV Investigators. Combination therapy with oral treprostinil for pulmonary arterial hypertension. A double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;201:707&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitbon O, Channick R, Chin KM, et al.; GRIPHON Investigators. Selexipag for the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. N Engl J Med. 2015;373:2522&#x2013;2533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenthal JA, Sherwood A, Smith PJ, et al. Lifestyle modification for resistant hypertension: the TRIUMPH randomized clinical trial. Am Heart J. 2015;170:986&#x2013;994.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said K. Macitentan in pulmonary arterial hypertension: the SERAPHIN trial. Glob Cardiol Sci Pract. 2014;2014:26&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M. Viewpoint: activin signalling inhibitors for the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2023;62:2301726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, McLaughlin V, Gibbs JSR, et al.; PULSAR Trial Investigators. Sotatercept for the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:1204&#x2013;1215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, McLaughlin VV, Badesch DB, et al.; ZENITH Trial Investigators. Sotatercept in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension at high risk for death. N Engl J Med. 2025;392:1987&#x2013;2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper MM, Badesch DB, Ghofrani HA, et al.; STELLAR Trial Investigators. Phase 3 trial of sotatercept for treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. N Engl J Med. 2023;388:1478&#x2013;1490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignarro LJ, Cirino G, Casini A, et al. Nitric oxide as a signaling molecule in the vascular system: an overview. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol. 1999;34:879&#x2013;886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SA, Lie JD. Phosphodiesterase-5 (PDE5) inhibitors in the management of erectile dysfunction. P T. 2013;38:407&#x2013;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimminger F, Weimann G, Frey R, et al. First acute haemodynamic study of soluble guanylate cyclase stimulator riociguat in pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2009;33:785&#x2013;792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasch JP, Pacher P, Evgenov OV. Soluble guanylate cyclase as an emerging therapeutic target in cardiopulmonary disease. Circulation. 2011;123:2263&#x2013;2273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, Kovacs G, Hoeper MM, et al.; ESC/ERS Scientific Document Group. 2022 ESC/ERS guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2023;61:2200879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frantz RP, Durst L, Burger CD, et al. Conversion from sildenafil to tadalafil: results from the sildenafil to tadalafil in pulmonary arterial hypertension (SITAR) study. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2014;19:550&#x2013;557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porst H, Padma-Nathan H, Giuliano F, et al. Efficacy of tadalafil for the treatment of erectile dysfunction at 24 and 36 hours after dosing: a randomized controlled trial. Urology. 2003;62:121&#x2013;5; discussion 125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadalafil (Cialis&#xae;) [package insert]. Indianapolis, IN: Eli Lilly and Company; December 5, 2005. Available at: http://pi.lilly.com/us/cialis-pi.pdf. Accessed July 25, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sildenafil (Revatio&#xae;) [summary of product characteristics]. European Medicines Agency. Available at: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/product-information/revatio-epar-product-information_en.pdf. Accessed June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forgue ST, Patterson BE, Bedding AW, et al. Tadalafil pharmacokinetics in healthy subjects. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2006;61:280&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischoff E. Potency, selectivity, and consequences of nonselectivity of PDE inhibition. Int J Impot Res. 2004;16:S11&#x2013;S14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrie AM, Nawarskas JJ, Anderson JR. Clinical utility of tadalafil in the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension: an evidence-based review. Core Evid. 2015;10:99&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper MM, Klinger JR, Benza RL, et al. Rationale and study design of RESPITE: an open-label, phase 3b study of riociguat in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension who demonstrate an insufficient response to treatment with phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitors. Respir Med. 2017;122:S18&#x2013;S22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper MM, Al-Hiti H, Benza RL, et al.; REPLACE investigators. Switching to riociguat versus maintenance therapy with phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitors in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension (REPLACE): a multicentre, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:573&#x2013;584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura M, Tamura Y, Takei M, et al. Dual phosphodiesterase type 5 inhibitor therapy for refractory pulmonary arterial hypertension: a pilot study. BMC Pulm Med. 2015;15:62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, M&#xfc;ller K, Scalise AV, et al. PATENT PLUS: a blinded, randomised and extension study of riociguat plus sildenafil in pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2015;45:1314&#x2013;1322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halank M, Tausche K, Gr&#xfc;nig E, et al. Practical management of riociguat in patients with pulmonary arterial hypertension. Ther Adv Respir Dis. 2019;13:1753466619868938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gall H, Vachi&#xe9;ry JL, Tanabe N, et al. Real-world switching to Riociguat: management and practicalities in patients with PAH and CTEPH [published correction appears in Lung. 2018 Jun;196(3):313. doi: 10.1007/s00408-018-0112-z.]. Lung. 2018;196:305&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran M, Keating G. Tadalafil [published correction appears in Drugs. 2003;63(23):2703]. Drugs. 2003;63:2203&#x2013;12; discussion 2213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland R, Roe EG, Jones BC, et al. Identification of the cytochrome P450 enzymes involved in the N-demethylation of sildenafil. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2001;51:239&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey R, Becker C, Unger S, et al. Assessment of the effects of hepatic impairment and smoking on the pharmacokinetics of a single oral dose of the soluble guanylate cyclase stimulator riociguat (BAY 63-2521). Pulm Circ. 2016;6(Suppl 1):S5&#x2013;S14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey R, Becker C, Saleh S, et al. Clinical pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic profile of riociguat. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2018;57:647&#x2013;661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Brundage BH, Ghofrani HA, et al.; Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension and Response to Tadalafil (PHIRST) Study Group. Tadalafil therapy for pulmonary arterial hypertension [published correction appears in Circulation. 2011 Sep 6;124(10):e279. Dosage error in article text]. Circulation. 2009;119:2894&#x2013;2903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazzoletti L, Zanolin ME, Dorelli G, et al. Six-minute walk distance in healthy subjects: reference standards from a general population sample. Respir Res. 2022;23:83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Sullivan MJ, Thompson PJ, et al. The 6-minute walk: a new measure of exercise capacity in patients with chronic heart failure. Can Med Assoc J. 1985;132:919&#x2013;923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barst RJ, McGoon M, Torbicki A, et al. Diagnosis and differential assessment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;43(12 Suppl S):40S&#x2013;47S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman-Rosenzweig E, Arneson C, Klinger JR. Effects of dose and age on adverse events associated with tadalafil in the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. Pulm Circ. 2014;4:45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathai SC, Hassoun PM, Puhan MA, et al. Sex differences in response to tadalafil in pulmonary arterial hypertension. Chest. 2015;147:188&#x2013;197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benza RL, Gomberg-Maitland M, Miller DP, et al. The REVEAL registry risk score calculator in patients newly diagnosed with pulmonary arterial hypertension. Chest. 2012;141:354&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruopp NF, Cockrill BA. Diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension: a review [published correction appears in JAMA. 2022 Sep 6;328(9):892. doi: 10.1001/jama.2022.13696.]. JAMA. 2022;327:1379&#x2013;1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Channick RN, Frantz RP, et al. Risk stratification and medical therapy of pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinger JR, Elliott CG, Levine DJ, et al. Therapy for pulmonary arterial hypertension in adults: update of the CHEST guideline and expert panel report [published correction appears in Chest. 2021 Jan;159(1):457. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2020.11.021.]. Chest. 2019;155:565&#x2013;586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; N, Barber&#xe0; JA, Frost AE, et al.; AMBITION Investigators. Initial use of ambrisentan plus tadalafil in pulmonary arterial hypertension. N Engl J Med. 2015;373:834&#x2013;844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin KM, Gaine SP, Gerges C, et al. Treatment algorithm for pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2024;64:2401325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin KM, Sitbon O, Doelberg M, et al. Three- versus two-drug therapy for patients with newly diagnosed pulmonary arterial hypertension. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;78:1393&#x2013;1403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonneau G, Torbicki A, Hoeper MM, et al. Selexipag: an oral, selective prostacyclin receptor agonist for the treatment of pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2012;40:874&#x2013;880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickel N, Golpon H, Greer M, et al. The prognostic impact of follow-up assessments in patients with idiopathic pulmonary arterial hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2012;39:589&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salloum FN, Chau VQ, Hoke NN, et al. Tadalafil prevents acute heart failure with reduced ejection fraction in mice. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2014;28:493&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammers DW, Sleeper MM, Forbes SC, et al. Tadalafil treatment delays the onset of cardiomyopathy in dystrophin-deficient hearts. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5:e003911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawless M, Caldwell JL, Radcliffe EJ, et al. Phosphodiesterase 5 inhibition improves contractile function and restores transverse tubule loss and catecholamine responsiveness in heart failure. Sci Rep. 2019;9:6801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora AG, Andrade DR, Janussi SC, et al. Tadalafil treatment improves cardiac, renal and lower urinary tract dysfunctions in rats with heart failure. Life Sci. 2022;289:120237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeper MM, Oerke B, Wissm&#xfc;ller M, et al. Tadalafil for treatment of combined postcapillary and precapillary pulmonary hypertension in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction: a randomized controlled phase 3 study [published correction appears in Circulation. 2025 Mar 18;151(11):e763. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001321.]. Circulation. 2024;150:600&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Samaja M, Arena R, et al. Long-term use of sildenafil in the therapeutic management of heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;50:2136&#x2013;2144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Vicenzi M, Arena R, et al. PDE5 inhibition with sildenafil improves left ventricular diastolic function, cardiac geometry, and clinical status in patients with stable systolic heart failure: results of a 1-year, prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled study. Circ Heart Fail. 2011;4:8&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redfield MM, Chen HH, Borlaug BA, et al.; RELAX Trial. Effect of phosphodiesterase-5 inhibition on exercise capacity and clinical status in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2013;309:1268&#x2013;1277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang XD, Long M, Li F, et al. PDE5 inhibitor sildenafil in the treatment of heart failure: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Cardiol. 2014;172:581&#x2013;587.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>