<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40895989</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Randomized Controlled Trial on the Therapeutic Effect of Aloe Vera Extract on Diabetic Foot Ulcers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e88956</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e88956</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e88956</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.88956</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Diabetes mellitus is a chronic metabolic disorder characterized by hyperglycemia resulting from defects in insulin secretion, insulin action, or both.&#xa0;Among its complications, diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs) pose a significant healthcare challenge which result from impaired healing and infection risks, demanding better therapies. The aloe vera extract promotes wound healing by enhancing tissue regeneration and offering antimicrobial effects. This study evaluates its therapeutic effect on DFUs through a randomized controlled trial. Methods The study involved 60 patients sampled and followed up between May 1, 2025, and June 15, 2025. It compared wound healing outcomes between two groups selected by the lottery method. A control group (30 patients) receiving standard care and a blinded study group (30 patients) treated with aloe vera extract were assessed using the Bates-Jensen Wound Assessment Tool (BWAT). Wound healing was monitored on days 0, 14, and 28, and data were analyzed for significant differences. Results The study's demographic data showed comparable baseline characteristics between groups, with no adverse effects from aloe vera use. BWAT scores were recorded on days 0, 14, and 28, and the average scores for the case group and the control group, respectively, were 42&#xb1;3.11 and 43&#xb1;3.58 on day 0, 31&#xb1;2.16 and 35&#xb1;2.61 on day 14, 19&#xb1;2.17 and 25&#xb1;2.17 on day 28. Average scores decreased more rapidly in the case group than in the control group. A chi-square test confirmed a significant association between aloe vera treatment and enhanced wound healing (p = 0.0029). Conclusion This single-blinded randomized controlled trial shows that topical aloe vera significantly improves DFU healing compared to standard care. Its effects are likely due to the promotion of angiogenesis, reduction in inflammation, and antimicrobial action. Aloe vera is a safe, affordable option, especially for low-resource settings. Larger studies with longer follow-up are needed to confirm and expand its clinical use.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, T et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T</LastName><ForeName>Sandhiya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine School, Madras Medical College, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adalarasan</LastName><ForeName>Sahasyaa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine School, Madras Medical College, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>U</LastName><ForeName>Samyuktha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine School, Madras Medical College, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Md</LastName><ForeName>Suganeshwari</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Pharmacology, Madras Medical College, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R</LastName><ForeName>Ramya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Sudha Saseendharan Siddha Medical College, Kaliyakkavilai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aloe vera extract</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bates jensen wound assessment tool (bwat) score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case control studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetic foot ulcers management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetic mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee, Madras Medical College issued approval IEC - MMC/Approva1 /63022025. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40895989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12392223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.88956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Diabetic foot ulcers. Jeffcoate WJ, Harding KG. Lancet. 2003;361:1545&#x2013;1551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12737879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Differential biological behavior of fibroblasts and endothelial cells under Aloe vera gel culturing. Shafaie S, Andalib S, Shafaei H, Montaseri A, Tavakolizadeh M. Int J Mol Cell Med. 2020;9:234&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7703660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33274186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of Aloe vera on the glycosaminoglycans in the matrix of healing dermal wounds in rats. Chithra P, Sajithlal GB, Chandrakasan G. J Ethnopharmacol. 1998;59:179&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9507902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antifungal and antibacterial activity of aloe vera plant extract. Danish P, Ali Q, Hafeez MM. Biol Clin Sci Res J. 2020;2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates-Jensen wound assessment tool: pictorial guide validation project. Harris C, Bates-Jensen B, Parslow N, Raizman R, Singh M, Ketchen R. J Wound Ostomy Continence Nurs. 2010;37:253&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antiinflammatory activity of extracts from Aloe vera gel. V&#xe1;zquez B, Avila G. J Ethnopharmacol. 2010;55:69&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9121170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; (TGF-&#x3b2;) activation in cutaneous wounds after topical application of aloe vera gel. Takzaree N, Hadjiakhondi A, Hassanzadeh G, Rouini MR, Manayi A, Zolbin MM. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2016;94:1285&#x2013;1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27660884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibacterial activities and antioxidant capacity of Aloe vera. Nejatzadeh-Barandozi F. Org Med Chem Lett. 2013;3:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3729540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23870710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An overview of Aloe vera impact on the healing process of Diabetic Foot Ulcer. Kania A, Ka&#x142;u&#x17c;y&#x144;ski G. J Educ Health Sport. 2024;54:67&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current scenario of traditional medicines in management of diabetic foot ulcers: a review. Rayate AS, Nagoba BS, Mumbre SS, Mavani HB, Gavkare AM, Deshpande AS. World J Diabetes. 2023;14:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9850800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36684382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An in vivo and in vitro investigation of the effect of Aloe vera gel ethanolic extract using animal model with diabetic foot ulcer. Daburkar M, Lohar V, Rathore AS, Bhutada P, Tangadpaliwar S. J Pharm Bioallied Sci. 2014;6:205&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4097935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25035641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of Aloe vera cream for healing diabetic foot ulcers. Aqsa T, Shafique MS, Qureshi U, Changeez M, Farooqi SA, Khan JS. https://www.journalrmc.com/index.php/JRMC/article/view/1110/1687 J Rawalpindi Med Coll. 2019;23:113&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of aloe vera on the healing of diabetic foot ulcer: a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. Irani PS, Ranjbar H, Mehdipour-Rabori R, Torkaman M, Amirsalari S, Alazmani-Noodeh F. Curr Drug Discov Technol. 2024;21:56&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37670716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of aloe vera/ plantago major gel in diabetic foot ulcer: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. Najafian Y, Khorasani ZM, Najafi MN, Hamedi SS, Mahjour M, Feyzabadi Z. Curr Drug Discov Technol. 2019;16:223&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29336265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Three-week topical treatment with placenta-derived mesenchymal stem cells hydrogel in a patient with diabetic foot ulcer: a case report. Zeng X, Tang Y, Hu K, et al. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017;96:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29390468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>