<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40994060</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-5391</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of evidence-based medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Evid Based Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Systematic Review and Network Meta-Analysis of the Comparative Effectiveness of Adherence Enhancement Strategies in Chronic Kidney Disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70078</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70078</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jebm.70078</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate and compare the effectiveness of adherence-enhancement strategies in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nine databases (PubMed, Embase, The Cochrane Library, Web of Science, Scopus, CNKI, VIP, WanFang, and CBM) were searched for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) to April 1, 2025. Two reviewers independently screened, extracted data, and assessed risk of bias with the Cochrane Risk of Bias 2.0 tool. Certainty of evidence was appraised using the Confidence in Network Meta-Analysis (CINeMA) tool. Network meta-analysis was performed, and surface under the cumulative ranking curve (SUCRA) was calculated to rank interventions. The review was registered in PROSPERO (CRD42024604771).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirty-five RCTs with 5084 patients were included. Evidence quality was limited by high risk of bias and low certainty. For medication adherence, education plus phone follow-up with short message service education showed the greatest effect (standardized mean differences [SMD] = 2.15, 95% confidence interval [CI] 1.09-3.21; SUCRA = 98.7), followed by empowerment (SMD = 1.19, 95% CI 0.20-2.18; SUCRA = 82.1). For diet adherence, education with phone follow-up was most effective (SMD = 6.68, 95% CI 5.64-7.71; SUCRA = 100), with empowerment also beneficial (SMD = 1.83, 95% CI 1.23-2.43; SUCRA = 87.9). For fluid adherence, education with medication management and pharmacist follow-up was most effective on scale-based outcomes (SMD = 3.06, 95% CI 2.18-3.94; SUCRA = 99.8), while cognitive behavioral therapy reduced interdialytic weight gain (SMD = -0.76, 95% CI -1.30 to -0.22; SUCRA = 71.1).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Adherence-enhancement strategies improve medication, diet, and fluid adherence in CKD. High-quality RCTs are needed to confirm these findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Chinese Cochrane Center, West China Hospital of Sichuan University and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3724-4581</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Rehabilitation, Cheeloo College of Medicine,Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Yuanmin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Rehabilitation, Cheeloo College of Medicine,Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Haixia</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Rehabilitation, Cheeloo College of Medicine,Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ou</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Rehabilitation, Cheeloo College of Medicine,Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82172543</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZR2024MH071</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Shandong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Evid Based Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101497477</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-5391</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network meta&#x2010;analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strategies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40994060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jebm.70078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>N. R. Hill, S. T. Fatoba, J. L. Oke, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Prevalence of Chronic Kidney Disease&#x2014;A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; PLoS ONE 11, no. 7 (2016): e0158765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wu, F. Tang, H. Li, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Development and Validation of a Nomogram Model for Medication Non&#x2010;Adherence in Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease,&#x201d; Journal of Psychosomatic Research 171 (2023): 111385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Levin, M. Tonelli, J. Bonventre, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Kidney Health 2017 and Beyond: A Roadmap for Closing Gaps in Care, Research, and Policy,&#x201d; Lancet 390, no. 10105 (2017): 1888&#x2013;1917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. E. Lunardi, K. Hill, Q. Xu, R. Le Leu, and P. N. Bennett, &#x201c;The Effectiveness of Patient Activation Interventions in Adults With Chronic Kidney Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Worldviews on Evidence&#x2010;Based Nursing 20, no. 3 (2023): 238&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Tesfaye, N. Parrish, K. Sud, A. Grandinetti, and R. Castelino, &#x201c;Medication Adherence Among Patients with Kidney Disease: An Umbrella Review,&#x201d; Advances in Kidney Disease and Health 31, no. 1 (2024): 68&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. B. Seng, J. Y. Tan, C. T. Yeam, H. Htay, and W. Y. M. Foo, &#x201c;Factors Affecting Medication Adherence Among Pre&#x2010;Dialysis Chronic Kidney Disease Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Literature,&#x201d; International Urology and Nephrology 52, no. 5 (2020): 903&#x2013;916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. L. Matteson and C. Russell, &#x201c;Interventions to Improve Hemodialysis Adherence: A Systematic Review of Randomized&#x2010;controlled Trials,&#x201d; Hemodialysis International 14, no. 4 (2010): 370&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Saran, J. L. Bragg&#x2010;Gresham, H. C. Rayner, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Nonadherence in Hemodialysis: Associations With Mortality, Hospitalization, and Practice Patterns in the DOPPS,&#x201d; Kidney International 64, no. 1 (2003): 254&#x2013;262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Ammous, R. Kampo, M. Wollsching&#x2010;Strobel, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Adherence&#x2010;enhancing Interventions for Pharmacological and Oxygen Therapy in Patients With COPD: A Systematic Review and Component Network Meta&#x2010;Analyses,&#x201d; European Respiratory Review 33, no. 173 (2024): 240011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Alkenizan, &#x201c;Innovative Care for Chronic Conditions: Building Blocks for Action,&#x201d; Annals of Saudi Medicine 24, no. 2 (2004): 148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. P. Valsaraj, S. M. Bhat, R. Prabhu, and A. Kamath, &#x201c;Follow&#x2010;Up Study on the Effect of Cognitive Behaviour Therapy on Haemodialysis Adherence: A Randomised Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Sultan Qaboos University Medical Journal 21, no. 1 (2021): e58&#x2013;e65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Milazi, C. Douglas, and A. Bonner, &#x201c;A Bundled Phosphate Control Intervention (4Ds) for Adults With End&#x2010;Stage Kidney Disease Receiving Haemodialysis: A Cluster Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Advanced Nursing 77, no. 3 (2021): 1345&#x2013;1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Dawson, K. L. Campbell, J. C. Craig, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Text Messaging Intervention for Dietary Behaviors for People Receiving Maintenance Hemodialysis: A Feasibility Study of KIDNEYTEXT,&#x201d; American Journal of Kidney Diseases 78, no. 1 (2021): 85&#x2013;95. e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. F. Teong, B. H. Khor, H. M. Ng, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effectiveness of a Nutritional Mobile Application for Management of Hyperphosphatemia in Patients on Hemodialysis: A Multicenter Open&#x2010;Label Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Personalized Medicine 12, no. 6 (2022): 961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Eaton, N. Vallejo, X. McDonald, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;User Engagement With mHealth Interventions to Promote Treatment Adherence and Self&#x2010;Management in People With Chronic Health Conditions: Systematic Review,&#x201d; Journal of Medical Internet Research [Electronic Resource] 26 (2024): e50508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Chiocchia, A. Holloway, and G. Salanti, &#x201c;Semi&#x2010;automated Assessment of the Risk of Bias due to Missing Evidence in Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis: A Guidance Paper for the ROB&#x2010;MEN Web&#x2010;Application,&#x201d; BMC Medical Research Methodology [Electronic Resource] 23, no. 1 (2023): 223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Arad, R. Goli, N. Parizad, D. Vahabzadeh, and R. Baghaei, &#x201c;Do the Patient Education Program and Nurse&#x2010;Led Telephone Follow&#x2010;Up Improve Treatment Adherence in Hemodialysis Patients? A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; BMC Nephrology [Electronic Resource] 22, no. 1 (2021): 119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Alikari, M. Tsironi, V. Matziou, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Impact of Education on Knowledge, Adherence and Quality of Life Among Patients on Haemodialysis,&#x201d; Quality of Life Research 28, no. 1 (2019): 73&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Alilu, S. Pazirofteh, H. Habibzadeh, and J. Rasouli, &#x201c;The Impact of Teach&#x2010;Back Training Method (TBTM) on Treatment Adherence in Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Ann Med Surg (Lond) 86, no. 5 (2024): 2723&#x2013;2728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Dsouza, R. Prabhu, B. Unnikrishnan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Educational Intervention on Knowledge and Level of Adherence Among Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Glob Health Epidemiol Genom 2023 (2023): 4295613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhang, J. S. Wang, and X. H. Xie, &#x201c;Effect of Hospital&#x2010;Community Online Management on Medication Management of Elderly Patients With Peritoneal Dialysis During COVID&#x2010;19,&#x201d; Therapeutic Apheresis and Dialysis: Official Peer&#x2010;Reviewed Journal of the International Society for Apheresis, the Japanese Society for Apheresis, the Japanese Society for Dialysis Therapy 28, no. 2 (2024): 297&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Eaton, M. Comer, C. Pruette, K. Psoter, and K. Riekert, &#x201c;Text Messaging Adherence Intervention for Adolescents and Young Adults With Chronic Kidney Disease: Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial and Stakeholder Interviews,&#x201d; Journal of Medical Internet Research [Electronic Resource] 22, no. 8 (2020): e19861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Vasli, M. Hosseini, M. Nasiri, and N. Bakhtiari, &#x201c;Family&#x2010;Centered Empowerment Approach to Optimize Phosphate Management Among Hemodialysis Patients: An Experimental Study,&#x201d; BMC Nephrology [Electronic Resource] 24, no. 1 (2023): 259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Wu, S. Feng, H. Quan, Y. Zhang, R. Fu, and H. Li, &#x201c;Effect of Self&#x2010;Determination Theory on Knowledge, Treatment Adherence, and Self&#x2010;Management of Patients With Maintenance Hemodialysis,&#x201d; Contrast Media &amp; Molecular Imaging 2022 (2022): 1416404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Cooney, H. Moon, Y. Liu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Pharmacist Based Intervention to Improve the Care of Patients With CKD: A Pragmatic, Randomized, Controlled Trial,&#x201d; BMC Nephrology [Electronic Resource] 16 (2015): 56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Mollao &#x11f;lu, F. Candan, G. Solmaz, S. Mollao &#x11f;lu, E. Ba&#x15f;er, and S. Yanmi&#x15f;, &#x201c;The Effect of Education and Art Therapy With Telehealth Method on Diet&#x2010;Fluid Restriction and Anxiety in Hemodialysis Patients During the COVID&#x2010;19 Pandemic,&#x201d; Alternative Therapies in Health and Medicine 30, no. 7 (2024): 58&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Dehghan, M. Azizzadeh Forouzi, A. Etminan, C. Roy, and M. Dehghan, &#x201c;The Effects of Lavender, Rosemary and Orange Essential Oils on Memory Problems and Medication Adherence Among Patients Undergoing Hemodialysis: A Parallel Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Explore (NY) 18, no. 5 (2022): 559&#x2013;566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Khokhar, Y. H. Khan, T. H. Mallhi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effectiveness of Pharmacist Intervention Model for Chronic Kidney Disease Patients: A Prospective Comparative Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Clinical Pharmacy 42, no. 2 (2020): 625&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Y. Alshogran, M. H. Hajjar, S. M. Muflih, and K. H. Alzoubi, &#x201c;The Role of Clinical Pharmacist in Enhancing Hemodialysis Patients' Adherence and Clinical Outcomes: A Randomized&#x2010;Controlled Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Clinical Pharmacy 44, no. 5 (2022): 1169&#x2013;1178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Griva, M. Nandakumar, J. H. Ng, K. F. Y. Lam, H. McBain, and S. P. Newman, &#x201c;Hemodialysis Self&#x2010;management Intervention Randomized Trial (HED&#x2010;SMART): A Practical Low&#x2010;Intensity Intervention to Improve Adherence and Clinical Markers in Patients Receiving Hemodialysis,&#x201d; American Journal of Kidney Diseases 71, no. 3 (2018): 371&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Kauric&#x2010;Klein, &#x201c;Improving Blood Pressure Control in End Stage Renal Disease Through a Supportive Educative Nursing Intervention,&#x201d; Nephrology Nursing Journal 39, no. 3 (2012): 217&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Seyyedrasooli, K. Parvan, A. Rahmani, and Z. Rahimi, &#x201c;Effect of Illness Perception Promoting Interventions on Treatment Adherence in Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Iran Journal of Critical Care Nursing 6, no. 2 (2013): 77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Zhianfar, H. Nadrian, M. Asghari Jafarabadi, F. Espahbodi, and A. Shaghaghi, &#x201c;Effectiveness of a Multifaceted Educational Intervention to Enhance Therapeutic Regimen Adherence and Quality of Life Amongst Iranian Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial (MEITRA Study),&#x201d; Journal of Multidisciplinary Healthcare 13 (2020): 361&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ok and Y. Kutlu, &#x201c;The Effect of Motivational Interviewing on Adherence to Treatment and Quality of Life in Chronic Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Clinical Nursing Research 30, no. 3 (2021): 322&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Irajpour, M. S. Hashemi, P. Abazari, and S. Shahidi, &#x201c;The Effects of Peer Education on Treatment Adherence Among Patients Receiving Hemodialysis: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Iranian Journal of Nursing and Midwifery Research 29, no. 1 (2024): 46&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Torabi Khah, Z. Farsi, and S. A. Sajadi, &#x201c;Comparing the Effects of mHealth Application Based on Micro&#x2010;Learning Method and Face&#x2010;to&#x2010;Face Training on Treatment Adherence and Perception in Haemodialysis Patients: A Randomised Clinical Trial,&#x201d; BMJ Open 13, no. 6 (2023): e071982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Y. Fang, &#x201c;Effect of Cognitive Behavior Intervention on Hemodialysis&#x2010;Related Knowledge, Emotions, and Compliance of Hemodialysis Patients With Chronic Renal Failure,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Nursing in Practice 7, no. 09 (2021): 133&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Lim, S. Hyun, J. M. Lee, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of Education on Low&#x2010;Phosphate Diet and Phosphate Binder Intake to Control Serum Phosphate Among Maintenance Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Kidney Research and Clinical Practice 37, no. 1 (2018): 69&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Wei, W. H. Chen, X. N. Zhang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Short Message Service&#x2010;Based Health Education on Medication Compliance of Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease,&#x201d; Chinese General Practice 16, no. 25 (2013): 2287&#x2013;2289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. S. Yun and J. Y. Choi, &#x201c;Effects of Dietary Program Based on Self&#x2010;Efficacy Theory on Dietary Adherence, Physical Indices and Quality of Life for Hemodialysis Patients],&#x201d; Journal of Korean Academy of Nursing 46, no. 4 (2016): 598&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Hashemi, A. Tayebi, A. Rahimi, and B. Einolahi, &#x201c;Examining the Effect of Continuous Care Model on Adherence to Dietary Regimen Among Patients Receiving Hemodialysis,&#x201d; Iran Journal of Critical Care Nursing 7, no. 4 (2015): 215&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Sabouri, M. Rambod, and Z. Khademian, &#x201c;The Effect of Positive Thinking Training on Hope and Adherence to Treatment in Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; BMC Psychology 11, no. 1 (2023): 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ba&#x15f;er and M. Mollao &#x11f;lu, &#x201c;The Effect of a Hemodialysis Patient Education Program on Fluid Control and Dietary Compliance,&#x201d; Hemodialysis International 23, no. 3 (2019): 392&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Sharp, M. R. Wild, A. I. Gumley, and C. J. Deighan, &#x201c;A Cognitive Behavioral Group Approach to Enhance Adherence to Hemodialysis Fluid Restrictions: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; American Journal of Kidney Diseases 45, no. 6 (2005): 1046&#x2013;1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. L. Tanner, C. B. Craig, A. A. Bartolucci, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Effect of a Self&#x2010;monitoring Tool on Self&#x2010;efficacy, Health Beliefs, and Adherence in Patients Receiving Hemodialysis,&#x201d; Journal of Renal Nutrition 8, no. 4 (1998): 203&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Torabikhah, Z. Farsi, and S. A. Sajadi, &#x201c;Comparing the Effects of mHealth App Use and Face&#x2010;to&#x2010;face Training on the Clinical and Laboratory Parameters of Dietary and Fluid Intake Adherence in Hemodialysis Patients: A Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; BMC Nephrology [Electronic Resource] 24, no. 1 (2023): 194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Cukor, N. Ver Halen, D. R. Asher, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Psychosocial Intervention Improves Depression, Quality of Life, and Fluid Adherence in Hemodialysis,&#x201d; Journal of the American Society of Nephrology 25, no. 1 (2014): 196&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Karavetian, N. de Vries, H. Elzein, R. Rizk, and F. Bechwaty, &#x201c;Effect of Behavioral Stage&#x2010;based Nutrition Education on Management of Osteodystrophy Among Hemodialysis Patients, Lebanon,&#x201d; Patient Education and Counseling 98, no. 9 (2015): 1116&#x2013;1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. J. Brantley, T. H. Mosley Jr., B. K. Bruce, G. T. McKnight, and G. N. Jones, &#x201c;Efficacy of Behavioral Management and Patient Education on Vascular Access Cleansing Compliance in Hemodialysis Patients,&#x201d; Health Psychology 9, no. 1 (1990): 103&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Chen, X. H. Lu, and T. Wang, &#x201c;Menu Suggestion: An Effective Way to Improve Dietary Compliance in Peritoneal Dialysis Patients,&#x201d; Journal of Renal Nutrition 16, no. 2 (2006): 132&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. P. Reese, O. Mgbako, A. Mussell, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Pilot Randomized Trial of Financial Incentives or Coaching to Lower Serum Phosphorus in Dialysis Patients,&#x201d; Journal of Renal Nutrition 25, no. 6 (2015): 510&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. K. Wong, S. K. Chow, and T. M. Chan, &#x201c;Evaluation of a Nurse&#x2010;Led Disease Management Programme for Chronic Kidney Disease: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing Studies 47, no. 3 (2010): 268&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Patel, M. Huang, and S. Miliara, &#x201c;Understanding Treatment Adherence in Chronic Diseases: Challenges, Consequences, and Strategies for Improvement,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 14, no. 17 (2025): 6034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. J. Schrauben, L. Appel, E. Rivera, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mobile Health (mHealth) Technology: Assessment of Availability, Acceptability, and Use in CKD,&#x201d; American Journal of Kidney Diseases 77, no. 6 (2021): 941&#x2013;950. e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Coulter and J. Ellins, &#x201c;Effectiveness of Strategies for Informing, Educating, and Involving Patients,&#x201d; Bmj 335, no. 7609 (2007): 24&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Praha, A. Sriyuktasuth, W. Puwarawuttipanit, P. Chuengsaman, and W. Kusakunniran, &#x201c;Factors Influencing Telehealth Service Use and Health Outcomes in Patients Undergoing Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis: Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study,&#x201d; Journal of Medical Internet Research [Electronic Resource] 25 (2023): e48623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. L. Tsay and L. O. Hung, &#x201c;Empowerment of Patients With End&#x2010;Stage Renal Disease&#x2014;A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing Studies 41, no. 1 (2004): 59&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Brathwaite, F. M. Ssewamala, M. Mutumba, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Long&#x2010;term (5&#x2010;year) Impact of a Family Economic Empowerment Intervention on Adolescents Living With HIV in Uganda: Analysis of Longitudinal Data From a Cluster Randomized Controlled Trial From the Suubi+Adherence Study (2012&#x2010;2018),&#x201d; Aids and Behavior 26, no. 10 (2022): 3337&#x2013;3344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Cao, F. Hong, Y. Ruan, and M. Lin, &#x201c;Effect of Patient&#x2010;Empowerment Interaction Model on Self&#x2010;Management Ability of Peritoneal Dialysis Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Patient Prefer Adherence 17 (2023): 873&#x2013;881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. K. Moser, V. Dickson, T. Jaarsma, C. Lee, A. Stromberg, and B. Riegel, &#x201c;Role of Self&#x2010;Care in the Patient With Heart Failure,&#x201d; Current Cardiology Reports 14, no. 3 (2012): 265&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. S. Yu, P. W. Li, S. X. Li, R. D. Smith, S. C. Yue, and B. P. Y. Yan, &#x201c;Effectiveness and Cost&#x2010;Effectiveness of an Empowerment&#x2010;Based Self&#x2010;Care Education Program on Health Outcomes Among Patients with Heart Failure: A Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; JAMA Network Open 5, no. 4 (2022): e225982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Thomas, S. Wulf, B. Bikbov, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Maintenance Dialysis Throughout the World in Years 1990 and 2010,&#x201d; Journal of the American Society of Nephrology 26, no. 11 (2015): 2621&#x2013;2633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. T. Beck and E. A. Haigh, &#x201c;Advances in Cognitive Theory and Therapy: The Generic Cognitive Model,&#x201d; Annual Review of Clinical Psychology 10 (2014): 1&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. L. St Peter, T. M. Farley, and B. L. Carter, &#x201c;Role of Collaborative Care Models Including Pharmacists in Improving Blood Pressure Management in Chronic Kidney Disease Patients,&#x201d; Current Opinion in Nephrology and Hypertension 20, no. 5 (2011): 498&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. S. Conn and T. M. Ruppar, &#x201c;Medication Adherence Outcomes of 771 Intervention Trials: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Preventive Medicine 99 (2017): 269&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Santschi, A. Chiolero, A. L. Colosimo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Improving Blood Pressure Control Through Pharmacist Interventions: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials,&#x201d; Journal of the American Heart Association 3, no. 2 (2014): e000718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. El&#x2010;Deyarbi, L. Ahmed, J. King, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Effects of Multifactorial Pharmacist&#x2010;led Intervention Protocol on Medication Optimisation and Adherence Among Patients With Type 2 Diabetes: A Randomised Control Trial,&#x201d; F1000Res 13 (2024): 493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Mason, K. Khunti, M. Stone, A. Farooqi, and S. Carr, &#x201c;Educational Interventions in Kidney Disease Care: A Systematic Review of Randomized Trials,&#x201d; American Journal of Kidney Diseases 51, no. 6 (2008): 933&#x2013;951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. A. Lopez&#x2010;Vargas, A. Tong, M. Howell, and J. C. Craig, &#x201c;Educational Interventions for Patients with CKD: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; American Journal of Kidney Diseases 68, no. 3 (2016): 353&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>