<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41014023</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-3479</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of gynaecology and obstetrics: the official organ of the International Federation of Gynaecology and Obstetrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Gynaecol Obstet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Online decision aids for contraceptive choices in women with chronic conditions: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ijgo.70555</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Women with chronic conditions face increased risks of unintended pregnancy and adverse maternal and perinatal outcomes. Tailored, online contraceptive decision aids might improve informed decision-making and support reproductive health by promoting patient-centered care in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study systematically reviews the characteristics and effectiveness of online decision aids designed to support contraceptive and reproductive health choices in women with chronic conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH STRATEGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">We searched Medline, Embase, CINAHL, Maternity and Infant Care Database, and Emcare up until November 30, 2024, using terms related to contraception, decision aids, chronic conditions, and women's health. We also searched thesis repositories and reference lists of relevant reviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA" NlmCategory="METHODS">Included studies evaluated web-based decision aids with a contraceptive choice component, targeted women of reproductive age (15-50&#x2009;years) with chronic conditions, and assessed outcomes related to feasibility, user experience, knowledge, communication, or contraceptive uptake and behavior change.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Two reviewers independently extracted data on study characteristics, intervention features, and outcomes and assessed methodological quality using the Mixed Methods Appraisal Tool (MMAT). A narrative synthesis was conducted due to heterogeneity in study designs and outcomes. The GRADE approach was not applied to assess the quality of the included studies due to variability in study designs and outcomes. The protocol was registered with PROSPERO (CRD42023473313).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ten studies evaluating nine distinct decision aids met the inclusion criteria. Eight focused primarily on contraceptive choices, while two addressed broader reproductive health planning. Most studies were conducted in the USA (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;8) and employed various designs: randomized controlled trials (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;4), mixed-methods studies (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2), and descriptive studies (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;3). The decision aids targeted various chronic conditions, including hypertension, diabetes, cancer, rheumatic diseases, cystic fibrosis, and sickle cell disease. The aids incorporated interactive features, personalized recommendations, and multimedia formats, with high user satisfaction and usability ratings reported. Some decision aids demonstrated improvements in contraceptive use, reproductive health knowledge, and communication. However, the effect on long-term contraceptive behaviors was mixed, with three studies showing positive but not statistically significant changes and one study reporting a negative correlation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Online decision aids tailored for women with chronic conditions showed promise in improving user satisfaction, reproductive health knowledge, and patient-provider communication. However, their impact on long-term contraceptive behaviors remains inconclusive. Future studies should employ rigorous designs, validated outcome measures, and larger, more diverse populations to further evaluate the effectiveness of these aids and optimize their impact on contraceptive decision-making in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). International Journal of Gynecology &amp; Obstetrics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of International Federation of Gynecology and Obstetrics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebresillassie</LastName><ForeName>Begashaw Melaku</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0071-732X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, The University of Newcastle, University Drive, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Women's Health Research, The University of Newcastle, University Drive, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunter Medical Research Institute, Kookaburra Circuit, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doley</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, The University of Newcastle, University Drive, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Melissa L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, The University of Newcastle, University Drive, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Women's Health Research, The University of Newcastle, University Drive, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunter Medical Research Institute, Kookaburra Circuit, New Lambton, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Gynaecol Obstet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0210174</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-7292</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">contraceptive decision aids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">web&#x2010;based interventions</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41014023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijgo.70555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hayes DK, Fan AZ, Smith RA, Bombard JM. Trends in Selected Chronic Conditions and Behavioral Risk Factors Among Women of Reproductive Age, Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System, 2001&#x2013;2009. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr SL, Hayes DK, Bitsko RH, Bansil P, Dietz PM. Peer reviewed: depression, diabetes, and chronic disease risk factors among US women of reproductive age. Prev Chronic Dis. 2011;8(6):2133&#x2010;2161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boghossian NS, Yeung E, Albert PS, et&#xa0;al. Changes in diabetes status between pregnancies and impact on subsequent newborn outcomes. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2014;210(5):431. doi:10.1016/j.ajog.2013.12.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiely M, El&#x2010;Mohandes AA, Gantz MG, Chowdhury D, Thornberry JS, El&#x2010;Khorazaty MN. Understanding the association of biomedical, psychosocial and behavioral risks with adverse pregnancy outcomes among African&#x2010;Americans in Washington, DC. Matern Child Health J. 2011;15:85&#x2010;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy VE, Clifton VL, Gibson PG. Asthma exacerbations during pregnancy: incidence and association with adverse pregnancy outcomes. Thorax. 2006;61(2):169&#x2010;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves E, Azevedo A, Rodrigues T, Santos AC, Barros H. Impact of risk factors on hypertensive disorders in pregnancy, in primiparae and multiparae. Ann Hum Biol. 2013;40(5):377&#x2010;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg CJ, Harper MA, Atkinson SM, et&#xa0;al. Preventability of pregnancy&#x2010;related deaths: results of a state&#x2010;wide review. Obstet Gynecol. 2005;106(6):1228&#x2010;1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawron LM, Gawron AJ, Kasper A, Hammond C, Keefer L. Contraceptive method selection by women with inflammatory bowel diseases: a cross&#x2010;sectional survey. Contraception. 2014;89(5):419&#x2010;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslow B&#x2010;SL, Morse CB, Schanne A, Loren A, Domchek SM, Gracia CR. Contraceptive use and the role of contraceptive counseling in reproductive&#x2010;aged women with cancer. Contraception. 2014;90(1):79&#x2010;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz EB, Braughton MY, Riedel JC, et&#xa0;al. Postpartum care and contraception provided to women with gestational and preconception diabetes in California's Medicaid program. Contraception. 2017;96(6):432&#x2010;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chor J, Rankin K, Harwood B, Handler A. Unintended pregnancy and postpartum contraceptive use in women with and without chronic medical disease who experienced a live birth. Contraception. 2011;84(1):57&#x2010;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips&#x2010;Bell GS, Sappenfield W, Robbins CL, Hernandez L. Chronic diseases and use of contraception among women at risk of unintended pregnancy. J Women's Health. 2016;25(12):1262&#x2010;1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg DL, Stika C, Desai A, Baker D, Yost KJ. Providing contraception for women taking potentially teratogenic medications: a survey of internal medicine physicians' knowledge, attitudes and barriers. J Gen Intern Med. 2010;25:291&#x2010;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo AM, Wilkie DJ, Yao Y, et&#xa0;al. Reproductive health CHOICES for young adults with sickle cell disease or trait: randomized controlled trial outcomes over two years. J Genet Couns. 2016;25(2):325&#x2010;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehlendorf C, Levy K, Kelley A, Grumbach K, Steinauer J. Women's preferences for contraceptive counseling and decision making. Contraception. 2013;88(2):250&#x2010;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo J, Peters M, Teal S, Guiahi M. Adolescent and young women's contraceptive decision&#x2010;making processes: choosing &#x201c;the best method for her&#x201d;. J Pediatr Adolesc Gynecol. 2015;28(4):224&#x2010;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitzer J, Cupanik V, Fait T, et&#xa0;al. Factors influencing women's selection of combined hormonal contraceptive methods after counselling in 11 countries: results from a subanalysis of the CHOICE study. Eur J Contracept Reprod Health Care. 2013;18(5):372&#x2010;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper CC, Brown BA, Foster&#x2010;Rosales A, Raine TR. Hormonal contraceptive method choice among young, low&#x2010;income women: how important is the provider? Patient Educ Couns. 2010;81(3):349&#x2010;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YM, Kols A, Martin A, et&#xa0;al. Promoting informed choice: evaluating a decision&#x2010;making tool for family planning clients and providers in Mexico. Int Fam Plan Perspect. 2005;31:162&#x2010;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goueth RC, Maki KG, Babatunde A, Eden KB, Darney BG. Effects of technology&#x2010;based contraceptive decision aids: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2022;227(5):705&#x2010;713.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall C, Nuru&#x2010;Jeter A, Guendelman S, Mauldon J, Raine&#x2010;Bennett T. Patient perceptions of a decision support tool to assist with young women's contraceptive choice. Patient Educ Couns. 2017;100(2):343&#x2010;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng CJ, Lee YK, Lee PY, Abdullah KL. Health innovations in patient decision support: bridging the gaps and challenges. Australas Med J. 2013;6(2):95&#x2010;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A, Allison BA, Perry M. Effectiveness of contraceptive decision aids in adolescents and young adults: a systematic review. J Pediatr Adolesc Gynecol. 2022;35(1):7&#x2010;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly KZ, Foster TC, Thompson R. What matters most? The content and concordance of patients' and providers' information priorities for contraceptive decision making. Contraception. 2014;90(3):280&#x2010;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alston C, Berger Z, Brownlee S, et&#xa0;al. Shared decision&#x2010;making strategies for best care: patient decision aids. NAM Perspectives 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzopardi&#x2010;Muscat N, S&#xf8;rensen K. Towards an equitable digital public health era: promoting equity through a health literacy perspective. Eur J Pub Health. 2019;29(Supplement_3):13&#x2010;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, et&#xa0;al. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babineau J. Product review: covidence (systematic review software). J Canadian Health Libr Assoc. 2014;35(2):68&#x2010;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Tufanaru C, Aromataris E. JBI's systematic reviews: data extraction and synthesis. AJN Am J Nurs. 2014;114(7):49&#x2010;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong QN, F&#xe0;bregues S, Bartlett G, et&#xa0;al. The mixed methods appraisal tool (MMAT) version 2018 for information professionals and researchers. Educ Inf. 2018;34(4):285&#x2010;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman M, Brian J, Wang D. Evaluation of an online decision aid for selection of contraceptive methods. Appl Clin Inform. 2023;14(1):153&#x2010;163. doi:10.1055/a-2004-2304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Himes KP, Donovan H, Wang S, Weaver C, Grove JR, Facco FL. Healthy beyond pregnancy, a web&#x2010;based intervention to improve adherence to postpartum care: randomized controlled feasibility trial. JMIR Hum Factors. 2017;4(4):e26. doi:10.2196/humanfactors.7964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedict C, Dauber&#x2010;Decker KL, Ford JS, et&#xa0;al. Development of a web&#x2010;based decision aid and planning tool for family building after cancer (roadmap to parenthood): usability testing. JMIR Cancer. 2022;8(2):e33304. doi:10.2196/33304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talabi MB, Kazmerski T, O'Leary R, et&#xa0;al. Development of a person&#x2010;centered family planning decision aid for women with rheumatic diseases. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2022;74(Supplement 9):1867&#x2010;1868. doi:10.1002/art.42355</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazmerski TM, Stransky OM, Wright CE, et&#xa0;al. Feasibility testing of a web&#x2010;based reproductive decision support tool for cystic fibrosis. J Cyst Fibros. 2023;23:404&#x2010;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra P, Mangione CM, Cheng E, et&#xa0;al. A cluster randomized controlled trial of the MyFamilyPlan online preconception health education tool. Am J Health Promot. 2018;32(4):897&#x2010;905. doi:10.1177/0890117117700585</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbers S, Meserve A, Kottke M, Hatcher R, Ventura A, Chiasson MA. Randomized controlled trial of a computer&#x2010;based module to improve contraceptive method choice. Contraception. 2012;86(4):383&#x2010;390. doi:10.1016/j.contraception.2012.01.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen LN, Hahn PM, Jamieson MA. Characteristics and concerns of women choosing an online contraception selection tool ("choosing wisely"). J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2010;32(8):763&#x2010;766. doi:10.1016/S1701-2163%2816%2934617-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen LN, Jamieson MA. Adolescent users of an online contraception selection tool: how user preferences and characteristics differ from those of adults. J Pediatr Adolesc Gynecol. 2011;24(5):317&#x2010;319. doi:10.1016/j.jpag.2011.06.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavric V, Kayes NM, Rashid U, Saywell NL. The effectiveness of self&#x2010;guided digital interventions to improve physical activity and exercise outcomes for people with chronic conditions: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Front Rehabil Sci. 2022;3:925620. doi:10.3389/fresc.2022.925620</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan K, Zhao Y. Mobile health technology: a novel tool in chronic disease management. Intell Med. 2022;2(1):41&#x2010;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Van Stralen MM, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011;6(1):42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine (US) Committee on Health Literacy. Health Literacy: A Prescription to End Confusion. National Academies Press; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry MJ, Edgman&#x2010;Levitan S. Shared decision making&#x2014;the pinnacle of patient&#x2010;centered care. N Engl J Med. 2012;366(9):780&#x2010;781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodenheimer T, Lorig K, Holman H, Grumbach K. Patient self&#x2010;management of chronic disease in primary care. JAMA. 2002;288(19):2469&#x2010;2475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacey D, L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; F, Lewis KB. Patient decision aids to engage adults in treatment or screening decisions. JAMA. 2017;318(7):657&#x2010;658.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>