<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40959458</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1663-9812</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of antibody-drug conjugates in the treatment of advanced urological cancers: a systematic review and a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1583654</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1583654</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1583654</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphar.2025.1583654</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) offer novel therapeutic options for advanced urological cancers, but their efficacy and safety vary across cancer types. Many non-urothelial cancer ADC trials are small, nonrandomized studies with limited validated evaluation indicators. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of ADCs across various urological cancers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Relevant studies were identified through searches in Embase, PubMed, Web of Science, Cochrane Library, CNKI, VIP database and WanFang dataset, including randomized controlled trials, single-arm studies, and retrospective analyses on ADCs for advanced urological cancers. RoB 2.0, MINORS, and NOS were used for quality assessment, with R 4.4.0 for data analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This meta-analysis included 46 studies with 3,250 patients, covering urothelial cancer (29 studies), renal cell carcinoma (5 studies), testicular cancer (2 studies), and metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (10 studies). Three ADCs for urothelial cancer have received approval, including enfortumab vedotin (EV), sacituzumab govitecan (SG), and the HER2-ADC vedicilizumab (RC-48)/disitamab vedotin (DV). For urothelial cancer, the pooled overall response rate (ORR) was 43% (95% CI: 39%-47%) and disease control rate (DCR) was 76% (95% CI: 71%-80%). Median overall survival (OS) and progression-free survival (PFS) were 11.55 months (95% CI: 10.63-12.47) and 5.52 months (95% CI: 5.32-5.72) for enfortumab vedotin (EV), and 15.30 months (95% CI: 11.21-19.40) and 5.80 months (95% CI: 4.88-6.72) for DV. DV combined with immunotherapy achieved a pooled median PFS of 9.78 months (95% CI: 7.73-11.83). For renal cell carcinoma, the ORR was 6% (95% CI: 2%-10%) with median OS of 12.71 months (95% CI: 9.67-15.75). For metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer, ADC efficacy was higher in chemotherapy-experienced patients (ORR: 17% vs. 5%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ADCs demonstrate efficacy and safety in treating urological cancers, but further clinical trials are needed, particularly for renal, testicular, and prostate cancers, to support personalized treatment strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Liu, Xie, Ren, Li, Cai, Yu and Zhuo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tian</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Pingxiang Affiliated Hospital, Pingxiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Pingxiang Affiliated Hospital, Pingxiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Yangz-Zi</ForeName><Initials>YZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zongyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Tongji Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Maoping</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Fudan University Shanghai Cancer Center, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Yuzhong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Nanfang Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuo</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Pingxiang Affiliated Hospital, Pingxiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1663-9812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibody-drug conjugates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urological cancers</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The reviewer SCZ declared a shared affiliation with the author YY to the handling editor at the time of review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40959458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12433865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2025.1583654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1583654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal R. R., Vuky J., VanderWeele D. J., Rettig M., Heath E. I., Beer T. M., et al. (2022). Phase 1a/1b study of FOR46, an antibody drug conjugate (ADC), targeting CD46 in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC). J. Clin. Oncol. 40, 3001. 10.1200/JCO.2022.40.16_suppl.3001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2022.40.16_suppl.3001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12084135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40138611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Andrea Necchi D. M., Anichini A., Raggi D., Giannatempo P., Nicolai N., Colecchia M., et al.  (2016). An open-label, single-group, phase 2 study of brentuximab vedotin as salvage therapy for males with relapsed germ-cell tumors (GCT): results at the end of first stage (FM12GCT01). 34
480. Available online at: https://ascopubs.org/doi/10.1200/jco.2016.34.2_suppl.480.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2016.34.2_suppl.480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashkar R., Feldman D. R., Adra N., Zaid M. A., Funt S. A., Althouse S. K., et al. (2021). Phase II trial of brentuximab vedotin in relapsed/refractory germ cell tumors. Invest New Drugs 39, 1656&#x2013;1663. 10.1007/s10637-021-01134-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10637-021-01134-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34031784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardia A., Messersmith W. A., Kio E. A., Berlin J. D., Vahdat L., Masters G. A., et al. (2021). Sacituzumab govitecan, a Trop-2-directed antibody-drug conjugate, for patients with epithelial cancer: final safety and efficacy results from the phase I/II IMMU-132-01 basket trial. Ann. Oncol. official J. Eur. Soc. Med. Oncol. 32, 746&#x2013;756. 10.1016/j.annonc.2021.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2021.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33741442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordeau B. M., Nguyen T. D., Polli J. R., Chen P., Balthasar J. P. (2023). Payload-binding fab fragments increase the therapeutic index of MMAE antibody-drug conjugates. Mol. Cancer Ther. 22, 459&#x2013;470. 10.1158/1535-7163.Mct-22-0440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1535-7163.Mct-22-0440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10073278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36723609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray F., Laversanne M., Sung H., Ferlay J., Siegel R. L., Soerjomataram I., et al. (2024). Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J. Clin. 74, 229&#x2013;263. 10.3322/caac.21834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang E., Weinstock C., Zhang L., Charlab R., Dorff S. E., Gong Y., et al. (2021). FDA approval summary: enfortumab vedotin for locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma. Clin. cancer Res. official J. Am. Assoc. Cancer Res. 27, 922&#x2013;927. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-20-2275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-20-2275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32962979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Yao K., Cao M., Liu H., Xue C., Qin T., et al. (2023). HER2-targeting antibody-drug conjugate RC48 alone or in combination with immunotherapy for locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma: a multicenter, real-world study. Cancer Immunol. Immunother. CII 72, 2309&#x2013;2318. 10.1007/s00262-023-03419-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00262-023-03419-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10264489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36897337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Wang M., Qi X., Long H., Qi N., Wu L., et al. (2024). RC48-Antibody-Drug conjugate in metastatic urothelial carcinoma: a multicenter real-world study in China. Clin. Genitourin. cancer 22, 102093. 10.1016/j.clgc.2024.102093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clgc.2024.102093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38762350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo R., Tarantino P., Rich J. R., LoRusso P. M., de Vries E. G. E. (2024). The journey of antibody-drug conjugates: lessons learned from 40 Years of development. Cancer Discov. 14, 2089&#x2013;2108. 10.1158/2159-8290.Cd-24-0708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/2159-8290.Cd-24-0708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti R. M., Frank R. G., Gruber J. (2021). Regulating drug prices while increasing innovation. N. Engl. J. Med. 385, 1921&#x2013;1923. 10.1056/NEJMp2113764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp2113764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danila D. C., Szmulewitz R. Z., Vaishampayan U., Higano C. S., Baron A. D., Gilbert H. N., et al. (2019). Phase I study of DSTP3086S, an antibody-drug conjugate targeting six-transmembrane epithelial antigen of prostate 1, in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. official J. Am. Soc. Clin. Oncol. 37, 3518&#x2013;3527. 10.1200/jco.19.00646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.19.00646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31689155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bono J. S., Fleming M. T., Wang J. S., Cathomas R., Miralles M. S., Bothos J., et al. (2021). Phase I study of MEDI3726: a prostate-specific membrane antigen-targeted antibody-drug conjugate, in patients with mCRPC after failure of abiraterone or enzalutamide. Clin. Cancer Res. 27, 3602&#x2013;3609. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-20-4528</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-20-4528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries E. G. E., R&#xfc;schoff J., Lolkema M., Tabernero J., Gianni L., Voest E., et al. (2023). Phase II study (KAMELEON) of single-agent T-DM1 in patients with HER2-positive advanced urothelial bladder cancer or pancreatic cancer/cholangiocarcinoma. Cancer Med. 12, 12071&#x2013;12083. 10.1002/cam4.5893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.5893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37119523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drago J. Z., Modi S., Chandarlapaty S. (2021). Unlocking the potential of antibody-drug conjugates for cancer therapy. Nat. Rev. Clin. Oncol. 18, 327&#x2013;344. 10.1038/s41571-021-00470-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41571-021-00470-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33558752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy G. W., Gore J. L., Forouzanfar M. H., Naghavi M., Fitzmaurice C. (2017). Global burden of urologic cancers, 1990-2013. Eur. Urol. 71, 437&#x2013;446. 10.1016/j.eururo.2016.10.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2016.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhauer E. A., Therasse P., Bogaerts J., Schwartz L. H., Sargent D., Ford R., et al. (2009). New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur. J. Cancer 45, 228&#x2013;247. 10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19097774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emens L. A., Esteva F., Beresford M., Saura C., De Laurentiis M., Kim S. B., et al. (2019). Overall survival (OS) in KATE2, a phase II study of programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) inhibitor atezolizumab (atezo)+trastuzumab emtansine (T-DM1) vs placebo (pbo)+T-DM1 in previously treated HER2+ advanced breast cancer (BC). Ann. Oncol. 30, v104. 10.1093/annonc/mdz242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdz242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emens L. A., Esteva F. J., Beresford M., Saura C., De Laurentiis M., Kim S. B., et al. (2020). Trastuzumab emtansine plus atezolizumab versus trastuzumab emtansine plus placebo in previously treated, HER2-positive advanced breast cancer (KATE2): a phase 2, multicentre, randomised, double-blind trial. Lancet Oncol. 21, 1283&#x2013;1295. 10.1016/S1470-2045(20)30465-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(20)30465-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo Y., Akatsuka J., Takeda H., Hasegawa H., Yanagi M., Toyama Y., et al. (2024). Real-world insights into efficacy and safety of enfortumab vedotin in Japanese patients with metastatic urothelial carcinoma: findings, considerations, and future directions. Curr. Oncol. Tor. Ont. 31, 759&#x2013;768. 10.3390/curroncol31020056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/curroncol31020056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10887831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38392050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelberg A. B., Avorn J., Kesselheim A. S. (2022). A new way to contain unaffordable medication costs - exercising the government's existing Rights. N. Engl. J. Med. 386, 1104&#x2013;1106. 10.1056/NEJMp2117102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp2117102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35139270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Food U., Administration D. (2023). FDA grants accelerated approval to enfortumab vedotin-ejfv with pembrolizumab for locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma. FDA. Available online at: www.fda.gov/drugs/resources-information-approved-drugs/fda-grants-accelerated-approval-enfortumab-vedotin-ejfv-pembrolizumab-locally-advanced-or-metastatic.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Z., Zhou Y., Yan T., Lu Y. (2022). Numerical modelling of drying induced cracks in wood discs using the extended finite element method. J. Renew. Mater. 11, 93&#x2013;102. 10.32604/jrm.2022.021808</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/jrm.2022.021808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuokaya W., Koike Y., Yata Y., Komura K., Uchimoto T., Tsujino T., et al. (2024). Real world evidence of enfortumab vedotin in patients with advanced urothelial cancer: a multicenter observational study. Int. J. urology official J. Jpn. Urological Assoc. 31, 342&#x2013;347. 10.1111/iju.15368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iju.15368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38113343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabison E. E., Rousseau A., Labetoulle M., Gazzah A., Besse B. (2024). Ocular adverse events associated with antibody-drug conjugates used in cancer: focus on pathophysiology and management strategies. Prog. Retin Eye Res. 103, 101302. 10.1016/j.preteyeres.2024.101302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.preteyeres.2024.101302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39303762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galsky M. D., Eisenberger M., Moore-Cooper S., Kelly W. K., Slovin S. F., DeLaCruz A., et al. (2008). Phase I trial of the prostate-specific membrane antigen-directed immunoconjugate MLN2704 in patients with progressive metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. 26, 2147&#x2013;2154. 10.1200/jco.2007.15.0532</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2007.15.0532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18362364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan K., Gao Y., Liu K., Xu B., Qin W. (2021). The clinical significance and prognostic value of HER2 expression in bladder cancer: a meta-analysis and a bioinformatic analysis. Front. Oncol. 11, 653491. 10.3389/fonc.2021.653491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2021.653491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34540657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber H. P., Sapra P., Loganzo F., May C. (2016). Combining antibody-drug conjugates and immune-mediated cancer therapy: what to expect? Biochem. Pharmacol. 102, 1&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.bcp.2015.12.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcp.2015.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26686577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grivas P., Pouessel D., Park C. H., Barthelemy P., Bupathi M., Petrylak D. P., et al. (2024). Sacituzumab govitecan in combination with pembrolizumab for patients with metastatic urothelial cancer that progressed after platinum-based chemotherapy: TROPHY-U-01 cohort 3. J. Clin. Oncol. official J. Am. Soc. Clin. Oncol. 42, 1415&#x2013;1425. 10.1200/jco.22.02835</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.22.02835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38261969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton E. P., Kaklamani V., Falkson C., Vidal G. A., Ward P. J., Patre M., et al. (2021). Impact of anti-HER2 treatments combined with atezolizumab on the tumor immune microenvironment in early or metastatic breast cancer: results from a phase ib study. Clin. Breast Cancer 21, 539&#x2013;551. 10.1016/j.clbc.2021.04.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clbc.2021.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34154926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton E. P., Shapiro C., Boni V., Martin Jimenez M., Del Conte G., Cort&#xe9;s J., et al. (2022). 162O Primary analysis from DS8201-A-U105: a 2-part, open label, phase Ib trial assessing trastuzumab deruxtecan (T-DXd) with nivolumab (nivo) in patients (pts) with HER2-expressing advanced breast cancer. Ann. Oncol. 33, S196. 10.1016/j.annonc.2022.03.181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2022.03.181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann R. M., Coumbe B. G. T., Josephs D. H., Mele S., Ilieva K. M., Cheung A., et al. (2018). Antibody structure and engineering considerations for the design and function of Antibody Drug Conjugates (ADCs). Oncoimmunology 7, e1395127. 10.1080/2162402x.2017.1395127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2162402x.2017.1395127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5769674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29375935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez R. E., Hussain M., Bianco F. J., Vaishampayan U., Tabazcka P., Sakr W. A., et al. (2001). Her-2/neu overexpression in muscle-invasive urothelial carcinoma of the bladder: prognostic significance and comparative analysis in primary and metastatic tumors. Clin. Cancer Res. 7, 2440&#x2013;2447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11489824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollmannsberger C., Choueiri T. K., Heng D. Y. C., George S., Jie F., Croitoru R., et al. (2021). A randomized phase II study of AGS-16C3F versus axitinib in previously treated patients with metastatic renal cell carcinoma. Oncol. 26, 182-e361. 10.1002/onco.13628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/onco.13628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koshkin V. S., Henderson N., James M., Natesan D., Freeman D., Nizam A., et al. (2022). Efficacy of enfortumab vedotin in advanced urothelial cancer: analysis from the urothelial cancer network to investigate therapeutic experiences (UNITE) study. Cancer 128, 1194&#x2013;1205. 10.1002/cncr.34057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.34057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei H., Ling Y., Yuan P., Yan X., Wang L., Shi Y., et al. (2023). Assessment of the expression pattern of HER2 and its correlation with HER2-targeting antibody-drug conjugate therapy in urothelial cancer. J. Natl. Cancer Cent. 3, 121&#x2013;128. 10.1016/j.jncc.2023.02.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jncc.2023.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11256704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39035731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Xu M. Z., Wang L., Jiang J., Dong L. H., Chen F., et al. (2020). Conjugating MMAE to a novel anti-HER2 antibody for selective targeted delivery. Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci. 24, 12929&#x2013;12937. 10.26355/eurrev_202012_24196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_202012_24196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maecker H., Jonnalagadda V., Bhakta S., Jammalamadaka V., Junutula J. R. (2023). Exploration of the antibody-drug conjugate clinical landscape. MAbs 15, 2229101. 10.1080/19420862.2023.2229101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19420862.2023.2229101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37639687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majumdar S., Siahaan T. J. (2012). Peptide-mediated targeted drug delivery. Med. Res. Rev. 32, 637&#x2013;658. 10.1002/med.20225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/med.20225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20814957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marei H. E., Cenciarelli C., Hasan A. (2022). Potential of antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) for cancer therapy. Cancer Cell Int. 22, 255. 10.1186/s12935-022-02679-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-022-02679-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9375290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35964048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks S., Naidoo J. (2022). Antibody drug conjugates in non-small cell lung cancer: an emerging therapeutic approach. Lung Cancer 163, 59&#x2013;68. 10.1016/j.lungcan.2021.11.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2021.11.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34923203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massard C., Soria J. C., Krauss J., Gordon M., Lockhart A. C., Rasmussen E., et al. (2019). First-in-human study to assess safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics of the anti-CD27L antibody-drug conjugate AMG 172 in patients with relapsed/refractory renal cell carcinoma. Cancer Chemother. Pharmacol. 83, 1057&#x2013;1063. 10.1007/s00280-019-03796-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00280-019-03796-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30915497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCombs J. R., Owen S. C. (2015). Antibody drug conjugates: design and selection of linker, payload and conjugation chemistry. Aaps J. 17, 339&#x2013;351. 10.1208/s12248-014-9710-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1208/s12248-014-9710-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4365093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25604608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor B. A., Gordon M., Flippot R., Agarwal N., George S., Quinn D. I., et al. (2020). Safety and efficacy of CDX-014, an antibody-drug conjugate directed against T cell immunoglobulin mucin-1 in advanced renal cell carcinoma. Investig. new drugs 38, 1807&#x2013;1814. 10.1007/s10637-020-00945-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10637-020-00945-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32472319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor B. A., Sonpavde G. P., Kwak L., Regan M. M., Gao X., Hvidsten H., et al. (2024). The Double Antibody Drug Conjugate (DAD) phase I trial: sacituzumab govitecan plus enfortumab vedotin for metastatic urothelial carcinoma. Ann. Oncol. official J. Eur. Soc. Med. Oncol. 35, 91&#x2013;97. 10.1016/j.annonc.2023.09.3114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2023.09.3114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37871703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh D., Eisenberger M., Heath E. I., Bruce J., Danila D. C., Rathkopf D. E., et al. (2019). A phase I study of the antibody drug conjugate ASG-5ME, an SLC44A4-targeting antibody carrying auristatin E, in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. Investig. new drugs 37, 1052&#x2013;1060. 10.1007/s10637-019-00731-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10637-019-00731-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6684870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milowsky M. I., Galsky M. D., Morris M. J., Crona D. J., George D. J., Dreicer R., et al. (2016). Phase 1/2 multiple ascending dose trial of the prostate-specific membrane antigen-targeted antibody drug conjugate MLN2704 in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. Urol. Oncol. 34, 530.e515&#x2013;530. 10.1016/j.urolonc.2016.07.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.urolonc.2016.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27765518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minato A., Kimuro R., Ohno D., Tanigawa K., Kuretake K., Matsukawa T., et al. (2023). Efficacy and tolerability of enfortumab vedotin for metastatic urothelial carcinoma: early experience in the real world. Anticancer Res. 43, 4055&#x2013;4060. 10.21873/anticanres.16594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/anticanres.16594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37648337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minato A., Furubayashi N., Tomoda T., Masaoka H., Song Y., Hori Y., et al. (2024). Clinical outcomes of enfortumab vedotin in advanced urothelial carcinoma with prior avelumab versus pembrolizumab therapy. Anticancer Res. 44, 3419&#x2013;3426. 10.21873/anticanres.17162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/anticanres.17162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39060065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyake M., Nishimura N., Oda Y., Miyamoto T., Ohmori C., Takamatsu N., et al. (2024). Enfortumab vedotin following platinum-based chemotherapy and immune checkpoint inhibitors for advanced urothelial carcinoma: response, survival and safety analysis from a multicentre real-world Japanese cohort. Jpn. J. Clin. Oncol. 54, 329&#x2013;338. 10.1093/jjco/hyad170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyad170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38061911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol&#xf2; E., Giugliano F., Ascione L., Tarantino P., Corti C., Tolaney S. M., et al. (2022). Combining antibody-drug conjugates with immunotherapy in solid tumors: current landscape and future perspectives. Cancer Treat. Rev. 106, 102395. 10.1016/j.ctrv.2022.102395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctrv.2022.102395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35468539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell P. H., Milowsky M. I., Petrylak D. P., Hoimes C. J., Flaig T. W., Mar N., et al. (2023). Enfortumab vedotin with or without pembrolizumab in cisplatin-ineligible patients with previously untreated locally advanced or metastatic urothelial cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. official J. Am. Soc. Clin. Oncol. 41, 4107&#x2013;4117. 10.1200/jco.22.02887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.22.02887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10852367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37369081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldenburg J., Berney D. M., Bokemeyer C., Climent M. A., Daugaard G., Gietema J. A., et al. (2022). Testicular seminoma and non-seminoma: ESMO-EURACAN Clinical Practice Guideline for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann. Oncol. 33, 362&#x2013;375. 10.1016/j.annonc.2022.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2022.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal S. K., Forero-Torres A., Thompson J. A., Morris J. C., Chhabra S., Hoimes C. J., et al. (2019). A phase 1 trial of SGN-CD70A in patients with CD70-positive, metastatic renal cell carcinoma. Cancer 125, 1124&#x2013;1132. 10.1002/cncr.31912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.31912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30624766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker C., Castro E., Fizazi K., Heidenreich A., Procopio G. (2020). Prostate cancer: ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann. Oncol. 31, 1119&#x2013;1134. 10.1016/j.annonc.2020.06.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2020.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrylak D. P., Tagawa S. T., Jain R. K., Bupathi M., Balar A., Kalebasty A. R., et al. (2024). TROPHY-U-01 cohort 2: a phase II study of sacituzumab govitecan in cisplatin-ineligible patients with metastatic urothelial cancer progressing after previous checkpoint inhibitor therapy. J. Clin. Oncol. official J. Am. Soc. Clin. Oncol. 42, 3410&#x2013;3420. 10.1200/jco.23.01720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.23.01720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11458109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39186707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S., Loi S., Andr&#xe9; F., Chandarlapaty S., Felip E., Finn S. P., et al. (2024). Antibody&#x2013;drug conjugates in lung and breast cancer: current evidence and future directions&#x2014;a position statement from the ETOP IBCSG Partners Foundation. Ann. Oncol. 35, 607&#x2013;629. 10.1016/j.annonc.2024.04.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2024.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38648979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrylak D. P., Kantoff P., Vogelzang N. J., Mega A., Fleming M. T., Stephenson J. J., et al. (2019). Phase 1 study of PSMA ADC, an antibody-drug conjugate targeting prostate-specific membrane antigen, in chemotherapy-refractory prostate cancer. Prostate 79, 604&#x2013;613. 10.1002/pros.23765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pros.23765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrylak D. P., Vogelzang N. J., Chatta K., Fleming M. T., Smith D. C., Appleman L. J., et al. (2020). PSMA ADC monotherapy in patients with progressive metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer following abiraterone and/or enzalutamide: efficacy and safety in open-label single-arm phase 2 study. Prostate 80, 99&#x2013;108. 10.1002/pros.23922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pros.23922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31742767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powles T., Rosenberg J. E., Sonpavde G. P., Loriot Y., Dur&#xe1;n I., Lee J. L., et al. (2021). Enfortumab vedotin in previously treated advanced urothelial carcinoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 384, 1125&#x2013;1135. 10.1056/NEJMoa2035807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2035807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powles T., Bellmunt J., Comperat E., De Santis M., Huddart R., Loriot Y., et al. (2022). Bladder cancer: ESMO Clinical Practice Guideline for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann. Oncol. official J. Eur. Soc. Med. Oncol. 33, 244&#x2013;258. 10.1016/j.annonc.2021.11.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2021.11.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powles T., Valderrama B. P., Gupta S., Bedke J., Kikuchi E., Hoffman-Censits J., et al. (2024a). Enfortumab vedotin and pembrolizumab in untreated advanced urothelial cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 390, 875&#x2013;888. 10.1056/NEJMoa2312117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2312117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38446675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powles T., Albiges L., Bex A., Comperat E., Gr&#xfc;nwald V., Kanesvaran R., et al. (2024b). Renal cell carcinoma: ESMO Clinical Practice Guideline for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann. Oncol. 35, 692&#x2013;706. 10.1016/j.annonc.2024.05.537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2024.05.537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38788900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J. W., Chen Z. Y., Bai Y. J., Han P. (2024). Efficacy and safety of antibody-drug conjugates in the treatment of urothelial cell carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective clinical trials. Front. Pharmacol. 15, 1377924. 10.3389/fphar.2024.1377924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1377924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11199396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38933670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg J. E., O'Donnell P. H., Balar A. V., McGregor B. A., Heath E. I., Yu E. Y., et al. (2019). Pivotal trial of enfortumab vedotin in urothelial carcinoma after platinum and anti-programmed death 1/programmed death ligand 1 therapy. J. Clin. Oncol. 37, 2592&#x2013;2600. 10.1200/jco.19.01140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.19.01140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6784850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31356140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg J., Sridhar S. S., Zhang J., Smith D., Ruether D., Flaig T. W., et al. (2020). EV-101: a phase I study of single-agent enfortumab vedotin in patients with nectin-4-positive solid tumors, including metastatic urothelial carcinoma. J. Clin. Oncol. 38, 1041&#x2013;1049. 10.1200/jco.19.02044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.19.02044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7106979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardinha M., Palma Dos Reis A. F., Barreira J. V., Fontes Sousa M., Pacey S., Luz R. (2023). Antibody-drug conjugates in prostate cancer: a systematic review. Cureus 15, e34490. 10.7759/cureus.34490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.34490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9983052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36874351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatz C. A., Zitzmann-Kolbe S., Moen I., Klotz M., Nair S., Stargard S., et al. (2024). Preclinical efficacy of a PSMA-targeted actinium-225 conjugate (225Ac-Macropa-Pelgifatamab): a targeted alpha therapy for prostate cancer. Clin. cancer Res. official J. Am. Assoc. Cancer Res. 30, 2531&#x2013;2544. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-23-3746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-23-3746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38593212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen J., Pachynski R., Nordquist L., Adra N., Bilen M., Aggarwal R., et al. (2023). 1804P APEX-01: first-in-human phase I/II study of ARX517 an anti-prostate-specific membrane antigen (PSMA) antibody-drug conjugate (ADC) in patients (pts) with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC). Ann. Oncol. 34, S974&#x2013;S975. 10.1016/j.annonc.2023.09.2752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2023.09.2752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng X., Yan X., Wang L., Shi Y., Yao X., Luo H., et al. (2021). Open-label, multicenter, phase II study of RC48-ADC, a HER2-targeting antibody-drug conjugate, in patients with locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma. Clin. cancer Res. official J. Am. Assoc. Cancer Res. 27, 43&#x2013;51. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-20-2488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-20-2488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33109737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng X., Wang L., He Z., Shi Y., Luo H., Han W., et al. (2024). Efficacy and safety of disitamab vedotin in patients with human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-positive locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma: a combined analysis of two phase II clinical trials. J. Clin. Oncol. official J. Am. Soc. Clin. Oncol. 42, 1391&#x2013;1402. 10.1200/jco.22.02912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.22.02912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37988648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel R. L., Miller K. D., Wagle N. S., Jemal A. (2023). Cancer statistics, 2023. CA Cancer J. Clin. 73, 17&#x2013;48. 10.3322/caac.21763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36633525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Siming Li Y. S., Dong H., Guo H., Li Y., Kadeerbai H., Xu C., et al.  (2023). EV-203: phase 2 trial of enfortumab vedotin in patients with previously treated advanced urothelial carcinoma in China. 41
e16574. Available online at: https://ascopubs.org/.
10.1200/JCO.2023.41.16_suppl.e16574
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2023.41.16_suppl.e16574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11555717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39530574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slim K., Nini E., Forestier D., Kwiatkowski F., Panis Y., Chipponi J. (2003). Methodological index for non-randomized studies (minors): development and validation of a new instrument. ANZ J. Surg. 73, 712&#x2013;716. 10.1046/j.1445-2197.2003.02748.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1445-2197.2003.02748.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12956787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. (2010). Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur. J. Epidemiol. 25, 603&#x2013;605. 10.1007/s10654-010-9491-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-010-9491-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20652370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne J. A. C., Savovi&#x107; J., Page M. J., Elbers R. G., Blencowe N. S., Boutron I., et al. (2019). RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Bmj 366, l4898. 10.1136/bmj.l4898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strebhardt K., Ullrich A. (2008). Paul Ehrlich's magic bullet concept: 100 years of progress. Nat. Rev. Cancer 8, 473&#x2013;480. 10.1038/nrc2394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrc2394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagawa S. T., Balar A. V., Petrylak D. P., Kalebasty A. R., Loriot Y., Fl&#xe9;chon A., et al. (2021). TROPHY-U-01: a phase II open-label study of sacituzumab govitecan in patients with metastatic urothelial carcinoma progressing after platinum-based chemotherapy and checkpoint inhibitors. J. Clin. Oncol. official J. Am. Soc. Clin. Oncol. 39, 2474&#x2013;2485. 10.1200/jco.20.03489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.20.03489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8315301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33929895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi S., Uemura M., Kimura T., Kawasaki Y., Takamoto A., Yamaguchi A., et al. (2020). A phase I study of enfortumab vedotin in Japanese patients with locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma. Invesst New Drugs 38, 1056&#x2013;1066. 10.1007/s10637-019-00844-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10637-019-00844-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31444589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarantino P., Carmagnani Pestana R., Corti C., Modi S., Bardia A., Tolaney S. M., et al. (2022). Antibody-drug conjugates: smart chemotherapy delivery across tumor histologies. CA Cancer J. Clin. 72, 165&#x2013;182. 10.3322/caac.21705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson J. A., Motzer R. J., Molina A. M., Choueiri T. K., Heath E. I., Redman B. G., et al. (2018). Phase I trials of anti-ENPP3 antibody-drug conjugates in advanced refractory renal cell carcinomas. Clin. Cancer Res. 24, 4399&#x2013;4406. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-18-0481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-18-0481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6731023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
U.S.Food and administration (2021). FDA grants accelerated approval to sacituzumab govitecan for advanced urothelial cancer. Available online at: https://www.fda.gov/drugs/resources-information-approved-drugs/fda-grants-accelerated-approval-sacituzumab-govitecan-advanced-urothelial-cancer.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Yi Y., Wan X., Zeng X., Peng Y., Tan C. (2022). Cost-effectiveness analysis of trastuzumab deruxtecan versus trastuzumab emtansine in human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-positive metastatic breast cancer in the USA. Adv. Ther. 39, 4583&#x2013;4593. 10.1007/s12325-022-02273-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-022-02273-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35943715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wasilijiang Wahafu S. W., Qiao X., Zhang Xi, Wang M., Han S., Cui Yu, et al.  (2024). Disitamab vedotin (DV, RC48-ADC) combined with cadonilimab (anti-PD-1/CTLA-4 bispecific antibody) in patients with locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma (la/mUC): An open-label, single-arm, phase II study. 42
e16572. Available online at: https://ascopubs.org/doi/10.1200/JCO.2024.42.16_suppl.e16572.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2024.42.16_suppl.e16572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y., Zhang R., Yu C., Hong Z., Lin L. (2023). Disitamab vedotin in combination with immune checkpoint inhibitors for locally and locally advanced bladder urothelial carcinoma: a two-center's real-world study. Front. Pharmacol. 14, 1230395. 10.3389/fphar.2023.1230395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1230395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10461006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37645442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Cancer Research Fund International (2023). Cancer trends. Available online at: https://www.wcrf.org/cancer-trends.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Xinan Sheng L. Z., Yang K., Zhang S., Xu H., Yan X., Li S., et al.  (2023). Disitamab vedotin, a novel humanized anti-HER2 antibody-drug conjugate (ADC), combined with toripalimab in patients with locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma: an open-label phase 1b/2 study. 41
4566. Available online at: https://ascopubs.org/doi/10.1200/JCO.2023.41.16_suppl.4566.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2023.41.16_suppl.4566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H., Zhou L., Yan X., Li S., Chi Z., Cui C., et al. (2022). A phase II study of RC48-ADC in HER2-negative patients with locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma. 40 4519. 10.1200/JCO.2022.40.16_suppl.4519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2022.40.16_suppl.4519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Zhang H., Zhang L., Chu X., Li Y., Li G., et al. (2023). Real-world effectiveness and safety of RC48-ADC alone or in combination with PD-1 inhibitors for patients with locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma: a multicenter, retrospective clinical study. Cancer Med. 12, 21159&#x2013;21171. 10.1002/cam4.6680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.6680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10726858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37935113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh Y., Chen C., Ko Y. (2022). Effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of trastuzumab emtansine in women with HER2-positive locally advanced or metastatic breast cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Cancer Res. Ther. 18, 1061&#x2013;1072. 10.4103/jcrt.jcrt_1095_21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jcrt.jcrt_1095_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36149162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu E. Y., Petrylak D. P., O'Donnell P. H., Lee J. L., van der Heijden M. S., Loriot Y., et al. (2021). Enfortumab vedotin after PD-1 or PD-L1 inhibitors in cisplatin-ineligible patients with advanced urothelial carcinoma (EV-201): a multicentre, single-arm, phase 2 trial. Lancet. Oncol. 22, 872&#x2013;882. 10.1016/s1470-2045(21)00094-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(21)00094-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33991512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Wu S., Li R., Jiang Y., Zheng J., Li Z., et al. (2023). Novel ADCs and combination therapy in urothelial carcinoma: latest updates from the 2023 ASCO-GU Cancers Symposium. J. Hematol. and Oncol. 16, 85. 10.1186/s13045-023-01475-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-023-01475-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10385919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37507780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y., Zhu X., Wei X., Tang C., Zhang W. (2021). HER2-targeted therapies in gastric cancer. Biochim. Biophys. Acta Rev. Cancer 1876, 188549. 10.1016/j.bbcan.2021.188549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbcan.2021.188549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y., Liu K., Wang M., Wang K., Zhu H. (2022). Trastuzumab deruxtecan versus trastuzumab emtansine for patients with human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-positive metastatic breast cancer: a cost-effectiveness analysis. Breast 66, 191&#x2013;198. 10.1016/j.breast.2022.10.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.breast.2022.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9619174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36327624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu K., Chang Y., Zhao D., Guo A., Cao J., Wu C., et al. (2024). Expression of HER2 in high-grade urothelial carcinoma based on Chinese expert consensus and the clinical effects of disitamab vedotin-tislelizumab combination therapy in the treatment of advanced patients. Front. Pharmacol. 15, 1355081. 10.3389/fphar.2024.1355081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1355081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10918465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38455962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zsch&#xe4;bitz S., Biernath N., Hilser T., H&#xf6;llein A., Zengerling F., Cascucelli J., et al. (2023). Enfortumab vedotin in metastatic urothelial carcinoma: survival and safety in a European multicenter real-world patient cohort. Eur. urology open Sci. 53, 31&#x2013;37. 10.1016/j.euros.2023.04.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euros.2023.04.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10334227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37441344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>