<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40913094</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1740-634X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropsychopharmacology : official publication of the American College of Neuropsychopharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropsychopharmacology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Towards causal inference-based antidepressant selection with brain and blood biomarkers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41386-025-02183-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This report sought to employ multi-modal integration of pre-treatment brain (electroencephalogram, resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging) and blood (immune and metabolic) biomarkers to facilitate causal inference-based treatment selection by virtue of establishing predictability of remission to multi-stage antidepressant treatment. Data from two stages of pharmacotherapy in the 'Establishing Moderators and Biosignatures of Antidepressant Response for Clinical Care for Depression' (EMBARC) study from participants with both brain and blood biomarkers were included (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;197). Participants were initially randomized to sertraline or placebo (Stage 1), and depending on clinical response at week-8, their therapy in Stage 2 was either maintained or switched (to sertraline, if a non-responder to placebo, or to bupropion, if a non-responder to sertraline). Three readily accessible clinical features combined with 15 multi-modal features associated with baseline depression severity predicted stage 2 remission with an AUC of 0.74, 0.71, and 0.73 for sertraline, bupropion, and placebo treatment respectively. Propensity score-matching (causal inference) was conducted across Stage 2 treatment arms, and the same features were used to build an unsupervised model to produce the probability of remission to the given Stage 2 treatment (as factual outcome), as well as the alternative treatment not given (as counter factual). While the accuracy of observed outcomes across treatment arms was 82%, the accuracies of predicted counterfactual (unobserved) outcomes warrant future prospective studies. 16 weeks and associated biomarker-based prediction of counterfactuals suggest that the selected markers are highly sensitive features for guiding antidepressant treatment selection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barac</LastName><ForeName>Milica</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-2266-5953</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grant</LastName><ForeName>Caroline W</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9342-2138</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toll</LastName><ForeName>Russell</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carmody</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science and Biostatistics, Peter O'Donnell Jr. School of Public Health, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minhajuddin</LastName><ForeName>Abu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fatt</LastName><ForeName>Cherise Chin</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5080-6799</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foster</LastName><ForeName>Jane A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8579-4705</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science and Biostatistics, Peter O'Donnell Jr. School of Public Health, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Croarkin</LastName><ForeName>Paul E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6843-6503</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bobo</LastName><ForeName>William V</ForeName><Initials>WV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5674-3079</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Behavioral Sciences and Social Medicine, Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jha</LastName><ForeName>Manish K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2764-2391</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science and Biostatistics, Peter O'Donnell Jr. School of Public Health, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Athreya</LastName><ForeName>Arjun P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9764-1768</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA. athreya.arjun@mayo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA. athreya.arjun@mayo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trivedi</LastName><ForeName>Madhukar H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2983-1110</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Depression Research and Clinical Care, Peter O'Donnell Jr. Brain Institute and the Department of Psychiatry, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA. Madhukar.Trivedi@utsouthwestern.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23MH126202</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services | NIH | National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01MH092221</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services | NIH | National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropsychopharmacology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904907</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0893-133X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: Dr. Jha has the following conflicts to report: Contract research grants from Neurocrine Bioscience, Navitor/Supernus and Janssen Research &amp; Development; consultant fees from Janssen Scientific Affairs and Boehringer Ingelheim; and fees to serve on Data Safety and Monitoring Board for Worldwide Clinical Trials (Eliem, Skye and Inversargo), Vicore Pharma and IQVIA (Click). Dr. Croarkin has received research support from the National Institutes of Health (NIH), National Science Foundation (NSF), Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), Brain and Behavior Research Foundation and the Mayo Clinic Foundation. Dr. Croarkin has received research support from Pfizer, Inc. He has received grant-in-kind equipment support from Neuronetics, Inc.and MagVenture, Inc. for investigator-initiated studies. He received grant-in-kind supplies and genotyping from Assurex Health, Inc. for an investigator-initiated study. He served as the principal investigator for a multicenter study funded by Neuronetics Inc., a site principal investigator for a study funded by NeoSync, Inc., and site principal investigator for a study funded by Innosphere. Dr. Croarkin served as a paid consultant for Engrail Therapeutics, Meta Platforms, Inc, MindMed, Myriad Neuroscience,Procter &amp; Gamble Company, and Sunovion. .Dr. Croarkin is employed by Mayo Clinic. He receives compensation as the Editor-in-Chief for the Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. Dr. Chin Fatt has served as an advisor for Janssen Research &amp; Development. Dr. Foster has served on the Scientific Advisory Board for MRM Health NL and has received consulting/speaker fees from Takeda Canada, Rothman, Benson, Hedges Inc., and WebMD. Dr. Trivedi has provided consulting services to Alkermes Inc, Axsome Therapeutics, Biogen MA Inc., Cerebral Inc., Circular Genomics Inc, Compass Pathfinder Limited, GH Research Limited, Heading Health Inc, Janssen, Legion Health Inc, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp., Mind Medicine (MindMed) Inc, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme LLC, Naki Health, Ltd., Neurocrine Biosciences Inc, Noema Pharma AG, Orexo US Inc, Otsuka American Pharmaceutical Inc, Otsuka Canada Pharmaceutical Inc, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Development &amp; Commercialization Inc, Praxis Precision Medicines Inc, SAGE Therapeutics, SparianBiosciences Inc, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Ltd, WebMD. He sits on the Scientific Advisory Board of Alto Neuroscience Inc, Cerebral Inc., Compass Pathfinder Limited, Heading Health, GreenLight VitalSign6 Inc, Legion Health Inc, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp, Orexo US Inc, Signant Health. He holds stock in Alto Neuroscience Inc, Cerebral Inc, Circular Genomics Inc, GreenLight VitalSign6 Inc, Legion Health Inc. Additionally, he has received editorial compensation from American Psychiatric Association, and Oxford University Press. Dr Carmody has received consultant fees from Holmusk Technologies, Inc. Dr. Minhajuddin reports no conflicts of interest. Dr. Bobo has received research support from NIH, NSF, AHRQ, the Watzinger Foundation, the Blue Gator Foundation, the Myocarditis Foundation, and the Mayo Foundation for Medical Education and Research. He has contributed chapters to UpToDate on the pharmacological management of bipolar major depression. Dr. Toll reports no conflicts of interest. Dr. Athreya has received research support from NIH, NSF, the Watzinger Foundation, the Blue Gator Foundation, and the Mayo Foundation for Medical Education and Research. The remaining authors have nothing to disclose. Prior Presentation: This work&#x2019;s earlier findings were presented as a Poster at the 2025 Annual meeting of Am. College of Neuropsychopharmacology, Scottsdale, AZ, USA.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40913094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-025-02183-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41386-025-02183-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Friedrich MJ. Depression Is the leading cause of disability around the world. JAMA. 2017;317:1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28418491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kupcova I, Danisovic L, Klein M, Harsanyi S. Effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental health, anxiety, and depression. BMC Psychol. 2023;11:108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37041568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10088605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-023-01130-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi MH, Rush AJ, Wisniewski SR, Nierenberg AA, Warden D, Ritz L, et al. Evaluation of outcomes with citalopram for depression using measurement-based care in STAR*D: implications for clinical practice. Am J Psychiatry. 2006;163:28&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16390886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.163.1.28</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg PE, Fournier AA, Sisitsky T, Pike CT, Kessler RC. The economic burden of adults with major depressive disorder in the United States (2005 and 2010). J Clin Psychiatry. 2015;76:155&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25742202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.14m09298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips ML, Chase HW, Sheline YI, Etkin A, Almeida JR, Deckersbach T, et al. Identifying predictors, moderators, and mediators of antidepressant response in major depressive disorder: neuroimaging approaches. Am J Psychiatry. 2015;172:124&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25640931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4464814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.14010076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caspani G, Turecki G, Lam RW, Milev RV, Frey BN, MacQueen GM, et al. Metabolomic signatures associated with depression and predictors of antidepressant response in humans: A CAN-BIND-1 report. Commun Biol. 2021;4:903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34294869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8298446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-021-02421-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobo WV, Van Ommeren B, Athreya AP. Machine learning, pharmacogenomics, and clinical psychiatry: predicting antidepressant response in patients with major depressive disorder. Expert Rev Clin Pharm. 2022;15:927&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17512433.2022.2112949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EY, Ahn HS, Lee MY, Yu J, Yeom J, Jeong H, et al. An exploratory pilot study with plasma protein signatures associated with response of patients with depression to antidepressant treatment for 10 weeks. Biomedicines. 2020;8:455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7692261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines8110455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SE, Zantvoord JB, Wezenberg BN, Bockting C, van Wingen GA. Magnetic resonance imaging for individual prediction of treatment response in major depressive disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11:168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7960732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-021-01286-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts D, Pulice RF, Reilly J, Brunoni AR, Kapczinski F, Passos IC. Predicting treatment response using EEG in major depressive disorder: A machine-learning meta-analysis. Transl Psychiatry. 2022;12:332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35961967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9374666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-022-02064-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook IA, Hunter AM, Caudill MM, Abrams MJ, Leuchter AF. Prospective testing of a neurophysiologic biomarker for treatment decisions in major depressive disorder: The PRISE-MD trial. J Psychiatr Res. 2020;124:159&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32169689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7141143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2020.02.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Liu R, Zhou J, Feng L, Wang Y, Chen X, et al. Prediction of remission among patients with a major depressive disorder based on the resting-state functional connectivity of emotion regulation networks. Transl Psychiatry. 2022;12:391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36115833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9482642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-022-02152-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajjadian M, Uher R, Ho K, Hassel S, Milev R, Frey BN, et al. Prediction of depression treatment outcome from multimodal data: a CAN-BIND-1 report. Psychol Med. 2023;53:5374&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291722002124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajjadian M, Lam RW, Milev R, Rotzinger S, Frey BN, Soares CN, et al. Machine learning in the prediction of depression treatment outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychol Med. 2021;51:2742&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35575607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291721003871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi MH, McGrath PJ, Fava M, Parsey RV, Kurian BT, Phillips ML, et al. Establishing moderators and biosignatures of antidepressant response in clinical care (EMBARC): Rationale and design. J Psychiatr Res. 2016;78:11&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27038550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6100771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2016.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi MH, South C, Jha MK, Rush AJ, Cao J, Kurian B, et al. A novel strategy to identify placebo responders: prediction index of clinical and biological markers in the EMBARC trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2018;87:285&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30110685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000491093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poirot MG, Ruhe HG, Mutsaerts H, Maximov II, Groote IR, Bj&#xf8;rnerud A, et al. Treatment response prediction in major depressive disorder using multimodal MRI and clinical data: secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. Am J Psychiatry. 2024;181:223&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.20230206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busner J, Targum SD. The clinical global impressions scale: applying a research tool in clinical practice. Psychiatry. 2007;4:28&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20526405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2880930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobo WV, Angler&#xf3; GC, Jenkins G, Hall-Flavin DK, Weinshilboum R, Biernacka JM. Validation of the 17-item Hamilton Depression Rating Scale definition of response for adults with major depressive disorder using equipercentile linking to Clinical Global Impression scale ratings: analysis of Pharmacogenomic Research Network Antidepressant Medication Pharmacogenomic Study (PGRN-AMPS) data. Hum Psychopharmacol. 2016;31:185&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26999588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5008690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hup.2526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush AJ. STAR*D: what have we learned? Am J Psychiatry. 2007;164:201&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17267779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.2007.164.2.201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolle CE, Fonzo GA, Wu W, Toll R, Jha MK, Cooper C, et al. Cortical connectivity moderators of antidepressant vs placebo treatment response in major depressive disorder: secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2020;77:397&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6990859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.3867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenke CE, Kayser J, Pechtel P, Webb CA, Dillon DG, Goer F, et al. Demonstrating test-retest reliability of electrophysiological measures for healthy adults in a multisite study of biomarkers of antidepressant treatment response. Psychophysiology. 2017;54:34&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28000259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5181116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/psyp.12758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K, Xie H, Fonzo GA, Tong X, Carlisle N, Chidharom M, et al. Individualized fMRI connectivity defines signatures of antidepressant and placebo responses in major depression. Mol Psychiatry. 2023;28:2490&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36732585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-023-01958-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Zhang Y, Jiang J, Lucas MV, Fonzo GA, Rolle CE, et al. An electroencephalographic signature predicts antidepressant response in major depression. Nat Biotechnol. 2020;38:439&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32042166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7145761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41587-019-0397-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehmke BM, Boehmke BC. Variable Importance Plots-An Introduction to the vip Package. The R Journal. 2020;12:343&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman ES, Davis LL, Zisook S, Wisniewski SR, Trivedi MH, Fava M, et al. Baseline depression severity as a predictor of single and combination antidepressant treatment outcome: results from the CO-MED trial. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2012;22:183&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21920711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2011.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laken Pvd. paulvanderlaken/ppsr: CRAN ppsr 0.0.5. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao QY, Luo JC, Su Y, Zhang YJ, Tu GW, Luo Z. Propensity score matching with R: conventional methods and new features. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8246231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/atm-20-3998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart EA. Matching methods for causal inference: A review and a look forward. Stat Sci. 2010;25:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20871802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2943670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1214/09-STS313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis RH. Abandoning personalization to get to precision in the pharmacotherapy of depression. World Psychiatry. 2016;15:228&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5032508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnadas R, Leighton SP, Jones PB. Precision psychiatry: thinking beyond simple prediction models - enhancing causal predictions. Br J Psychiatry. 2025;226:184&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39810474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.2024.258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iniesta R, Malki K, Maier W, Rietschel M, Mors O, Hauser J, et al. Combining clinical variables to optimize prediction of antidepressant treatment outcomes. J Psychiatr Res. 2016;78:94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27089522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2016.03.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush AJ, Wisniewski SR, Warden D, Luther JF, Davis LL, Fava M, et al. Selecting among second-step antidepressant medication monotherapies: predictive value of clinical, demographic, or first-step treatment features. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2008;65:870&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18678792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.65.8.870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlman K, Mehltretter J, Benrimoh D, Armstrong C, Fratila R, Popescu C, et al. Development of a differential treatment selection model for depression on consolidated and transformed clinical trial datasets. Transl Psychiatry. 2024;14:263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38906883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11192904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-024-02970-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettorruso M, Di Lorenzo G, Benatti B, d'Andrea G, Cavallotto C, Carullo R, et al. Overcoming treatment-resistant depression with machine-learning based tools: a study protocol combining EEG and clinical data to personalize glutamatergic and brain stimulation interventions (SelecTool Project). Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1436006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39086731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11288917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2024.1436006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner RL. The brain&#x2019;s default network: origins and implications for the study of psychosis. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2013;15:351&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24174906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3811106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31887/DCNS.2013.15.3/rbuckner</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou T, Deckersbach T, Dougherty DD, Hooley JM. The default mode network and rumination in individuals at risk for depression. Soc Cogn Affect Neurosci, 2023;18:nsad032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiwei L, Xiaojing Z, Yingli Z, Shengli C, Xiaoshan L, Ziyun X, et al. Cortical hierarchy disorganization in major depressive disorder and its association with suicidality. Front Psychiatry. 2023;14:1140915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37168085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10165114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1140915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Yu X, Ma Y, Su J, Li Y, Zhu S, et al. Neural signatures of default mode network in major depression disorder after electroconvulsive therapy. Cereb Cortex. 2023;33:3840&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36089839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhac311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martens MAG, Filippini N, Harmer CJ, Godlewska BR. Resting state functional connectivity patterns as biomarkers of treatment response to escitalopram in patients with major depressive disorder. Psychopharmacology. 2022;239:3447&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34477887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-021-05915-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruse JL, Olmstead R, Hellemann G, Breen EC, Tye SJ, Brooks JO, et al. Interleukin-8 and lower severity of depression in females, but not males, with treatment-resistant depression. J Psychiatr Res. 2021;140:350&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34139457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8319139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2021.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;hler CA, Freitas TH, Maes M, de Andrade NQ, Liu CS, Fernandes BS, et al. Peripheral cytokine and chemokine alterations in depression: a meta-analysis of 82 studies. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2017;135:373&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.12698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyre HA, Air T, Pradhan A, Johnston J, Lavretsky H, Stuart MJ, et al. A meta-analysis of chemokines in major depression. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2016;68:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5536843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2016.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowlati Y, Herrmann N, Swardfager W, Liu H, Sham L, Reim EK, et al. A meta-analysis of cytokines in major depression. Biol Psychiatry. 2010;67:446&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20015486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.09.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu ZH, Song XY, Man LJ, Chen P, Tang Z, Li RH, et al. Comparisons of Serum Interleukin-8 Levels in Major Depressive Patients With Drug-Free Versus SSRIs Versus Healthy Controls. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:858675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9046727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.858675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruse JL, Vasavada MM, Olmstead R, Hellemann G, Wade B, Breen EC, et al. Depression treatment response to ketamine: sex-specific role of interleukin-8, but not other inflammatory markers. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11:167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7960960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-021-01268-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Zhang X, Cai Y, Zheng L, Pang H, Lou L. Sex difference in incidence of major depressive disorder: an analysis from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Ann Gen Psychiatry. 2023;22:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38087353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10714584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12991-023-00486-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerman BA, Hernan MA. Counterfactual prediction is not only for causal inference. Eur J Epidemiol. 2020;35:615&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32623620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7393612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-020-00659-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>