<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40821329</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Clinical and Angiographic Profile and Outcomes of Patients With Left Bundle Branch Block (LBBB): An Observational Study From a Tertiary Care Center in North India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e87953</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e87953</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e87953</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.87953</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background and objective Left bundle branch block (LBBB) is a common electrocardiographic abnormality resulting from impaired conduction in both the His-Purkinje system's anterior and posterior left fascicles. LBBB prevalence varies with age, gender, race, and underlying cardiovascular conditions. It affects 0.06-0.1% of the general population, rising to 6-7% in those over 80, and is often detected incidentally in older males. Although once considered a ST-segment-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) equivalent in chest pain, recent data indicate a low risk of myocardial infarction. Diagnosing coronary artery disease (CAD) in these patients is challenging due to limitations of noninvasive tests, often necessitating coronary angiography (CAG) for confirmation. CT angiography is typically the first-line test for patients under 65, while stress nuclear imaging or dobutamine stress echo is preferred in those 65 and older. Certain ECG changes, like ST elevation or depression, may suggest myocardial infarction in LBBB cases. This study aimed to examine various demographic and clinical features, as well as outcomes, in patients presenting with&#xa0;symptomatic LBBB Methods This non-randomized, prospective, single-center observational study aimed to evaluate the clinical characteristics, demographic profile, and outcomes of patients presenting with symptomatic LBBB. All enrolled patients underwent CAG, with or without subsequent revascularization, as part of their diagnostic workup. Results A total of 200 symptomatic LBBB patients, comprising 104 males (52%), with a mean age of 60.2 &#xb1; 11.4 years, were included in the study. Hypertension and diabetes mellitus were the most common comorbidities, observed in 98 (49%) and 68 (34%) patients, respectively. Additionally, 160 (80%) patients exhibited some degree of left ventricular (LV) systolic dysfunction. CAG showed normal findings in 100 patients (50%), obstructive CAD in 78 (39%), and non-obstructive CAD in 22 (11%). The left anterior descending (LAD) artery was the most involved vessel, affected in 70 patients (70%). Among the 78 patients with obstructive CAD, 72 (92.3%) had severe obstruction. The LAD artery was the most affected vessel, observed in 60 patients (76.9%). Percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) was performed in 42 patients, eight were referred for coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG), and 28 were managed with guideline-directed medical therapy (GDMT). Age &#x2265;50 years (p=0.005), angina (p&lt;0.001), diabetes mellitus (p&lt;0.001), and LV ejection fraction (LVEF) &#x2264;50% (p=0.006) were significantly associated with obstructive CAD. Mortality was also significantly higher in this group (p=0.001). During the six-month follow-up, 12 patients (6%), all over 70 years, died, resulting in an overall survival rate of 94% despite the high-risk profile. Conclusions Older patients with LBBB who present with angina, cardiovascular risk factors, and LV systolic dysfunction should be evaluated for CAD by using CAG, especially when troponin markers are elevated (troponin I&#xa0;&gt;0.04 ng/mL).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Khanal et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khanal</LastName><ForeName>Suraj</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER), Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thakur</LastName><ForeName>Jitender</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER), Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Basant</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER), Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dahiya</LastName><ForeName>Neelam</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER), Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiographic profile</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">left bundle branch block</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pci</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee issued approval IEC-INT/2022/DM-701. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40821329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12351135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.87953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scherbak D, Shams P, Hicks GJ. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Left Bundle Branch Block.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implications of left bundle branch block in patient treatment. Kumar V, Venkataraman R, Aljaroudi W, Osorio J, Heo J, Iskandrian AE, Hage FG. Am J Cardiol. 2013;111:291&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23111137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Functional abnormalities in isolated left bundle branch block. The effect of interventricular asynchrony. Grines CL, Bashore TM, Boudoulas H, Olson S, Shafer P, Wooley CF. Circulation. 1989;79:845&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2924415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block: Epidemiology, etiology, anatomic features, electrovectorcardiography, and classification proposal. P&#xe9;rez-Riera AR, Barbosa-Barros R, de Rezende Barbosa MP, Daminello-Raimundo R, de Abreu LC, Nikus K. Ann Noninvasive Electrocardiol. 2019;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6931474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29932265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racial and socioeconomic determinants of cardiovascular health: a comprehensive review. Borkowski P, Borkowska N, Mangeshkar S, Adal BH, Singh N. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11143437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38826910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Framingham Heart Study and the epidemiology of cardiovascular disease: a historical perspective. Mahmood SS, Levy D, Vasan RS, Wang TJ. Lancet. 2014;383:999&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24084292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Analysis of the electrocardiogram (Article in German) Zur EH. Wien Klin Wochenschr. 1909;22:1091&#x2013;1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AHA/ACCF/HRS recommendations for the standardization and interpretation of the electrocardiogram: part III: intraventricular conduction disturbances: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association Electrocardiography and Arrhythmias Committee, Council on Clinical Cardiology; the American College of Cardiology Foundation; and the Heart Rhythm Society: endorsed by the International Society for Computerized Electrocardiology. Surawicz B, Childers R, Deal BJ, et al. Circulation. 2009;119:0&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2018 ACC/AHA/HRS guideline on the evaluation and management of patients with bradycardia and cardiac conduction delay: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on clinical practice guidelines, and the Heart Rhythm Society. Kusumoto FM, Schoenfeld MH, Barrett C, et al. Circulation. 2019;140:0&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining left bundle branch block patterns in cardiac resynchronisation therapy: a return to his bundle recordings. Tung R, Upadhyay GA. Arrhythm Electrophysiol Rev. 2020;9:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7330724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining left bundle branch block in the era of cardiac resynchronization therapy. Strauss DG, Selvester RH, Wagner GS. Am J Cardiol. 2011;107:927&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21376930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block: from cardiac mechanics to clinical and diagnostic challenges. Surkova E, Badano LP, Bellu R, et al. Europace. 2017;19:1251&#x2013;1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A novel pacing strategy with low and stable output: pacing the left bundle branch immediately beyond the conduction block. Huang W, Su L, Wu S, Xu L, Xiao F, Zhou X, Ellenbogen KA. Can J Cardiol. 2017;33:1736&#x2013;1733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ECG characteristics of "true" left bundle branch block: Insights from transcatheter aortic valve-related LBBB and His-Purkinje conduction system pacing-correctable LBBB. Kawamura I, Batul SA, Vijayaraman P, et al. Heart Rhythm. 2023;20:1659&#x2013;1666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37696443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block, an old-new entity. Breithardt G, Breithardt OA. J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2012;5:107&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3294212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22258866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic/iatrogenic left bundle branch block-induced reversible left ventricle dysfunction: JACC state-of-the-art review. Auffret V, Martins RP, Daubert C, Leclercq C, Le Breton H, Mabo P, Donal E. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:3177&#x2013;3188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is the treadmill exercise test useful for evaluating coronary artery disease in patients with complete left bundle branch block? Orzan F, Garcia E, Mathur VS, Hall RJ. Am J Cardiol. 1978;42:36&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">677034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block-Innocent bystander, silent menace, or both. Lau EW, Bonnemeier H, Baldauf B. Heart Rhythm. 2025;22:0&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39742988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic and prognostic value of left bundle branch block and its correlation with left ventricular functions: a prospective observational study. Bharath M, Sunayana N, Channakeshava S. Int J Adv Med. 2017;4:713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asymptomatic left bundle branch block predicts new-onset congestive heart failure and death from cardiovascular diseases. Azadani PN, Soleimanirahbar A, Marcus GM, Haight TJ, Hollenberg M, Olgin JE, Lee BK. Cardiol Res. 2012;3:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5358299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28352414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of left bundle branch block with obstructive coronary artery disease on coronary CT angiography: a case-control study. Clerc OF, Possner M, Maire R, et al. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2016;17:765&#x2013;771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26320169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A strain-based staging classification of left bundle branch block-induced cardiac remodeling. Calle S, Kamoen V, De Buyzere M, De Pooter J, Timmermans F. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2021;14:1691&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33865764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block-induced cardiomyopathy: insights from left bundle branch pacing. Ponnusamy SS, Vijayaraman P. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2021;7:1155&#x2013;1165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33812829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A revised definition of left bundle branch block using time to notch in lead I. Treger JS, Allaw AB, Razminia P, et al. JAMA Cardiol. 2024;9:449&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10974693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38536171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block induces ventricular remodelling and functional septal hypoperfusion. Vernooy K, Verbeek XA, Peschar M, Crijns HJ, Arts T, Cornelussen RN, Prinzen FW. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:91&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15615805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prognostic significance of incident complete left bundle branch block observed over a 40-year period. Imanishi R, Seto S, Ichimaru S, Nakashima E, Yano K, Akahoshi M. Am J Cardiol. 2006;98:644&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16923453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usefulness of ECG criteria to rule out left ventricular hypertrophy in older individuals with true left bundle branch block: an observational study. Tavares CA, Samesima N, Lazar Neto F, et al. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2021;21:547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8600759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34789151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical outcomes of permanent left bundle branch area pacing in patients with left bundle branch block and left ventricular ejection fraction &gt;35 vs. &#x2264;35. Jiang Z, Wu T, Wu Y, et al. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:838708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35369330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newly acquired left bundle-branch block: the Framingham study. Schneider JF, Thomas HE Jr, Kreger BE, McNamara PM, Kannel WB. Ann Intern Med. 1979;90:303&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">154870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronary angiographic profile in patients with left bundle branch block-an observational study. Karthikeyan S, Elamaran C, Swaminathan N. https://www.worldwidejournals.com/international-journal-of-scientific-research-(IJSR)/article/coronary-angiographic-profile-in-patients-with-left-bundle-branch-block-an-observational-study/MTU4OTE=/ Int J Sci Res. 2018;7:53&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors and angiographic findings in patients with LBBB who underwent coronary angiography in Duhok Heart Center. Mutar M, Merza MA, Issa HA, Shaikhow SK. https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/document?repid=rep1&amp;type=pdf&amp;doi=4a5da9ebf60f9c8e7df43ebdd1e974e1f0ac007b JMSCR. 2016;4:14112&#x2013;14117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block. Boyle DM, Fenton SS. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC2384928/ Ulster Med J. 1966;35:93&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2384928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5922878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes with left bundle branch block and mildly to moderately reduced left ventricular function. Witt CM, Wu G, Yang D, Hodge DO, Roger VL, Cha YM. JACC Heart Fail. 2016;4:897&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27614941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left bundle branch block: current and future perspectives. Tan NY, Witt CM, Oh JK, Cha YM. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2020;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32186936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>