<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40769373</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6744</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American heart journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am Heart J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Design and rationale of a randomized clinical trial assessing the effect of inclisiran on atherosclerotic plaque in individuals without previous cardiovascular event and without flow- limiting lesions identified in an in-hospital screening: The VICTORION-PLAQUE primary prevention trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0002-8703(25)00291-1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ahj.2025.08.001</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The impact of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) on atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease (ASCVD) risk is influenced by both the magnitude and duration of exposure. Patients with nonobstructive coronary artery disease (NOCAD) and a CT-adapted Leaman score (CT-LeSc) &gt;5 have a higher risk of cardiac events. The CT-LeSc semi-quantitatively assesses total coronary atherosclerotic burden via coronary computed tomography angiography (CCTA). Treatment with an antiproprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 (PCSK9) monoclonal antibody (mAb) leads to significant reductions in LDL-C levels. The addition of an anti-PCSK9 mAb to statin therapy produced greater LDL-C lowering and significant reduction in percent atheroma volume (PAV) and total atheroma volume (TAV) in patients with CAD. Inclisiran, a small-interfering ribonucleic acid (siRNA) therapy, targets PCSK9 messenger ribonucleic acid (mRNA) to reduce LDL-C levels by approximately 50% providing sustained and effective long-term LDL-C reduction after an initial and 90-day dose and a favorable safety profile alongside maximally tolerated statins. A similar treatment impact on total atheroma volume reduction is therefore hypothetically expected with inclisiran, given its exceptional dosing interval.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">VICTORION-PLAQUE is a multicenter, international, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial assessing inclisiran's efficacy in reducing total coronary atheroma volume in patients with NOCAD without prior cardiovascular (CV) events. Patients receive inclisiran or placebo in addition to maximally tolerated high-intensity statin therapy. The primary objective is to demonstrate inclisiran's superiority compared to placebo in reducing total coronary atheroma volume, measured by CCTA, from baseline to Month 24. The primary endpoint is percentage change from baseline to Month 24 in total coronary atheroma volume. Secondary endpoints include percentage change in LDL-C from baseline to Month 24, percentage change in low attenuation plaque volume evaluated by CCTA, percentage of participants with progression, regression, or no change in total plaque atheroma volume, and incidence and severity of treatment-emergent adverse event (TEAEs) and serious adverse event (SAEs) and their relationship with the study drug. In total, 608 patients have been randomized at 96 sites across 18 countries worldwide and enrolment was closed on October 25, 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The VICTORION-PLAQUE study evaluates the efficacy of inclisiran, compared with placebo, on top of maximally tolerated statin therapy, in reducing total coronary atheroma volume in NOCAD patients, as assessed by CCTA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov. Identifier: NCT05360446.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Revaiah</LastName><ForeName>Pruthvi C</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CORRIB Research Centre for Advanced Imaging and Core Lab, University of Galway, Galway, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serruys</LastName><ForeName>Patrick W</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CORRIB Research Centre for Advanced Imaging and Core Lab, University of Galway, Galway, Ireland. Electronic address: patrick.serruys@universityofgalway.ie.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onuma</LastName><ForeName>Yoshinobu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CORRIB Research Centre for Advanced Imaging and Core Lab, University of Galway, Galway, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andreini</LastName><ForeName>Daniele</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of University Cardiology, IRCCS Galeazzi Sant'Ambrogio, Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Budoff</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Lundquist Institute at Harbor-University of California, Los Angeles Medical Center, Torrance, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharif</LastName><ForeName>Faisal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Hospital Galway, Galway, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chernofsky</LastName><ForeName>Ariel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corp, East Hanover, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vikarunnessa</LastName><ForeName>Sheikh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corp, East Hanover, NJ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiethoff</LastName><ForeName>Andrea J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yates</LastName><ForeName>Denise</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Research, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Achouba</LastName><ForeName>Assya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novartis Pharma AG, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05360446</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am Heart J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370465</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-8703</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest Patrick Serruys reports personal consultancy fees from Sino Medical Sciences Technology, Philips/Volcano, Xeltis and Heartflow, outside the submitted work. Prtuthvi Revaiah, Yoshinobu Onoma, Daniele Andreini, Mathew Budoff declare no conflicts of interest. Ariel Chernofsky, and Sheikh Vikarunnessa are full-time employees of Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corp, East Hanover, NJ, USA. Denise Yates, and Andrea Wiethoff are full-time employees of Biomedical Research, Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA. Assya Achouba is a full-time employee of Novartis Pharma AG, Basel, Switzerland</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40769373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2025.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-8703(25)00291-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>