<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39493642</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1756-283X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Therap Adv Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mirtazapine for gastrointestinal and neuropsychological symptoms in older adults with irritable bowel syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17562848241278125</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17562848241278125</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17562848241278125</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17562848241278125</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is a common and potentially modifiable contributor to excess disability, morbidity, and poor quality of life. Clinical trials of medications for IBS have largely been in younger adults. Yet, a growing number of adults aged 65 and older are living with IBS. No data exist to guide clinicians in the safe and effective use of medications (e.g., anticholinergics, anti-spasmodics, and tricyclic antidepressants (TCA)) for IBS in the geriatric population. These medications-especially anticholinergics and TCAs-carry a high risk of adverse effects (ADE) in older adults because of age-associated decline in drug metabolism and the high prevalence of multiple chronic conditions. Five or more medications (polypharmacy) are frequently used to treat common psychiatric and medical comorbidities of IBS: anxiety, depression, insomnia, migraine headache, diarrhea, nausea, poor appetite, pruritus/skin atopy, and fibromyalgia. These neurological and psychiatric comorbidities reflect shared pathogenic mechanisms and bidirectional crosstalk of high inflammation, alteration of gut microbiota, and dysregulation of multiple gastrointestinal and central nervous system-active neurotransmitters (e.g., serotonin, neuropeptides). Currently, these IBS-associated conditions are treated with multiple medications-which increase the risk of adverse drug-drug interactions. One way to reduce the number of medications used for IBS-associated conditions is the use of one medication that treats many or all of these conditions-Mirtazapine. In this perspective article, we present evidence from basic science, case series, observational and epidemiological studies, clinical studies, and clinical trials supporting mirtazapine, a noradrenergic and specific serotonergic receptor antagonist-with 5-hydroxytryptamine-2 and 3 antagonism, as a potential pharmacotherapeutic intervention for the myriad symptoms and conditions associated with IBS. Specifically, we found evidence of mirtazapine's role in treating diarrhea, insomnia, migraine headache, nausea, and poor appetite. We propose a large randomized controlled trial to study mirtazapine as a potential one-stop treatment for multiple IBS symptoms, with the potential to reduce polypharmacy and ADEs, especially in the geriatric population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Ayesha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-5531-6873</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Texas at Medical Branch, 301 University Blvd, 5.138 RS, Galveston, TX 77555-5302, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Raakhi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Texas at Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corning</LastName><ForeName>Brooke</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University of Texas at Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohn</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University of Texas at Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumfa</LastName><ForeName>Cecil</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Texas at Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raji</LastName><ForeName>Mukaila</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Texas at Medical Branch, Galveston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Therap Adv Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101478893</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1756-283X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Mirtazapine for gastrointestinal and neuropsychological symptoms in older adults with irritable bowel syndrome A growing number of adults aged 65 and older are living with irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). Clinical trials of medications for IBS have largely focused on younger adults, leaving a gap in data to guide clinicians in the safe and effective use of these medications for the geriatric population. Many of these medications&#x2014;especially anticholinergics and tricyclic antidepressants (TCAs)&#x2014;carry a high risk of adverse effects (ADEs) in older adults. Additionally, polypharmacy, defined as the use of five or more medications, is frequently employed to treat common IBS-associated conditions, including anxiety, depression, insomnia, migraine headaches, diarrhea, nausea, poor appetite, pruritus/skin atopy, and fibromyalgia. One strategy to reduce the number of medications used for IBS-associated conditions is to manage these conditions with a single agent: mirtazapine, a noradrenergic and specific serotonergic receptor antagonist. In this perspective article, we present evidence from basic and clinical studies supporting mirtazapine as a potential therapy for the myriad gastrointestinal and neuropsychological symptoms associated with IBS. Specifically, we found strong evidence for mirtazapine&#x2019;s role in treating diarrhea, insomnia, anxiety, migraine headaches, and nausea, as well as modest evidence for its effectiveness in treating pruritus/skin atopy and fibromyalgia. We propose a large-scale study on mirtazapine as a potential one-stop treatment for multiple IBS symptoms, with the potential to reduce polypharmacy and ADEs, especially in the geriatric population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2024.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IBS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mirtazapine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polypharmacy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39493642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11526313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17562848241278125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_17562848241278125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lembo A, Sultan S, Chang L, et al.. AGA clinical practice guideline on the pharmacological management of irritable bowel syndrome with diarrhea. Gastroenterology 2022; 163(1): 137&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35738725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simr&#xe9;n M, T&#xf6;rnblom H, Palsson OS, et al.. Management of the multiple symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2017; 2(2): 112&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28403981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arzani M, Jahromi SR, Ghorbani Z, et al.. Gut&#x2013;brain axis and migraine headache: a comprehensive review. J Headache Pain 2020; 21(1): 15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7020496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32054443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurora SK, Shrewsbury SB, Ray S, et al.. A link between gastrointestinal disorders and migraine: insights into the gut&#x2013;brain connection. Headache 2021; 61(4): 576&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8251535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33793965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher HM, Black CJ, Teasdale SB, et al.. Irritable bowel syndrome and mental health comorbidity&#x2014;approach to multidisciplinary management. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2023; 20(9): 1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37268741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staudacher HM, Mikocka-Walus A, Ford AC. Common mental disorders in irritable bowel syndrome: pathophysiology, management, and considerations for future randomised controlled trials. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021; 6(5): 401&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiha MG, Aziz I. Review article: physical and psychological comorbidities associated with irritable bowel syndrome. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2021; 54(Suppl. 1): S12&#x2013;S23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34927759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ottman AA, Warner CB, Brown JN. The role of mirtazapine in patients with fibromyalgia: a systematic review. Rheumatol Int 2018; 38(12): 2217&#x2013;2224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29860538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AC, Sperber AD, Corsetti M, et al.. Irritable bowel syndrome. Lancet 2020; 396(10263): 1675&#x2013;1688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekiz &#xd6;, Balta I, &#xd6;zu&#x11f;uz P, et al.. Irritable bowel syndrome in patients with chronic pruritus of undetermined origin. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2013; 28(8): 1034&#x2013;1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24033408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai JD, Wang I-C, Shen TC, et al.. A 8-year population-based cohort study of irritable bowel syndrome in childhood with history of atopic dermatitis. J Investig Med 2018; 66(4): 755&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29374025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee AD, Spiegel BM, Hays RD, et al.. Gastrointestinal symptom severity in irritable bowel syndrome, inflammatory bowel disease and the general population. Neurogastroenterol Motil 2017; 29(5): e13003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27981684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcum ZA, Hanlon JT. Commentary on the new American Geriatric Society Beers criteria for potentially inappropriate medication use in older adults. Am J Geriatr Pharmacother 2012; 10(2): 151&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tornkvist NT, T&#xf6;rnblom H. European guidelines on functional bowel disorders with diarrhoea: United European Gastroenterology (UEG) and European Society for Neurogastroenterology and Motility (ESNM) statements and recommendations. United European Gastroenterol J 2022; 10(7): 615&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9486482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35765230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur ER, Quigley BM, El-Serag HB, et al.. Medical comorbidity and distress in patients with irritable bowel syndrome: the moderating role of age. J Psychosom Res 2016; 88: 48&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5006683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27521653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrenpreis ED. Irritable bowel syndrome. 10% to 20% of older adults have symptoms consistent with diagnosis. Geriatrics 2005; 60(1): 25&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15700946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahora IS, Tsouklidis N, Kumar R, et al.. How serotonin level fluctuation affects the effectiveness of treatment in irritable bowel syndrome. Cureus 2020; 12(8): e9871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moayyedi P, Andrews CN, MacQueen G, et al.. Canadian association of gastroenterology clinical practice guideline for the management of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS). J Can Assoc Gastroenterol 2019; 2(1): 6&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6507291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almario CV, Sharabi E, Chey WD, et al.. Prevalence and burden of illness of Rome IV irritable bowel syndrome in the United States: results from a nationwide cross-sectional study. Gastroenterology 2023; 165(6): 1475&#x2013;1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37595647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya &#x130;slamog&#x2c7;lu ZG, Unal M, K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;k A. Atopic dermatitis in adults and irritable bowel syndrome: a cross-sectional study. Indian J Dermatol 2019; 64(5): 355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6749755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31543528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldas S, Pagan AD, Correa J, et al.. Irritable bowel syndrome and interstitial cystitis/bladder pain syndrome are associated with pruritus bidirectionally in U.S. adults. Arch Dermatol Res 2023; 315(9): 2745&#x2013;2747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37548685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MP, Walker MM, Ford AC, et al.. The overlap of atopy and functional gastrointestinal disorders among 23 471 patients in primary care. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2014; 40(4): 382&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24961872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung H, Choung RS, Locke GR, et al.. Diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome is associated with diverticular disease: a population-based study. Am J Gastroenterol 2010; 105(3): 652&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2857983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19861955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich M, Grady SE, Wall GC. Effects of antidepressants in patients with irritable bowel syndrome and comorbid depression. Clin Ther 2010; 32(7): 1221&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20678672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frieling T, Cook H, Wood J. Ctions of 5-hydroxytryptamine on guinea pig colonic submucosal neurons: 5-HT2, 5-HT3 and 5-HT4 receptors. Gastroenterology 1991; 100: 443A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pithadia A, Jain S. 5-Hydroxytryptamine receptor subtypes and their modulators with therapeutic potentials. J Clin Med Res 2009; 1(2): 72&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3318857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22505971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh SV, Ganguly R, Jaiswal K, et al.. Molecular signalling during cross talk between gut brain axis regulation and progression of irritable bowel syndrome: a comprehensive review. World J Clin Cases 2023; 11(19): 4458&#x2013;4476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10353503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37469740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershon MD, Wade P, Kirchgessner AL, et al.. 5-HT receptor subtypes outside the central nervous system. Roles in the physiology of the gut. Neuropsychopharmacology 1990; 3(5&#x2013;6): 385&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2078274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalilian A, Ahmadimoghaddam D, Saki S, et al.. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study to assess efficacy of mirtazapine for the treatment of diarrhea predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Biopsychosoc Med 2021; 15(1): 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7860197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M. Current and future pharmacological treatments for diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Expert Opin Pharmacother 2013; 14(9): 1151&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23621801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel DR, Kolb R. Treatment of irritable bowel syndrome with comorbid anxiety symptoms with mirtazapine. Clin Neuropharmacol 2011; 34(1): 36&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21242743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanagapalli S, Kim E, Zarate-Lopez N, et al.. Mirtazapine in diarrhea-predominant irritable bowel syndrome: an open-label study. J Gastroenterol Dig Dis 2018; 3(1): 17&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freynhagen R, Muth-Selbach U, Lipfert P, et al.. The effect of mirtazapine in patients with chronic pain and concomitant depression. Curr Med Res Opin 2005; 22(2): 257&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16466597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe N, Omori IM, Nakagawa A, et al.. Mirtazapine versus other antidepressive agents for depression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2011; 12: CD006528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4158430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22161405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remeron [package insert]. Whitehouse Station, NJ: Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp., 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anttila SA, Leinonen EV. A review of the pharmacological and clinical profile of mirtazapine. CNS Drug Rev 2001; 7(3): 249&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11607047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe N, Omori IM, Nakagawa A, et al.. Safety reporting and adverse-event profile of mirtazapine described in randomized controlled trials in comparison with other classes of antidepressants in the acute-phase treatment of adults with depression: systematic review and meta-analysis. CNS Drugs 2010; 24(1): 35&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20030418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole JA, Rothman KJ, Cabral HJ, et al.. Migraine, fibromyalgia, and depression among people with IBS: a prevalence study. BMC Gastroenterol 2006; 6(1): 26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1592499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17007634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;vy E, Margolese HC. Migraine headache prophylaxis and treatment with low-dose mirtazapine. Int Clin Psychopharmacol 2003; 18(5): 301&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12920393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendtsen L, Jensen R. Mirtazapine is effective in the prophylactic treatment of chronic tension-type headache. Neurology 2004; 62(10): 1706&#x2013;1711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendtsen L, Buchgreitz L, Ashina S, et al.. Combination of low-dose mirtazapine and ibuprofen for prophylaxis of chronic tension-type headache. Eur J Neurol 2007; 14(2): 187&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17250728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J, Wang W, Winston JH, et al.. Ameliorating effects of mirtazapine on visceral hypersensitivity in rats with neonatal colon sensitivity. Neurogastroenterol Motil 2010; 22(9): 1022&#x2013;1028, e267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20507543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam A, Voronovich Z, Carley JA. A review of therapeutic uses of mirtazapine in psychiatric and medical conditions. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord 2013; 15(5): PCC.13r01525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24511451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;yberg OJ, Maragakis B, Mullin J, et al.. A double-blind multicentre comparison of mirtazapine and amitriptyline in elderly depressed patients. Acta Psychiatr Scand 1996; 93(3): 184&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8739664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambi F, De Berardis D, Campanella D, et al.. Mirtazapine treatment of generalized anxiety disorder: a fixed dose, open label study. J Psychopharmacol 2005; 19(5): 483&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16166185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varia I, Venkataraman S, Hellegers C, et al.. Effect of mirtazapine orally disintegrating tablets on health-related quality of life in elderly depressed patients with comorbid medical disorders: a pilot study. Psychopharmacol Bull 2007; 40(1): 47&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17285095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roose SP, Nelson JC, Salzman C, et al.. Open-label study of mirtazapine orally disintegrating tablets in depressed patients in the nursing home. Curr Med Res Opin 2003; 19(8): 737&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatzberg AF, Kremer C, Rodrigues HE, et al..; Mirtazapine vs. Paroxetine Study Group. Double-blind, randomized comparison of mirtazapine and paroxetine in elderly depressed patients. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry 2002; 10(5): 541&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12213688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fond G, Loundou A, Hamdani N, et al.. Anxiety and depression comorbidities in irritable bowel syndrome (IBS): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 2014; 264(8): 651&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24705634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan L, Wang B, Duan R. Prevalence of sleep disorder in irritable bowel syndrome: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Saudi J Gastroenterol 2018; 24(3): 141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5985632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29652034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winokur A, DeMartinis NA, McNally DP, et al.. Comparative effects of mirtazapine and fluoxetine on sleep physiology measures in patients with major depression and insomnia. J Clin Psychiatry 2003; 64(10): 1224&#x2013;1229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14658972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakishun FS, van den Bos J, van der Heijden BC, et al.. Mirtazapine effects on alertness and sleep in patients as recorded by interactive telecommunication during treatment with different dosing regimens. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2000; 20(5): 531&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11001237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalani E, Menon R, Mufti MA, et al.. Mirtazapine: a one-stop strategy for treatment of opioid withdrawal symptoms. Cureus 2023; 15(8): e43821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10509332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37736438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pae CU. Low-dose mirtazapine may be successful treatment option for severe nausea and vomiting. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 2006; 30(6): 1143&#x2013;1145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16632163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang FL, Ho ST, Sheen MJ. Efficacy of mirtazapine in preventing intrathecal morphine-induced nausea and vomiting after orthopaedic surgery. Anaesthesia 2010; 65(12): 1206&#x2013;1211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21182602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malamood M, Roberts A, Kataria R, et al.. Mirtazapine for symptom control in refractory gastroparesis. Drug Des Devel Ther 2017; 11: 1035&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28408802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avena-Woods C, Hilas O. Antidepressant use in underweight older adults. Consult Pharm 2012; 27(12): 868&#x2013;870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23229075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White W, Emlore L, Luthin D, et al.. Psychotropic-induced weight gain: a review of management strategies. Consultant 2013; 53: 153&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barai S, Kumar N, Gambhir S, et al.. Effect of mirtazapine on gastric emptying in patients with cancer-associated anorexia. Indian J Palliat Care 2017; 23(3): 335&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5545964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28827942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laimer M, Kramer-Reinstadler K, Rauchenzauner M, et al.. Effect of mirtazapine treatment on body composition and metabolism. J Clin Psychiatry 2006; 67(3): 421&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16649829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennings JM, Heel S, Lechner K, et al.. Effect of mirtazapine on metabolism and energy substrate partitioning in healthy men. JCI Insight 2019; 4(1): e123786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30626746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riechelmann RP, Burman D, Tannock IF, et al.. Phase II trial of mirtazapine for cancer-related cachexia and anorexia. Am J Hosp Palliat Med 2010; 27(2): 106&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholyaf M, Sheikh V, Yasrebifar F, et al.. Effect of mirtazapine on pruritus in patients on hemodialysis: a cross-over pilot study. Int Urol Nephrol 2020; 52(6): 1155&#x2013;1165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32383050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanna R, Boozalis E, Belzberg M, et al.. Mirtazapine for the treatment of chronic pruritus. Medicines 2019; 6(3): 73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6789675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31284577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawaz B, Chamseddin BH, Griffin JR. Defining the role of mirtazapine in the treatment of refractory pruritus. J Dermatolog Treat 2019; 32(2): 132&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31180795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samborski W, Lezanska-Szpera M, Rybakowski JK. Open trial of mirtazapine in patients with fibromyalgia. Pharmacopsychiatry 2004; 37(4): 168&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15467973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber S, Rigai T, Katz Y, et al.. The antinociceptive effect of mirtazapine in mice is mediated through serotonergic, noradrenergic and opioid mechanisms. Brain Res Bull 2002; 58(6): 601&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>