<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40895849</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Blood Pressure Control on Stroke and Myocardial Infarction Risk in Hypertensive Patients With and Without Diabetes: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e88984</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e88984</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e88984</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.88984</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hypertension (HTN) is a well-acknowledged and modifiable risk factor that significantly increases the risk of cardiovascular disease. Left uncontrolled, HTN may result in severe complications, including myocardial infarction and stroke. Also, when HTN coexists with diabetes, the adverse effects on cardiovascular health are amplified as a result of the combined vascular and metabolic effects.&#xa0;This narrative review synthesizes evidence from large observational cohorts, randomized clinical trials (e.g., Systolic Blood Pressure Intervention Trial or SPRINT, Action to Control Cardiovascular Risk in Diabetes or ACCORD), and contemporary guideline recommendations to assess these outcomes. The coexistence of diabetes mellitus with hypertension may further worsen vascular health through combined metabolic and endothelial effects, increasing rates of myocardial infarction and stroke. While pharmacological blood pressure (BP) lowering and lifestyle interventions (e.g., sodium restriction, exercise) generally reduce risk, overly aggressive diastolic BP reduction (&lt;&#x202f;60&#x202f;mmHg) can pose hazards in older adults or patients with chronic kidney disease. Current strategies adjust systolic and diastolic targets based on individual factors, age, comorbidity burden, and baseline cardiovascular risk&#xa0;and may include combined drug regimens, dietary counseling, or device&#x2011;based therapies. Further studies should prospectively evaluate optimal BP targets in under&#x2011;represented populations (e.g., elderly &#x2265; 75 years, chronic kidney disease stages 3-5, sub&#x2011;Saharan cohorts) and compare pharmacologic versus lifestyle&#x2011;only strategies, particularly in patients with multiple comorbidities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Anyaogu et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anyaogu</LastName><ForeName>Christy N</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Richmond Gabriel University, Kingstown, VCT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Momodu</LastName><ForeName>Paul A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, International University of the Health Sciences, Basseterre, KNA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okobi</LastName><ForeName>Okelue E</ForeName><Initials>OE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, IMG Research Academy and Consulting, Homestead, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amadi</LastName><ForeName>Adaora T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Enugu State University College of Medicine, Enugu, NGA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okechukwu</LastName><ForeName>Judah K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University, Ivano-Frankivsk, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polna</LastName><ForeName>Oksana</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University, Ivano-Frankivsk, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adeola</LastName><ForeName>Dorcas A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomosho, NGA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dike</LastName><ForeName>Olamma A</ForeName><Initials>OA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Abia State University Teaching Hospital, Aba, NGA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nwachukwu</LastName><ForeName>Ebere M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology-Exercise Science, Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akudinobi</LastName><ForeName>Ogechi K</ForeName><Initials>OK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Abia State University, Aba, NGA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabriel</LastName><ForeName>Hannatu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, National Pirogov Memorial Medical University, Vinnytsya, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40895849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12393132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.88984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>&#x3b2;-blockers in hypertension, diabetes, heart failure and acute myocardial infarction: a review of the literature. DiNicolantonio JJ, Fares H, Niazi AK, et al. Open Heart. 2015;21:230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4371808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25821584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glycated haemoglobin A1c as a risk factor of cardiovascular outcomes and all-cause mortality in diabetic and non-diabetic populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cavero-Redondo I, Peleteiro B, &#xc1;lvarez-Bueno C, Rodriguez-Artalejo F, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. BMJ Open. 2017;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5642750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28760792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of single-pill combination in uncontrolled essential hypertension: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Xie M, Tang T, Liang H. Clin Cardiol. 2023;46:886&#x2013;898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10436803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetes and hypertension: a comparative review of current guidelines. Cryer MJ, Horani T, DiPette DJ. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2016;18:95&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26234374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plant-based nutrition: exploring health benefits for atherosclerosis, chronic diseases, and metabolic syndrome-a comprehensive review. Pe&#xf1;a-Jorquera H, Cid-Jofr&#xe9; V, Landaeta-D&#xed;az L, et al. Nutrients. 2023;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10386413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized trial of intensive versus standard blood-pressure control. Wright JT Jr, Williamson JD, Whelton PK, et al. N Engl J Med. 2015;373:2103&#x2013;2116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26551272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of intensive systolic blood pressure lowering on cardiovascular events and mortality in patients with Type 2 diabetes mellitus on standard glycemic control and in those without diabetes mellitus: reconciling results from ACCORD BP and SPRINT. Beddhu S, Chertow GM, Greene T, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2018;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6222943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetic nephropathy and hypertension in diabetes patients of sub-Saharan countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Wagnew F, Eshetie S, Kibret GD, et al. BMC Res Notes. 2018;11:565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6080368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decreased hypertension in non-obese non-diabetic gastric cancer patients after gastrectomy. Wang Y, Yang W, Zhu Y, et al. Asian J Surg. 2020;43:926&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32593493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gender differences in the factors associated with hypertension in non-diabetic saudi adults-a cross-sectional study. Al-Raddadi R, Al-Ahmadi J, Bahijri S, et al. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8583204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between hypertension and other cardiovascular risk factors among non-diabetic Saudis adults-a cross sectional study. Ajabnoor GM, Bahijri S, Alamoudi AA, et al. PLoS One. 2021;16:246568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33621259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetes management in chronic kidney disease: a consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) de Boer IH, Khunti K, Sadusky T, et al. Diabetes Care. 2022;45:3075&#x2013;3090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9870667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comprehensive management of cardiovascular risk factors for adults with Type 2 diabetes: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Joseph JJ, Deedwania P, Acharya T, et al. Circulation. 2022;145:0&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35000404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood pressure management in stroke. Gorelick PB, Whelton PK, Sorond F, et al. Hypertension. 2020;76:1688&#x2013;1695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7666043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33040620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroke risk factors, genetics, and prevention. Boehme AK, Esenwa C, Elkind MS. Circ Res. 2017;120:472&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28154098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention of stroke by antihypertensive drug treatment in older persons with isolated systolic hypertension: final results of the Systolic Hypertension in the Elderly Program (SHEP) JAMA. 1991;265:3255&#x2013;3264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2046107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomised trial of a perindopril-based blood-pressure-lowering regimen among 6,105 individuals with previous stroke or transient ischaemic attack. Lancet. 2001;358:1033&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11589932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for ischaemic and intracerebral haemorrhagic stroke in 22 countries (INTERSTROKE): a case-control study. O&#x2019;Donnell MJ, Xavier D, Liu L, et al. Lancet. 2010;376:112&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood pressure lowering for prevention of cardiovascular disease and death: a systematic review and meta&#x2011;analysis. Ettehad D, Emdin CA, Kiran A, et al. Lancet. 2016;387:957&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood pressure targets and clinical outcomes in patients with acute myocardial infarction. Park H, Hong YJ, Cho JY, et al. Korean Circ J. 2017;47:446&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28765735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimum blood pressure in patients with shock after acute myocardial infarction and cardiac arrest. Ameloot K, Jakkula P, H&#xe4;stbacka J, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:812&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32792079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diastolic blood pressure, subclinical myocardial damage, and cardiac events: implications for blood pressure control. McEvoy JW, Chen Y, Rawlings A, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2016;68:1713&#x2013;1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5089057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight-loss strategies for prevention and treatment of hypertension: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Hall ME, Cohen JB, Ard JD, et al. Hypertension. 2021;78:0&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34538096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term impact of bariatric surgery on major adverse cardiovascular events in patients with obesity, diabetes and hypertension: a population-level study. Bouchard P, Al-Masrouri S, Demyttenaere S, Court O, Andalib A. Obes Surg. 2022;32:771&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35060016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proximal culprit lesion and coronary artery occlusion independently predict the risk of microvascular obstruction in acute myocardial infarction. Abanador-Kamper N, Kamper L, Karamani V, et al. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2016;32:1235&#x2013;1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27139461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low systolic blood pressure and mortality in elderly patients after acute myocardial infarction. Mouhat B, Putot A, Hanon O, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7335552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32098597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2017 ACC/AHA blood pressure treatment guideline recommendations and cardiovascular risk. Colantonio LD, Booth JN 3rd, Bress AP, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:1187&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6346270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30189994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2018 ESC/ESH guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension. Williams B, Mancia G, Spiering W, et al. Eur Heart J. 2018;39:3021&#x2013;3104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of blood pressure level on progression of diabetic nephropathy: results from the RENAAL study. Bakris GL, Weir MR, Shanifar S, Zhang Z, Douglas J, van Dijk DJ, Brenner BM. Arch Intern Med. 2003;163:1555&#x2013;1565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12860578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular outcomes and achieved blood pressure in patients with and without diabetes at high cardiovascular risk. B&#xf6;hm M, Schumacher H, Teo KK, et al. Eur Heart J. 2019;40:2032&#x2013;2043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30919899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Target blood pressure in diabetes mellitus: a review. Acharya V, Nandakrishna B. https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Target-Blood-Pressure-in-Diabetes-Mellitus%3A-A-Acharya-Nandakrishna/ea3a741313833acaeda5132953cafdd02cc46d08?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=transaction Hypertens J. 2020;6:36&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACC/AHA versus ESC/ESH on hypertension guidelines: JACC guideline comparison. Bakris G, Ali W, Parati G. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:3018&#x2013;3026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31196460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of antihypertensive treatment at different blood pressure levels in patients with diabetes mellitus: systematic review and meta-analyses. Brunstr&#xf6;m M, Carlberg B. BMJ. 2016;352:717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4770818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease risk assessment: an American Society for Preventive Cardiology clinical practice statement. Wong ND, Budoff MJ, Ferdinand K, et al. Am J Prev Cardiol. 2022;15:100335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35342890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of blood-pressure-lowering treatment on outcome incidence in hypertension: 10 - Should blood pressure management differ in hypertensive patients with and without diabetes mellitus? Overview and meta-analyses of randomized trials. Thomopoulos C, Parati G, Zanchetti A. J Hypertens. 2017;35:922&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28141660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of blood pressure reduction in mild hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sundstr&#xf6;m J, Arima H, Jackson R, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:184&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25531552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adherence in hypertension. Burnier M, Egan BM. Circ Res. 2019;124:1124&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30920917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic inertia is an impediment to achieving the Healthy People 2010 blood pressure control goals. Okonofua EC, Simpson KN, Jesri A, et al. Hypertension. 2006;47:345&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of intensive blood pressure lowering in older hypertensive patients. Bavishi C, Bangalore S, Messerli FH. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;69:486&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The hypertension team: the role of the pharmacist, nurse, and teamwork in hypertension therapy. Carter BL, Bosworth HB, Green BB. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2012;14:51&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3257828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22235824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>