<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40959362</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Empagliflozin Treatment for Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease in Type 2 Diabetes Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e90205</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e90205</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e90205</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.90205</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Empagliflozin, a sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitor, has emerged as a promising therapeutic option for patients with concurrent type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). This systematic review and meta-analysis evaluated the efficacy of empagliflozin on liver enzymes and metabolic parameters in this dual-pathology population. A comprehensive search was conducted across PubMed/MEDLINE, Embase, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL), and Web of Science databases from inception to July 2025. Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) comparing empagliflozin with placebo in adults with T2DM and NAFLD were included. Primary outcomes included changes in liver enzymes (alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), gamma-glutamyl transferase (GGT)), while secondary outcomes comprised systolic blood pressure (SBP) and glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) levels. Four studies met the inclusion criteria, encompassing 393 participants (206 empagliflozin, 187 control) with follow-up periods ranging from 20 to 24 weeks. Meta-analysis demonstrated significant reductions in ALT (mean difference (MD): -11.61; 95% confidence interval (CI): -19.18 to -4.04), AST (MD: -10.31; 95% CI: -15.41 to -5.21), and GGT levels (MD: -15.19; 95% CI: -18.13 to -12.25) with empagliflozin treatment compared to placebo. However, no statistically significant differences were observed for SBP (MD: -0.87; 95% CI: -7.93 to 6.20) or HbA1c (MD: -0.44; 95% CI: -1.10 to 0.22). Considerable heterogeneity was noted across studies for most outcomes. These findings suggest that empagliflozin offers hepatoprotective benefits in patients with concurrent T2DM and NAFLD, primarily through significant improvements in liver enzyme profiles. However, larger long-term studies with histological endpoints are needed to establish definitive clinical recommendations for this therapeutic approach.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Alsarkhi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsarkhi</LastName><ForeName>Loiy Naser</ForeName><Initials>LN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Hamad Medical Corporation, Doha, QAT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eda</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, MNR Medical College and Hospital, Fasalwadi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammed Abdul</LastName><ForeName>Rahman Hameed</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Royal Derby Hospital, Stoke-on-Trent, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussaini</LastName><ForeName>Helai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, West Anaheim Medical Center, Anaheim, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fadeyi</LastName><ForeName>Olaniyi</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, West Anaheim Medical Center, Anaheim, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudhari</LastName><ForeName>Sandipkumar S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiothoracic Surgery, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, University of North Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Fargo, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rauf</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed Qasim</ForeName><Initials>MQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopaedics, The Hillingdon Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, London, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allahwala</LastName><ForeName>Danish</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology, Fatima Memorial Hospital, Karachi, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">empagliflozin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-alcoholic fatty liver disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sglt2 inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40959362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12434543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.90205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The global epidemiology of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) and nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH): a systematic review. Younossi ZM, Golabi P, Paik JM, Henry A, Van Dongen C, Henry L. Hepatology. 2023;77:1335&#x2013;1347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10026948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36626630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and risk of incident type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Mantovani A, Byrne CD, Bonora E, Targher G. Diabetes Care. 2018;41:372&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29358469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The diagnosis and management of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: practice guidance from the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases. Chalasani N, Younossi Z, Lavine JE, et al. Hepatology. 2018;67:328&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The complex link between NAFLD and type 2 diabetes mellitus - mechanisms and treatments. Targher G, Corey KE, Byrne CD, Roden M. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;18:599&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathophysiology of diabetic kidney disease: impact of SGLT2 inhibitors. DeFronzo RA, Reeves WB, Awad AS. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2021;17:319&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin effectively lowers liver fat content in well-controlled type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, phase 4, placebo-controlled trial. Kahl S, Gancheva S, Stra&#xdf;burger K, et al. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:298&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31540903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the effects of dapagliflozin, a sodium-glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitor, on hepatic steatosis and fibrosis using transient elastography in patients with type 2 diabetes and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Shimizu M, Suzuki K, Kato K, et al. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2019;21:285&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of SGLT2 selective inhibitor ipragliflozin on hyperglycemia, hyperlipidemia, hepatic steatosis, oxidative stress, inflammation, and obesity in type 2 diabetic mice. Tahara A, Kurosaki E, Yokono M, et al. Eur J Pharmacol. 2013;715:246&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23707905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of empagliflozin on liver fat in patients with type 2 diabetes and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial (E-LIFT trial) Kuchay MS, Krishan S, Mishra SK, et al. Diabetes Care. 2018;41:1801&#x2013;1808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the Cochrane tool for assessing risk of bias in randomized clinical trials: overview of published comments and analysis of user practice in Cochrane and non-Cochrane reviews. J&#xf8;rgensen L, Paludan-M&#xfc;ller AS, Laursen DR, et al. Syst Rev. 2016;5:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4862216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27160280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empagliflozin improves liver steatosis and fibrosis in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Chehrehgosha H, Sohrabi MR, Ismail-Beigi F, et al. Diabetes Ther. 2021;12:843&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of an SGLT2 inhibitor versus ursodeoxycholic acid on liver steatosis in diabetic patients. Elhini SH, Wahsh EA, Elberry AA, et al. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 2022;15:1516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9786599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36558967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of empagliflozin on non-alcoholic fatty liver disease-related parameters in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled trial. Shojaei F, Erfanifar A, Kalbasi S, Nikpour S, Gachkar L. BMC Endocr Disord. 2025;25:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11863618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40011855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of empagliflozin on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zhang Y, Liu X, Zhang H, Wang X. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2022;13:836455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8908261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35282455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors on hepatic parameters: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Simental-Mend&#xed;a M, S&#xe1;nchez-Garc&#xed;a A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Ram&#xed;rez M, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE. Pharmacol Res. 2021;163:105319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33246172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SGLT2 inhibitors and risk of cancer in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Tang H, Dai Q, Shi W, Zhai S, Song Y, Han J. Diabetologia. 2017;60:1862&#x2013;1872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ipragliflozin improves the hepatic outcomes of patients with diabetes with NAFLD. Takahashi H, Kessoku T, Kawanaka M, et al. Hepatol Commun. 2022;6:120&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8710792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34558835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SGLT2 inhibition by empagliflozin promotes fat utilization and browning and attenuates inflammation and insulin resistance by polarizing M2 macrophages in diet-induced obese mice. Xu L, Nagata N, Nagashimada M, et al. EBioMedicine. 2017;20:137&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5478253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28579299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dapagliflozin in patients with chronic kidney disease. Heerspink HJ, Stef&#xe1;nsson BV, Correa-Rotter R, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:1436&#x2013;1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of canagliflozin treatment on hepatic triglyceride content and glucose metabolism in patients with type 2 diabetes. Cusi K, Bril F, Barb D, et al. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2019;21:812&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30447037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CV protection in the EMPA-REG OUTCOME trial: a "thrifty substrate" hypothesis. Ferrannini E, Mark M, Mayoux E. Diabetes Care. 2016;39:1108&#x2013;1114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27289126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in patients with type 2 diabetes: a call to action. Bril F, Cusi K. Diabetes Care. 2017;40:419&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28223446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and risk of incident diabetes mellitus: an updated meta-analysis of 501022 adult individuals. Mantovani A, Petracca G, Beatrice G, Tilg H, Byrne CD, Targher G. Gut. 2021;70:962&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NGM282 for treatment of non-alcoholic steatohepatitis: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Harrison SA, Rinella ME, Abdelmalek MF, et al. Lancet. 2018;391:1174&#x2013;1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29519502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>