<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40900605</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-6238</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Occurrence of Psychosis and Bipolar Disorder in Individuals With Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder Treated With Stimulants: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e252311</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2025.2311</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Individuals with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) may present with psychosis or bipolar disorder (BD) following treatment with stimulants. The extent to which this occurs is currently unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To meta-analytically quantify the occurrence of psychosis or BD after exposure to stimulants in individuals with ADHD and assess possible moderating factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PubMed, Web of Science, Ovid/PsycINFO, and Cochrane Central Register of Reviews were searched from inception until October 1, 2024, without language restrictions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY SELECTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Studies of any design with DSM or International Classification of Diseases-defined ADHD populations exposed to stimulants, where psychosis or BD outcomes were evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA EXTRACTION AND SYNTHESIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PRISMA Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-analyses and MOOSE Meta-analysis of Observational Studies in Epidemiology guidelines were followed, the protocol was registered, and the Newcastle-Ottawa scale and Cochrane risk of bias-2 tool were used for quality appraisal. Random-effects meta-analysis, subgroup analyses, and meta-regressions were conducted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For the proportion of individuals developing psychotic symptoms, psychotic disorders, and BD, effect sizes are reported as percentages with 95% CIs. For the comparison between amphetamines and methylphenidate, effect sizes are presented as odds ratios with 95% CIs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sixteen studies (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;391&#x202f;043; mean [range] age, 12.6 [8.5-31.1] years; 288&#x202f;199 [73.7%] male) were eligible. Among individuals with ADHD prescribed stimulants, 2.76% (95% CI, 0.73-9.88; k&#x2009;=&#x2009;10; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;237&#x202f;035), 2.29% (95% CI, 1.52-3.40; k&#x2009;=&#x2009;4; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;91&#x202f;437), and 3.72% (95% CI, 0.77-16.05; k&#x2009;=&#x2009;4; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;92&#x202f;945) developed psychotic symptoms, a psychotic disorder, and BD, respectively. Heterogeneity across the studies was significant (I2&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;95%). Psychosis occurrence risk was significantly higher in individuals exposed to amphetamines than to methylphenidate (odds ratio [OR], 1.57, 95% CI, 1.15-2.16; k&#x2009;=&#x2009;3, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;231&#x202f;325). Subgroup analyses showed significantly higher prevalence of psychotic symptoms in studies from North America and in those with longer follow-up periods. Increased psychosis occurrence was associated with a higher proportion of female participants, smaller sample sizes, and higher dose of stimulants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This systematic review and meta-analysis found a nonnegligible occurrence of psychotic symptoms, psychotic disorders, or BD in individuals with ADHD treated with stimulants. Amphetamines were associated with higher occurrence compared to methylphenidate. The included studies cannot establish causality, highlighting the need for further research, including randomized clinical trials and mirror-image studies comparing individuals exposed and not exposed to stimulants. Nonetheless, clinicians should inform patients about the increased occurrence of psychosis or BD when discussing stimulant pharmacotherapy and systematically monitor for these conditions throughout treatment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salazar de Pablo</LastName><ForeName>Gonzalo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child and Adolescent Mental Health Services, South London and Maudsley National Health Service Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychiatry and Mental Health, Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n School of Medicine, Universidad Complutense, Instituto de Investigaci&#xf3;n Sanitaria Gregorio Mara&#xf1;&#xf3;n, Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Salud Mental, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aymerich</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatry Department, Biocruces Bizkaia Health Research Institute, OSI Bilbao- Basurto, Facultad de Medicina y Odontolog&#xed;a, University of the Basque Country UPV/EHU, Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Salud Mental, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Barakaldo, Bizkaia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chart-Pascual</LastName><ForeName>Juan Pablo</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BioAraba, Department of Psychiatry, Hospital Universitario de Alava, UPV/EHU, Vitoria, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solmi</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sciences Lab, Department of Mental Health, The Ottawa Hospital, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Charit&#xe9; Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres-Cortes</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Hospital Universitario Ram&#xf3;n y Cajal, IRYCIS, Universidad de Alcala, Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Salud Mental, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelhafez</LastName><ForeName>Nessma</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child and Adolescent Mental Health Services, South London and Maudsley National Health Service Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Catalan</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatry Department, Biocruces Bizkaia Health Research Institute, OSI Bilbao- Basurto, Facultad de Medicina y Odontolog&#xed;a, University of the Basque Country UPV/EHU, Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Salud Mental, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Barakaldo, Bizkaia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychosis Studies, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corbeil</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, Universit&#xe9; Laval, Quebec City, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Quebec Mental Health University Institute, Quebec City, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adamo</LastName><ForeName>Nicoletta</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child and Adolescent Mental Health Services, South London and Maudsley National Health Service Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Philip</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fusar-Poli</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Hospital Universitario Ram&#xf3;n y Cajal, IRYCIS, Universidad de Alcala, Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Red de Salud Mental, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Brain and Behavioral Sciences, University of Pavia, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Outreach and Support in South-London Service, South London and Maudlsey National Health Service Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Ludwig-Maximilian-University of Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cortese</LastName><ForeName>Samuele</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Developmental Evidence Synthesis, Prediction, Implementation Lab, Centre for Innovation in Mental Health, School of Psychology, Faculty of Environmental and Life Sciences, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Experimental Sciences, Faculty of Medicine, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hampshire and Isle of Wight Healthcare National Health Service Foundation Trust, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hassenfeld Children's Hospital at New York University Langone, New York University Child Study Center, New York City.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DiMePRe-J-Department of Precision and Rigenerative Medicine-Jonic Area, University of Bari Aldo Moro, Bari, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101589550</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-622X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Salazar de Pablo reported personal fees from Janssen Cilag and Lundbeck outside the submitted work. Dr Aymerich reported personal fees from Janssen and Rovi outside the submitted work. Dr Chart-Pascual reported grants from Alicia Koplowitz Foundation outside the submitted work. Dr Solmi reported honoraria for advisory board service or presentations from AbbVie, Angelini, Lundbeck, and Otsuka outside the submitted work. Dr Catalan reported personal fees from Johnson &amp; Johnson, Rovi, and Lundbeck outside the submitted work. Dr Corbeil reported grants from Canadian Institutes of Health Research outside the submitted work. Dr Shaw reported employment at King&#x2019;s College London during the conduct of the study. Prof Fusar-Poli reported personal fees from Lundbeck, Angelini, Menarini, Sunovion, Boehringer, Proxymm, Science, Otsuka, Gedeon, and Richter outside the submitted work. Prof Cortese reported personal fees from the British Association of Psychopharmacology, Association for Child and Adolescent Mental Health, MEDICE, and National Institute for Health and Care Research and grants from the European Research Agency outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40900605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12409658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2025.2311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2838206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National institute for Health and Care Excellence . Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: diagnosis and management. Accessed July 29, 2025. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng87</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29634174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran LV, Skinner JP, Shinn AK, et al. Risk of incident psychosis and mania with prescription amphetamines. Am J Psychiatry. 2024;181(10):901-909. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.20230329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.20230329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11905971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39262211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese S, Holtmann M, Banaschewski T, et al. ; European ADHD Guidelines Group . Practitioner review: current best practice in the management of adverse events during treatment with ADHD medications in children and adolescents. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2013;54(3):227-246. doi: 10.1111/jcpp.12036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpp.12036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese S. Psychosis during attention deficit-hyperactivity disorder treatment with stimulants. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(12):1178-1180. doi: 10.1056/NEJMe1900502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMe1900502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30893541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudbrandsdottir RK, Sigurdsson E, Albertsson &#xde;I, Jonsdottir H, Ingimarsson O. Risk of hospitalisation for first-onset psychosis or mania within a year of ADHD medication initiation in adults with ADHD. BMJ Ment Health. 2025;28(1):e301521. doi: 10.1136/bmjment-2024-301521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjment-2024-301521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11997813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross RG. Psychotic and manic-like symptoms during stimulant treatment of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. Am J Psychiatry. 2006;163(7):1149-1152. doi: 10.1176/ajp.2006.163.7.1149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.2006.163.7.1149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16816217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiorean A, Jones BDM, Murong M, et al. Prescribed psychostimulants and other pro-cognitive medications in bipolar disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis of recurrence of manic symptoms. Bipolar Disord. 2024;26(5):418-430. doi: 10.1111/bdi.13440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bdi.13440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38670627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European ADHD guidelines group RCT dataset curated at University of Southampton. Accessed July 29, 2025. https://med-adhd.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese S, Adamo N, Del Giovane C, et al. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of medications for attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder in children, adolescents, and adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2018;5(9):727-738. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(18)30269-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(18)30269-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6109107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30097390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials. 1986;7(3):177-188. doi: 10.1016/0197-2456(86)90046-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0197-2456(86)90046-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629-634. doi: 10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsey M, Wilson D. Practical Meta-Analysis. Sage Publications; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Spiegelhalter DJ. A re-evaluation of random-effects meta-analysis. J R Stat Soc Ser A Stat Soc. 2009;172(1):137-159. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-985X.2008.00552.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-985X.2008.00552.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19381330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar de Pablo G, Soardo L, Cabras A, et al. Clinical outcomes in individuals at clinical high risk of psychosis who do not transition to psychosis: a meta-analysis. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2022;31:e9. doi: 10.1017/S2045796021000639</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S2045796021000639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35042573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aymerich C, Pacho M, Catalan A, et al. Prevalence and correlates of the concurrence of autism spectrum disorder and obsessive compulsive disorder in children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Sci. 2024;14(4):379. doi: 10.3390/brainsci14040379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci14040379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11048346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38672028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashok AH, Marques TR, Jauhar S, et al. The dopamine hypothesis of bipolar affective disorder: the state of the art and implications for treatment. Mol Psychiatry. 2017;22(5):666-679. doi: 10.1038/mp.2017.16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2017.16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5401767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et al. ; GRADE Working Group . GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008;336(7650):924-926. doi: 10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusar-Poli P, Salazar de Pablo G, Correll CU, et al. Prevention of psychosis: advances in detection, prognosis, and intervention. JAMA Psychiatry. 2020;77(7):755-765. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.4779</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.4779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baweja R, Belin PJ, Humphrey HH, et al. The effectiveness and tolerability of central nervous system stimulants in school-age children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder and disruptive mood dysregulation disorder across home and school. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2016;26(2):154-163. doi: 10.1089/cap.2015.0053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2015.0053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4800382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26771437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf6;rkenstam E, Pierce M, Bj&#xf6;rkenstam C, Dalman C, Kosidou K. Attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder and risk for non-affective psychotic disorder: the role of ADHD medication and comorbidity, and sibling comparison. Schizophr Res. 2020;218:124-130. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2020.01.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2020.01.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32001080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherland E, Fitzpatrick R. Psychotic side effects of psychostimulants: a 5-year review. Can J Psychiatry. 1999;44(8):811-813. doi: 10.1177/070674379904400810</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/070674379904400810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10566114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coghill DR, Banaschewski T, Nagy P, et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of lisdexamfetamine dimesylate in children and adolescents with ADHD: a phase IV, 2-year, open-label study in Europe. CNS Drugs. 2017;31(7):625-638. doi: 10.1007/s40263-017-0443-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-017-0443-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5511319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28667569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese S, Panei P, Arcieri R, et al. Safety of methylphenidate and atomoxetine in children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD): data from the Italian National ADHD Registry. CNS Drugs. 2015;29(10):865-877. doi: 10.1007/s40263-015-0266-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-015-0266-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26293742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalsgaard S, Mortensen PB, Frydenberg M, Maibing CM, Nordentoft M, Thomsen PH. Association between attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder in childhood and schizophrenia later in adulthood. Eur Psychiatry. 2014;29(4):259-263. doi: 10.1016/j.eurpsy.2013.06.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eurpsy.2013.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24016863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmaghraby R, Pines A, Geske JR, et al. Risk of newly diagnosed psychotic symptoms in youth receiving medications for attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. JAACAP Open. 2024;2(2):135-144. doi: 10.1016/j.jaacop.2024.01.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaacop.2024.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11562438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39554204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golubchik P, Weizman A. The effect of methylphenidate treatment on suspiciousness in children with ADHD alone or comorbid with ODD. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract. 2018;22(2):109-114. doi: 10.1080/13651501.2017.1383436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13651501.2017.1383436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28959903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamard J, Rousseau V, Durrieu G, et al. Psychosis with use of amphetamine drugs, methylphenidate and atomoxetine in adolescent and adults. BMJ Ment Health. 2024;27(1):e300876. doi: 10.1136/bmjment-2023-300876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjment-2023-300876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11029235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38609318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie LE, Abidi S, Fisher HL, et al. Stimulant medication and psychotic symptoms in offspring of parents with mental illness. Pediatrics. 2016;137(1). doi: 10.1542/peds.2015-2486</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2015-2486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran LV, Ongur D, Hsu J, Castro VM, Perlis RH, Schneeweiss S. Psychosis with methylphenidate or amphetamine in patients with ADHD. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(12):1128-1138. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1813751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1813751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30893533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Lee DY, Kim C, et al. Long-term methylphenidate use for children and adolescents with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder and risk for depression, conduct disorder, and psychotic disorder: a nationwide longitudinal cohort study in South Korea. Child Adolesc Psychiatry Ment Health. 2022;16(1):80. doi: 10.1186/s13034-022-00515-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13034-022-00515-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36221129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shyu YC, Yuan SS, Lee SY, et al. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder, methylphenidate use and the risk of developing schizophrenia spectrum disorders: a nationwide population-based study in Taiwan. Schizophr Res. 2015;168(1-2):161-167. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2015.08.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2015.08.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26363968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi N, Koh T, Tominaga Y, Saito Y, Kashimoto Y, Matsumura T. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of osmotic-controlled release oral delivery system methylphenidate HCl in adults with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in Japan. World J Biol Psychiatry. 2014;15(6):488-498. doi: 10.3109/15622975.2013.868925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/15622975.2013.868925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24456065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillman R, Geller B. Controlled study of switching from attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder to a prepubertal and early adolescent bipolar I disorder phenotype during 6-year prospective follow-up: rate, risk, and predictors. Dev Psychopathol. 2006;18(4):1037-1053. doi: 10.1017/S0954579406060512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0954579406060512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17064428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LJ, Shyu YC, Yuan SS, et al. Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder, its pharmacotherapy, and the risk of developing bipolar disorder: a nationwide population-based study in Taiwan. J Psychiatr Res. 2016;72:6-14. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychires.2015.10.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2015.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26519764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasha K, Paul S, Abbas MS, et al. Psychosis induced by methylphenidate in children and young patients with attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder. Cureus. 2023;15(1):e34299. doi: 10.7759/cureus.34299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.34299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9970721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar de Pablo G, Aymerich C, Guinart D, et al. What is the duration of untreated psychosis worldwide? a meta-analysis of pooled mean and median time and regional trends and other correlates across 369 studies. Psychol Med. 2024;54(4):652-662. doi: 10.1017/S0033291723003458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291723003458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38087871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nourredine M, Gering A, Fourneret P, et al. Association of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in childhood and adolescence with the risk of subsequent psychotic disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78(5):519-529. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.4799</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.4799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33625499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongsma HE, Turner C, Kirkbride JB, Jones PB. International incidence of psychotic disorders, 2002-17: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Public Health. 2019;4(5):e229-e244. doi: 10.1016/S2468-2667(19)30056-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(19)30056-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31054641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck K, Andreou C, Studerus E, et al. Clinical and functional long-term outcome of patients at clinical high risk (CHR) for psychosis without transition to psychosis: a systematic review. Schizophr Res. 2019;210:39-47. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2018.12.047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2018.12.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30651204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uher R, Pavlova B, Radua J, et al. Transdiagnostic risk of mental disorders in offspring of affected parents: a meta-analysis of family high-risk and registry studies. World Psychiatry. 2023;22(3):433-448. doi: 10.1002/wps.21147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.21147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10503921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37713573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollis C, Chen Q, Chang Z, et al. Methylphenidate and the risk of psychosis in adolescents and young adults: a population-based cohort study. Lancet Psychiatry. 2019;6(8):651-658. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(19)30189-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(19)30189-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man KK, Coghill D, Chan EW, et al. Methylphenidate and the risk of psychotic disorders and hallucinations in children and adolescents in a large health system. Transl Psychiatry. 2016;6(11):e956. doi: 10.1038/tp.2016.216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/tp.2016.216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5314128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27845780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakhan SE, Kirchgessner A. Prescription stimulants in individuals with and without attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: misuse, cognitive impact, and adverse effects. Brain Behav. 2012;2(5):661-677. doi: 10.1002/brb3.78</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.78</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23139911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher KE, Funaro MC, Woods SW. Prescription stimulants and the risk of psychosis: a systematic review of observational studies. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2022;42(3):308-314. doi: 10.1097/JCP.0000000000001552</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCP.0000000000001552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35489031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arunogiri S, Petrie M, Sharkey M, Lubman DI. Key differences in treatment-seeking stimulant users attending a specialised treatment service: a means of early intervention? Australas Psychiatry. 2017;25(3):246-249. doi: 10.1177/1039856216684737</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1039856216684737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28068828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar de Pablo G, Radua J, Pereira J, et al. Probability of transition to psychosis in individuals at clinical high risk: an updated meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78(9):970-978. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.0830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.0830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8281006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34259821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalaby AS, Bahanan AO, Alshehri MH, Elag KA. Sleep deprivation &amp; amphetamine induced psychosis. Psychopharmacol Bull. 2022;52(3):31-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9235313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35815175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cressman AM, Macdonald EM, Huang A, et al. ; Canadian Drug Safety and Effectiveness Research Network . prescription stimulant use and hospitalization for psychosis or mania: a population-based study. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2015;35(6):667-671. doi: 10.1097/JCP.0000000000000406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCP.0000000000000406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4898903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26485338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKetin R, Gardner J, Baker AL, et al. Correlates of transient versus persistent psychotic symptoms among dependent methamphetamine users. Psychiatry Res. 2016;238:166-171. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2016.02.038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2016.02.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27086229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hechtman L. ADHD medication treatment and risk of psychosis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2019;6(8):632-633. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(19)30248-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(19)30248-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lappin JM, Sara GE, Farrell M. Methamphetamine-related psychosis: an opportunity for assertive intervention and prevention. Addiction. 2017;112(6):927-928. doi: 10.1111/add.13663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.13663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27905179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty K, Grover S. Methylphenidate-induced mania-like symptoms. Indian J Pharmacol. 2011;43(1):80-81. doi: 10.4103/0253-7613.75678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0253-7613.75678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3062130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21455430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hah M, Chang K. Atomoxetine for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in children and adolescents with bipolar disorders. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2005;15(6):996-1004. doi: 10.1089/cap.2005.15.996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2005.15.996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16379520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegerl U, Sander C, Olbrich S, Schoenknecht P. Are psychostimulants a treatment option in mania? Pharmacopsychiatry. 2009;42(5):169-174. doi: 10.1055/s-0029-1220888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0029-1220888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19724978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiweck C, Arteaga-Henriquez G, Aichholzer M, et al. Comorbidity of ADHD and adult bipolar disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2021;124:100-123. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2021.01.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2021.01.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33515607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar de Pablo G, Cabras A, Pereira J, et al. Predicting bipolar disorder I/II in individuals at clinical high-risk: results from a systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2023;325:778-786. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2023.01.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2023.01.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36657494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar de Pablo G, Perez-Rodriguez V, de Otazu Olivares J, et al. Development and predictors of bipolar disorder in children and adolescents with depressive disorders: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Eur Psychiatry. 2025;68(1):e16. doi: 10.1192/j.eurpsy.2024.1814</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/j.eurpsy.2024.1814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11822963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39773691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintero J, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Casares JR, &#xc1;lamo C. Molecular characterisation of the mechanism of action of stimulant drugs lisdexamfetamine and methylphenidate on ADHD neurobiology: a review. Neurol Ther. 2022;11(4):1489-1517. doi: 10.1007/s40120-022-00392-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-022-00392-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9588136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegerl U, Himmerich H, Engmann B, Hensch T. Mania and attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: common symptomatology, common pathophysiology and common treatment? Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2010;23(1):1-7. doi: 10.1097/YCO.0b013e328331f694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCO.0b013e328331f694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19770771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre RS, Lee Y, Zhou AJ, et al. the efficacy of psychostimulants in major depressive episodes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2017;37(4):412-418. doi: 10.1097/JCP.0000000000000723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCP.0000000000000723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28590365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schimmelmann BG, Michel C, Martz-Irngartinger A, Linder C, Schultze-Lutter F. Age matters in the prevalence and clinical significance of ultra-high-risk for psychosis symptoms and criteria in the general population: findings from the BEAR and BEARS-kid studies. World Psychiatry. 2015;14(2):189-197. doi: 10.1002/wps.20216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4471976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26043337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>