<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40932963</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness and Safety of Direct Oral Anticoagulants Versus Warfarin in Patients With Mechanical Heart Valves: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e89736</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e89736</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e89736</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.89736</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Patients with mechanical heart valves require lifelong anticoagulation primarily due to the thrombogenic nature of these valves. Warfarin has been the mainstay of therapy, but its drug-drug interactions and frequent monitoring requirements have diverted attention toward DOACs (direct oral anticoagulants) such as apixaban, rivaroxaban, and dabigatran. However, the use of DOACs in this group of patients remains controversial, particularly after negative outcomes in earlier trials. This systematic review focuses on the efficacy of DOACs compared to warfarin for preventing thromboembolic events and associated bleeding risks in patients with mechanical heart valves. Most evidence comes from observational studies and meta-analyses. More limited data exist for patients with mechanical heart valves.&#xa0;We systematically searched PubMed, PubMed Central, and Google Scholar for English-language studies published between January 2015 and May 5, 2025. Eligible studies included randomized controlled trials (RCTs), observational studies, systematic reviews, and meta-analyses comparing DOACs and warfarin in adults with mechanical heart valves and related comorbidities such as atrial fibrillation and valvular heart disease. Articles were screened and assessed using standard quality appraisal tools. We included three observational studies, two RCTs, and six systematic reviews and meta-analyses.&#xa0;Most of the studies favored warfarin as the standard therapy for patients with mechanical heart valves, while DOACs showed relatively inferior outcomes. Current practice guidelines from the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force suggest warfarin as the standard treatment for patients with mechanical heart valves. There is a further need for long-term, high-quality clinical trials using a newer generation of DOACs among this high-risk group.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Mandefro et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mandefro</LastName><ForeName>Bethel T</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sundara</LastName><ForeName>Sri Vidya</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Xinyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Busmail</LastName><ForeName>Hamide</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weerakoon</LastName><ForeName>Sasika</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avula</LastName><ForeName>Sravanthi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iftikhar</LastName><ForeName>Laraib</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, California Institute of Behavioral Neurosciences &amp; Psychology, Fairfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coagulation inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">direct oral anticoagulant (doac)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical heart valve (mhv)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prosthetic heart valve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">warfarin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40932963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12419551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.89736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>How did we get here?: a historical review and critical analysis of anticoagulation therapy following mechanical valve replacement. MacIsaac S, Jaffer IH, Belley-C&#xf4;t&#xe9; EP, McClure GR, Eikelboom JW, Whitlock RP. Circulation. 2019;140:1933&#x2013;1942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31790297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>iData Research: Over 290,000 heart valve replacements per year in the United States by 2029. States by.  [
Jun;
2025 
]. 2024. https://idataresearch.com/heart-valve-replacements-per-year-in-the-united-states/ https://idataresearch.com/heart-valve-replacements-per-year-in-the-united-states/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanical valves: past, present, and future - a review. Leviner DB, Abraham D, Ronai T, Sharoni E. J Clin Med. 2024;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11242849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38999334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimizing age-specific outcomes after mechanical vs bioprosthetic prosthetic heart valve replacement. Otto CM. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37213105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anticoagulants: a short history, their mechanism of action, pharmacology, and indications. Heestermans M, Poenou G, Hamzeh-Cognasse H, Cognasse F, Bertoletti L. Cells. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9600347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36291080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2013 ACCF/AHA guideline for the management of ST-elevation myocardial infarction: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. O'Gara PT, Kushner FG, Ascheim DD, et al. Circulation. 2013;127:0&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabigatran versus warfarin in patients with mechanical heart valves. Eikelboom JW, Connolly SJ, Brueckmann M, et al. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:1206&#x2013;1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of direct oral anticoagulants in patients with atrial fibrillation and valvular heart lesions. Di Biase L. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4802477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x201c;A tale of two cities&#x201d;: anticoagulation management in patients with atrial fibrillation and prosthetic valves in the era of direct oral anticoagulants. Palmiero G, Melillo E, Rubino AS. Medicina (Kaunas) 2019;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31382702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Off-label use of direct oral anticoagulants in patients receiving surgical mechanical and bioprosthetic heart valves. Kalra A, Raza S, Jafry BH, King HE, Lahorra JA, Svensson LG, Kapadia SR. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7941196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33683332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of patients with a mechanical heart valve and poor anticoagulation control on warfarin. Johansson I, Benz AP, Kovalova T, et al. Thromb Haemost. 2024;124:613&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11199045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38158198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Direct oral anticoagulants compared with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation and valvular heart disease without mechanical valves. Dawwas GK, Lewis JD, Cuker A. J Am Heart Assoc. 2025;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12074781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39950313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apixaban or warfarin in patients with an On-X mechanical aortic valve. Wang TY, Svensson LG, Wen J, et al. NEJM Evid. 2023;2:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38320162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rationale and design of PROACT Xa: a randomized, multicenter, open-label, clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy and safety of apixaban versus warfarin in patients with a mechanical On-X aortic heart valve. Jawitz OK, Wang TY, Lopes RD, et al. Am Heart J. 2020;227:91&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32693197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warfarin versus direct oral anticoagulants in patients with artificial heart valves: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Srivastava Y, Deo S, Almader-Douglas D, et al.  https://www.clinicalcasereportsint.com/open-access/warfarin-versus-direct-oral-anticoagulants-in-patients-with-artificial-heart-9838.pdf Clin Case Rep Int. 2024;4:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of the new oral anticoagulants and warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation and valvular heart disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. de Souza Lima Bitar Y, Neto MG, Filho JA, et al. Drugs R D. 2019;19:117&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31055767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing clinical outcomes of NOACs with warfarin on atrial fibrillation with valvular heart diseases: a meta-analysis. He Q, Sze CY, Shum TY, et al. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2019;19:113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31092194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antithrombotic management after aortic valve replacement with biological prosthesis: a meta-analysis. Uimonen M, Kuitunen I, Ponkilainen V, Mennander A, Mattila MS. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2024;19:385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11202358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38926789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation and valvular heart disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pan KL, Singer DE, Ovbiagele B, Wu YL, Ahmed MA, Lee M. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5586302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28720644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meta-analysis comparing direct oral anticoagulants versus vitamin K antagonists in patients with left ventricular thrombus. Kido K, Ghaffar YA, Lee JC, Bianco C, Shimizu M, Shiga T, Hashiguchi M. PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8177531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34086768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>