<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40232317</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1437-160X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rheumatology international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatol Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of Kinesio taping without physical therapy for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>99</StartPage><MedlinePgn>99</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00296-025-05853-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Knee osteoarthritis (KOA) is a common musculoskeletal disorder causing pain and stiffness. Kinesio tape (KT) is a flexible tape used for various musculoskeletal conditions, including KOA. This study systematically evaluates the effectiveness of KT without conventional physical therapy for KOA. A comprehensive search was conducted through PubMed, Scopus, Cochrane Library, Embase, and Web of Science from inception to March 2025 for randomized trials evaluating KT without physical therapy for KOA (Prospero: CRD42024615432). The risk of bias was assessed using the ROB-2 tool, and the data analysis was conducted using Review Manager V5.4. A total of 16 randomized trials were included. KT significantly reduced the post-treatment pain at rest (MD: -0.75, 95% CI: -1.15, -0.34) and during movement (MD: -0.92, 95% CI: -1.65, -0.20) compared to sham KT. However, KT did not demonstrate a significant effect on long-term pain reduction. Additionally, KT significantly improved the WOMAC total score (MD: -0.60, 95% CI: -1.19, -0.01) and increased knee flexion range of motion (FROM) (MD: 6.04, 95% CI: 3.13, 8.96). However, KT showed no significant effect on knee extension range of motion (MD: -0.23, 95% CI: -1.70, 1.25). No risk of publication bias observed. KT reduces pain, improves function, and enhances knee FROM in KOA patients even without physical therapy. However, its long-term effects remain uncertain. Future studies should evaluate the long-term application of KT and its integration with other KOA management strategies. Prospero ID CRD42024615432.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldalati</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah Yousef</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-2260-0326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan. dalatia29@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussein</LastName><ForeName>Ayham Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3277-1549</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Al- Balqa' Applied University, Salt, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammadeh</LastName><ForeName>Bara M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-1025-1068</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Al- Balqa' Applied University, Salt, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alrabadi</LastName><ForeName>Bassel</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1115-4610</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albliwi</LastName><ForeName>Moath</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-1914-0054</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Cleveland Clini, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abuassi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9728-6310</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Department, College of Medicine, University of Central Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Rheumatol Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8206885</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0172-8172</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesio tape</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Disclaimer: No part of this manuscript, including the text and graphics, has been copied or published elsewhere, in whole or in part and no artificial intelligence tools were used for writing or editing this manuscript. Congress abstract publication: This study has not been previously presented as an abstract at any scientific congress or conference. Conflicts of interest: All of the authors affirm that they have no financial interest in the topic or materials covered in this manuscript, nor do they have any affiliations with or involvement in any organizations or entities that may have such an interest. The authors have no competing interests to declare that are relevant to the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40232317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-025-05853-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00296-025-05853-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Giorgino R, Albano D, Fusco S, Peretti GM, Mangiavini L, Messina C (2023) Knee osteoarthritis: epidemiology, pathogenesis, and mesenchymal stem cells: what else is new?? An update. Int J Mol Sci 24(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24076405</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui A, Li H, Wang D, Zhong J, Chen Y, Lu H (2020) Global, regional prevalence, incidence and risk factors of knee osteoarthritis in population-based studies. EClinicalMedicine;29&#x2013;30:100587. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100587</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandasamy S, Vadivelu R, Shanmugam SK, Mahendran BS (2024) Exploring the burden of knee osteoarthritis in rural South India: community prevalence, risk factors, and functional assessment among adults aged 40 and above. Cureus 16(11):e73452. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.73452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.73452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39664154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11633723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giaretta S, Magni A, Migliore A, Natoli S, Puntillo F, Ronconi G, Santoiemma L, Sconza C, Viapiana O, Zanoli G (2024) A review of current approaches to pain management in knee osteoarthritis with a focus on Italian clinical landscape. J Clin Med 13(17). https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13175176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BW, Lee JJ, Jung JY, Ju JH (2025) Intra-Articular injection of human bone Marrow-Derived mesenchymal stem cells in knee osteoarthritis: A randomized, Double-Blind, controlled trial. Cell Transpl 34:9636897241303275. https://doi.org/10.1177/09636897241303275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09636897241303275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams S, Whatman C, Hume PA, Sheerin K (2012) Kinesio taping in treatment and prevention of sports injuries: a meta-analysis of the evidence for its effectiveness. Sports Med 42(2):153&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.2165/11594960-000000000-00000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11594960-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghan F, Fouladi R, Martin J (2024) Kinesio taping in sports: A scoping review. J Bodyw Mov Ther 40:1213&#x2013;1223. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2023.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39593437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ager AL, de Oliveira FCL, Roy JS, Borms D, Deraedt M, Huyge M, Deschepper A, Cools AM (2023) Effects of elastic kinesiology taping on shoulder proprioception: a systematic review. Braz J Phys Ther 27(3):100514. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjpt.2023.100514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2023.100514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37224618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10225892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hei P, Zhang Z, Wei J, Lan C, Wang X, Jing X, Chen X, Wu Z (2025) The effect of dynamic neuromuscular stabilization technique combined with Kinesio taping on neuromuscular function and pain self-efficacy in individuals with chronic nonspecific low back pain: A randomized trial. Med (Baltim) 104(4):e41265. https://doi.org/10.1097/md.0000000000041265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000041265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng P, Zhao Z, Zhang S, Xiao T, Li Y (2021) Effect of Kinesio taping on hemiplegic shoulder pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Rehabil 35(3):317&#x2013;331. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269215520964950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215520964950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Y, Zheng C, Zheng J, Xu S (2020) Kinesio tape reduces pain in patients with lateral epicondylitis: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Surg 76:190&#x2013;199. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsu.2020.02.044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2020.02.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32165280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y, Duan Z, Qu Q, Chen W, Yu B (2019) Kinesio taping in treatment of chronic non-specific low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Rehabil Med 51(10):734&#x2013;740. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977-2605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-2605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31544952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;nceboy D, Aytekin E, O&#x11f;uz M, Dede BT, Bulut GT, Pekin Do&#x11f;an Y (2025) Is Kinesio taping an alternative to static wrist orthosis in patients with carpal tunnel syndrome? A randomized clinical trial. J Hand Ther Doi. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jht.2024.08.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jht.2024.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Chen X, Shen X, Chen L, Gong H (2024) Effectiveness of Kinesio tape in the treatment of patients with patellofemoral pain syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Med (Baltim) 103(23):e38438. https://doi.org/10.1097/md.0000000000038438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000038438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan T, Li H, Wang G (2025) Effects of Kinesio taping on lower limb Biomechanical characteristics during dynamic postural control tasks in individuals with chronic ankle instability. PLoS ONE 20(1):e0317357. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0317357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0317357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39792885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11723623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Yao R, Wu J, Wen G, Wang Y (2022) Does Kinesio taping plus exercise improve pain and function in patients with knee osteoarthritis? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Physiol 13:961264. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.961264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.961264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36160871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9500481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CH, Lee M, Lu KY, Chang CH, Huang SS, Chen CM (2020) Comparative effects of combined physical therapy with Kinesio taping and physical therapy in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil 34(8):1014&#x2013;1027. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269215520928398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215520928398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32597199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karamitabar A, Shahali S, Dadgo M, Mansor Sohani S, Ghorbanpour A, Abrishamkarzadeh H, Jaafary H, Mirbehresi PJF, Journal D (2019) The effect of kinesio tape on knee pain and quality of life in subjects with knee osteoarthritis&#x2013;a randomized clinical trial.2(1):27&#x2013;36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho H-y, Kim E-H, Kim J, Yoon, YWJAjopm (2015) rehabilitation. Kinesio taping improves pain, range of motion, and proprioception in older patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial.94(3):192&#x2013;200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Ioannidis JP, Clarke M, Devereaux PJ, Kleijnen J, Moher D (2009) The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions: explanation and elaboration. BMJ 339:b2700. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.b2700</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.b2700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2714672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, Cates CJ, Cheng H-Y, Corbett MS, Eldridge SM et al (2019) RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. 366:l4898. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.l4898</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi AI, Ogunfowodu OM, Akinbo SRJJoCS (2018). Kinesio taping is an effective stop-gap measure in alleviating the symptoms of osteoarthritis of the knee.15(2):102-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahlf AL, Braumann K-M, Zech AJJosr (2019). Kinesio taping improves perceptions of pain and function of patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized, controlled trial.28(5):481-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anandkumar S, Sudarshan S, Nagpal, PJPt (2014) practice. Efficacy of kinesio taping on isokinetic quadriceps torque in knee osteoarthritis: a double blinded randomized controlled study.30(6):375&#x2013;&#x2009;83</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ata&#x15f; A, Abit Kocaman A, Karaca &#x15e;B, Kasikci &#xc7;avdar MJP, Skills M (2024) Acute effect of kinesiology taping on muscle activation, functionality and proprioception in patients with knee osteoarthritis: A randomized controlled trial. 131(2):446&#x2013;468</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x15f;kurt Z, Ercan S, Parpucu T&#x130;, Ba&#x15f;kurt F, &#xdc;nal MJSHDTJSM (2017) Short term effects of kinesiotape application in patients with knee Osteoarthritis.52(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wageck B, Nunes GS, Bohlen NB, de Santos GM (2016) Kinesio taping does not improve the symptoms or function of older people with knee osteoarthritis: a randomised trial. 62(3):153&#x2013;158Noronha MJJop</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocyigit F, Turkmen MB, Acar M, Guldane N, Kose T, Kuyucu E, Erdil MJCticp (2015). Kinesio taping or sham taping in knee osteoarthritis? A randomized, double-blind, sham-controlled trial.21(4):262-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, Kn (2018) Kim ShJG, international g. Effects of knee taping during functional activities in older people with knee osteoarthritis: A randomized controlled clinical trial.18(8):1206-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abolhasani M, Halabchi F, Honarpishe R, Cleland JA, Hakakzadeh AJJoer (2019). Effects of kinesiotape on pain, range of motion, and functional status in patients with osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial.15(4):603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya Mutlu E, Mustafaoglu R, Birinci T, Razak Ozdincler A (2017) Does Kinesio taping of the knee improve pain and functionality in patients with knee osteoarthritis?? A randomized controlled clinical trial. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 96(1):25&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1097/phm.0000000000000520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/phm.0000000000000520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27149590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayanti AP, Prabowo T, Sari DMJJoM H (2020) The effects of Kinesio taping and quadriceps muscle strengthening exercise on quadriceps muscle strength and functional status in knee Osteoarthritis.2(5)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro YT, Barbosa GM, Fialho HRF, Silva CAM, de Oliveira Anuncia&#xe7;&#xe3;o J, de Almeida Silva HJ, de Souza MC, Almeida Lins CAJBo (2020). Does tension applied in kinesio taping affect pain or function in older women with knee osteoarthritis? A randomised controlled trial.10(12):e041121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donec V, Kubilius R (2020) The effectiveness of Kinesio Taping(<sup>&#xae;</sup>) for mobility and functioning improvement in knee osteoarthritis: a randomized, double-blind, controlled trial. Clin Rehabil 34(7):877&#x2013;889. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269215520916859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215520916859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32372651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7376619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakunkaruna S, Sakunkaruna Y, Sakulsriprasert P, Mongkonpattarasuk A, Yotsungneon S, Laskin JJJWwic (2020) The effect of Kinesio taping on gait parameters in Osteoarthritic knee patients. Randomized Controlled Trial 14(02):2272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melese H, Alamer A, Hailu Temesgen M, Nigussie F (2020) Effectiveness of Kinesio taping on the management of knee osteoarthritis: A systematic review of randomized controlled trials. J Pain Res 13:1267&#x2013;1276. https://doi.org/10.2147/jpr.S249567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/jpr.S249567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32547187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7266391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogan N, Yilmaz H, Ince B, Akcay S (2022) Is Kinesio taping effective for knee osteoarthritis?? Randomised, controlled, Double-blind study. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak 32(11):1441&#x2013;1447. https://doi.org/10.29271/jcpsp.2022.11.1441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29271/jcpsp.2022.11.1441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36377012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed SHP, Alatawi SF (2023) Effectiveness of Kinesio taping and conventional physical therapy in the management of knee osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Ir J Med Sci 192(5):2223&#x2013;2233. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-022-03247-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11845-022-03247-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36527538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S-h, Lee S-K, Ahn S-HJJER (2024) The effect of Kinesio taping on joint range of motion and balance in total knee replacement patients. 20(4):131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guner S, Alsancak S, Koz MJJ (2015) Effect of two different Kinesio taping techniques on knee kinematics and kinetics in young females. 27(10):3093&#x2013;3096</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>