<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37649852</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-7074</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of general medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Gen Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Plecanatide Improves Symptoms of Irritable Bowel Syndrome with Constipation: Results of an Integrated Efficacy and Safety Analysis of Two Phase 3 Trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3769</StartPage><EndPage>3777</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3769-3777</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/IJGM.S400431</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients with irritable bowel syndrome with constipation (IBS-C) experience abdominal pain with altered bowel movements. Plecanatide is indicated as IBS-C treatment in adults. This integrated analysis further characterizes plecanatide efficacy and safety in IBS-C.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Data pooled from 2 identically designed phase 3 trials included adults with IBS-C randomized to plecanatide 3 mg or 6 mg, or placebo once daily for 12 weeks. A daily diary recorded stool frequency/symptoms, with abdominal pain, bloating, cramping, discomfort, fullness, and straining intensity individually rated. Overall response (primary endpoint) was defined as &#x2265;30% improvement from baseline in average worst abdominal pain severity and increase of &#x2265;1 complete spontaneous bowel movement, during same week (composite), for &#x2265;6 of 12 weeks. Secondary endpoints included sustained response (overall response, plus meeting weekly composite criteria during &#x2265;2 of last 4 treatment weeks) and changes from baseline in individual symptoms. Safety assessments included adverse event monitoring.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Overall, 2176 patients (74.0% female; mean [SD] age, 43.5 [14.1] years) were included in efficacy analyses (plecanatide 3 mg [n = 724], 6 mg [n = 723], placebo [n = 729]). A significantly greater percentage of patients achieved overall response with plecanatide 3 mg (25.6%) and 6 mg (26.7%) versus placebo (16.0%; both P &lt; 0.001 vs placebo). A significantly greater percentage of patients were sustained responders with plecanatide 3 mg (24.3%) and 6 mg (25.6%) versus placebo (15.6%; both P &lt; 0.001 vs placebo). Significant improvements from baseline in abdominal discomfort, abdominal fullness, abdominal pain, bloating, and cramping occurred as early as Week 1 (Week 2 for abdominal pain) with plecanatide and were maintained through Week 12 versus placebo. Diarrhea, the most common adverse event, occurred in 4.3% (3 mg), 4.0% (6 mg) and 1.0% (placebo) of patients, leading to study discontinuation in 1.2%, 1.4%, and 0 patients, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Plecanatide is safe and effective for treating global and individual IBS-C symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Brenner et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brenner</LastName><ForeName>Darren M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine-Gastroenterology, Northwestern University-Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorn</LastName><ForeName>Spencer D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, UNC School of Medicine, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fogel</LastName><ForeName>Ronald P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Digestive Health Center of Michigan, Chesterfield, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christie</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laitman</LastName><ForeName>Adam P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Salix Pharmaceuticals, Bridgewater, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenberg</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GI Alliance of Illinois, Gurnee, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Gen Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101515487</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-7074</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abdominal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bloating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional GI disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">guanylate cyclase-C agonist</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Darren M. Brenner is a consultant and speaker for Salix Pharmaceuticals and is supported in research by an unrestricted gift from the IDP Foundation. Jennifer Christie reports being an advisory board member for Evoke Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, USA, Inc., and Grail, LLC, as well as grants from Syneos Pharmaceuticals. Adam P. Laitman is an employee of Salix Pharmaceuticals. Jonathan Rosenberg reports serving on speakers bureaus for AbbVie (Allergan), Salix Pharmaceuticals, and Takeda Pharmaceuticals USA, Inc. The authors report no other conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37649852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S400431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">400431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Mearin F, Chang L, et al. Bowel disorders. Gastroenterology. 2016;150(6):1393&#x2013;1407. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2016.02.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2016.02.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah ED, Almario CV, Spiegel BM, Chey WD. Presentation and characteristics of abdominal pain vary by irritable bowel syndrome subtype: results of a nationwide population-based study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115(2):294&#x2013;301. doi:10.14309/ajg.0000000000000502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000000502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7469977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Cangemi D, Vazquez-Roque M. Management of chronic abdominal distension and bloating. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(2):219&#x2013;231. doi:10.1016/j.cgh.2020.03.056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2020.03.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32246999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor DCA, Abel JL, Martin C, et al. Comprehensive assessment of patients with irritable bowel syndrome with constipation and chronic idiopathic constipation using deterministically linked administrative claims and patient-reported data: the Chronic Constipation and IBS-C Treatment and Outcomes Real-World Research Platform (CONTOR). J Med Econ. 2020;23(10):1072&#x2013;1083. doi:10.1080/13696998.2020.1799816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13696998.2020.1799816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballou S, McMahon C, Lee HN, et al. Effects of irritable bowel syndrome on daily activities vary among subtypes based on results from the IBS in America survey. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;17(12):2471&#x2013;2478. doi:10.1016/j.cgh.2019.08.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2019.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31419572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Par&#xe9; P, Gray J, Lam S, et al. Health-related quality of life, work productivity, and health care resource utilization of subjects with irritable bowel syndrome: baseline results from LOGIC (Longitudinal Outcomes Study of Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Canada), a naturalistic study. Clin Ther. 2006;28(10):1726&#x2013;1735. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2006.10.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2006.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17157129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doshi JA, Cai Q, Buono JL, et al. Economic burden of irritable bowel syndrome with constipation: a retrospective analysis of health care costs in a commercially insured population. J Manag Care Pharm. 2014;20(4):382&#x2013;390. doi:10.18553/jmcp.2014.20.4.382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18553/jmcp.2014.20.4.382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10437385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24684643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nellesen D, Yee K, Chawla A, Edelman Lewis B, Carson RT. A systematic review of the economic and humanistic burden of illness in irritable bowel syndrome and chronic constipation. J Manage Care Pharm. 2013;19(9):755&#x2013;764. doi:10.18553/jmcp.2013.19.9.755</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18553/jmcp.2013.19.9.755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10437427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24156644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner DM, Lacy BE, Ford AC, et al. Linaclotide reduced response time for irritable bowel syndrome with constipation symptoms: analysis of 4 randomized controlled trials. Am J Gastroenterol. 2023;118(5):872&#x2013;879. doi:10.14309/ajg.0000000000002064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000002064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10144280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36227782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salix Pharmaceuticals. Trulance tablets, for oral use [package insert]. Salix Pharmaceuticals, Bridgewater, NJ; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner DM, Fogel R, Dorn SD, et al. Efficacy, safety, and tolerability of plecanatide in patients with irritable bowel syndrome with constipation: results of two phase 3 randomized clinical trials. Am J Gastroenterol. 2018;113(5):735&#x2013;745. doi:10.1038/s41395-018-0026-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41395-018-0026-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29545635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SJ, Fuller G, Patel D, et al. Chronic constipation in the United States: results from a population-based survey assessing healthcare seeking and use of pharmacotherapy. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115(6):895&#x2013;905. doi:10.14309/ajg.0000000000000614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000000614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32324606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley EMM, Horn J, Kissous-Hunt M, Crozier RA, Harris LA. Better understanding and recognition of the disconnects, experiences, and needs of patients with irritable bowel syndrome with constipation (BURDEN IBS-C) study: results of an online questionnaire. Adv Ther. 2018;35(7):967&#x2013;980. doi:10.1007/s12325-018-0733-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-018-0733-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11343793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacy BE, Pimentel M, Brenner DM, et al. ACG clinical guideline: management of irritable bowel syndrome. Am J Gastroenterol. 2021;116(1):17&#x2013;44. doi:10.14309/ajg.0000000000001036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000001036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad RA, Camacho S. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of polyethylene glycol effects on fasting and postprandial rectal sensitivity and symptoms in hypersensitive constipation-predominant irritable bowel syndrome. Colorectal Dis. 2010;12(11):1131&#x2013;1138. doi:10.1111/j.1463-1318.2009.01990.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1463-1318.2009.01990.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19575740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman RW, Stanghellini V, Geraint M, Halphen M. Randomized clinical trial: macrogol/PEG 3350 plus electrolytes for treatment of patients with constipation associated with irritable bowel syndrome. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013;108(9):1508&#x2013;1515. doi:10.1038/ajg.2013.197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ajg.2013.197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23835436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh JE, Chey WD, Spiegel B. Abdominal bloating in the US: results of a survey of 88,795 Americans examining prevalence and healthcare seeking. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;21:2370&#x2013;2377. doi:10.1016/j.cgh.2022.10.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2022.10.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36396061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>