<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40796531</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4604</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reversal of Fentanyl-Induced Respiratory Depression in Healthy Subjects by Intramuscular Nalmefene Administered by Auto-Injector Versus Intranasal Naloxone.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcph.70088</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As illegally made fentanyl and congeners continue to drive overdose deaths in the US, experts have called for stronger and longer-lasting antagonists. A randomized, 4-period, 2-treatment crossover replicate-design study in healthy moderately-experienced opioid users (n = 24) evaluated the reversal of opioid-induced respiratory depression (OIRD) by intramuscular (IM) nalmefene 1.5 mg administered by auto-injector delivering a formulation developed for faster onset, compared to intranasal (IN) naloxone 4 mg. Fentanyl infusions were administered to induce a 50% reduction in minute ventilation (MV). Reversal of OIRD, pharmacokinetics, and safety were investigated under steady-state fentanyl agonism. For the primary endpoint, nalmefene demonstrated superiority at 5 min with an MV increase of 4.59 L/min, more than twice the 1.99 L/min increase for naloxone (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.0001). Nalmefene superiority was also demonstrated at 10, 15, 20, and 30 min, while non-inferiority was demonstrated at 2.5 and 90 min. The time-course of mean antagonist concentrations correlated with increases in mean MV, peaking at approximately 5-10 min following nalmefene compared to 20-30 min following naloxone. Decreases in transcutaneous CO<sub>2</sub> (TCO<sub>2</sub>) followed a similar time-course with a slight delay. At each threshold of percent reversal (25%-100%), nalmefene consistently showed a faster time to onset than naloxone. Both antagonist treatments were tolerated with no serious adverse events. This study shows that nalmefene 1.5 mg IM administered by auto-injector achieved a faster onset, higher magnitude, and longer duration of reversal of OIRD compared to naloxone 4 mg IN and represents another option for the treatment of opioid overdose.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Purdue Pharma L.P. The Journal of Clinical Pharmacology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American College of Clinical Pharmacology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cipriano</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imbrium Therapeutics L.P., a subsidiary of Purdue Pharma L.P., Stamford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Ellie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imbrium Therapeutics L.P., a subsidiary of Purdue Pharma L.P., Stamford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shet</LastName><ForeName>Manjunath</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imbrium Therapeutics L.P., a subsidiary of Purdue Pharma L.P., Stamford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apseloff</LastName><ForeName>Glen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ohio Clinical Trials, LLC, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Stephen C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imbrium Therapeutics L.P., a subsidiary of Purdue Pharma L.P., Stamford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0366372</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0091-2700</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nalmefene</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid antagonist</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid overdose reversal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid&#x2010;induced respiratory depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">overdose</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40796531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcph.70088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahmad FB, Rossen LM, Sutton P. Provisional Drug Overdose Death Counts. National Center for Health Statistics. Accessed March 28, 2025. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nvss/vsrr/drug&#x2010;overdose&#x2010;data.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciccarone D. The rise of illicit fentanyls, stimulants and the fourth wave of the opioid overdose crisis. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2021;34(4):344&#x2010;350. doi:10.1097/yco.0000000000000717</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciccarone D. Fentanyl in the US heroin supply: A rapidly changing risk environment. Int J Drug Policy. 2017;46:107&#x2010;111. doi:10.1016/j.drugpo.2017.06.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leen JLS, Juurlink DN. Carfentanil: A narrative review of its pharmacology and public health concerns. Can J Anesth. 2019;66(4):414&#x2010;421. doi:10.1007/s12630&#x2010;019&#x2010;01294&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delcher C, Wang Y, Vega RS, et&#xa0;al. Carfentanil outbreak &#x2010; Florida, 2016&#x2013;2017. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(5):125&#x2010;129. doi:10.15585/mmwr.mm6905a2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki J, El&#x2010;Haddad S. A review: Fentanyl and non&#x2010;pharmaceutical fentanyls. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2017;171:107&#x2010;116. doi:10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2016.11.033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pergolizzi J, Jr., Raffa R, LeQuang JAK, Breve F, Varrassi G. Old drugs and new challenges: A narrative review of nitazenes. Cureus. 2023;15(6):e40736. doi:10.7759/cureus.40736</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laffont CM, Purohit P, Delcamp N, Gonzalez&#x2010;Garcia I, Skolnick P. Comparison of intranasal naloxone and intranasal nalmefene in a translational model assessing the impact of synthetic opioid overdose on respiratory depression and cardiac arrest. Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1399803. doi:10.3389/fpsyt.2024.1399803</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad FB, Cisewski JA, Rossen LM, Sutton P. Provisional drug overdose death counts. National Center for Health Statistics; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie B, Goldberg A, Shi L. A comprehensive evaluation of the potential binding poses of fentanyl and its analogs at the &#x3bc;&#x2010;opioid receptor. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2022;20:2309&#x2010;2321. doi:10.1016/j.csbj.2022.05.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshleman AJ, Nagarajan S, Wolfrum KM, et&#xa0;al. Affinity, potency, efficacy, selectivity, and molecular modeling of substituted fentanyls at opioid receptors. Biochem. Pharmacol. 2020;182:114293. doi:10.1016/j.bcp.2020.114293</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nallani S, Smith LT, Uppoor RS, Mehta MU. Reversal of high potency synthetic opioid overdose: literature review [poster]. Presented at: 2021 FDA Science Forum; May 26, 2021; virtual. https://www.fda.gov/science&#x2010;research/fda&#x2010;science&#x2010;forum/reversal&#x2010;high&#x2010;potency&#x2010;synthetic&#x2010;opioid&#x2010;overdose&#x2010;literature&#x2010;review.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA approves naloxone injection to counteract opioid overdoses [press release]. U.S. Food &amp; Drug Administration. Accessed March 14, 2025. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news&#x2010;events&#x2010;human&#x2010;drugs/fda&#x2010;approves&#x2010;naloxone&#x2010;injection&#x2010;counteract&#x2010;opioid&#x2010;overdoses</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA approves higher dosage of naloxone nasal spray to treat opioid overdose [press release]. U.S. Food &amp; Drug Administration. Accessed March 14, 2025. https://www.fda.gov/news&#x2010;events/press&#x2010;announcements/fda&#x2010;approves&#x2010;higher&#x2010;dosage&#x2010;naloxone&#x2010;nasal&#x2010;spray&#x2010;treat&#x2010;opioid&#x2010;overdose</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Data from: State Unintentional Drug Overdose Reporting System (SUDORS). Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2024. Accessed March 14, 2025. https://www.cdc.gov/drugoverdose/fatal/dashboard</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skolnick P. Treatment of overdose in the synthetic opioid era. Pharmacol Ther. 2021;233:108019. doi:10.1016/j.pharmthera.2021.108019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow ND, Collins FS. The role of science in addressing the opioid crisis. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(4):391&#x2010;394. doi:10.1056/NEJMsr1706626</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. Determination that REVEX (nalmefene hydrochloride injection), 0.1 milligram base/milliliter and 1.0 milligram base/milliliter, was not withdrawn from sale for reasons of safety or effectiveness. Federal Regist. 2017;82(212):51282&#x2011;51283. https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2017/11/03/2017&#x2010;23952/determination&#x2010;that&#x2010;revex&#x2010;nalmefene&#x2010;hydrochloride&#x2010;injection&#x2010;01&#x2010;milligram&#x2010;basemilliliter&#x2010;and&#x2010;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieter P, Gyaw S, Crystal R, Skolnick P. Fighting fire with fire: development of intranasal nalmefene to treat synthetic opioid overdose. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2019;371(2):409&#x2010;415. doi:10.1124/jpet.118.256115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieter P, Chiang N, Gyaw S, et&#xa0;al. Pharmacokinetic properties and human use characteristics of an FDA&#x2010;approved intranasal naloxone product for the treatment of opioid overdose. J Clin Pharmacol. 2016;56(10):1243&#x2010;1253. doi:10.1002/jcph.759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indivior I. OPVEE&#xae; (nalmefene) nasal spray: full prescribing information [package insert]. Revised June 2023. Accessed March 24, 2025. https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=999a4269&#x2010;9e54&#x2010;4801&#x2010;b2ac&#x2010;2a7276f0b94f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassel JA, Daubert JD, DeHaven RN. [(3)H]Alvimopan binding to the mu opioid receptor: comparative binding kinetics of opioid antagonists. Eur J Pharmacol. 2005;520(1&#x2010;3):29&#x2010;36. doi:10.1016/j.ejphar.2005.08.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA approves nalmefene HCl Injection, 2mg/2mL (1mg/1mL) for the treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose with natural or synthetic opioids [press release]. Purdue Pharma L.P. Accessed March 14, 2025. https://www.purduepharma.com/news/2022/02/23/fda&#x2010;approves&#x2010;nalmefene&#x2010;hcl&#x2010;injection&#x2010;2mg&#x2010;2ml&#x2010;1mg&#x2010;1ml&#x2010;for&#x2010;the&#x2010;treatment&#x2010;of&#x2010;known&#x2010;or&#x2010;suspected&#x2010;opioid&#x2010;overdose&#x2010;with&#x2010;natural&#x2010;or&#x2010;synthetic&#x2010;opioids/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalmefene hydrochloride injection, solution. Full prescribing information. Purdue Pharma L.P. Accessed May 13, 2024. https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=3abfbffc&#x2010;9e52&#x2010;4fc6&#x2010;ae92&#x2010;6e0a97f4afe7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA approves prescription nasal spray to reverse opioid overdose [press release]. US Food and Drug Administration. Accessed August 21, 2024. https://www.fda.gov/news&#x2010;events/press&#x2010;announcements/fda&#x2010;approves&#x2010;prescription&#x2010;nasal&#x2010;spray&#x2010;reverse&#x2010;opioid&#x2010;overdose</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA approves Zurnai&#x2122; (nalmefene injection) auto&#x2010;injector for the emergency treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose induced by natural or synthetic opioids in adults and pediatric patients 12 years and older [press release]. Purdue Pharma L.P. Accessed August 21, 2024. https://www.purduepharma.com/news/2024/08/07/fda&#x2010;approves&#x2010;zurnai&#x2010;nalmefene&#x2010;injection&#x2010;auto&#x2010;injector&#x2010;for&#x2010;the&#x2010;emergency&#x2010;treatment&#x2010;of&#x2010;known&#x2010;or&#x2010;suspected&#x2010;opioid&#x2010;overdose&#x2010;induced&#x2010;by&#x2010;natural&#x2010;or&#x2010;synthetic&#x2010;opioids&#x2010;in&#x2010;adults&#x2010;and&#x2010;pediatric&#x2010;patie/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriano A, Apseloff G, Kapil RP, He E, Shet M, Harris SC. Time course of reversal of fentanyl&#x2010;induced respiratory depression in healthy subjects by intramuscular nalmefene and intramuscular and intranasal naloxone. J Clin Pharmacol. 2025;65(2):206&#x2010;216. doi:10.1002/jcph.6132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voscopoulos C, Brayanov J, Ladd D, Lalli M, Panasyuk A, Freeman J. Special article: evaluation of a novel noninvasive respiration monitor providing continuous measurement of minute ventilation in ambulatory subjects in a variety of clinical scenarios. Anesth Analg. 2013;117(1):91&#x2010;100. doi:10.1213/ANE.0b013e3182918098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voscopoulos CJ, MacNabb CM, Freeman J, Galvagno SM, Jr, Ladd D, George E. Continuous noninvasive respiratory volume monitoring for the identification of patients at risk for opioid&#x2010;induced respiratory depression and obstructive breathing patterns. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2014;77(3 Suppl 2):S208&#x2010;S215. doi:10.1097/TA.0000000000000400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non&#x2010;inferiority clinical trials to establish effectiveness. Guidance for industry. Food and Drug Administration. Accessed 14 October 2024. https://www.fda.gov/media/78504/download</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konieczko KM, Jones JG, Barrowcliffe MP, Jordan C, Altman DG. Antagonism of morphine&#x2010;induced respiratory depression with nalmefene. Br J Anaesth. 1988;61(3):318&#x2010;323. doi:10.1093/bja/61.3.318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury BA, Meyer RJ. Intramuscular versus subcutaneous injection of epinephrine in the treatment of anaphylaxis. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2002;109(4):720&#x2010;721. doi:10.1067/mai.2002.123252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armenian P, Vo KT, Barr&#x2010;Walker J, Lynch KL. Fentanyl, fentanyl analogs and novel synthetic opioids: A comprehensive review. Neuropharmacology. 2018;134(Pt A):121&#x2010;132. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2017.10.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fentanyl citrate injection, for intravenous use, CII. Full prescribing information. Exela Pharma Sciences, LLC. Accessed October 26, 2024. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2023/215870s000lbl.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahonen J, Olkkola KT, Hynynen M, et&#xa0;al. Comparison of alfentanil, fentanyl and sufentanil for total intravenous anaesthesia with propofol in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass surgery. Br J Anaesth. 2000;85(4):533&#x2010;540. doi:10.1093/bja/85.4.533</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul M, Lurie P, Kinsman JM, Dailey MW, Crabaugh C, Sasser SM. Multiple naloxone administrations among emergency medical service providers is increasing. Prehosp Emerg Care. 2017;21(4):411&#x2010;419. doi:10.1080/10903127.2017.1315203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uddayasankar U, Lee C, Oleschuk C, Eschun G, Ariano RE. The pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of carfentanil after recreational exposure: A case report. Pharmacotherapy. 2018;38(6):e41&#x2010;e45. doi:10.1002/phar.2117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britch SC, Walsh SL. Treatment of opioid overdose: current approaches and recent advances. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 2022;239(7):2063&#x2010;2081. doi:10.1007/s00213&#x2010;022&#x2010;06125&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaeta TJ, Capodano RJ, Spevack TA. Potential danger of nalmefene use in the emergency department. Ann Emerg Med. 1997;29(1):193&#x2010;194. doi:10.1016/s0196&#x2010;0644(97)70334&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan JL, Marx JA, Calabro JJ, et&#xa0;al. Double&#x2010;blind, randomized study of nalmefene and naloxone in emergency department patients with suspected narcotic overdose. Ann Emerg Med. 1999;34(1):42&#x2010;50. doi:10.1016/s0196&#x2010;0644(99)70270&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posner LS, Camargo CA, Jr. Update on the usage and safety of epinephrine auto&#x2010;injectors, 2017. Drug Healthc Patient Saf. 2017;9:9&#x2010;18. doi:10.2147/dhps.S121733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZURNAI&#xae; (nalmefene injection), for intramuscular or subcutaneous use. Full prescribing information. Purdue Pharma L.P. Accessed March 24, 2025. https://zurnai.com/pdf/zurnai_FPI.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narcan&#xae; (naloxone hydrochloride) Nasal Spray. Full prescribing information. Emergent Devices Inc. Accessed March 24, 2025. https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=724df050-5332-4d0a-9a5f-17bf08a547e1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OPVEE&#xae; (nalmefene) nasal spray. Full prescribing information. Indivior Inc. Accessed March 24, 2025. https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=999a4269-9e54-4801-b2ac-2a7276f0b94f</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>