<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41030699</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beta-Blockers in Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction: A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e91266</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e91266</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e91266</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.91266</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF) remains a significant global health burden, with beta-blockers serving as a cornerstone therapy due to their ability to modulate neurohormonal activation and improve outcomes. However, their efficacy in post-myocardial infarction (MI) patients with preserved ejection fraction (EF) remains debated. This systematic review evaluates the clinical effects of beta-blockers in HFrEF and post-MI populations to clarify their role across different patient phenotypes. Eight randomized controlled trials (RCTs) were systematically reviewed following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. Eligible studies assessed beta-blockers in HFrEF or post-MI patients, reporting outcomes such as mortality, hospitalizations, or changes in EF. Data were extracted independently by two reviewers, and risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2 tool. A narrative synthesis was performed due to heterogeneity in study designs and interventions. Beta-blockers demonstrated significant reductions in all-cause mortality and heart failure hospitalizations in chronic HFrEF patients. In contrast, they showed neutral effects on mortality and cardiovascular outcomes in post-MI patients with preserved EF. Safety profiles were favorable, with no excess adverse events. Methodological quality was high, with most trials rated as low risk of bias. Beta-blockers are highly effective in HFrEF but offer limited benefits in post-MI patients with preserved EF. These findings support phenotype-specific therapy, reinforcing guideline recommendations for HFrEF while questioning routine use in preserved EF post-MI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Elmobark et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elmobark</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Aberdeen Royal Infirmary, Aberdeen, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamad</LastName><ForeName>Fouad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, University Hospital Galway, Galway, IRL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassan Mutwali</LastName><ForeName>Lemia Gameil</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Primary Health Care, Oman Ministry of Health, Muscat, OMN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali Mohamed Zain</LastName><ForeName>Nora Qassem Alsyed</ForeName><Initials>NQA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, SEHA Salma Rehabilitation Hospital, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>Zainab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Heartlands Hospital, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Tartel Abdelhamed</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nizwa Hospital, Nizwa, OMN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassan Almzaini</LastName><ForeName>Othman Awad</ForeName><Initials>OA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Royal Papworth Hospital, Bedfordshire, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta-blockers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure with reduced ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">preserved ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41030699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12477414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.91266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global public health burden of heart failure: an updated review. Shahim B, Kapelios CJ, Savarese G, Lund LH. Card Fail Rev. 2023;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10398425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent high burden of heart failure across the ejection fraction spectrum in a nationwide setting. Stolfo D, Lund LH, Benson L, Hage C, Sinagra G, Dahlstr&#xf6;m U, Savarese G. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9750084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unraveling the complex pathophysiology of heart failure: insights into the role of renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS) and sympathetic nervous system (SNS) Maryam Maryam, Varghese TP, Tazneem B. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2024;49:102411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38246316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blocker management in patients admitted for acute heart failure and reduced ejection fraction: a review and expert consensus opinion. Schurtz G, Mewton N, Lemesle G, et al. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1263482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38050613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart failure management with &#x3b2;-blockers: can we do better? de Oliveira MT Jr, Baptista R, Chavez-Leal SA, Bonatto MG. Curr Med Res Opin. 2024;40:43&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38597068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The use of &#x3b2;-blockers in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. Masarone D, Martucci ML, Errigo V, Pacileo G. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2021;8:101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The four pillars of HFrEF therapy: is it time to treat heart failure regardless of ejection fraction? Docherty KF, Bayes-Genis A, Butler J, Coats AJ, Drazner MH, Joyce E, Lam CS. Eur Heart J Suppl. 2022;24:0&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9762881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. BMJ. 2021;372:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. BMJ. 2019;366:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blockers in patients with myocardial infarction and preserved left ventricular ejection: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sabina M, Shah S, Grimm M, et al. J Clin Med. 2024;14:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11721919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term use of carvedilol in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction treated with primary percutaneous coronary intervention. Watanabe H, Ozasa N, Morimoto T, et al. PLoS One. 2018;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6112626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blockers after myocardial infarction and preserved ejection fraction. Yndigegn T, Lindahl B, Mars K, et al. N Engl J Med. 2024;390:1372&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38587241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta-blocker interruption or continuation after myocardial infarction. Silvain J, Cayla G, Ferrari E, et al. N Engl J Med. 2024;391:1277&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39213187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of metoprolol CR/XL in chronic heart failure. Metoprolol CR. https://cir.nii.ac.jp/crid/1571135650384141440. Lancet. 1999;353:2001&#x2013;2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10376614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of carvedilol on survival in severe chronic heart failure. Packer M, Coats AJ, Fowler MB, et al. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:1651&#x2013;1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of carvedilol and metoprolol on clinical outcomes in patients with chronic heart failure in the Carvedilol Or Metoprolol European Trial (COMET): randomised controlled trial. Poole-Wilson PA, Swedberg K, Cleland JG, et al. Lancet. 2003;362:7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A trial of the beta-blocker bucindolol in patients with advanced chronic heart failure. Eichhorn EJ, Domanski MJ, Krause-Steinrauf H, Bristow MR, Lavori PW. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:1659&#x2013;1667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomized trial to determine the effect of nebivolol on mortality and cardiovascular hospital admission in elderly patients with heart failure (SENIORS) Flather MD, Shibata MC, Coats AJ, et al. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:215&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beta blockers in heart failure. Dargie HJ. Lancet (London, England) 2003;362:0&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, et al. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34447992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x3b2;-Blocker use and clinical outcomes in stable outpatients with and without coronary artery disease. Bangalore S, Steg G, Deedwania P, et al. JAMA. 2012;308:1340&#x2013;1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23032550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanism of action of beta-blocking agents in heart failure. Bristow MR. Am J Cardiol. 1997;80:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9412540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of &#x3b2; blockers in patients with heart failure plus atrial fibrillation: an individual-patient data meta-analysis. Kotecha D, Holmes J, Krum H, et al. Lancet. 2014;384:2235&#x2013;2243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>org. 2008. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of metoprolol CR/XL in chronic heart failure: Metoprolol CR/XL Randomised Intervention Trial in-Congestive Heart Failure (MERIT-HF) MERIT-HF Study Group. Lancet. 1999;353:35320012007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x3b2; blockers and mortality after myocardial infarction in patients without heart failure: multicentre prospective cohort study. Puymirat E, Riant E, Aissaoui N, et al. BMJ. 2016;354:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5029148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27650822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of beta-blockade on mortality among high-risk and low-risk patients after myocardial infarction. Gottlieb SS, McCarter RJ, Vogel RA. N Engl J Med. 1998;339:489&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9709041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>