<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40837797</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3206</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application and efficacy of quetiapine in patients with high-risk factors for bipolar disorder: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>104221</StartPage><MedlinePgn>104221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">104221</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5498/wjp.v15.i8.104221</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Bipolar disorder (BD), marked by recurring manic and depressive episodes, often coexists with anxiety disorder (AD), which increases treatment complexity and morbidity. Although quetiapine, an atypical antipsychotic, has demonstrated efficacy in treating BD and AD, further investigation is needed regarding its effectiveness and safety in patients with AD at high-risk factors for BD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore the application and efficacy of quetiapine in combination therapy for patients with AD at high-risk factors for BD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study included 67 patients, with two excluded, leaving 65 divided into Group A (sertraline treatment) and Group B (combination treatment). All patients received sertraline, with Group B additionally receiving quetiapine. Efficacy was assessed using the Hamilton anxiety scale (HAMA), Hamilton depression scale (HAMD), and Bech-Rafaelsen Mania sale (BRMS) throughout the treatment period. Side effects and physiological indicators were also monitored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No significant baseline differences existed between the two groups at treatment onset. Over the treatment course, Group B exhibited significantly lower HAMA scores than Group A at the end of weeks 1 and 24. HAMD scores gradually decreased over time, with Group B consistently showing lower scores than Group A. BRMS scores decreased significantly from baseline by week 8. In Group A, 27.27% of patients received zolpidem treatment compared to 10.53% in Group B, which was a significant difference. Incidence of adverse reactions did not differ significantly between groups at treatment onset, but most patients experienced relief from adverse reactions within 4 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Combination of quetiapine and sertraline can more rapidly alleviate anxiety and depressive symptoms in patients with AD at high-risk factors for BD, improving treatment outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Li-Lei</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosis and Psychosomatic Diseases, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Jie</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Management Division, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Psychiatry, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Psychiatry, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosis and Psychosomatic Diseases, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shi-Liang</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Management Division, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Min-Cai</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosis and Psychosomatic Diseases, Huzhou Third Municipal Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Huzhou University, Huzhou 313000, Zhejiang Province, China. 13757289002@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3206</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bipolar disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quetiapine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factor</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest regarding the publication of this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40837797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12362661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v15.i8.104221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nierenberg AA, Agustini B, K&#xf6;hler-Forsberg O, Cusin C, Katz D, Sylvia LG, Peters A, Berk M. Diagnosis and Treatment of Bipolar Disorder: A Review. JAMA. 2023;330:1370&#x2013;1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley V, Young AH, Smith P. Child and adolescent anxiety as a risk factor for bipolar disorder: A systematic review of longitudinal studies. Bipolar Disord. 2023;25:278&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36949612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala R, Axelson DA, Castro-Fornieles J, Goldstein TR, Ha W, Liao F, Gill MK, Iyengar S, Strober MA, Goldstein BI, Yen S, Hower H, Hunt J, Ryan ND, Dickstein D, Keller MB, Birmaher B. Comorbid anxiety in children and adolescents with bipolar spectrum disorders: prevalence and clinical correlates. J Clin Psychiatry. 2010;71:1344&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2978760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20868643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altinba&#x15f; K. Treatment of Comorbid Psychiatric Disorders with Bipolar Disorder. Noro Psikiyatr Ars. 2021;58:S41&#x2013;S46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8498808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34658634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre RS, Alda M, Baldessarini RJ, Bauer M, Berk M, Correll CU, Fagiolini A, Fountoulakis K, Frye MA, Grunze H, Kessing LV, Miklowitz DJ, Parker G, Post RM, Swann AC, Suppes T, Vieta E, Young A, Maj M. The clinical characterization of the adult patient with bipolar disorder aimed at personalization of management. World Psychiatry. 2022;21:364&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9453915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36073706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marangoni C, Faedda GL, Baldessarini RJ. Clinical and Environmental Risk Factors for Bipolar Disorder: Review of Prospective Studies. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2018;26:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29303917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornaro M, Anastasia A, Novello S, Fusco A, Solmi M, Monaco F, Veronese N, De Berardis D, de Bartolomeis A. Incidence, prevalence and clinical correlates of antidepressant-emergent mania in bipolar depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bipolar Disord. 2018;20:195&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29441650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith KA, Cipriani A. Lithium and suicide in mood disorders: Updated meta-review of the scientific literature. Bipolar Disord. 2017;19:575&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28895269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Pinto A, Gal&#xe1;n J, Mart&#xed;n-Carrasco M, Ballesteros J, Maurino J, Vieta E. Anxiety as a marker of severity in acute mania. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2012;126:351&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22620488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xuan R, Li X, Qiao Y, Guo Q, Liu X, Deng W, Hu Q, Wang K, Zhang L. Mindfulness-based cognitive therapy for bipolar disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2020;290:113116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32480120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suttajit S, Srisurapanont M, Maneeton N, Maneeton B. Quetiapine for acute bipolar depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2014;8:827&#x2013;838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier SM, Uher R, Mors O, Dalsgaard S, Munk-Olsen T, Laursen TM, Mattheisen M, Nordentoft M, Mortensen PB, Pavlova B. Specific anxiety disorders and subsequent risk for bipolar disorder: a nationwide study. World Psychiatry. 2016;15:187&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4911786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27265717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafeman DM, Merranko J, Axelson D, Goldstein BI, Goldstein T, Monk K, Hickey MB, Sakolsky D, Diler R, Iyengar S, Brent D, Kupfer D, Birmaher B. Toward the Definition of a Bipolar Prodrome: Dimensional Predictors of Bipolar Spectrum Disorders in At-Risk Youths. Am J Psychiatry. 2016;173:695&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4930393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JN, Taylor Dryman M, Morrison AS, Gilbert KE, Heimberg RG, Gruber J. Positive and Negative Affect as Links Between Social Anxiety and Depression: Predicting Concurrent and Prospective Mood Symptoms in Unipolar and Bipolar Mood Disorders. Behav Ther. 2017;48:820&#x2013;833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6028186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29029678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue T, Kimura T, Inagaki Y, Shirakawa O. Prevalence of Comorbid Anxiety Disorders and Their Associated Factors in Patients with Bipolar Disorder or Major Depressive Disorder. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2020;16:1695&#x2013;1704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CY, Chiang CH, Tseng MM, Tam KW, Loh EW. Effects of quetiapine on sleep: A systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2023;67:22&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36463762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;&#xf6;rek&#xe7;io&#x11f;lu S, Cesur E, Devrim Balaban &#xd6;. Relationship between impulsivity, comorbid anxiety and neurocognitive functions in bipolar disorder. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract. 2021;25:62&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadriu B, Deng ZD, Kraus C, Johnston JN, Fijtman A, Henter ID, Kasper S, Zarate CA Jr. The impact of body mass index on the clinical features of bipolar disorder: A STEP-BD study. Bipolar Disord. 2024;26:160&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10839568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37536999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spoorthy MS, Chakrabarti S, Grover S. Comorbidity of bipolar and anxiety disorders: An overview of trends in research. World J Psychiatry. 2019;9:7&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30631749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titone MK, Freed RD, O'Garro-Moore JK, Gepty A, Ng TH, Stange JP, Abramson LY, Alloy LB. The role of lifetime anxiety history in the course of bipolar spectrum disorders. Psychiatry Res. 2018;264:202&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5972058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29653349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Zhang J, Zhu H, Lu J. Association of anxiety disorder, depression, and bipolar disorder with autoimmune thyroiditis: A bidirectional two-sample mendelian randomized study. J Affect Disord. 2025;368:720&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39313161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre RS, Calabrese JR. Bipolar depression: the clinical characteristics and unmet needs of a complex disorder. Curr Med Res Opin. 2019;35:1993&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31311335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucci F, Toni C, Favaretto E, Vannucchi G, Marazziti D, Perugi G. Obsessive-compulsive Disorder with Comorbid Bipolar Disorders: Clinical Features and Treatment Implications. Curr Med Chem. 2018;25:5722&#x2013;5730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29119914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb N, Young AH. Antidepressants and Bipolar Disorder: The Plot Thickens. Am J Psychiatry. 2024;181:575&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38946275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altamura AC, Buoli M, Caldiroli A, Caron L, Cumerlato Melter C, Dobrea C, Cigliobianco M, Zanelli Quarantini F. Misdiagnosis, duration of untreated illness (DUI) and outcome in bipolar patients with psychotic symptoms: A naturalistic study. J Affect Disord. 2015;182:70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25978716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulin TG, Jaworska N, Stelfox HT, Fiest KM, Moss SJ. Clinical practice guideline recommendations for diagnosis and management of anxiety and depression in hospitalized adults with delirium: a systematic review. Syst Rev. 2023;12:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10519074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott SJ, Marshall D, Morley K, Uphoff E, Kumar M, Meader N. Behavioural and cognitive behavioural therapy for obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) in individuals with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;9:CD013173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8543671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34693989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JSW, Atkinson LZ, Al-Juffali N, Awad A, Geddes JR, Tunbridge EM, Harrison PJ, Cipriani A. Gabapentin and pregabalin in bipolar disorder, anxiety states, and insomnia: Systematic review, meta-analysis, and rationale. Mol Psychiatry. 2022;27:1339&#x2013;1349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9095464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34819636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasco-Fontecilla H, Bragado Jim&#xe9;nez MD, Garc&#xed;a Santos LM, Barjau Romero JM. Delusional disorder with delusions of parasitosis and jealousy after stroke: treatment with quetiapine and sertraline. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2005;25:615&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16282853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melhuish Beaupre LM, Tiwari AK, Gon&#xe7;alves VF, Lisoway AJ, Harripaul RS, M&#xfc;ller DJ, Zai CC, Kennedy JL. Antidepressant-Associated Mania in Bipolar Disorder: A Review and Meta-analysis of Potential Clinical and Genetic Risk Factors. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2020;40:180&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32134853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>