<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39780334</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1440-1746</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of gastroenterology and hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Probiotics Combined With Trimebutine for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>677</StartPage><EndPage>691</EndPage><MedlinePgn>677-691</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jgh.16858</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to assess the efficacy and safety of probiotics combined with trimebutine in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome (IBS), addressing an important gap in current treatment strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of trimebutine combined with probiotics for the treatment of IBS were collected from various databases. All retrieved articles were screened and assessed for quality. The methodological quality of the included studies was assessed following the guidelines recommended by the Cochrane Collaboration. The meta-analysis of the included studies was conducted using RevMan 5.3 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 37 RCTs involving 4360 participants were included in this study. Among them, the treatment group consisted of 2177 participants, and the control group consisted of 2183 participants. The results showed that the overall efficacy of trimebutine combined with probiotics in the treatment of IBS was significantly higher than that of trimebutine alone (odds ratio [OR]&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.09, 95&#x2009;% confidence interval [CI] [4.19, 6.20], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.00001). The effective rate in the combination therapy group was 93.5&#x2009;% compared with 73.8&#x2009;% in the trimebutine alone group. The safety profile was favorable, with adverse event rates of 1.75&#x2009;% and 1.69&#x2009;% in the combination and monotherapy groups, respectively. The most common adverse events were mild and included dry mouth, nausea and dizziness. No serious adverse events were reported in either group. Subgroup analysis based on the type of probiotic intervention showed that combination use was better than trimebutine alone, and the differences between each subgroup were statistically significant. Combination use of compound Lactobacillus capsules had the best effect (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;16.03, 95&#x2009;% CI [4.57, 56.21], p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001]. These results highlight the potential role of strain-specific benefits in IBS treatment and suggest that probiotic strain selection may significantly influence treatment outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The combination of trimebutine and probiotics is more effective in the treatment of IBS compared with trimebutine alone.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/prospero/, identifier: CRD42024516044.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology Foundation and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Qiu-Xiang</ForeName><Initials>QX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Proctology, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Dong-Dong</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical, Tumote Right Banner Hospital, Baotou, Inner Mongolia, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Peng-Ju</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical, Tumote Right Banner Hospital, Baotou, Inner Mongolia, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Li-Hua</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-1550-4187</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Proctology, China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8607909</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0815-9319</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>QZ1OJ92E5R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014287">Trimebutine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019936" MajorTopicYN="Y">Probiotics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Irritable Bowel Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014287" MajorTopicYN="Y">Trimebutine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta&#x2010;analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">probiotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trimebutine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39780334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgh.16858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>I. Shaidullov, D. Bouchareb, D. Sorokina, and G. Sitdikova, &#x201c;Nitric Oxide in the Mechanisms of Inhibitory Effects of Sodium Butyrate on Colon Contractions in a Mouse Model of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Naunyn&#x2010;Schmiedeberg's Archives of Pharmacology (2024), Epub ahead of print, https://doi.org/10.1007/s00210&#x2010;024&#x2010;03403&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Teasdale, H. Everitt, S. Alderson, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Low&#x2010;Dose Amitriptyline for Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS): A Qualitative Study of Patients' and GPs' Views and Experiences,&#x201d; British Journal of General Practice (2024), Epub ahead of print, https://doi.org/10.3399/BJGP.2024.0303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International EM, &#x201c;Retracted: Efficacy and Mechanism of Trimebutine Maleate Combined with Lactulose in the Treatment of Constipation&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome in the Elderly [retraction of: Emerg Med Int. 2022 Nov 11;2022:6125120],&#x201d; Emergency Medicine International 2024 (2024): 9837328, https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9837328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. A. Makarova, G. M. Diukova, I. N. Ruchkina, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Visceral Sensitivity in Diagnostics and Treatment of Severe Irritated Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Terapevticheski&#x12d; Arkhiv 94, no. 2S (2022): 356&#x2013;361, https://doi.org/10.26442/00403660.2022.02.201394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. T. Lee and B. J. Kim, &#x201c;Trimebutine as a Modulator of Gastrointestinal Motility,&#x201d; Archives of Pharmacal Research 34, no. 6 (2011): 861&#x2013;864, https://doi.org/10.1007/s12272&#x2010;011&#x2010;0600&#x2010;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. M. M. Quigley, &#x201c;Prebiotics and Probiotics in Digestive Health,&#x201d; Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology 17, no. 2 (2019): 333&#x2013;344, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cgh.2018.09.028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhu, &#x201c;Clinical Effect of High&#x2010;Quality Nursing on Electroacupuncture and Trimebutine Maleate Combined With Probiotics in the Treatment of Diarrhea&#x2010;Type Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese Modern Doctor 57, no. 13 (2019): 145&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. X. Liu, &#x201c;Observation on the Clinical Efficacy of Trimebutine Maleate Combined With Probiotic Preparations in the Treatment of Diarrhea&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Capital Food and Medicine 27, no. 8 (2020): 62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. C. Ford, E. M. Quigley, B. E. Lacy, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Efficacy of Prebiotics, Probiotics, and Synbiotics in Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Chronic Idiopathic Constipation: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; American Journal of Gastroenterology 109, no. 10 (2014): 1547&#x2013;1562, https://doi.org/10.1038/ajg.2014.202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. T. Higgins, D. G. Altman, J. A. C. Sterne, S. Green, Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. https://handbook&#x2010;5&#x2010;1.cochrane.org/index.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. H. Bao and S. S. Yang, &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Trimebutine Maleate Combined With Bifidobacteria in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS),&#x201d; Qinghai Medical Journal 44, no. 11 (2014): 40&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Guo, &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Trimebutine Combined With Bifidobacteria in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Anhui Medicine 16, no. 1 (2012): 4, https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1009&#x2010;6469.2012.01.038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Yang, &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;analysis of Trimebutine Combined With Bifidobacteria in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; World Latest Medical Information Abstracts (Electronic Edition) 15, no. 28 (2015): 107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. X. Bao, T. F. Ma, and Z. L. Li, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Two Drugs in the Combined Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Medical Forum 35 (2008): 1103&#x2013;1104, https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;1721.2008.35.036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Chen, Q. Q. Zeng, and H. Huang, &#x201c;Clinical Study of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Mezanam Capsule in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Medical Frontier 6, no. 11 (2011): 29&#x2013;29,48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Y. Fei, &#x201c;Trimebutine Maleate Combined With Bifidobacterium Bifidum for the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Primary Medical Forum 19, no. 29 (2015): 4069&#x2013;4070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Y. Gao, &#x201c;Clinical Observation on 50 Cases of Irritable Bowel Syndrome Treated With Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan,&#x201d; China Medical Guide 10, no. 1 (2012): 102&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. N. Gao, C. Liu, and Q. Yuan, &#x201c;Effect of Trimethoprim Maleate Tablets Combined With Compound Eosinophi 1&#x2010;Lactobacillus Tablets on Gastrointestinal Hormones in Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Marker Immunoanalytical and Clinical 25, no. 11 (2018): 1721&#x2013;1724,1749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Hou, &#x201c;Effect of Saccharomyces Boulardii Combined With Trimebutine Maleate in the Treatment of Diarrhea Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Clinical Medicine Research and Practice 4, no. 5 (2019): 41&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. A. Hua, Y. L. Zhang, and X. H. Huang, &#x201c;Clinical Study of Compound Eosinophil&#x2010;Lactobacillus Combined With Trimebutine in Treatment of Diarrhea&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Modern Drugs and Clinics 7 (2015): 867&#x2013;870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. K. Kou, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Lactobacillus Complex in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Clinical Practical Medicine 4, no. 5 (2010): 212&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Y. Lan, H. Y. Wu, and L. H. Han, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Pepcid Combined With Trimethoprim in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Medical Theory and Practice 25, no. 16 (2012): 2003&#x2013;2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, &#x201c;Clinical Study of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Community Physician (Medical Specialty) 13, no. 21 (2011): 128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Li, L. Cai, and J. Wang, &#x201c;Clinical Observation of Treating Diarrhea Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) by Trimebutine Maleate and Saccharomyces boulardii,&#x201d; Chinese Medical Science 13 (2015): 76&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Li, &#x201c;Observation on the Effect of Pepcid Combined With Trimethoprim in the Treatment of 48 Cases of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Transportation Medicine 21, no. 4 (2007): 406&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. F. Li, &#x201c;Clinical Effect of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Bifidobacterium Bifidum Triple Live Bacterial Powder in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of Practical Medicine 35, no. 2 (2018): 128&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. R. Liang, &#x201c;Influence and Efficacy of Bifid Triple Viable Capsules Combined With Trimebutine on Serum Inflammatory Factor Levels of Patients With Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Microecology 26, no. 12 (2014): 1414&#x2013;1417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Y. Liu, &#x201c;Analysis of the Clinical Effect of the Combination of Bacillus Subtilis Diphtheriae Capsule (Enteric) and Trimethoprim Maleate in the Treatment of Functional Diarrhea,&#x201d; Straits Pharmacology 30, no. 7 (2018): 192&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Liu and Y. Wu, &#x201c;Effect of Probiotics Combined With Trimebutine Maleate on Treatment of Constipation&#x2010;Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; International Journal of Digestive Diseases 37, no. 6 (2017): 377&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wang, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in 40 Cases,&#x201d; China Medical Guide 9, no. 31 (2011): 121&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. W. Liu and J. G. Hu, &#x201c;Clinical Curative Effect Observing of Live Bifidobacterium Capsules Combined With Tramebutine Maleate Capsules on Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Medical Innovation 7, no. 14 (2010): 3&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. J. Liu, H. J. Li, and Y. X. Qi, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of 76 Cases of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Practical Medicine 7, no. 28 (2012): 174&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Liu and X. Q. Xing, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in 40 Cases,&#x201d; Journal of Chengdu Medical College 7, no. 02Z (2012): 81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. H. Lu, &#x201c;Clinical Efficacy Analysis of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Bifidobacterium Bifidum Tetragonum Tablets in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Practical Medicine 6, no. 10 (2011): 168&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. H. Luo, &#x201c;Clinical Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Bifidobacterium Bifidum Tetragonum Tablets in the Treatment of 260 Cases of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese and Foreign Medicine Research 9, no. 32 (2011): 134&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. G. Qi and Z. Y. Dong, &#x201c;Clinical Efficacy Observation on Trimebutine Maleate Capsule Plus Live Combined With Bifidobacterium for Diarrhea&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Anorectal Diseases 33, no. 3 (2013): 49&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. L. Shen, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Compound Lactobacillus Acidophilus Tablets Combined With Trimethoprim Maleate in the Treatment of 71 Cases of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Modern Drug Application 1 (2015): 94&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Sun, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Pepcid Combined With Tramebutine in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Misdiagnosis 10, no. 6 (2010): 1285&#x2013;1286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Z. Sun, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Diarrhea&#x2010;Type Irritable Bowel Syndrome in 75 Cases,&#x201d; China Modern Drug Application 7, no. 21 (2013): 149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. G. Wan, &#x201c;Efficacy of Trimethoprim Dispersible Tablets Combined With Bifidobacterium Breve Triplex Capsules in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome and the Effect on IL&#x2010;6 Levels,&#x201d; China Pharmacist 4 (2014): 637&#x2013;638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Z. Wang, B. J. Xie, H. B. Wang, Y. J. Zhang, and X. B. Liang, &#x201c;Clinical Efficacy Analysis of Compound Lactobacillus Acidophilus Combined With Trimethoprim in the Treatment of Diarrhea&#x2010;Type Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Primary Care Medicine 18, no. 19 (2011): 2663&#x2013;2664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. H. Wang, &#x201c;A Clinical Observation of Diarrhea&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome Treated by Live Combined Bacillus Subtilis and Enterococcus Feacium Enteric&#x2010;Coated Capsules Combined With Trimebutine Maleate,&#x201d; China Medical Guide 11, no. 2 (2013): 33&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. X. Xiao, Y. Jiang, and D. H. Wang, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in 126 Cases,&#x201d; Straits Pharmacology 8 (2011): 167&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. L. Yang, &#x201c;Effect of Probiotics and Trimebutine Maleate for Constipation&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Contemporary Medicine Series 16, no. 13 (2018): 13&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Yang, &#x201c;Observation on the Clinical Efficacy of Trimethoprim Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; China Practical Medicine 8, no. 35 (2013): 143&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. H. Ye, &#x201c;Effect of Bifidobacterium Triple Probiotics on Constipation&#x2010;Predominant Irritable Bowel Syndrome in Elderly Patients With Defecation,&#x201d; Journal of Hainan Medical College 19, no. 4 (2013): 481&#x2013;483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. H. Yuan, &#x201c;The Effect of Bifid Triple Viable Capsule on Irritable Bowel Syndrome Treatment and the Probiotics Group,&#x201d; Modern Preventive Medicine 38, no. 3 (2011): 594&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Y. Zhang, X. Y. Li, and R. Cao, &#x201c;Trimebutine Maleate Combined With Pefecan in the Treatment of Irritable Bowel Syndrome in 100 Cases,&#x201d; Shaanxi Medical Journal 39, no. 6 (2010): 766&#x2013;767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zheng, &#x201c;Observation on the Efficacy of Trimethoprim Combined With Bacillus Licheniformis in the Treatment of Diarrhea&#x2010;Type Irritable Bowel Syndrome in 50 Cases,&#x201d; China Modern Drug Application 4, no. 18 (2010): 128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. M. Zhu and J. Wang, &#x201c;Effect of Bifidobacterium Terrestris Combined With Trimethoprim on Gastrointestinal Hormone Secretion in Patients With Constipated Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Straits Pharmacology 31, no. 4 (2019): 156&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. L. Rao, A. S. Cifu, L. W. Yang, and American Gastroenterological Association, &#x201c;Pharmacologic Management of Irritable Bowel Syndrome,&#x201d; Journal of the American Medical Association 314, no. 24 (2015): 2684&#x2013;2685, https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2015.16943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Duracinsky and O. Chassany, &#x201c;D&#xe9;velopper un m&#xe9;dicament Dans le Syndrome de l'intestin Irritable : Une Mission Impossible? [How can an Effective Drug to Treat Irritable Bowel Syndrome Be Successfully Developed?],&#x201d; Gastroent&#xe9;rologie Clinique et Biologique 33, no. Suppl 1 (2009): S26&#x2013;S34, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0399&#x2010;8320(09)71522&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. R. Sun, C. F. Kong, X. K. Qu, C. Deng, Y. N. Lou, and L. Q. Jia, &#x201c;Efficacy and Safety of Probiotics in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Saudi Journal of Gastroenterology 26, no. 2 (2020): 66&#x2013;77, https://doi.org/10.4103/sjg.SJG_384_19.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>