<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40935651</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2233-6087</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetes &amp; metabolism journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetes Metab J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinically Practical and Affordable Lifestyle Modification to Prevent Diabetes Mellitus in Real Practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>951</StartPage><EndPage>963</EndPage><MedlinePgn>951-963</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4093/dmj.2025.0675</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As the prevalence of type 2 diabetes mellitus continues to rise, the development of effective and sustainable prevention strategies has become a critical public health priority. Evidence from large-scale randomized controlled trials has established that lifestyle modification (LSM) programs can substantially reduce the risk of diabetes in high-risk individuals. However, routine implementation is limited by high intensity, costs, and resource requirements. We summarize major prevention trials and their effectiveness, feasibility, and limitations. Building on these insights, we introduce the Korean Diabetes Prevention Study (KDPS) as a contextually tailored model for the Korean healthcare system. The KDPS-LSM program was designed to integrate cultural and clinical relevance with practical applicability, consisting of a 6-month intensive phase of structured nutrition and lifestyle education followed by a maintenance phase to support long-term adherence. To promote sustainable change, the program incorporates the '10 habit' lifestyle messages, grounded in the transtheoretical model of behavior change, which are designed for easy implementation in daily life. This review underscores the importance of developing culturally appropriate LSM programs that balance effectiveness with feasibility, and suggests that the KDPS-LSM model could serve as a useful foundation for establishing practical diabetes prevention strategies within national healthcare systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Inji</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Nutrition, Graduate School of East-West Medical Science, Kyung Hee University, Yongin, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Medical Nutrition, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Minji</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Nutrition, Graduate School of East-West Medical Science, Kyung Hee University, Yongin, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Medical Nutrition, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Ji Hye</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Kyung Hee University Hospital, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regulatory Science, Graduate School, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Hyunjung</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Nutrition, Graduate School of East-West Medical Science, Kyung Hee University, Yongin, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Medical Nutrition, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chon</LastName><ForeName>Suk</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Kyung Hee University Hospital, College of Medicine, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2020-ER6402-00</GrantID><Agency>Korea National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020-ER6402-01</GrantID><Agency>Korea National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020-ER6402-02</GrantID><Agency>Korea National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023-ER1103-00</GrantID><Agency>Korea National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023-ER1103-01</GrantID><Agency>Korea National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023-ER1103-02</GrantID><Agency>Korea National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetes Metab J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101556588</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-6079</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008019" MajorTopicYN="Y">Life Style</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040242" MajorTopicYN="Y">Risk Reduction Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes mellitus, type 2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Korea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lifestyle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICTS OF INTEREST</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40935651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12436029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2025.0675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">dmj.2025.0675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hossain MJ, Al-Mamun M, Islam MR. Diabetes mellitus, the fastest growing global public health concern: early detection should be focused. Health Sci Rep. 2024;7:e2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10958528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Diabetes Federation . IDF Diabetes Atlas. Brussels: IDF; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph JJ, Deedwania P, Acharya T, Aguilar D, Bhatt DL, Chyun DA, et al. Comprehensive management of cardiovascular risk factors for adults with type 2 diabetes: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2022;145:e722&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35000404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruss SM, Nhim K, Gregg E, Bell M, Luman E, Albright A, et al. Public health approaches to type 2 diabetes prevention: the US National Diabetes Prevention Program and Beyond. Curr Diab Rep. 2019;19:78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6682852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31385061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An X, Zhang Y, Sun W, Kang X, Ji H, Sun Y, et al. Early effective intervention can significantly reduce all-cause mortality in prediabetic patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis based on high-quality clinical studies. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2024;15:1294819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10941028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38495794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galaviz KI, Weber MB, Straus A, Haw JS, Narayan KMV, Ali MK, et al. Global diabetes prevention interventions: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of the real-world impact on incidence, weight, and glucose. Diabetes Care. 2018;41:1526&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6463613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha S, Gerdtham UG, Johansson P. Economic evaluation of lifestyle interventions for preventing diabetes and cardiovascular diseases. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2010;7:3150&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20948954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs-van der Bruggen MA, van Baal PH, Hoogenveen RT, Feenstra TL, Briggs AH, Lawson K, et al. Cost-effectiveness of lifestyle modification in diabetic patients. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:1453&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2713648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19435958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Xie Q, Pan X, Zhang R, Zhang X, Peng G, et al. Type 2 diabetes mellitus in adults: pathogenesis, prevention and therapy. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2024;9:262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11445387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39353925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Kriti M, Anamika KS, Sarma DK, Verma V, Nagpal R, et al. Deciphering the complex interplay of risk factors in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a comprehensive review. Metabol Open. 2024;22:100287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11137529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38818227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galicia-Garcia U, Benito-Vicente A, Jebari S, Larrea-Sebal A, Siddiqi H, Uribe KB, et al. Pathophysiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:6275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32872570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali O. Genetics of type 2 diabetes. World J Diabetes. 2013;4:114&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23961321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillil H, Kobberling J. Age-corrected empirical genetic risk estimates for first-degree relatives of IDDM patients. Diabetes. 1987;36:93&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3792666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Good to know: race and type 2 diabetes. Clin Diabetes. 2020;38:403&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7566924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33132511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham TM, Carpenter JR, Morris TP, Sharma M, Petersen I. Ethnic differences in the prevalence of type 2 diabetes diagnoses in the UK: cross-sectional analysis of the health improvement network primary care database. Clin Epidemiol. 2019;11:1081&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6948201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32021464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golden SH, Yajnik C, Phatak S, Hanson RL, Knowler WC. Racial/ethnic differences in the burden of type 2 diabetes over the life course: a focus on the USA and India. Diabetologia. 2019;62:1751&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7181870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31451876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahelic V, Perkovic T, Romic L, Perkovic P, Klobucar S, Pavic E, et al. The role of behavioral factors on chronic diseases-practice and knowledge gaps. Healthcare (Basel) 2024;12:2520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11675894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39765947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dendup T, Feng X, Clingan S, Astell-Burt T. Environmental risk factors for developing type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15:78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29304014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Briggs F, Adler NE, Berkowitz SA, Chin MH, Gary-Webb TL, Navas-Acien A, et al. Social determinants of health and diabetes: a scientific review. Diabetes Care. 2020;44:258&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7783927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33139407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu FB, Manson JE, Stampfer MJ, Colditz G, Liu S, Solomon CG, et al. Diet, lifestyle, and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus in women. N Engl J Med. 2001;345:790&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Fukasawa M, Ohira T, Yasumura S, Suzuki T, Furuyama A, et al. Lifestyle behaviour patterns in the prevention of type 2 diabetes mellitus: the Fukushima Health Database 2015-2020. Public Health. 2023;224:98&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37742586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsueh WA, Orloski L, Wyne K. Prediabetes: the importance of early identification and intervention. Postgrad Med. 2010;122:129&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20675976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratley RE. The early treatment of type 2 diabetes. Am J Med. 2013;126(9 Suppl 1):S2&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23953075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SE, Ko SH, Kim JY, Kim K, Moon JH, Kim NH, et al. Diabetes fact sheets in Korea 2024. Diabetes Metab J. 2025;49:524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12086556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40367996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldroyd JC, Unwin NC, White M, Mathers JC, Alberti KG. Randomised controlled trial evaluating lifestyle interventions in people with impaired glucose tolerance. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2006;72:117&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16297488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo S, Ciccone G, Baldi C, Benini L, Dusio F, Forastiere G, et al. Effectiveness of a lifestyle intervention on metabolic syndrome. A randomized controlled trial. J Gen Intern Med. 2007;22:1695&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2219825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17922167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roumen C, Corpeleijn E, Feskens EJ, Mensink M, Saris WH, Blaak EE, et al. Impact of 3-year lifestyle intervention on postprandial glucose metabolism: the SLIM study. Diabet Med. 2008;25:597&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18445174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh EG, Bang SY, Hyun SS, Kim SH, Chu SH, Jeon JY, et al. Effects of a 6-month lifestyle modification intervention on the cardiometabolic risk factors and health-related qualities of life in women with metabolic syndrome. Metabolism. 2010;59:1035&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20045151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanri A, Tomita K, Matsushita Y, Ichikawa F, Yamamoto M, Nagafuchi Y, et al. Effect of six months lifestyle intervention in Japanese men with metabolic syndrome: randomized controlled trial. J Occup Health. 2012;54:215&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22790524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama C, Kimura M, Okumura H, Hayashi K, Arao T. Effect of a worksite-based intervention program on metabolic parameters in middle-aged male white-collar workers: a randomized controlled trial. Prev Med. 2010;51:11&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20403374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu YH, Lu JM, Wang SY, Li CL, Zheng RP, Tian H, et al. Outcome of intensive integrated intervention in participants with impaired glucose regulation in China. Adv Ther. 2011;28:511&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21533568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Wan X, Wu B. The cost-effectiveness of lifestyle interventions for preventing diabetes in a health resource-limited setting. J Diabetes Res. 2020;2020:7410797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan XR, Li GW, Hu YH, Wang JX, Yang WY, An ZX, et al. Effects of diet and exercise in preventing NIDDM in people with impaired glucose tolerance. The Da Qing IGT and Diabetes Study. Diabetes Care. 1997;20:537&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9096977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuomilehto J, Lindstrom J, Eriksson JG, Valle TT, Hamalainen H, Ilanne-Parikka P, et al. Prevention of type 2 diabetes mellitus by changes in lifestyle among subjects with impaired glucose tolerance. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:1343&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11333990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowler WC, Barrett-Connor E, Fowler SE, Hamman RF, Lachin JM, Walker EA, et al. Reduction in the incidence of type 2 diabetes with lifestyle intervention or metformin. N Engl J Med. 2002;346:393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1370926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11832527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakane N, Sato J, Tsushita K, Tsujii S, Kotani K, Tsuzaki K, et al. Prevention of type 2 diabetes in a primary healthcare setting: three-year results of lifestyle intervention in Japanese subjects with impaired glucose tolerance. BMC Public Health. 2011;11:40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21235825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran A, Snehalatha C, Mary S, Mukesh B, Bhaskar AD, Vijay V, et al. The Indian Diabetes Prevention Programme shows that lifestyle modification and metformin prevent type 2 diabetes in Asian Indian subjects with impaired glucose tolerance (IDPP-1) Diabetologia. 2006;49:289&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16391903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis-Lameloise N, Hernan A, Janus ED, Stewart E, Carter R, Bennett CM, et al. The Melbourne Diabetes Prevention Study (MDPS): study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2013;14:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3598212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laatikainen T, Dunbar JA, Chapman A, Kilkkinen A, Vartiainen E, Heistaro S, et al. Prevention of type 2 diabetes by lifestyle intervention in an Australian primary health care setting: Greater Green Triangle (GGT) Diabetes Prevention Project. BMC Public Health. 2007;7:249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2039742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17877832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunbar JA. Diabetes prevention in Australia: 10 years results and experience. Diabetes Metab J. 2017;41:160&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5489495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28537055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower P, Soiland-Reyes C, Bennett C, Brunton L, Burch P, Cameron E, et al. The effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of the NHS Diabetes Prevention Programme (NHS-DPP): the DIPLOMA long-term multimethod assessment. Health Soc Care Deliv Res. 2025;13:1&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40323644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valabhji J, Barron E, Bradley D, Bakhai C, Fagg J, O&#x2019;Neill S, et al. Early outcomes from the English National Health Service Diabetes Prevention Programme. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:152&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31719054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Abraham C, Whittington C, McAteer J, Gupta S. Effective techniques in healthy eating and physical activity interventions: a meta-regression. Health Psychol. 2009;28:690&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves CJ, Sheppard KE, Abraham C, Hardeman W, Roden M, Evans PH, et al. Systematic review of reviews of intervention components associated with increased effectiveness in dietary and physical activity interventions. BMC Public Health. 2011;11:119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3048531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Phelan S. Long-term weight loss maintenance. Am J Clin Nutr. 2005;82(1 Suppl):222S&#x2013;5S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BH, Lim H. Effects of customized nutritional education &#x2018;change 10 habits&#x2019; program according to stage of behavior change in mildly obese adults. J Korean Diet Assoc. 2015;21:215&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BH, Kang M, Kim DY, Son K, Lim H. High compliance with the lifestyle-modification program &#x201c;change 10 habits&#x201d; is effective for obesity management. J Obes Metab Syndr. 2024;33:155&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11224923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38692887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee SY, Chon S, Ahn KJ, Woo JT. Hospital-based Korean Diabetes Prevention Study: a prospective, multi-center, randomized, open-label controlled study. Diabetes Metab J. 2019;43:49&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6387881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30398039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JH, Lee JH, Chon S. Medical nutrition therapy as a hospital-based lifestyle modification in the Korean Diabetes Prevention Study. J Korean Diabetes. 2025;26:39&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>