<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40782191</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1867-1314</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Probiotics and antimicrobial proteins</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Probiotic and Synbiotic Supplementation on Glycemic Indices in Adult Individuals with Prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Grade-Assessed Systematic Review and Dose-Response Meta-analysis of RCTs.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12602-025-10644-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Probiotic and synbiotic supplementation has garnered attention for its potential to modulate metabolic parameters, including glycemic control, in individuals with prediabetes and type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). This systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis aims to evaluate the effectiveness of these supplements on glycemic indices, synthesizing evidence from randomized controlled trials (RCTs) with grade-assessed methodologies. A comprehensive search of scientific databases was conducted from inception through January 2025 to identify RCTs assessing the effects of probiotic and synbiotic supplementation on glycemic indices, including fasting blood glucose (FBG), fasting insulin (FI), hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c), and homeostatic model assessment for insulin resistance (HOMA-IR). Eligible studies were screened; relevant data were extracted, and the quality of evidence was evaluated using the GRADE approach. Statistical analyses were performed using STATA to generate pooled results. The pooled analysis of 48 RCTs demonstrated that probiotics and synbiotics supplementation significantly decreased FBG (WMD:&#x2009;-&#x2009;7.00&#xa0;mg/dL), FI (WMD:&#x2009;-&#x2009;1.72 &#xb5;IU/mL), HbA1c levels (WMD:&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.34%), and HOMA-IR (WMD:&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.91), with a substantial heterogeneity across all outcomes (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Subgroup analyses indicated reductions in FBG, FI, HbA1c, and HOMA-IR across varying baseline characteristics, including glycemic levels, trial durations, and participant health status. Both probiotics and synbiotics were effective, with notable benefits for patients with T2DM, longer intervention durations, and higher baseline BMI. Meta-regression and dose-response analyses revealed no significant association between the duration of probiotic and synbiotic supplementation and changes in glycemic indices. Probiotic and synbiotic supplements significantly reduce FBG, FI, HbA1c, and HOMA-IR, leading to improvements in glycemic markers in individuals with prediabetes and T2DM. These supplements can be used as effective adjunctive strategies to enhance glycemic control, highlighting the promising role of gut microbiota modulation in diabetes management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Setayesh</LastName><ForeName>Azin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-4305-9992</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Nutrition, School of Nutritional Sciences and Dietetics, Tehran University of Medical Sciences (TUMS), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimi</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-4388-0214</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Bogomolets National Medical University (NMU), Kyiv, Ukraine. Karimi9010@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Amin</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0638-1743</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences (SBUMS), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pirzad</LastName><ForeName>Samira</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-9220-3891</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Islamic Azad University, Tehran Medical Sciences Branch (IAUTMU), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heydari</LastName><ForeName>Mahdis</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-3157-9453</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Bushehr University of Medical Sciences, Bushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asbaghi</LastName><ForeName>Omid</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7740-4711</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Research Center, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences (SBUMS), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davoodi</LastName><ForeName>Sayed Hossein</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6404-8367</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Nutrition and Food Technology Research Institute, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences (SBUMS), Tehran, Iran. hdavoodi@sbmu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larijani</LastName><ForeName>Bagher</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5386-7597</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology and Metabolism Research Center, Endocrinology and Metabolism Clinical Sciences Institute, Tehran University of Medical Sciences (TUMS), Tehran, Iran. Larijanib1340@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101484100</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1867-1306</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glycemic markers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Probiotic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synbiotic</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Conflicts of Interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40782191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12602-025-10644-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12602-025-10644-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wild S, Roglic G, Green A, Sicree R, King H (2004) Global prevalence of diabetes: estimates for the year 2000 and projections for 2030. Diabetes Care 27(5):1047&#x2013;1053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15111519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali MK, Pearson-Stuttard J, Selvin E, Gregg EW (2022) Interpreting global trends in type 2 diabetes complications and mortality. Diabetologia 65(1):3&#x2013;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34837505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, Bannuru RR, Brown FM, Bruemmer D et al (2022) 6. Glycemic targets: standards of care in diabetes&#x2014;2023. Diabetes Care 46(Supplement_1):S97-S110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin Rakhis SA Sr, AlDuwayhis NM, Aleid N, AlBarrak AN, Aloraini AA (2022) Glycemic control for type 2 diabetes mellitus patients: a systematic review. Cureus 14(6):e26180</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Ley SH, Hu FB (2018) Global aetiology and epidemiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus and its complications. Nat Rev Endocrinol 14(2):88&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29219149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor SI (2020) The high cost of diabetes drugs: disparate impact on the most vulnerable patients. Diabetes Care 43(10):2330&#x2013;2332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32958616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8051261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokgalaboni K, Lebelo SL, Modjadji P, Ghaffary S (2023) Okra ameliorates hyperglycaemia in pre-diabetic and type 2 diabetic patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the clinical evidence. Front Pharmacol 14:1132650</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10107009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi M, Vakili K, Rashidian P, Razavi-Amoli SK, Akhbari M, Kazemi K (2024) Effect of boswellia (Boswellia serrata L.) supplementation on glycemic markers and lipid profile in type 2 diabetic patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Clin Diabetes Healthc 5:1466408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim M, Pirzad S, Shirsalimi N, Hosseini MH, Ebrahimi P, Khoshdooz S et al (2024) Effects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) supplementation on cardiometabolic Indices in diabetic and prediabetic overweight patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of RCTs. Diabetol Metab Syndr 16(1):286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi M, Pirzad S, Pourfaraji SMA, Sedgi FM, Darouei B, Amani-Beni R, Kazemi K, Rabiee R (2025) Effects of black seed (Nigella sativa L.) on cardiometabolic indices in type 2 diabetic patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of RCTs. Complement Ther Med 90:103174. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ctim.2025.103174</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulang&#xe9; CL, Neves AL, Chilloux J, Nicholson JK, Dumas M-E (2016) Impact of the gut microbiota on inflammation, obesity, and metabolic disease. Genome Med 8(1):42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4839080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang HR, Lee HY (2021) Mechanisms linking gut microbial metabolites to insulin resistance. World J Diabetes 12(6):730&#x2013;744</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8192250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thursby E, Juge N (2017) Introduction to the human gut microbiota. Biochem J 474(11):1823&#x2013;1836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28512250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Tripathi P (2019) Gut microbiome and type 2 diabetes: Where we are and where to go? J Nutr Biochem 63:101&#x2013;108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin J, Li Y, Cai Z, Li S, Zhu J, Zhang F et al (2012) A metagenome-wide association study of gut microbiota in type 2 diabetes. Nature 490(7418):55&#x2013;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23023125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilg H, Zmora N, Adolph TE, Elinav E (2020) The intestinal microbiota fuelling metabolic inflammation. Nat Rev Immunol 20(1):40&#x2013;54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31388093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe9;rard C, Vidal H (2019) Impact of gut microbiota on host glycemic control. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 10:29</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30761090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dash NR, Al Bataineh MT, Alili R, Al Safar H, Alkhayyal N, Prifti E et al (2023) Functional alterations and predictive capacity of gut microbiome in type 2 diabetes. Sci Rep 13(1):22386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38104165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10725451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson KS, Gibson GR, Hutkins R, Reimer RA, Reid G, Verbeke K et al (2020) The International Scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics (ISAPP) consensus statement on the definition and scope of synbiotics. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 17(11):687&#x2013;701</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7581511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill C, Guarner F, Reid G, Gibson GR, Merenstein DJ, Pot B et al (2014) The International Scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics consensus statement on the scope and appropriate use of the term probiotic. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 11(8):506&#x2013;514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey KR, Naik SR, Vakil BV (2015) Probiotics, prebiotics and synbiotics- a review. J Food Sci Technol 52(12):7577&#x2013;7587</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4648921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crudele L, Gadaleta RM, Cariello M, Moschetta A (2023) Gut microbiota in the pathogenesis and therapeutic approaches of diabetes. EBioMedicine 97:104821. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craciun CI, Neag MA, Catinean A, Mitre AO, Rusu A, Bala C, Roman G, Buzoianu AD, Muntean DM, Craciun AE (2022) The relationships between gut microbiota and diabetes mellitus, and treatments for diabetes mellitus. Biomedicines 10(2):308. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines10020308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8869176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R, Meng X, Xue Y, Mao M, Liu Y, Tian X et al (2022) Bile acids-gut microbiota crosstalk contributes to the improvement of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Front Pharmacol 13:1027212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36386219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9640995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Zhang Q, Zhang X, Du S, Zhang Y, Wang X et al (2025) Effects of synbiotics surpass probiotics alone in improving type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Nutr 44:248&#x2013;258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39719724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mafi A, Namazi G, Soleimani A, Bahmani F, Aghadavod E, Asemi Z (2018) Metabolic and genetic response to probiotics supplementation in patients with diabetic nephropathy: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Food Funct 9(9):4763&#x2013;4770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perraudeau F, McMurdie P, Bullard J, Cheng A, Cutcliffe C, Deo A, Eid J, Gines J, Iyer M, Justice N, Loo WT, Nemchek M, Schicklberger M, Souza M, Stoneburner B, Tyagi S, Kolterman O (2020) Improvements to postprandial glucose control in subjects with type 2 diabetes: a multicenter, double blind, randomized placebo-controlled trial of a novel probiotic formulation. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care 8(1):e001319. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjdrc-2020-001319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD et al (2021) The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Int J Surg 88:105906</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J (2011) Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Version 5.1. 0 [updated March 2011]. The Cochrane Collaboration. www cochrane-handbook org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao S-C, Kuo L-T, Huang Y-T, Lai P-C, Chi C-C (2023) Using Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) to rate the certainty of evidence of study outcomes from systematic reviews: a quick tutorial. Dermatol Sin 41(1):3&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N (1986) Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials 7(3):177&#x2013;188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asbaghi O, Sadeghian M, Mozaffari-Khosravi H, Maleki V, Shokri A, Hajizadeh-Sharafabad F et al (2020) The effect of vitamin d-calcium co-supplementation on inflammatory biomarkers: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cytokine 129:155050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32113022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukaka MM (2012) Statistics corner: a guide to appropriate use of correlation coefficient in medical research. Malawi Med J 24(3):69&#x2013;71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23638278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3576830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hozo SP, Djulbegovic B, Hozo I (2005) Estimating the mean and variance from the median, range, and the size of a sample. BMC Med Res Methodol 5:13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15840177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1097734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu R, Gartlehner G, Grant M, Shamliyan T, Sedrakyan A, Wilt TJ et al (2011) Conducting quantitative synthesis when comparing medical interventions: AHRQ and the Effective Health Care Program. J Clin Epidemiol 64(11):1187&#x2013;1197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21477993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>(2008) Methods Guide for Effectiveness and Comparative Effectiveness Reviews [Internet]. Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (US),&#xa0;Rockville (MD)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begg CB, Mazumdar M (1994) Operating characteristics of a rank correlation test for publication bias. Biometrics 50(4):1088&#x2013;101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7786990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C (1997) Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ 315(7109):629&#x2013;634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2127453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C, Doi SA (2018) The robust error meta-regression method for dose&#x2013;response meta-analysis. JBI Evid Implement 16(3):138&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Gou L, Peng M, Zheng J, Chen L (2021) Effects of soluble fiber supplementation on glycemic control in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Nutr 40(4):1800&#x2013;1810</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33162192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S (2005) The trim and fill method. Publication bias in meta-analysis: prevention, assessment and adjustments. Wiley Online Books, pp 127&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moroti C, Souza Magri LF, de Rezende CM, Cavallini DC, Sivieri K (2012) Effect of the consumption of a new symbiotic shake on glycemia and cholesterol levels in elderly people with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Lipids Health Dis 11:1&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asemi Z, Zare Z, Shakeri H, Sabihi S-s, Esmaillzadeh A (2013) Effect of multispecies probiotic supplements on metabolic profiles, hs-CRP, and oxidative stress in patients with type 2 diabetes. Ann Nutr Metab 63(1&#x2013;2):1&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazloom Z, Yousefinejad A, Dabbaghmanesh MH (2013) Effect of probiotics on lipid profile, glycemic control, insulin action, oxidative stress, and inflammatory markers in patients with type 2 diabetes: a clinical trial. Iran J Med Sci 38(1):38&#x2013;43</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23645956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3642943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheth M, chand v, Thakuria A (2015) Inflated levels of SCFA, Bifidobacteria and Lactobacillus improves the status of pre hypertension and type 2 diabetes mellitus in subjects residing in north east INDIA&#x2013;a randomized control trial with synbiotic supplementation. International J Curr Pharm Res 7:33&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadian F, Ejtahed HS, Javadi M, Razmpoosh E, Mirmiran P, Azizi F&#xa0;(2017) The effects of probiotic supplementation on glycemic control, insulin resistance and inflammatory biomarkers of type 2 diabetic patients.&#xa0; https://www.cabidigitallibrary.org/doi/full/10.5555/20183098809</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi ZS, Nasli-Esfahani E, Nadjarzade A, Mozaffari-Khosravi H (2017) Effect of symbiotic supplementation on glycemic control, lipid profiles and microalbuminuria in patients with non-obese type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, clinical trial. J Diabetes Metab Disord 16:1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firouzi S, Majid HA, Ismail A, Kamaruddin NA, Barakatun-Nisak M-Y (2017) Effect of multi-strain probiotics (multi-strain microbial cell preparation) on glycemic control and other diabetes-related outcomes in people with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Nutr 56:1535&#x2013;1550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobini R, Tremaroli V, St&#xe5;hlman M, Karlsson F, Levin M, Ljungberg M et al (2017) Metabolic effects of L actobacillus reuteri DSM 17938 in people with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab 19(4):579&#x2013;589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28009106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabico S, Al-Mashharawi A, Al-Daghri NM, Yakout S, Alnaami AM, Alokail MS et al (2017) Effects of a multi-strain probiotic supplement for 12 weeks in circulating endotoxin levels and cardiometabolic profiles of medication na&#xef;ve T2DM patients: a randomized clinical trial. J Transl Med 15:1&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani A, Mojarrad MZ, Bahmani F, Taghizadeh M, Ramezani M, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M et al (2017) Probiotic supplementation in diabetic hemodialysis patients has beneficial metabolic effects. Kidney Int 91(2):435&#x2013;442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27927601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M, Sharifi N, Farrokhian A, Raygan F, Karamali F, Razzaghi R et al (2017) A randomized controlled clinical trial investigating the effect of synbiotic administration on markers of insulin metabolism and lipid profiles in overweight type 2 diabetic patients with coronary heart disease. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes 125(01):21&#x2013;27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27219886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan T, Zhao W, Cao Y, Li Q, Yao M, Hao X et al (2017) Effect of Bifidobacterium tetragenous viable bacteria tablets on blood glucose level in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Chin J Clin Nutr 25:205&#x2013;213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh M-C, Tsai W-H, Jheng Y-P, Su S-L, Wang S-Y, Lin C-C et al (2018) The beneficial effects of Lactobacillus reuteri ADR-1 or ADR-3 consumption on type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. Sci Rep 8(1):16791</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6235926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassaian N, Feizi A, Aminorroaya A, Jafari P, Ebrahimi MT, Amini M (2018) The effects of probiotics and synbiotic supplementation on glucose and insulin metabolism in adults with prediabetes: a double-blind randomized clinical trial. Acta Diabetol 55:1019&#x2013;1028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29931423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobyliak N, Falalyeyeva T, Mykhalchyshyn G, Kyriienko D, Komissarenko I (2018) Effect of alive probiotic on insulin resistance in type 2 diabetes patients: randomized clinical trial. Diabetes Metab Syndr 12(5):617&#x2013;624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29661605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohseni S, Bayani M, Bahmani F, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M, Bayani MA, Jafari P et al (2018) The beneficial effects of probiotic administration on wound healing and metabolic status in patients with diabetic foot ulcer: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 34(3):e2970</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raygan F, Rezavandi Z, Bahmani F, Ostadmohammadi V, Mansournia MA, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M et al (2018) The effects of probiotic supplementation on metabolic status in type 2 diabetic patients with coronary heart disease. Diabetol Metab Syndr 10:1&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalili L, Alipour B, Jafar-Abadi MA, Faraji I, Hassanalilou T, Abbasi MM et al (2019) The effects of Lactobacillus casei on glycemic response, serum sirtuin1 and fetuin-a levels in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled trial. Iran Biomed J 23(1):68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29803203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6305821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madempudi RS, Ahire JJ, Neelamraju J, Tripathi A, Nanal S (2019) Efficacy of UB0316, a multi-strain probiotic formulation in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a double blind, randomized, placebo controlled study. PLoS ONE 14(11):e0225168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31721790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6853318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razmpoosh E, Javadi A, Ejtahed HS, Mirmiran P, Javadi M, Yousefinejad A (2019) The effect of probiotic supplementation on glycemic control and lipid profile in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized placebo controlled trial. Diabetes Metab Syndr 13(1):175&#x2013;182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30641692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabico S, Al-Mashharawi A, Al-Daghri NM, Wani K, Amer OE, Hussain DS et al (2019) Effects of a 6-month multi-strain probiotics supplementation in endotoxemic, inflammatory and cardiometabolic status of T2DM patients: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Nutr 38(4):1561&#x2013;1569</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30170781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani A, Motamedzadeh A, Zarrati Mojarrad M, Bahmani F, Amirani E, Ostadmohammadi V et al (2019) The effects of synbiotic supplementation on metabolic status in diabetic patients undergoing hemodialysis: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins 11:1248&#x2013;1256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30560426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath A, Leber B, Feldbacher N, Tripolt N, Rainer F, Blesl A et al (2020) Effects of a multispecies synbiotic on glucose metabolism, lipid marker, gut microbiome composition, gut permeability, and quality of life in diabesity: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot study. Eur J Nutr 59:2969&#x2013;2983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31729622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios T, Vitetta L, Coulson S, Madigan CD, Lam YY, Manuel R et al (2020) Targeting the intestinal microbiota to prevent type 2 diabetes and enhance the effect of metformin on glycaemia: a randomised controlled pilot study. Nutrients 12(7):2041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32660025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7400852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perraudeau F, McMurdie P, Bullard J, Cheng A, Cutcliffe C, Deo A et al (2020) Improvements to postprandial glucose control in subjects with type 2 diabetes: a multicenter, double blind, randomized placebo-controlled trial of a novel probiotic formulation. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care 8(1):e001319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7368581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay A, Pringle H, Penning E, Plank LD, Murphy R (2020) PROFAST: a randomized trial assessing the effects of intermittent fasting and Lacticaseibacillus rhamnosus probiotic among people with prediabetes. Nutrients 12(11):3530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33212907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7698325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Gu Y, Ren H, Wang S, Zhong H, Zhao X et al (2020) Gut microbiome-related effects of berberine and probiotics on type 2 diabetes (the PREMOTE study). Nat Commun 11(1):5015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7538905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Zhang Y, Xu D, Wang Q (2021) Probiotics ameliorates glycemic control of patients with diabetic nephropathy: a randomized clinical study. J Clin Lab Anal 35(4):e23650</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33666270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8059722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanazawa A, Aida M, Yoshida Y, Kaga H, Katahira T, Suzuki L et al (2021) Effects of synbiotic supplementation on chronic inflammation and the gut microbiota in obese patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled study. Nutrients 13(2):558</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33567701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7914668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miryousefiata SF, Ata FAM (2021) The effect of Familact probiotic supplement in patients with diabetes: evaluation of blood glucose parameters, lipid profile. Acad J Health Sci: Medicina Balear 36(3):52&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh M-R, Jang H-Y, Lee S-Y, Jung S-J, Chae S-W, Lee S-O et al (2021) Lactobacillus plantarum HAC01 supplementation improves glycemic control in prediabetic subjects: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Nutrients 13(7):2337</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8308899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toejing P, Khampithum N, Sirilun S, Chaiyasut C, Lailerd N (2021) Influence of Lactobacillus paracasei HII01 supplementation on glycemia and inflammatory biomarkers in type 2 diabetes: a randomized clinical trial. Foods 10(7):1455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34201653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8303256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barthow C, Hood F, Crane J, Huthwaite M, Weatherall M, Parry-Strong A et al (2022) A randomised controlled trial of a probiotic and a prebiotic examining metabolic and mental health outcomes in adults with pre-diabetes. BMJ Open 12(3):e055214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35332040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8948404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a G, Soto J, Rodr&#xed;guez L, Nuez M, Dom&#xed;nguez N, Buchaca EF, Mart&#xed;nez D, G&#xf3;mez RJ, &#xc1;vila Y, Carlin MR, Cano RJ&#xa0;(2022) A randomized placebo controlled clinical trial of a metabolic shifting probiotic, sugar shift, for the treatment of T2DM. medRxiv&#xa0;2022&#x2013;12.&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.12.06.22283186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin K, &#x15e;ahint&#xfc;rk Y, K&#xf6;ker G, K&#xf6;ker G&#xd6;, Bostan F, K&#xf6;k M et al (2022) Metformin with versus without concomitant probiotic therapy in newly diagnosed patients with type 2 diabetes or prediabetes: a comparative analysis in relation to glycemic control, gastrointestinal side effects, and treatment compliance. Turk J Gastroenterol 33(11):925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36098362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9797791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei F, Zhou L, Wang Q, Zheng G, Su S (2022) Effect of compound lactic acid bacteria capsules on the small intestinal bacterial overgrowth in patients with depression and diabetes: a blinded randomized controlled clinical trial. Dis Markers 2022(1):6721695</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35677636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9168214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AkbariRad M, Shariatmaghani SS, Razavi BM, Majd HM, Shakhsemampour Z, Sarabi M et al (2023) Probiotics for glycemic and lipid profile control of the pre-diabetic patients: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled clinical trial study. Diabetol Metab Syndr 15(1):71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37038214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10084663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaiyasut C, Sivamaruthi BS, Lailerd N, Sirilun S, Thangaleela S, Khongtan S et al (2023) Influence of Bifidobacterium breve on the glycaemic control, lipid profile and microbiome of type 2 diabetic subjects: a preliminary randomized clinical trial. Pharmaceuticals 16(5):695</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37242478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10220806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Shen X, Ma T, Yu X, Kwok L-Y, Li Y et al (2023) Adjunctive Probio-X treatment enhances the therapeutic effect of a conventional drug in managing type 2 diabetes mellitus by promoting short-chain fatty acid-producing bacteria and bile acid pathways. Msystems 8(1):e01300-e1322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36688679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9948714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliuz Tipici B, Coskunpinar E, Altunkanat D, Cagatay P, Omer B, Palanduz S et al (2023) Lactobacillus GG is associated with mucin genes expressions in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Eur J Nutr 62(5):2155&#x2013;2164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36997822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanpour A, Babajafari S, Mazloomi SM, Shams M (2023) The effects of soymilk plus probiotics supplementation on cardiovascular risk factors in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized clinical trial. BMC Endocr Disord 23(1):36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9912676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savytska M, Kyriienko D, Komisarenko I, Kovalchuk O, Falalyeyeva T, Kobyliak N (2023) Probiotic for pancreatic &#x3b2;-cell function in type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Diabetes Ther 14(11):1915&#x2013;1931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37713103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10570251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velayati A, Kareem I, Sedaghat M, Sohrab G, Nikpayam O, Hedayati M et al (2023) Does symbiotic supplementation which contains Bacillus Coagulans Lactobacillus rhamnosus, Lactobacillus acidophilus and fructooligosaccharide has favourite effects in patients with type-2 diabetes? A randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Arch Physiol Biochem 129(6):1211&#x2013;1218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zikou E, Dovrolis N, Dimosthenopoulos C, Gazouli M, Makrilakis K (2023) The effect of probiotic supplements on metabolic parameters of people with type 2 diabetes in Greece&#x2014;a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Nutrients 15(21):4663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37960315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10647535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farajipour H, Matin HR, Asemi Z, Sadr S, Tajabadi-Ebrahimi M, Sharifi N, Banikazemi Z, Taghizadeh M, Mirzaei H (2024) The effects of probiotics supplements on metabolic indices and clinical signs in patients with diabetic retinopathy, a randomized double blind clinical trial. J Diabetes Metab Disord 23(1):1133&#x2013;1140. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40200-024-01399-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38932908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11196520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaff S, Gubari M, Shab-Bidar S, Djafarian K (2024) Effect of probiotic supplementation on lipoprotein-associated phospholipase A2 in type 2 diabetic patients: a randomized double blind clinical controlled trial. Nutr Metab 21(1):3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X, Xian H, Ge N, Hou L, Tang T, Xie D, Gao L, Yue J (2024) Effect of probiotics on glycemic control and lipid profiles in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized, double blind, controlled trial. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 15:1440286.&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2024.1440286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bock PM, Telo GH, Ramalho R, Sbaraini M, Leivas G, Martins AF et al (2021) The effect of probiotics, prebiotics or synbiotics on metabolic outcomes in individuals with diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetologia 64(1):26&#x2013;41</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikbakht E, Khalesi S, Singh I, Williams LT, West NP, Colson N (2018) Effect of probiotics and synbiotics on blood glucose: a systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. Eur J Nutr 57(1):95&#x2013;106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delzenne NM, Cani PD, Everard A, Neyrinck AM, Bindels LB (2015) Gut microorganisms as promising targets for the management of type 2 diabetes. Diabetologia 58(10):2206&#x2013;2217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26224102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunkwall L, Orho-Melander M (2017) The gut microbiome as a target for prevention and treatment of hyperglycaemia in type 2 diabetes: from current human evidence to future possibilities. Diabetologia 60(6):943&#x2013;951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28434033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5423958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabico S, Al-Mashharawi A, Al-Daghri NM, Yakout S, Alnaami AM, Alokail MS et al (2017) Effects of a multi-strain probiotic supplement for 12 weeks in circulating endotoxin levels and cardiometabolic profiles of medication na&#xef;ve T2DM patients: a randomized clinical trial. J Transl Med 15(1):249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29228964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5725828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittiphairoj T, Pongpirul K, Janchot K, Mueller NT, Li T (2021) Probiotics contribute to glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Adv Nutr 12(3):722&#x2013;734</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Juan Q-F, He Y-W, Zhuang L, Fang Y-Y, Wang Y-H (2017) Multiple effects of probiotics on different types of diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized, placebo-controlled trials. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab 30(6):611&#x2013;622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28599375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barengolts E, Smith ED, Reutrakul S, Tonucci L, Anothaisintawee T (2019) The effect of probiotic yogurt on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes or obesity: a meta-analysis of nine randomized controlled trials. Nutrients 11(3):671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30897796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6471569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon H, Abdulla F, Reljic T, Alnuaimi S, Serdarevic F, Asimi ZV et al (2023) Effects of combined treatment of probiotics and metformin in management of type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 202:110806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37369280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zikou E, Dovrolis N, Dimosthenopoulos C, Gazouli M, Makrilakis K (2023) The effect of probiotic supplements on metabolic parameters of people with type 2 diabetes in greece-a randomized, double-blind,&#xa0;placebo-controlled study. Nutrients 15(21):4663. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15214663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X, Xian H, Ge N, Hou L, Tang T, Xie D et al (2024) Effect of probiotics on glycemic control and lipid profiles in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized, double blind, controlled trial. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 15:1440286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39351535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi H, Kamikado K, Aoki R, Suganuma N, Nishijima T, Nakatani A et al (2020) Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. lactis GCL2505 modulates host energy metabolism via the short-chain fatty acid receptor GPR43. Sci Rep 10(1):4158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K-K, Tian P-J, Wang S-D, Lei P, Qu L, Huang J-P et al (2017) Targeting gut microbiota: Lactobacillus alleviated type 2 diabetes via inhibiting LPS secretion and activating GPR43 pathway. J Funct Foods 38:561&#x2013;570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabelsi MS, Lestavel S, Staels B, Collet X (2017) Intestinal bile acid receptors are key regulators of glucose homeostasis. Proc Nutr Soc 76(3):192&#x2013;202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27846919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobini R, Tremaroli V, St&#xe5;hlman M, Karlsson F, Levin M, Ljungberg M et al (2017) Metabolic effects of actobacillus reuteri DSM 17938 in people with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab 19(4):579&#x2013;589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28009106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav H, Lee JH, Lloyd J, Walter P, Rane SG (2013) Beneficial metabolic effects of a probiotic via butyrate-induced GLP-1 hormone secretion. J Biol Chem 288(35):25088&#x2013;25097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23836895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3757173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Dilidaxi D, Wu Y, Sailike J, Sun X, Nabi X-h (2020) Composite probiotics alleviate type 2 diabetes by regulating intestinal microbiota and inducing GLP-1 secretion in db/db mice. Biomed Pharmacother125:109914</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon M-C, Strassburger K, Nowotny B, Kolb H, Nowotny P, Burkart V et al (2015) Intake of Lactobacillus reuteri improves incretin and insulin secretion in glucose-tolerant humans: a proof of concept. Diabetes Care 38(10):1827&#x2013;1834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26084343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cani PD, Bibiloni R, Knauf C, Waget A, Neyrinck AM, Delzenne NM et al (2008) Changes in gut microbiota control metabolic endotoxemia-induced inflammation in high-fat diet-induced obesity and diabetes in mice. Diabetes 57(6):1470&#x2013;1481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18305141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths EA, Duffy LC, Schanbacher FL, Qiao H, Dryja D, Leavens A et al (2004) In vivo effects of bifidobacteria and lactoferrin on gut endotoxin concentration and mucosal immunity in Balb/c mice. Dig Dis Sci 49(4):579&#x2013;589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15185861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cani PD, Lecourt E, Dewulf EM, Sohet FM, Pachikian BD, Naslain D et al (2009) Gut microbiota fermentation of prebiotics increases satietogenic and incretin gut peptide production with consequences for appetite sensation and glucose response after a meal. Am J Clin Nutr 90(5):1236&#x2013;1243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parnell JA, Reimer RA (2009) Weight loss during oligofructose supplementation is associated with decreased ghrelin and increased peptide YY in overweight and obese adults. Am J Clin Nutr 89(6):1751&#x2013;1759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gmeiner M, Kneifel W, Kulbe KD, Wouters R, De Boever P, Nollet L et al (2000) Influence of a synbiotic mixture consisting of Lactobacillus acidophilus 74&#x2013;2 and a fructooligosaccharide preparation on the microbial ecology sustained in a simulation of the human intestinal microbial ecosystem (SHIME reactor). Appl Microbiol Biotechnol 53(2):219&#x2013;223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10709985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cani PD, Joly E, Horsmans Y, Delzenne NM (2006) Oligofructose promotes satiety in healthy human: a pilot study. Eur J Clin Nutr 60(5):567&#x2013;572. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16340949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel S, Veltman K, Cichon C, Sonnenborn U, Schmidt MA (2012) Differential targeting of the E-Cadherin/&#x3b2;-Catenin complex by gram-positive probiotic lactobacilli improves epithelial barrier function. Appl Environ Microbiol 78(4):1140&#x2013;1147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22179242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3272997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kothari D, Patel S, Kim S-K (2019) Probiotic supplements might not be universally-effective and safe: a review. Biomed Pharmacother 111:537&#x2013;547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30597307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>