<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40792681</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1897-4279</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Kardiologia polska</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Kardiol Pol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How to screen for atrial fibrillation on a community level? Recent advances.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.33963/v.phj.107879</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Atrial fibrillation (AF) is a common arrhythmia associated with elevated stroke risk, often undiagnosed due to asymptomatic presentation. Advances in technology have enabled AF detection beyond conventional hospital-based tools, expanding opportunities for communitylevel screening. This review summarizes current international guideline recommendations and recent studies evaluating community-based AF screening strategies. Observational studies across diverse global settings have demonstrated the feasibility and yield of screening using tools such as handheld electrocardiogram devices, blood pressure monitors, and smartphone-based technologies, with number-needed-to-screen ranging widely based on 3 population risk profiles. Randomized controlled trials, including STROKESTOP and eBRAVE-AF, suggest potential benefits in stroke reduction and anticoagulant uptake, though definitive consensus is still lacking. The emergence of consumer-led screening using wearable devices (e.g., smartwatches, wristbands) shows promise but raises questions about diagnostic yield and treatment impact in low-risk populations. Cost-effectiveness analyses support screening, especially in older adults, but highlight the need for tailored implementation based on local healthcare systems. Future directions include risk stratification using biomarkers, polygenic risk scores, and artificial intelligence models applied to electrocardiogram or health records to identify high-risk individuals. While enthusiasm for AF screening is growing, critical evidence gaps remain - particularly regarding clinical outcomes and optimal screening strategies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Ngai-Yin</ForeName><Initials>NY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Geriatrics, Princess Margaret Hospital, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Han</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University Hospital, Yilan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medicine, and Cardiovascular Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chao</LastName><ForeName>Tze-Fan</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>eyckeyck@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Kardiol Pol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376352</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-9032</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">device</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">screen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40792681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33963/v.phj.107879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">VM/OJS/J/107879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>