<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40718270</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ankle Arthrodesis Revisited: A Systematic Review of Techniques, Outcomes, and Complications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e86836</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e86836</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e86836</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.86836</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Ankle arthrodesis is a widely accepted treatment for managing end-stage ankle arthritis and various other conditions, including post-traumatic, inflammatory, congenital, and neurogenic deformities. Several surgical techniques&#xa0;for ankle arthrodesis have been developed, such as open ankle fusion, arthroscopic ankle fusion, and mini-open ankle arthrodesis. The purpose of this study was to explore the range of surgical approaches and techniques used in ankle arthrodesis, with particular emphasis on comparing their outcomes in terms of complications, hospital stay duration, pain relief, and functional improvement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">This systematic review was conducted following the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. The review included comparative studies, including randomized controlled trials, non-randomized controlled trials, and observational studies, that assessed patients undergoing ankle arthrodesis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study analyzed various surgical techniques, including the anterior versus transfibular approach, Ilizarov versus internal fixation, and open versus arthroscopic techniques. The results indicated that the visual analogue scale (VAS) scores did not show a statistically significant difference between the anterior and transfibular approaches or between the Ilizarov and internal stability methods. However, the length of hospital stay was statistically significant (p = 0.05) when comparing the arthroscopic technique (mean 2.5 days) to the open technique (mean 3.7 days). The comparison between the Ilizarov and internal stability techniques did not show a significant difference in length of stay. A statistically significant difference in postoperative alignment was observed between the anterior and transfibular approaches, with the transfibular approach resulting in an average valgus alignment of 2.4&#xb0;. Different studies employed various scoring systems to evaluate clinical outcomes, including the American Orthopaedic Foot &amp; Ankle Society Score (AOFAS), ankle osteoarthritis scale (AOS), foot and ankle ability measure (FAAM), and short form (36) (SF-36) scores. No significant differences were found between the techniques, except for the comparison between open and arthroscopic approaches. The arthroscopic technique demonstrated significantly better outcomes in terms of the AOS score (p = 0.05) and the physical component of the SF-36 (p = 0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Further research is necessary in this field, and it is essential for surgeons to reach a consensus on the most effective techniques for ankle arthrodesis, rather than employing a variety of approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Raufi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raufi</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Y</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopaedics, Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, Leeds, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ankle and foot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ankle arthrodesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ankle fusion arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ankle osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthopaedics and traumatology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40718270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12296955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.86836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clinical evaluation of ankle arthrodesis with Ilizarov fixation and internal fixation. Morasiewicz P, Dejnek M, Orzechowski W, et al. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2019;20:167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6460534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30975120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Total ankle replacement versus arthrodesis for end-stage ankle osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Goldberg AJ, Chowdhury K, Bordea E, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2022;175:1648&#x2013;1657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36375147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankle arthrodesis: a comparison of anterior approach and transfibular approach. Kim JG, Ha DJ, Gwak HC, et al. Clin Orthop Surg. 2018;10:368&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6107825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30174814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open ankle arthrodesis: a systematic review of approaches and fixation methods. van den Heuvel SB, Doorgakant A, Birnie MF, Blundell CM, Schepers T. Foot Ankle Surg. 2021;27:339&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. PLoS Med. 2009;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells G.A., Shea B., O&#x2019;Connell D., et al.  Download citation for the Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses. 2021. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/261773681_The_Newcastle-Ottawa_Scale_NOS_for_Assessing_the_Quality_of_Non-Randomized_Studies_in_Meta-Analysis/citation/download https://www.researchgate.net/publication/261773681_The_Newcastle-Ottawa_Scale_NOS_for_Assessing_the_Quality_of_Non-Randomized_Studies_in_Meta-Analysis/citation/download</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthroscopic versus open ankle arthrodesis: a multicenter comparative case series. Townshend D, Di Silvestro M, Krause F, Penner M, Younger A, Glazebrook M, Wing K. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2013;95:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23235956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The demand incidence of symptomatic ankle osteoarthritis presenting to foot and ankle surgeons in the United Kingdom. Goldberg AJ, MacGregor A, Dawson J, Singh D, Cullen N, Sharp RJ, Cooke PH. Foot (Edinb) 2012;22:163&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22436838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compression arthrodesis of the ankle and shoulder. Charnley J. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14832316/ J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1951;33:180&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14832316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical guide: transfibular ankle arthrodesis with fibular-onlay strut graft. Sung W, Greenhagen RM, Hobizal KB, Burns PR, Wukich DK. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2010;49:566&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20801690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthrodesis of the ankle with cancellous-bone screws and fibular strut graft: biomechanical analysis. Thordarson DB, Markolf KL, Cracchiolo A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2229113/ J Bone. 1990;72:1359&#x2013;1363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2229113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>