<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40368575</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1558-3597</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Coll Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Tirzepatide in Type 2 Diabetes: Individual Variation and Relationship to Cardiometabolic&#xa0;Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1858</StartPage><EndPage>1872</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1858-1872</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.03.516</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0735-1097(25)05995-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Tirzepatide-a dual GIP/GLP-1 receptor agonist-exerts pleiotropic effects on cardiometabolic health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The authors sought to investigate the efficacy of tirzepatide in improving different cardiometabolic risk factors across individuals and subpopulations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using an independent, global data-sharing and analytics platform, we performed an individual participant data meta-analysis by pooling data from 7 Phase 3 randomized clinical trials that compared tirzepatide with placebo or standard antihyperglycemic agents in individuals with type 2 diabetes. The study outcomes were the presence of a range of cardiometabolic abnormalities, representing components of metabolic syndrome (MetS) (elevated waist circumference, triglycerides, blood pressure, and fasting blood glucose, and decreased high-density lipoprotein cholesterol), as well as elevated body mass index and MetS (&#x2265;3 cardiometabolic abnormalities). Outcomes were modeled using mixed-effects models, with inverse probability weighting to account for study design differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We included 7,805 participants with a weighted median age of 59 years (Q1-Q3: 51-66 years) and 43.2% women. Over a weighted median treatment duration of 41.0&#xa0;weeks, tirzepatide reduced the odds of all cardiometabolic abnormalities, ranging from 34% reduction for the odds of decreased high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (OR: 0.66 [95%&#xa0;CI: 0.52-0.84]) to 96% reduction in the odds of elevated body mass index (OR: 0.04 [95% CI:0.02-0.08]), and 72% reduction for the odds of MetS (OR: 0.28 [95%&#xa0;CI: 0.24-0.33]). Tirzepatide's superior efficacy in resolving MetS was consistent across demographic and clinical subpopulations, with higher efficacy in&#xa0;age &lt;65 years vs&#xa0;&#x2265;65 years, and in individuals without vs with baseline use of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (P for interaction&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.008 and 0.009, respectively).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This pooled analysis suggests that tirzepatide may improve cardiometabolic abnormalities and resolve MetS in individuals with type 2 diabetes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 American College of Cardiology Foundation. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aminorroaya</LastName><ForeName>Arya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Cardiovascular Data Science (CarDS) Lab, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oikonomou</LastName><ForeName>Evangelos K</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Cardiovascular Data Science (CarDS) Lab, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biswas</LastName><ForeName>Dhruva</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Cardiovascular Data Science (CarDS) Lab, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jastreboff</LastName><ForeName>Ania M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Section of Pediatric Endocrinology, Department of Pediatrics, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Yale Obesity Research Center (Y-Weight) Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khera</LastName><ForeName>Rohan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Cardiovascular Data Science (CarDS) Lab, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE), Yale New Haven Hospital, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Section of Biomedical Informatics and Data Science, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA; Section of Health Informatics, Department of Biostatistics, Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, Connecticut, USA. Electronic address: rohan.khera@yale.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK136623</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK099039</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL167858</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>F32 HL170592</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL153775</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG089981</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK134398</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Coll Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8301365</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0735-1097</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>OYN3CCI6QE</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000098860">Tirzepatide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007004">Hypoglycemic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000098860" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tirzepatide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007004" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypoglycemic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083202" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiometabolic Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus type 2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart disease risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tirzepatide</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures The authors acknowledge funding through the National Institutes of Health (NIH) under awards F32HL170592 (to Dr Oikonomou), R01DK099039, R01DK136623, R01DK134398 (to Dr Jastreboff), R01AG089981, R01HL167858, and K23HL153775 (to Dr Khera) and the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation under award 2022060 (to Dr Khera). The funders had no role in the design and conduct of the study; collection, management, analysis, and interpretation of the data; preparation, review, or approval of the manuscript; and decision to submit the manuscript for publication. Dr Oikonomou receives support from the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute of the National Institutes of Health (under award F32HL170592); is named as a coinventor in patent applications (18/813,882, 17/720,068, 63/508,315, 63/580,137, 63/619,241, 63/562,335) and granted patents (US12067714B2, US11948230B2); has been a consultant for Caristo Diagnostics Ltd and Ensight-AI, Inc; and has received royalty fees from technology licensed through the University of Oxford, outside this work. Drs Oikonomou and Khera are cofounders of Evidence2Health, a precision health platform to improve evidence-based cardiovascular care. Dr Jastreboff conducts multicenter trials with Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Novo Nordisk, and Rhythm Pharmaceuticals; and serves on scientific advisory boards for Amgen, AstraZeneca, Biohaven, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Intellihealth, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Scholar Rock, Structure Therapeutics, Terns Pharmaceuticals, WeightWatchers, and Zealand Pharma. Dr Khera is an Associate Editor of JAMA; receives research support through Yale from Bristol Myers Squibb, Novo Nordisk, BridgeBio, and the Blavatnik Family Foundation; is a coinventor of&#xa0;U.S. Provisional Patent Applications WO2023230345A1, US20220336048A1, 63/346,610, 63/484,426, 63/508,315, 63/580,137, 63/606,203, 63/619,241, 63/562,335, and 18/813,882, all unrelated to the current work; and is an academic cofounder of Ensight-AI, Inc, an AI-ECG analytics company. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40368575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2088733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12186526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.03.516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0735-1097(25)05995-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bain SC, Min T. A new class of glucose-lowering therapy for type 2 diabetes: the latest development in the incretin arena. Lancet. 2023;402:504&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37385276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nauck MA, Meier JJ. The incretin effect in healthy individuals and those with type 2 diabetes: physiology, pathophysiology, and response to therapeutic interventions. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2016;4:525&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26876794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldrop G, Zhong J, Peters M, Rajagopalan S. Incretin-based therapy for diabetes: What a cardiologist needs to know. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2016;67:1488&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4861061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27012410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggio LL, Drucker DJ. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor co-agonists for treating metabolic disease. Mol Metab. 2021;46:101090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8085566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32987188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xed;as JP, Davies MJ, Rosenstock J, et al. Tirzepatide versus semaglutide once weekly in patients with type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:503&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34170647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludvik B, Giorgino F, J&#xf3;dar E, et al. Once-weekly tirzepatide versus once-daily insulin degludec as add-on to metformin with or without SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with type 2 diabetes (SURPASS-3): a randomised, open-label, parallel-group, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;398:583&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34370970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Prato S, Kahn SE, Pavo I, et al. Tirzepatide versus insulin glargine in type 2 diabetes and increased cardiovascular risk (SURPASS-4): a randomised, open-label, parallel-group, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;398:1811&#x2013;1824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahl D, Onishi Y, Norwood P, et al. Effect of subcutaneous tirzepatide vs placebo added to titrated insulin glargine on glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes: The SURPASS-5 randomized clinical trial: The SURPASS-5 randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2022;327:534&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35133415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inagaki N, Takeuchi M, Oura T, Imaoka T, Seino Y. Efficacy and safety of tirzepatide monotherapy compared with dulaglutide in Japanese patients with type 2 diabetes (SURPASS J-mono): a double-blind, multicentre, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10:623&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao L, Lee BW, Chawla M, et al. Tirzepatide versus insulin glargine as second-line or third-line therapy in type 2 diabetes in the Asia-Pacific region: the SURPASS-AP-Combo trial. Nat Med. 2023;29:1500&#x2013;1510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37231074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock J, Wysham C, Fr&#xed;as JP, et al. Efficacy and safety of a novel dual GIP and GLP-1 receptor agonist tirzepatide in patients with type 2 diabetes (SURPASS-1): a double-blind, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;398:143&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34186022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas MK, Nikooienejad A, Bray R, et al. Dual GIP and GLP-1 receptor agonist tirzepatide improves beta-cell function and insulin sensitivity in type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106:388&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7823251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33236115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown K, Lando LF, Bergman B, Thomas MK, Liu B, Lee C. 337-OR: Tirzepatide improved markers of islet-cell function (fasting glucagon and HOMA2-B) and insulin sensitivity (fasting insulin and HOMA2-IR) compared with semaglutide in people with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2022;71:337&#x2013;OR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heise T, Mari A, DeVries JH, et al. Effects of subcutaneous tirzepatide versus placebo or semaglutide on pancreatic islet function and insulin sensitivity in adults with type 2 diabetes: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, parallel-arm, phase 1 clinical trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10:418&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35468322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock J, V&#xe1;zquez L, Del Prato S, et al. Achieving normoglycemia with tirzepatide: Analysis of SURPASS 1&#x2013;4 trials. Diabetes Care. 2023;46:1986&#x2013;1992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37673061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xed;as JP, Galindo RJ, Wang H, Malik RE, Chivukula KK, Maldonado JM. Tirzepatide in Hispanic/Latino patients with type 2 diabetes: A subgroup analysis of the SURPASS program. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2024;109:557&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37602701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadowaki T, Chin R, Ozeki A, Imaoka T, Ogawa Y. Safety and efficacy of tirzepatide as an add-on to single oral antihyperglycaemic medication in patients with type 2 diabetes in Japan (SURPASS J-combo): a multicentre, randomised, open-label, parallel-group, phase 3 trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10:634&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart LA, Clarke M, Rovers M, et al. Preferred reporting items for a systematic review and meta-analysis of individual participant data: The PRISMA-IPD statement. JAMA. 2015;313:1657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25919529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti KGMM Eckel RH, Grundy SM, et al. Harmonizing the metabolic syndrome: A joint interim statement of the International Diabetes Federation task force on epidemiology and prevention; National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; American Heart Association; World heart federation; International atherosclerosis society; And international association for the study of obesity. Circulation. 2009;120:1640&#x2013;1645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundy SM, Cleeman JI, Daniels SR, et al. Diagnosis and management of the metabolic syndrome. Circulation. 2005;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16157765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khera R, Aminorroaya A, Dhingra LS, et al. Comparative effectiveness of second-line antihyperglycemic agents for cardiovascular outcomes. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024;84:904&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12045554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39197980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agresti A. Categorical data analysis, second edition. 2nd ed. Nashville, TN: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler J, McKenzie J, Boutron I, Welch V eds. Cochrane Methods 2016. Wiley, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10:ED000142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastreboff AM, Aronne LJ, Ahmad NN, et al. Tirzepatide once weekly for the treatment of obesity. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:205&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35658024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart LA, Tierney JF. To IPD or not to IPD? Advantages and disadvantages of systematic reviews using individual patient data. Eval Health Prof. 2002;25:76&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11868447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EUROASPIRE II Study Group. Lifestyle and risk factor management and use of drug therapies in coronary patients from 15 countries; principal results from EUROASPIRE II Euro Heart Survey Programme. Eur Heart J. 2001;22:554&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11259143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Bacquer D, Astin F, Kotseva K, et al. Poor adherence to lifestyle recommendations in patients with coronary heart disease: results from the EUROASPIRE surveys. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2022;29:383&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34293121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Wadden TA. Mechanisms, pathophysiology, and management of obesity. N Engl J Med. 2017;376:254&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28099824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadden TA, Tronieri JS, Butryn ML. Lifestyle modification approaches for the treatment of obesity in adults. Am Psychol. 2020;75:235&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32052997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Bhatta M, Davies M, et al. Semaglutide improves cardiometabolic risk factors in adults with overweight or obesity: STEP 1 and 4 exploratory analyses. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2023;25:468&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10092593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36200477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S, Bansal S, Aggarwal G. Effects of semaglutide on metabolic syndrome parameters in non-diabetics: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Metabolism. 2023;142:155462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mody R, Desai K, Teng C-C, et al. Characteristics and dosing patterns of tirzepatide users with type 2 diabetes in the United States. Diabetes Ther. 2025. Published onlineJanuary 10, 2025. 10.1007/s13300-024-01684-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13300-024-01684-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11794899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39794609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>