<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40894014</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2693-5015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research square</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Sq</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating a Comprehensive Multimodal Outpatient Rehabilitation Program to Improve the Functioning of Persons Suffering from Post-acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC): A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">rs.3.rs-7375832</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21203/rs.3.rs-7375832/v1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">About 10-20% of persons who contract SARS CoV-2 will experience persistent post-acute sequelae of SARSCoV-2 infection (referred here as PASC). Given that persistent symptoms are heterogeneous with multisystem involvement, recent consensus recommendations suggest that a holistic rehabilitation program may be required to manage PASC and restore function. While treatments offered at emerging outpatient COVID recovery clinics are being informed by previous similar diseases, the need is great for a better understanding of the unique needs of this growing population and for tested, efficacious rehabilitation programs to address them.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS/DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Data from a large and diverse ongoing longitudinal survey of persons positive for COVID-19 at the study health system will serve as the sampling frame from which to enroll PASC study patients. The targeted six-week program will comprise a core set of therapies including individually titrated isometrics, strengthening of accessory breathing muscles and diaphragm, resistance and aerobic conditioning, and neuropsychological and cognitive remediation tailored to patients' needs. Using a randomized controlled trial design, the effectiveness of the supervised multimodal rehabilitation intervention will be compared to that of a self-guided (active control) group receiving patient education materials adapted from the World Health Organization guidelines for PASC management. In addition to walking speed, a widely used global measure of aerobic capacity and endurance, and patient-reported health and functioning (primary outcomes), we will assess intervention effectiveness on: cognitive functioning, pain, fatigue, tension, stress, anxiety, and depression, and self-management of PASC symptoms (secondary outcomes). Outcomes will be measured at 8 weeks and at 90 day's post- study entry to examine sustainability of effects. Recruitment is ongoing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">It is unlikely that COVID-19 vaccines will lead to the end of PASC syndrome given the emergence of increasingly infectious variants and the high numbers of individuals with continued symptoms several months from initial infection. High rates of vaccine hesitancy and refusal will also contribute to the persistence of both COVID-19 and PASC. Given the dearth of rigorous scientific evidence regarding effective assessment and treatment of PASC and unresolved questions concerning post-COVID rehabilitation care, the results of this study will have significant implications for both policy and program development.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ClinicalTrials.gov ID: NCT06156202.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abramoff</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dillingham</LastName><ForeName>Timothy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rybicki</LastName><ForeName>Ava-Kathleen</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shofer</LastName><ForeName>Frances</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGinley</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Equity, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee WI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verma</LastName><ForeName>Shefali S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuns</LastName><ForeName>Monica Coran</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Good Shepherd Penn Partners, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barry</LastName><ForeName>John T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Good Shepherd Penn Partners, Philadelphia PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pezzin</LastName><ForeName>Liliana E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Equity, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee WI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06156202</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD108312</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Res Sq</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101768035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2693-5015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comparative effectiveness research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-acute sequela</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40894014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12393596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-7375832/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">rs.3.rs-7375832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A, Bernabei R, Landi F; Gemelli Against COVID-19 Post-Acute Care Study Group. Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. JAMA. 2020. Aug 11;324(6):603&#x2013;605. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.12603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.12603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin SJ, McIvor C, Whyatt G, et al. Postdischarge symptoms and rehabilitation needs in survivors of COVID-19 infection: A cross-sectional evaluation. J Med Virol. 2021;93(2):1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goertz YMJ, Van Herck M, Delbressine JM, et al. Persistent symptoms 3 months after a SARS-CoV-2 infection: the post-COVID-19 syndrome? ERJ Open Res. 2020;6(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera-Izquierdo M, L&#xe1;inez-Ramos-Bossini AJ, de Alba IG, Ortiz-Gonz&#xe1;lez-Serna R, Serrano-Ortiz &#xc1;, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez NF, Ruiz-Montero R, Cervilla JA. Long COVID 12 months after discharge: persistent symptoms in patients hospitalised due to COVID-19 and patients hospitalised due to other causes-a multicentre cohort study. BMC Med. 2022. Feb 23;20(1):92. doi: 10.1186/s12916-022-02292-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-022-02292-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8863509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35193574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra V, Flanders SA, O&#x2019;Malley M, Malani AN, Prescott HC. Sixty-Day Outcomes Among Patients Hospitalized With COVID-19. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(4):576&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7707210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33175566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenforde MW, Kim SS, Lindsell CJ, et al. Symptom Duration and Risk Factors for Delayed Return to Usual Health Among Outpatients with COVID-19 in a Multistate Health Care Systems Network - United States, March-June 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020;69(30):993&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavem K, Ghanima W, Olsen MK, Gilboe HM, Einvik G. Persistent symptoms 1.5&#x2013;6 months after COVID-19 in non-hospitalised subjects: a population-based cohort study. Thorax. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen M, Manoharan L, Elkheir N, et al. Characterising long-term covid-19: a rapid living systematic review. medRxiv : the preprint server for health sciences. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslo C, Friedland R, Toubkin M, Laubscher A, Akaloo T, Kama B. Characteristics and Outcomes of Hospitalized Patients in South Africa During the COVID-19 Omicron Wave Compared With Previous Waves. JAMA. 2022. Feb 8;327(6):583&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1001/jama.2021.24868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.24868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34967859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. The prevalence of long COVID symptoms and COVID-19 complications - Office for National Statistics. Published 2020. Accessed May 5, 2021. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Disease Long COVID Collaborators. Estimated Global Proportions of Individuals With Persistent Fatigue, Cognitive, and Respiratory Symptom Clusters Following Symptomatic COVID-19 in 2020 and 2021. JAMA. 2022;328(16):1604&#x2013;1615. doi: 10.1001/jama.2022.18931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.18931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36215063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JK, Franko NM, McCulloch DJ, et al. Sequelae in Adults at 6 Months After COVID-19 Infection. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(2):e210830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33606031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havervall S, Rosell A, Phillipson M, et al. Symptoms and Functional Impairment Assessed 8 Months After Mild COVID-19 Among Health Care Workers. JAMA. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33825846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai M., Xie Y., Topol E.J. et al. Three-year outcomes of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nat Med 30, 1564&#x2013;1573 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11186764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong AW, Shah AS, Johnston JC, Carlsten C, Ryerson CJ. Patient-reported outcome measures after COVID-19: a prospective cohort study. Eur Respir J. 2020;56(5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amenta EM, Spallone A, Rodriguez-Barradas MC, El Sahly HM, Atmar RL, Kulkarni PA. Postacute COVID19: An Overview and Approach to Classification. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7(12):ofaa509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YM, Shang YM, Song WB, et al. Follow-up study of the pulmonary function and related physiological characteristics of COVID-19 survivors three months after recovery. EClinicalMedicine. 2020;25:100463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabir MF, Nyein Yin K, Jeffree MS et al. A comprehensive systematic scoping review for physiotherapy interventions for people living with long COVID. F1000Research 2023, 12:368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopp S, Moik F, Klok FA, Gattinger D, Petrovic M, Vonbank K, Koczulla AR, Ay C, Zwick RH. Outpatient Pulmonary Rehabilitation in Patients with Long COVID Improves Exercise Capacity, Functional Status, Dyspnea, Fatigue, and Quality of Life. Respiration. 2022;101(6):593&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1159/000522118. Epub 2022 Feb 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000522118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9059007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compagno S, Palermi S, Pescatore V, Brugin E, Sarto M, Marin R, Calzavara V, Nizzetto M, Scevola M, Aloi A, Biffi A, Zanella C, Carretta G, Gallo S, Giada F. Physical and psychological reconditioning in long COVID syndrome: Results of an out-of-hospital exercise and psychological - based rehabilitation program. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2022. Jul 16;41:101080. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcha.2022.101080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcha.2022.101080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9286763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35854691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasenoehrl T, Palma S, Huber DF, Kastl S, Steiner M, Jordakieva G, Crevenna R. Post-COVID: effects of physical exercise on functional status and work ability in health care personnel. Disabil Rehabil. 2023. Sep;45(18):2872&#x2013;2878. doi: 10.1080/09638288.2022.2111467. Epub 2022 Aug 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2022.2111467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35980383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia-Ying L, Chia-Huei L, Ta-Chung C, Chueh-Ho L, Cheng-Chiang C, Chien-Yao H, Shang-Lin C. Effectiveness of a 12-week telerehabilitation training in people with long COVID: A randomized controlled trial, Annals of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine, 67(5), 2024. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S187706572400037X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38824899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalas M, Katsaras S, Spetsioti S, Spaggoulakis D, Antonoglou A, Asimakos A, Katsaounou P, Christakou A. The Effect of Physiotherapy on Dyspnea, Muscle Strength and Functional Status in Patients with Long COVID Syndrome. Journal of Personalized Medicine. 2024; 14(5):515. 10.3390/jpm14050515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm14050515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11121916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38793097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimeno-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Franco-L&#xf3;pez F, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, S&#xe1;nchez-Agar JA, S&#xe1;nchez-Alcaraz Mart&#xed;nez BJ, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Rehabilitation for post-COVID-19 condition through a supervised exercise intervention: A randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022. Dec;32(12):1791&#x2013;1801. doi: 10.1111/sms.14240. Epub 2022 Sep 23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouliopoulou DV, Macdermid JC, Saunders E, et al. Rehabilitation Interventions for Physical Capacity and Quality of Life in Adults With Post&#x2013;COVID-19 Condition: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(9):e2333838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10509723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arienti C, Lazzarini SG, Andrenelli E, Cordani C, Negrini F, Pollini E, Ceravolo MG; International Multiprofessional Steering Committee of Cochrane Rehabilitation REH-COVER Action. Rehabilitation and COVID-19: systematic review by Cochrane Rehabilitation. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2023. Dec;59(6):800&#x2013;818. doi: 10.23736/S1973-9087.23.08331-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.23.08331-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10792873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38214047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouliopoulou DV, Macdermid JC, Saunders E, et al. Rehabilitation Interventions for Physical Capacity and Quality of Life in Adults With Post&#x2013;COVID-19 Condition: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(9):e2333838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10509723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Support for Rehabilitation: Self-Management After COVID-19-Related Illness, Second Edition. https://www.who.int/europe/publications/i/item/WHO-EURO-2021-855-40590-59892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maley JH, Sampsel S, Abramoff BA, Herman E, Neerukonda KV, Mikkelsen ME. Consensus methodology for the development of postacute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 guidance statements. PM&amp;R. 2021; 13(9): 1021&#x2013; 1026. 10.1002/pmrj.12670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34240583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine Jeffrey S., Anne Felicia Ambrose Nyaz Didehbani, Fleming Talya K., Glashan Lissette, Longo Michele, Merlino Alexandra, Ng Rowena, Nora Gerald J., Rolin Summer, Silver Julie K., Terzic Carmen M., Monica Verduzco-Gutierrez Sarah Sampsel, Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of cognitive symptoms in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC), PM&amp;R, 10.1002/pmrj.12745, 14, 1, (96&#x2013;111), (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maley Jason H., Alba George A., Barry John T., Bartels Matthew N., Fleming Talya K., Oleson Christina V., Rydberg Leslie, Sampsel Sarah, Silver Julie K., Sipes Sabrina, Verduzco-Gutierrez Monica, Wood Jamie, Zibrak Joseph D., Whiteson Jonathan, Multi-disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of breathing discomfort and respiratory sequelae in patients with post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC), PM&amp;R, 10.1002/pmrj.12744, 14, 1, (77&#x2013;95), (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera Joseph E., Niehaus William N., Whiteson Jonathan, Azola Alba, Baratta John M., Fleming Talya K., Kim Soo Yeon, Naqvi Huma, Sampsel Sarah, Silver Julie K., Verduzco-Gutierrez Monica, Maley Jason H., Herman Eric, Abramoff Benjamin, Response to letter to the editor regarding &#x201c;Multi-Disciplinary collaborative consensus guidance statement on the assessment and treatment of fatigue in patients with Post-Acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC)&#x201d;, PM&amp;R, 10.1002/pmrj.12719, 13, 12, (1439&#x2013;1440), (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8662053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34617402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (U.S.). Perceived Exertion (Borg Rating of Perceived Exertion Scale) (https://www.cdc.gov/physicalactivity/basics/measuring/exertion.htm). Accessed 11/1/2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Support for Rehabilitation: Self-Management After COVID-19-Related Illness, Second Edition. (online)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation Measures: 6 Minute Walk Test. Chicago, IL, Shirley Ryan AbilityLab, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen ME, Still M, Anderson BJ, Bienvenu OJ, Brodsky MB, Brummel N, Butcher B, Clay AS, Felt H, Ferrante LE, Haines KJ, Harhay MO, Hope AA, Hopkins RO, Hosey M, Hough CTL, Jackson JC, Johnson A, Khan B, Lone NI, MacTavish P, McPeake J, Montgomery-Yates A, Needham DM, Netzer G, Schorr C, Skidmore B, Stollings JL, Umberger R, Andrews A, Iwashyna TJ, Sevin CM. Society of Critical Care Medicine&#x2019;s International Consensus Conference on Prediction and Identification of Long-Term Impairments After Critical Illness. Crit Care Med. 2020. Nov;48(11):1670&#x2013;1679. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000004586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000004586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32947467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE Jr, Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36). I. Conceptual framework and item selection. Med Care. 1992. Jun;30(6):473&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Crouch RH. Two-Minute Step Test of Exercise Capacity: Systematic Review of Procedures, Performance, and Clinimetric Properties. J Phys Ther. 2019. Apr/Jun;42(2):105&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1519/JPT.0000000000000164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29210933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Physical Therapy Association. The 5x sit-to-stand test.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson D.C., 2022. Pulmonary Function Testing and Reporting in the COVID-19 Era. Respiratory Therapy, 17(1), p. 49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shashikala K.T. and Jaiswal S., 2022. Assessment of pulmonary functions FVC, FEV1, and FEV1/FVC ratio among athletes and non-athletes. National Journal of Physiology, Pharmacy and Pharmacology, 12(9), pp. 1335&#x2013;1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudino EA, Geisler MW, Squires NK. Construct validity in the Trail Making Test: what makes Part B harder?. Journal of clinical and experimental neuropsychology. 1995. Aug 1;17(4):529&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7593473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdodi LA, Sagar S, Seke K, Zuccato BG, Schwartz ES, Roth RM. The Stroop test as a measure of performance validity in adults clinically referred for neuropsychological assessment. Psychological assessment. 2018. Jun;30(6):755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haefeli M, Elfering A. Pain assessment. Eur Spine J. 2006. Jan;15 Suppl 1(Suppl 1):S17&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1007/s00586-005-1044-x. Epub 2005 Dec 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00586-005-1044-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3454549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16320034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MJ, Close L, Gillon SC, Molassiotis A, Lee PH, Farquhar MC. Use of the modified Borg scale and numerical rating scale to measure chronic breathlessness: a pooled data analysis. European Respiratory Journal. 2016;47(6):1861&#x2013;1864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26989107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas S, Simoes MR, Maroco J, Alves L, Santana I. Construct Validity of the Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA). J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2012;18(2):242&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22115097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, Bedirian V, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53(4):695&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyer AK, Leach L, Vandermorris S, Rich JB. The measurement of participant-reported memory across diverse populations and settings: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the Multifactorial Memory Questionnaire. Memory. 2019. Aug 9;27(7):931&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983;67(6):361&#x2013;370. 96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6880820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason L.A., Holtzman C.S., Sunnquist M. and Cotler J., 2021. The development of an instrument to assess post-exertional malaise in patients with myalgic encephalomyelitis and chronic fatigue syndrome. Journal of health psychology, 26(2), pp. 238&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7988339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30354489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vries J., Michielsen H., Van Heck G.L. and Drent M., 2004. Measuring fatigue in sarcoidosis: the Fatigue Assessment Scale (FAS). British journal of health psychology, 9(3), pp. 279&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15296678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes S. E., Haroon S., Subramanian A., McMullan C., Aiyegbusi O. L., Turner G. M., Jackson L., Davies E. H., Frost C., McNamara G., Price G., Matthews K., Camaradou J., Ormerod J., Walker A., &amp; Calvert M. J. (2022). Development and validation of the Symptom Burden Questionnaire for Long Covid: A Rasch analysis. MedRxiv, 2022.01.16.22269146. 10.1101/2022.01.16.22269146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.01.16.22269146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9043395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>System P-ROMI. Self-Efficacy for Managing Chronic Conditions: A Brief Guide to the PROMIS Self Efficacy Instruments. 2105.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>