<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40954388</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-187X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of cardiovascular drugs : drugs, devices, and other interventions</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Cardiovasc Drugs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Nicotinamide Adenine Dinucleotide on Heart Failure Caused by Ischemic Cardiomyopathy: A Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40256-025-00764-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (NAD+) is a fundamental coenzyme that plays a crucial role in cellular energy metabolism and redox homeostasis. A deficiency in NAD+ has been associated with heart failure (HF), which often occurs in the advanced stages of cardiovascular diseases. While numerous studies have indicated that NAD+ supplementation may enhance cardiac bioenergetics and function in animal models, there is limited research investigating this potential effect in human patients. Therefore, this study aims to evaluate whether NAD+ treatment can lead to improved clinical outcomes for patients with HF due to ischemic cardiomyopathy (ICM).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This single-center, prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled trial enrolled 180 adults diagnosed with ICM whose left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) was &#x2264;&#xa0;45% and whose New York Heart Association (NYHA) grade was II-III. Participants were randomly assigned to receive either intravenous NAD&#x207a; (10 mg/day) or an equivalent placebo (5% glucose/normal saline) for a duration of 7 days, alongside guideline-directed medical therapy. The primary endpoint was the Change in LVEF at 1 month. Secondary endpoints included changes in N-terminal pro B-type natriuretic peptide (NT-proBNP) at 7 and 30 days; a composite of major adverse cardiac and cerebrovascular events (MACCE), which encompassed cardiac death, non-fatal myocardial infarction, stroke, and the first unplanned HF hospitalization within 6 months; and improvements in NYHA functional class.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At 1 month, the NAD+ group demonstrated a significantly greater improvement in LVEF compared to the placebo group (45.44 &#xb1; 8.55% vs. 42.44 &#xb1; 9.09%, p = 0.024). A trend towards decreased NT-proBNP levels was observed in the NAD+ group at day 7 (1471.00 [828.00-2950.00]pg/mL vs. 2317.50 [1155.00-4752.50]pg/mL, p = 0.102). The 6-month composite MACCE rate appeared lower among those receiving NAD+ treatment compared to the placebo group (14.6% vs. 24.7%, p = 0.089), primarily driven by a trend toward fewer first unplanned HF hospitalizations (13.5% vs. 23.6%, p = 0.078). Additionally, a greater proportion of patients in the NAD+ group demonstrated improvement in NYHA functional class at both 1 month (73.0% vs. 57.3%, p = 0.088) and 6 months (53.9% vs. 39.3%, p = 0.115). No significant differences were observed in structural parameters (left ventricular end-diastolic diameter, left ventricular end-diastolic volume, left atrial diameter).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study has confirmed that supplementation with NAD+ can enhance cardiac function in patients with from HF due to ICM, thereby affirming its beneficial impact on cardiac performance. Trends indicating reductions in NT-proBNP levels and composite clinical events (particularly HF hospitalization) and improvements in NYHA functional class were noted, suggesting potential broader clinical benefits. These findings advocate for NAD+ repletion as a promising therapeutic strategy that warrants further validation through more extensive multicenter trials focused on clinical endpoints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry identifier number ChiCTR2200059169.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaofan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5111-4257</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Jiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Qizhi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hongwu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Dongbiao</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Xunxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Kaibing</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Likun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, China. lkma@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Centre for Leading Medicine and Advanced Technologies of IHM, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, 230001, Anhui, China. lkma@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022-CCA-HX-077</GrantID><Agency>China Heart House-Chinese Cardiovascular Association HX fund</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Cardiovasc Drugs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967755</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1175-3277</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Xiaofan Yu, Jie Xu, Jiaoyu Cao, Qizhi Xu, Hongwu Chen, Dongbiao Yu, Xunxia Yao, Kaibing Chen, and Likun Ma declare that they have no potential conflicts of interest that might be relevant to the contents of this manuscript. Data Availability: The datasets used during the current study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request. Further inquiries can be directed to the corresponding authors. Author Contributions: X Yu and LM conceived and designed the study. HC, DY, QX, JX, X Yao, KC, and JC were involved in data collection, interpretation, and analysis. JX, X Yao, and JC were involved in telephone follow-up. X Yu wrote the manuscript. LM was involved in the editing of the manuscript. Ethics Statement: The Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of USTC approved this study (no. 2022KY053). Consent to Participate: All the participants provided written informed consent to participate in this study. Consent for Publication: All the authors agree to publish the article. Code Availability: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40954388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40256-025-00764-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40256-025-00764-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gheorghiade M, Sopko G, De Luca L, et al. Navigating the crossroads of coronary artery disease and heart failure. Circulation. 2006;114(11):1202&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.623199 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.623199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16966596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragazzi NL, Zhong W, Shu J, et al. Burden of heart failure and underlying causes in 195 countries and territories from 1990 to 2017. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2021;28(15):1682&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurjpc/zwaa147 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurjpc/zwaa147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Buono MG, Moroni F, Montone RA, et al. Ischemic cardiomyopathy and heart failure after acute myocardial infarction. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2022;24(10):1505&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11886-022-01766-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11886-022-01766-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35972638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9556362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felker GM, Shaw LK, O&#x2019;Connor CM. A standardized definition of ischemic cardiomyopathy for use in clinical research. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2002;39(2):210&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0735-1097(01)01738-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0735-1097(01)01738-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11788209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellermann JP, Jacobsen SJ, Redfield MM, et al. Heart failure after myocardial infarction: clinical presentation and survival. Eur J Heart Fail. 2005;7(1):119&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejheart.2004.04.011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejheart.2004.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suleiman M, Khatib R, Agmon Y, et al. Early inflammation and risk of long-term development of heart failure and mortality in survivors of acute myocardial infarction predictive role of c-reactive protein. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;47(5):962&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2005.10.055 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2005.10.055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16516078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popa IP, Haba MSC, Maranduca MA, et al. Modern approaches for the treatment of heart failure: recent advances and future perspectives. Pharmaceutics. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics14091964 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics14091964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9866384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Li Y, Chai K, et al. Mortality in patients admitted to hospital with heart failure in china: a nationwide cardiovascular association database-heart failure centre registry cohort study. Lancet Glob Health. 2024;12(4):e611&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2214-109X(23)00605-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(23)00605-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38485428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang X, Liu J, Wang Y, Guan X, Liu R. Mitochondrial disorder and treatment of ischemic cardiomyopathy: potential and advantages of Chinese herbal medicine. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;159:114171. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2022.114171 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2022.114171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taegtmeyer H. Cardiac metabolism as a target for the treatment of heart failure. Circulation. 2004;110(8):894&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.CIR.0000139340.88769.D5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000139340.88769.D5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15326079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kane AE, Sinclair DA. Sirtuins and NAD(+) in the development and treatment of metabolic and cardiovascular diseases. Circ Res. 2018;123(7):868&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.118.312498 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.118.312498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6206880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YJ, Paneni F, Stein S, Matter CM. Modulating sirtuin biology and nicotinamide adenine diphosphate metabolism in cardiovascular disease-from bench to bedside. Front Physiol. 2021;12:755060. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.755060 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.755060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34712151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8546231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdellatif M, Sedej S, Kroemer G. NAD(+) metabolism in cardiac health, aging, and disease. Circulation. 2021;144(22):1795&#x2013;817. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.056589 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.056589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34843394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu F, Zhao H, Luo L, Wu W. Nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide supplementation to alleviate heart failure: a mitochondrial dysfunction perspective. Nutrients. 2025;17(11):1855. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu17111855 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17111855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40507126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12157744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker MA, Tian R. NAD metabolism and heart failure: mechanisms and therapeutic potentials. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2024;195:45&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yjmcc.2024.07.008 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yjmcc.2024.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39096536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei Z, Yang C, Guo Y, Dong M, Wang F. The role of NAD+ in myocardial ischemia-induced heart failure in sprague-dawley rats and beagles. Curr Pharm Biotechnol. 2024. https://doi.org/10.2174/0113892010275059240103054554 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0113892010275059240103054554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39411959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong D, Schiattarella GG, Jiang N, et al. NAD(+) repletion reverses heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Circ Res. 2021;128(11):1629&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.120.317046 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.120.317046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8159891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang DD, Airhart SE, Zhou B, et al. Safety and tolerability of nicotinamide riboside in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2022;7(12):1183&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacbts.2022.06.012 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacbts.2022.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36644285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9831861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdellatif M, Trummer-Herbst V, Koser F, et al. Nicotinamide for the treatment of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Sci Transl Med. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.abd7064 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.abd7064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33568522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7611499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart Failure Group of Chinese Society of Cardiology, Chinese Medical Doctor Association Heart Failure Committee, Editorial Board of Chinese Journal of Cardiology. 2018 Chinese guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of heart failure. Chin J Cardiol. 2018;46(10):760-89. https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.issn.0253-3758.2018.10.004 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese College of Cardiovascular Physicians, China Cardiovascular Association, Expert Task Force on Post-Myocardial Infarction Heart Failure. 2020 Chinese expert consensus on the management of heart failure after myocardial infarction. Chin Circ J. 2020;35(12):1166-80. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1000-3614.2020.12.002 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac Electrophysiology and Function Branch of Chinese Geriatrics Society, Cardiovascular Physicians Branch of Chinese Medical Doctor Association, China Heart Failure Center Alliance Committee. 2022 Chinese expert consensus on comprehensive management of worsening chronic heart failure. Chin Circ J. 2022;37(3):215-25. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1000-3614.2022.03.003 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Wei L. Efficacy of coenzyme I for injection in elderly patients with coronary heart disease complicated by chronic heart failure. World Latest Med Inf. 2021;21(48):155&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1671-3141.2021.48.071 . (158).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1671-3141.2021.48.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang FF, Wang X, Zhang ML, Shi M, Mei Y. Clinical effects of coenzyme I in the treatment of chronic heart failure. J Clin Rational Drug Use. 2022. https://doi.org/10.15887/j.cnki.13-1389/r.2022.16.014 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15887/j.cnki.13-1389/r.2022.16.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei Z, Dong M, Meng X, et al. Effects of nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide on older patients with heart failure. Rev Cardiovasc Med. 2024. https://doi.org/10.31083/j.rcm2508297 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.rcm2508297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39484112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11522756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell C, Rahko PS, Blauwet LA, et al. Guidelines for performing a comprehensive transthoracic echocardiographic examination in adults: recommendations from the American Society of Echocardiography. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2019;32(1):1&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.echo.2018.06.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.echo.2018.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30282592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauritzen KH, Olsen MB, Ahmed MS, et al. Instability in NAD+ metabolism leads to impaired cardiac mitochondrial function and communication. Elife. 2021. https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.59828 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/elife.59828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8331182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deloux R, Tannous C, Diguet N, Li Z, Mericskay M. Alternative NAD+ biosynthesis pathway activated by energy stress stimulates glycolysis in cardiac cells. Arch Cardiovasc Dis Suppl. 2018;10(2):229. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.acvdsp.2018.02.115 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acvdsp.2018.02.115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouve C, Ruiz-Velasco A, Karoui A, et al. Cardiomyocytes-derived from NAMPT deficient human induced pluripotent stem cells exhibit reduced NAD pools and contractility dysfunction. Arch Cardiovasc Dis. 2024;117(6, Supplement):S211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acvd.2024.05.104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan NA, Auranen M, Paetau I, et al. Effective treatment of mitochondrial myopathy by nicotinamide riboside, a vitamin b3. EMBO Mol Med. 2014;6(6):721&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1002/emmm.201403943 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/emmm.201403943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24711540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4203351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>China Heart Failure Center Alliance Expert Committee. Chinese expert consensus on the clinical application of SGLT2 inhibitors for heart failure. J Clin Cardiol. 2022;38(8):599&#x2013;605. https://doi.org/10.13201/j.issn.1001-1439.2022.08.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13201/j.issn.1001-1439.2022.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>