<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41026176</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1912</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's archives of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy Of Combined Nutritional And Pharmacological Interventions In PCOS: A Six Month Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00210-025-04626-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Polycystic ovary syndrome is a complex heterogenous reproductive endocrine disorder affecting mainly reproductive age women worldwide. The syndrome primarily is associated with hyperandrogenism, hyperinsulinemia, menstrual irregularity, infertility, hormonal dysregulation and obesity. Here, we examined the effects of Acetyl-L-Carnitine, L-Arginine, CoQ10, (Carnitine&#x2009;+&#x2009;Arginine&#x2009;+&#x2009;CoQ10) and Metformin, alone and in combination, on PCOS management. The trial included 63 females diagnosed with PCOS. The participants were treated with either Carnitine&#x2009;+&#x2009;Arginine&#x2009;+&#x2009;CoQ10 alone (nutraceutical group) or in combination with metformin (combination group) for six months. The outcome measures included demographic, anthropometric, clinical, endocrine, metabolic, quality of Life and stress response of the participants. Over 24&#xa0;weeks, both treatment regimens improved metabolic, hormonal, and psychological outcomes in women with PCOS. Repeated-measures ANCOVA showed significant group&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;time interactions for BMI (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.220), waist circumference (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.314), and hip circumference (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.428), favoring the combination group. Hormonal responses varied: DHEAS (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.045, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.082), FAI (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.223), testosterone (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.004, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.113), and prolactin (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.032, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.072) declined more in the combination group, whereas LH decreased more in the nutraceutical group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.231). Quality of life improved significantly in both arms, with greater gains in the combination group (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.037, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.071). Oxidative stress (MDA) also declined significantly in both groups (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.003), with larger numerical reductions in the combination arm (-&#x2009;22% vs&#x2009;-&#x2009;6%), though between-group differences were not significant (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.329). Both nutraceutical and combination therapies led to significant improvements in metabolic, hormonal, and psychological outcomes in women with PCOS over 24&#xa0;weeks. Repeated-measures ANCOVA confirmed greater reductions in BMI, waist and hip circumference, DHEAS, FAI, testosterone, and prolactin, as well as superior quality-of-life gains with combination therapy. Nutraceutical therapy exerted stronger effects on LH suppression, while oxidative stress (MDA) decreased significantly in both groups without between-group differences. These findings highlight the potential of nutraceuticals as a non-pharmacological option and underscore the added benefits of metformin co-administration for patients with pronounced hyperandrogenism and central adiposity.&#xa0;Trial Registration: clinicalTrial.gov NCT05653895. Registered March 1, 2022.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zahra</LastName><ForeName>Musarrat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, Khyber Medical University, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Mohsin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, Khyber Medical University, Peshawar, Pakistan. mohsin.ibms@kmu.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Fiza</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, Khyber Medical University, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zubair</LastName><ForeName>Tariq</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Gajju Khan Medical College, Swabi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habib</LastName><ForeName>Rozina</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, DHQ Hospital, Mardan, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zulfiqar</LastName><ForeName>Fatima</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Khyber Girls Medical College, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05653895</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0326264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-1298</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acetyl-L-Carnitine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormonal Imbalance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metformin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCOS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SHBG Modulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Human Ethics and Consent to Participate declarations: All participants in this study were informed about the research objectives, potential risks, and benefits of the research. Written informed consent was obtained from each participant before to their inclusion in the study. The study was conducted in accordance with the ethical guidelines outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki, and ethical approval was obtained from the Khyber Medical University ethics committee. (Approval No. DIR/KMU-EB/IA/000838). Participants were assured of confidentiality, and their data were used solely for research purposes. They had the right to withdraw from the study at any stage without any consequences. Institutional Review Board Statement: This study was performed in line with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical approval was obtained from ethical committee of Khyber and its Advanced Study and Research Board (Approval No. DIR/KMU-AS&amp;RB/IA/001202). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants, and the trial was registered under ClinicalTrials.gov (NCT05653895). Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41026176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00210-025-04626-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00210-025-04626-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Arslanian SA, Lewy V, Danadian K, Saad R (2002) Metformin therapy in obese adolescents with polycystic ovary syndrome and impaired glucose tolerance: amelioration of exaggerated adrenal response to adrenocorticotropin with reduction of insulinemia/insulin resistance. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. https://doi.org/10.1210/jcem.87.4.8398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jcem.87.4.8398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assump&#xe7;&#xe3;o CR, Brunini TMC, Matsuura C et al (2008) Impact of the L-arginine-nitric oxide pathway and oxidative stress on the pathogenesis of the metabolic syndrome. Open Biochem J 2:108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874091X00802010108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2570556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auriemma RS, De Alcubierre D, Pirchio R et al (2018) The effects of hyperprolactinemia and its control on metabolic diseases. Expert Rev Endocrinol Metab 13:99&#x2013;106. https://doi.org/10.1080/17446651.2018.1434412</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17446651.2018.1434412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30058862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri S, Haddadi R, Saki S et al (2023) Neuroprotective effects of coenzyme Q10 on neurological diseases: a review article. Front Neurosci 17:1188839. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2023.1188839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2023.1188839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37424991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10326389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barba M, Schunemann HJ, Sperati F et al (2009) The effects of metformin on endogenous androgens and SHBG in women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Endocrinol. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.2008.03459.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2265.2008.03459.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber TM, Franks S (2021) Obesity and polycystic ovary syndrome. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 95:531&#x2013;541. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.14421</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.14421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazarganipour F, Ziaei S, Montazeri A et al (2013) Psychological investigation in patients with polycystic ovary syndrome. Health Qual Life Outcomes 11:141. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-7525-11-141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-11-141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23947827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3751454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazarganipour F, Taghavi SA, Montazeri A et al (2015) The impact of polycystic ovary syndrome on the health-related quality of life: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Iran J Reprod Med 13:61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25999994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4426142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmina E, Longo RA (2022) Increased prevalence of elevated DHEAS in PCOS women with non-classic (B or C) phenotypes: a retrospective analysis in patients aged 20 to 29 years. Cells 11:3255. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells11203255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells11203255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36291122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9601254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik O, Yildiz BO (2022) Adrenal and Polycystic Ovary Syndrome. In: Fauser B, Kovacs GT, Legro RS (eds) Polycystic Ovary Syndrome, 3rd edn. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, pp 67&#x2013;79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/9781108989831.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X, He B (2022) Clinical and biochemical potential of antioxidants in treating polycystic ovary syndrome. Int J Womens Health 14:467&#x2013;479. https://doi.org/10.2147/IJWH.S345853</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJWH.S345853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35392500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8982783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H, Zhang J, Zhang F et al (2021) Resistance to the insulin and elevated level of androgen: a major cause of polycystic ovary syndrome. Front Endocrinol. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2021.741764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.741764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escobar-Morreale HF (2018) Polycystic ovary syndrome: definition, aetiology, diagnosis and treatment. Nat Rev Endocrinol 14:270&#x2013;284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrendo.2018.24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29569621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontes AFS, Reis FM, C&#xe2;ndido AL et al (2023) Influence of metformin on hyperandrogenism in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Eur J Clin Pharmacol 79:445&#x2013;460. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00228-023-03461-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-023-03461-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36763111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foss MC, Paula FJA, Paccola GMGF, Piccinato CE (1995) Peripheral glucose metabolism in human hyperprolactinaemia. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 43:721&#x2013;726. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2265.1995.tb00541.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2265.1995.tb00541.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8736275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujikawa T, Soya H, Tamashiro KL et al (2004) Prolactin prevents acute stress-induced hypocalcemia and ulcerogenesis by acting in the brain of rat. Endocrinology 145:2006&#x2013;2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/en.2003-1446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genazzani AD, Prati A, Genazzani AR et al (2020) Synergistic effects of the integrative administration of acetyl-L-carnitine, L-carnitine, L-arginine and N-acetyl-cysteine on metabolic dynamics and on hepatic insulin extraction in overweight/obese patients with PCOS. Gynecological and Reproductive Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism 1:56&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glintborg D, Kolster ND, Ravn P, Andersen MS (2022a) Prospective risk of type 2 diabetes in normal weight women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Biomedicines 10:1455. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines10061455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10061455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35740476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9220967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glintborg D, Kolster ND, Ravn P, Andersen MS (2022b) Prospective risk of type 2 diabetes in normal weight women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Biomedicines 10:1455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10061455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35740476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9220967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo-Guti&#xe9;rrez A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garc&#xed;a P, D&#xed;az-Casado ME et al (2021) Metabolic targets of coenzyme Q10 in mitochondria. Antioxidants 10:520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox10040520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33810539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8066821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillier SG (1994) Current concepts of the roles of follicle stimulating hormone and luteinizing hormone in folliculogenesis. Hum Reprod 9:188&#x2013;191. https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordjournals.humrep.a138480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.humrep.a138480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8027271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu M, Li J, Zhang Y et al (2018) Endometrial progesterone receptor isoforms in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Am J Transl Res 10:2696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30210706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6129510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Wang W, Su X et al (2023) Comparison of nutritional supplements in improving glycolipid metabolism and endocrine function in polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. PeerJ 11:e16410. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.16410</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.16410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38025704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10652859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibanez L, Del R&#xed;o L, D&#xed;az M et al (2017) Normalizing ovulation rate by preferential reduction of hepato-visceral fat in adolescent girls with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Adolesc Health 61:446&#x2013;453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2017.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28712591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez L, De Zegher F (2020) Polycystic ovary syndrome in adolescent girls. Pediatr Obes 15:e12586. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijpo.12586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijpo.12586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31663293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito S, Taguchi K, Kodama G et al (2025) Involvement of impaired carnitine-induced fatty acid oxidation in experimental and human diabetic kidney disease. JCI Insight. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci.insight.179362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.179362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40875540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12288908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izadi A, Ebrahimi S, Shirazi S et al (2019) Hormonal and metabolic effects of coenzyme Q10 and/or vitamin E in patients with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 104:319&#x2013;327. https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2018-01221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2018-01221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30202998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarzadeh Esfehani A et al (2020) L-arginine supplementation improves sex hormone-binding globulin and reduces inflammation in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Womens Health 29:53&#x2013;59</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalhori Z, Mehranjani MS, Azadbakht M, Shariatzadeh MA (2019a) L-carnitine improves endocrine function and folliculogenesis by reducing inflammation, oxidative stress and apoptosis in mice following induction of polycystic ovary syndrome. Reprod Fertil Dev 31:282&#x2013;293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/RD18131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalhori Z, Mehranjani MS, Azadbakht M, Shariatzadeh MA (2019b) L-carnitine improves endocrine function and folliculogenesis by reducing inflammation, oxidative stress and apoptosis in mice following induction of polycystic ovary syndrome. Reprod Fertil Dev 31:282&#x2013;293. https://doi.org/10.1071/RD18131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/RD18131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazeminia M, Rajati F, Rajati M (2022) The effect of exercise on anti-Mullerian hormone levels in patients with polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Middle East Fertil Soc J 27:31. https://doi.org/10.1186/s43043-022-00121-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43043-022-00121-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelek SE, Af&#x15f;ar E, Ak&#xe7;ay G et al (2019) Effect of chronic L-carnitine supplementation on carnitine levels, oxidative stress and apoptotic markers in peripheral organs of adult Wistar rats. Food Chem Toxicol 134:110851</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2019.110851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31568849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krysiak R, Kowalcze K, Szkr&#xf3;bka W, Okopie&#x144; B (2023) Impaired prolactin-lowering effects of metformin in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Clin Med 12:5474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12175474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37685540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10488133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurhaluk N, Tkaczenko H (2025) L-arginine and nitric oxide in vascular regulation&#x2014;experimental findings in the context of blood donation. Nutrients 17:665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17040665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40004994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11858268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legro RS, Dodson WC, Kris-Etherton PM et al (2015) Randomized controlled trial of preconception interventions in infertile women with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 100:4048&#x2013;4058. https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2015-2778</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2015-2778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26401593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4702450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J-L, Wang Q-Y, Luan H-Y et al (2012) Effects of L-carnitine against oxidative stress in human hepatocytes: involvement of peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor alpha. J Biomed Sci 19:32. https://doi.org/10.1186/1423-0127-19-32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1423-0127-19-32</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22435679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3338374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Feng Y, Lin J-F et al (2014) Endometrial progesterone resistance and PCOS. J Biomed Sci 21:2. https://doi.org/10.1186/1423-0127-21-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1423-0127-21-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3917599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansourian M et al (2018) L-carnitine supplementation reduces oxidative stress and improves insulin sensitivity in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Eur J Endocrinol 178:359&#x2013;367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moinard C, Breuillard C, Charrueau C (2017) l-Arginine Metabolism Impairment in Sepsis and Diseases: Causes and Consequences. In: Patel VB, Preedy VR, Rajendram R (eds) L-Arginine in Clinical Nutrition. Springer International Publishing, Cham, pp 145&#x2013;158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojtahedi MF et al (2017) Metformin and L-carnitine supplementation improves insulin sensitivity and reduces oxidative stress in women with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 102:3469&#x2013;3478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller DM, Seim H, Kiess W et al (2002) Effects of oral L-carnitine supplementation on in vivo long-chain fatty acid oxidation in healthy adults. Metabolism 51:1389&#x2013;1391. https://doi.org/10.1053/meta.2002.35181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.35181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12404185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patani A, Balram D, Yadav VK et al (2023) Harnessing the power of nutritional antioxidants against adrenal hormone imbalance-associated oxidative stress. Front Endocrinol 14:1271521. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2023.1271521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1271521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellatt L, Rice S, Mason HD (2010) Anti-M&#xfc;llerian hormone and polycystic ovary syndrome: a mountain too high? REPRODUCTION 139:825&#x2013;833. https://doi.org/10.1530/REP-09-0415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/REP-09-0415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20207725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrillo T, Semprini E, Tomatis V et al (2022) Putative complementary compounds to counteract insulin-resistance in PCOS patients. Biomedicines 10:1924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10081924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36009471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9406066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi HM, Adeli I, Calina D et al (2022) Polycystic ovary syndrome: a comprehensive review of pathogenesis, management, and drug repurposing. Int J Mol Sci 23:583. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23020583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23020583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8775814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saghaei M (2004) Random allocation software for parallel group randomized trials. BMC Med Res Methodol 4:26. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2288-4-26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-4-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15535880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">533876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahmay S, Aydin Y, Oncul M, Senturk LM (2014) Diagnosis of polycystic ovary syndrome: AMH in combination with clinical symptoms. J Assist Reprod Genet 31:213&#x2013;220. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10815-013-0149-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10815-013-0149-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24343036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sam S, Ehrmann DA (2017) Metformin therapy for the reproductive and metabolic consequences of polycystic ovary syndrome. Diabetologia 60:1656&#x2013;1661. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-017-4306-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-017-4306-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28770330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samimi M, Jamilian M, Ebrahimi FA et al (2016) Expression of concern&#x202f;: Oral carnitine supplementation reduces body weight and insulin resistance in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 84:851&#x2013;857. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.13003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.13003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samimi M, Zarezade Mehrizi M, Foroozanfard F et al (2017) The effects of coenzyme Q10 supplementation on glucose metabolism and lipid profiles in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 86:560&#x2013;566. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.13288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.13288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27911471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangouni AA, Pakravanfar F, Ghadiri-Anari A et al (2022) The effect of l-carnitine supplementation on insulin resistance, sex hormone-binding globulin and lipid profile in overweight/obese women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized clinical trial. Eur J Nutr 61:1199&#x2013;1207. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00394-021-02659-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00394-021-02659-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34727201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schipper I, Hop WCJ, Fauser BCJM (1998) The follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) threshold/window concept examined by different interventions with exogenous FSH during the follicular phase of the normal menstrual cycle: duration, rather than magnitude, of FSH increase affects follicle development1. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 83(4):1292&#x2013;1298. https://doi.org/10.1210/jcem.83.4.4710</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jcem.83.4.4710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9543158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah FA, Bukhari SMS, Emal E, Shah M (2025) Effects of integrative administration of acetyl-L-carnitine, arginine, and Co-Q10 in mitigating oxidative stress in over-weight/obese PCOS women. J Appl Pharm Sci 15:274&#x2013;282. https://doi.org/10.7324/JAPS.2025.70521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva SV e, Gallia MC, da Luz JRD et al (2022) Antioxidant effect of coenzyme Q10 in the prevention of oxidative stress in arsenic-treated CHO-K1 cells and possible participation of zinc as a pro-oxidant agent. Nutrients 14:3265. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu14163265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidra S, Tariq MH, Farrukh MJ, Mohsin M (2019) Evaluation of clinical manifestations, health risks, and quality of life among women with polycystic ovary syndrome. PloS One 14(10):e0223329. https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0223329 . Accessed 20 May 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghavi SA, Bazarganipour F, Hugh-Jones S, Hosseini N (2015) Health-related quality of life in Iranian women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a qualitative study. BMC Womens Health 15:111. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-015-0272-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-015-0272-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26620588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4666094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teede HJ, Tay CT, Laven JJ et al (2023) Recommendations from the 2023 international evidence-based guideline for the assessment and management of polycystic ovary syndrome. Eur J Endocrinol 189:G43&#x2013;G64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ejendo/lvad096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37580861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G, Bazer FW, Davis TA et al (2009) Arginine metabolism and nutrition in growth, health and disease. Amino Acids 37:153&#x2013;168. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00726-008-0210-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-008-0210-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19030957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong F, Xiao J, Bai Y et al (2019) Metformin inhibits estradiol and progesterone-induced decidualization of endometrial stromal cells by regulating expression of progesterone receptor, cytokines and matrix metalloproteinases. Biomed Pharmacother 109:1578&#x2013;1585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2018.10.128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30551411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin MXC, Du LB, Zou XN et al (2021) Can psychosocial intervention suppress testosterone and triglycerides among women with polycystic ovary syndrome? A feasibility trial. Front Psychol. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.690539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.690539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8716369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X, Xie Y, Liu Y et al (2020) Polycystic ovarian syndrome: correlation between hyperandrogenism, insulin resistance and obesity. Clin Chim Acta 502:214&#x2013;221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cca.2019.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31733195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Xing C, Zhao H, He B (2021) The effectiveness of coenzyme Q10, vitamin E, inositols, and vitamin D in improving the endocrine and metabolic profiles in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a network meta-analysis. Gynecol Endocrinol 37:1063&#x2013;1071. https://doi.org/10.1080/09513590.2021.1926975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09513590.2021.1926975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33988478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, He Q, Xiu H et al (2023) Efficacy and safety of coenzyme Q10 supplementation in the treatment of polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Reprod Sci 30:1033&#x2013;1048. https://doi.org/10.1007/s43032-022-01038-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43032-022-01038-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35941510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zore T, Joshi N, Lizneva D, Azziz R (2017) Polycystic ovarian syndrome: long-term health consequences. Semin Reprod Med 35:271&#x2013;281. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0037-1603096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0037-1603096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28658711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>