<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40888876</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1912</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's archives of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A randomized controlled trial comparing the efficacy of resveratrol combined with metformin versus resveratrol monotherapy in the management of polycystic ovary syndrome.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00210-025-04495-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) is a common endocrine disorder affecting women of reproductive age characterized by metabolic dysfunction, insulin resistance, and hormonal imbalance. Metformin, a well-known insulin sensitizer, and Resveratrol, an antioxidant polyphenol, have both shown promise in managing the metabolic and reproductive features of PCOS. This study evaluates the effects of Resveratrol alone and in combination with Metformin on clinical, metabolic, endocrine and reproductive parameters in women with PCOS over a 6-month period. A randomized controlled trial was conducted with PCOS women, who were assigned to two groups: one receiving Resveratrol monotherapy (33 participants) and the other receiving a combination of Resveratrol plus Metformin (30 participants). Treatment effects on demographic, anthropometric, clinical, endocrine and metabolic parameters were assessed at baseline, after 3&#xa0;months and 6&#xa0;months. Following dropouts and adverse effects, 25 participants were analyzed in each group for the final evaluation. statistical analysis was performed using SPSS version 26., employing t-tests, repeated measures ANOVA, and chi-square test. Where baseline imbalances existed, Analysis of Covariance (ANCOVA) was additionally performed to adjust for pre-treatment differences., with p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 considered significant. Both treatment groups showed significant within-group improvements over 6&#xa0;months. Resveratrol monotherapy led to marked improvements in BMI, ovarian volume, Ferriman-Gallwey Score (FGS), LH levels, and quality of life (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The combination of Resveratrol with Metformin showed significantly reductions in fasting glucose (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002), BMI (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005), and oxidative stress marker MDA (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Menstrual regularity improved in both groups, with 96% of participants in the Resveratrol group and 85% in the combination group reporting regular cycles at 6&#xa0;months. Perceived stress levels improved in both groups, with a shift toward lower stress categories. Absolute change revealed significantly higher improvements in quality of life and ovarian morphology in the Resveratrol group, while metabolic parameters improved more in the combination group. Both Resveratrol alone and in combination with Metformin were effective in managing PCOS. Resveratrol monotherapy was superior in improving reproductive parameters and quality of life, whereas the combination therapy offered greater metabolic and antioxidant benefits. These findings highlight the need to tailor treatment strategies according to individual PCOS phenotypes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zahra</LastName><ForeName>Musarrat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, Khyber Medical University, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Mohsin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Institute of Basic Medical Sciences, Khyber Medical University, Peshawar, Pakistan. mohsin.ibms@kmu.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Farida</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Khyber Girls Medical College, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zulfiqar</LastName><ForeName>Fatima</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Khyber Girls Medical College, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tariq</LastName><ForeName>Aiman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Northwest School of Medicine, Peshawar, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Nadia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Women Medical College, Abbottabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0326264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-1298</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metformin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polycystic ovary syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resveratrol</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: This study was performed in line with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical approval was obtained from Khyber Medical University (Approval No. DIR/KMU-EB/IA/000838) and its Advanced Study and Research Board (Approval No. DIR/KMU-AS&amp;RB/IA/001202). Declaration of generative AI and AI-assisted technologies in the writing process: During the preparation of this work, the authors used ChatGPT to enhance readability, as they are not native English speakers. The content was thoroughly reviewed and edited, and the authors take full responsibility for the final version of the published article. Attestation statement: We attest that the subjects in this trial have not concomitantly been involved in other randomized trials. Data regarding any of the subjects in the study has not been previously published. Data will be made available to the editors of the journal for review or query upon request. Data sharing statement: Data will be made available upon reasonable request to the corresponding author. Submission declaration and verification: We declare that the work described has not been published previously, that it is not under consideration for publication elsewhere, that its publication is approved by all authors and tacitly or explicitly by the responsible authorities where the work was carried out, and that, if accepted, it will not be published elsewhere in the same form, in English or in any other language, including electronically without the written consent of the copyright- holder. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40888876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00210-025-04495-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00210-025-04495-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asgary S, Karimi R, Momtaz S et al (2019) Effect of resveratrol on metabolic syndrome components: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 20:173&#x2013;186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31065943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai H, Ding H, Wang M (2024) Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS): symptoms, causes, and treatment. Clin Exp Obstet Gynecol 51:126. https://doi.org/10.31083/j.ceog5105126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.ceog5105126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banaszewska B, Wroty&#x144;ska-Barczy&#x144;ska J, Spaczynski RZ et al (2016) Effects of resveratrol on polycystic ovary syndrome: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 101:4322&#x2013;4328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27754722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baur JA, Sinclair DA (2006) Therapeutic potential of resveratrol: the in vivo evidence. Nat Rev Drug Discov 5:493&#x2013;506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16732220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazarganipour F, Taghavi SA, Montazeri A et al (2015) The impact of polycystic ovary syndrome on the health-related quality of life: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Iran J Reprod Med 13:61&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25999994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4426142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenjian S, Moini A, Yamini N et al (2020) Resveratrol treatment in patients with polycystic ovary syndrome decreased pro-inflammatory and endoplasmic reticulum stress markers. Am J Reprod Immunol 83:e13186. https://doi.org/10.1111/aji.13186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aji.13186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31483910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang H, Shi B, Wang Y et al (2025) Effect and mechanism of resveratrol against polycystic ovary syndrome: a review. Front Endocrinol. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2025.1529231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2025.1529231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabravolski SA, Nikiforov NG, Eid AH et al (2021) Mitochondrial dysfunction and chronic inflammation in polycystic ovary syndrome. Int J Mol Sci 22:3923</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8070512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dokras A, Stener-Victorin E, Yildiz BO et al (2018) Androgen excess-polycystic ovary syndrome society: position statement on depression, anxiety, quality of life, and eating disorders in polycystic ovary syndrome. Fertil Steril 109:888&#x2013;899</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29778388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey P, Shi T, Coltharp M, Reddy S (2022) Effects of resveratrol on metabolic, biochemical, and endocrine manifestations in polycystic ovary syndrome. Dietetics 1:66&#x2013;77</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergenoglu M, Yildirim N, Yildirim AGS et al (2015) Effects of resveratrol on ovarian morphology, plasma anti-mullerian hormone, IGF-1 levels, and oxidative stress parameters in a rat model of polycystic ovary syndrome. Reprod Sci 22:942&#x2013;947. https://doi.org/10.1177/1933719115570900</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1933719115570900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25667201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadlalmola HA, Elhusein AM, Al-Sayaghi KM et al (2023) Efficacy of resveratrol in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Pan Afr Med J 44</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furat Rencber S, Kurnaz Ozbek S, Eraldem&#x131;r C et al (2018) Effect of resveratrol and metformin on ovarian reserve and ultrastructure in PCOS: an experimental study. J Ovarian Res 11:55. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13048-018-0427-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13048-018-0427-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29958542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6025739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheirollahi A, Hamidi H, Vatannejad A (2025) Distribution of polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) phenotypes in Iranian women: a cross-sectional study. BMC Res Notes 18:215. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13104-025-07202-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-025-07202-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40361207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12076859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kratz EM, Kokot I, Dymicka-Piekarska V, Piwowar A (2021) Sirtuins&#x2014;the new important players in women&#x2019;s gynecological health. Antioxidants 10:84</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33435147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7827899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang A, Huang L, Liu H et al (2021) Resveratrol improves follicular development of PCOS rats by regulating the glycolytic pathway. Mol Nutr Food Res 65:2100457. https://doi.org/10.1002/mnfr.202100457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.202100457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizneva D, Suturina L, Walker W et al (2016) Criteria, prevalence, and phenotypes of polycystic ovary syndrome. Fertil Steril 106:6&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.05.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27233760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lujan ME, Chizen DR, Pierson RA (2008) Diagnostic criteria for polycystic ovary syndrome: pitfalls and controversies. J Obstet Gynaecol Can JOGC J Obstet Gynecol Can JOGC 30:671&#x2013;679. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1701-2163(16)32915-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1701-2163(16)32915-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini A, Bruno C, Vergani E et al (2021) Oxidative stress and low-grade inflammation in polycystic ovary syndrome: controversies and new insights. Int J Mol Sci 22:1667. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22041667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22041667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7915804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghetti P, Castello R, Negri C et al (2000) Metformin effects on clinical features, endocrine and metabolic profiles, and insulin sensitivity in polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled 6-month trial, followed by open, long-term clinical evaluation. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 85:139&#x2013;146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10634377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polito CA, Cai Z-Y, Shi Y-L et al (2018) Association of tea consumption with risk of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and anti-beta-amyloid effects of tea. Nutrients 10:655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29789466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5986534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safiah M, Hyassat D, Khader Y et al (2021) Effect of metformin on anthropometric measurements and hormonal and biochemical profile in patients with prediabetes. J Diabetes Res 2021:8275303. https://doi.org/10.1155/2021/8275303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/8275303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34950736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8692055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samimi M, Jamilian M, Ebrahimi FA et al (2016) Oral carnitine supplementation reduces body weight and insulin resistance in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 84:851&#x2013;857. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.13003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.13003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MSB, Campbell RE (2022) Polycystic ovary syndrome and the neuroendocrine consequences of androgen excess. Compr Physiol 12:3347&#x2013;3369. https://doi.org/10.1002/j.2040-4603.2022.tb00215.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.2040-4603.2022.tb00215.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35578968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghavi SA, Bazarganipour F, Hugh-Jones S, Hosseini N (2015) Health-related quality of life in Iranian women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a qualitative study. BMC Womens Health 15:111. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-015-0272-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-015-0272-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26620588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4666094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan S, Hahn S, Benson S et al (2007) Metformin improves polycystic ovary syndrome symptoms irrespective of pre-treatment insulin resistance. Eur J Endocrinol 157:669&#x2013;676</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang T, Lord JM, Norman RJ et al (2012) Insulin-sensitising drugs (metformin, rosiglitazone, pioglitazone, D-chiro-inositol) for women with polycystic ovary syndrome, oligo amenorrhoea and subfertility. Cochrane Database Syst Rev</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teede HJ, Misso ML, Costello MF et al (2018) Recommendations from the international evidence-based guideline for the assessment and management of polycystic ovary syndrome. Hum Reprod Oxf Engl 33:1602&#x2013;1618. https://doi.org/10.1093/humrep/dey256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humrep/dey256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmers S, Konings E, Bilet L et al (2011) Calorie restriction-like effects of 30 days of resveratrol supplementation on energy metabolism and metabolic profile in obese humans. Cell Metab 14:612&#x2013;622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22055504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseilikman VE, Tseilikman OB, Yegorov ON et al (2024) Resveratrol: a multifaceted guardian against anxiety and stress disorders&#x2014;an overview of experimental evidence. Nutrients 16:2856</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39275174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11396965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X-L, Deng S-L, Lian Z-X, Yu K (2021) Resveratrol targets a variety of oncogenic and oncosuppressive signaling for ovarian cancer prevention and treatment. Antioxidants 10:1718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34829589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8614917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G, Myers R, Li Y et al (2001) Role of AMP-activated protein kinase in mechanism of metformin action. J Clin Invest 108:1167&#x2013;1174. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI13505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI13505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">209533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>