<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40955227</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Digoxin Versus Bisoprolol for Heart Rate Control in Atrial Fibrillation With Heart Failure on Quality of Life: A Prospective Randomised Comparative Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e90171</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e90171</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e90171</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.90171</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Atrial fibrillation (AF) and heart failure (HF) often co-exist, exerting synergistic adverse effects on patients' morbidity, quality of life (QOL) and mortality. This also poses a unique management challenge of heart failure in the AF population as compared to the sinus rhythm population. While beta blockers such as bisoprolol have been preferred treatment options for patients with heart failure, digoxin remains a cost-effective yet underrated alternative. However, its overall effect on QOL remains debated, especially in the South Asian population that carries a higher burden of heart failure than any other ethnicity. Objective The objective of this study was to compare the short-term effect of bisoprolol versus digoxin on quality of life in patients with permanent AF and concurrent HF in the South Asian population.&#xa0; Methods This single-centred prospective randomised comparative study was conducted at the outpatient department of Punjab Institute of Cardiology, Lahore, from March to September 2022. A total of 80 patients with permanent AF and established HF were enrolled and randomised in two groups to receive either digoxin (62.5-250 mcg/day) or bisoprolol (1.25-15 mg/day). The 36-Item Short Form Health Survey (SF-36) was administered at baseline and after three months to assess changes in QOL. Data were analysed using SPSS v25.0 (IBM Corp., Armonk, NY, USA), with significance at p &#x2264; 0.05. Results Both treatment groups significantly improved SF-36 QoL scores after three months (p &lt; 0.001). However, the digoxin group reported significantly greater improvement compared to the bisoprolol group (mean QoL score: 76.68 &#xb1; 9.37 vs. 70.90 &#xb1; 8.00; p = 0.004). No serious adverse events or digoxin-related toxicities were reported in either group.&#xa0; Conclusion In patients with permanent AF and HF, digoxin resulted in a statistically significant improvement in short-term quality of life compared to bisoprolol. These findings suggest that digoxin may serve as a viable and possibly superior alternative to bisoprolol in patients with permanent AF and HF, with a potential role for digoxin as a first-line agent in select populations. It also highlights the need to re-evaluate current treatment preferences, especially in resource-limited settings. Further multicentric and multi-ethnic studies are needed to substantiate these findings and evaluate long-term clinical outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Sarwar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarwar</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology, Punjab Institute of Cardiology, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nahar</LastName><ForeName>Noor Un</ForeName><Initials>NU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Acute Internal Medicine, Northampton General Hospital, Northampton, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amin</LastName><ForeName>Hajra</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Pakistan Kidney and Liver Institute, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Maheen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Allama Iqbal Teaching Hospital, Dera Ghazi Khan, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bader</LastName><ForeName>Aymen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Shiekh Zayed Hospital, Rahim Yar Khan, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fib</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality-of-life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomised controlled trial</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Department of Research, Training and Postgraduate Medical Education, Punjab Institute of Cardiology, Lahore issued approval RTPGME-Research-212/A. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40955227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12433684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.90171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Atrial fibrillation and heart failure: understanding the bidirectional relationship. Zakeri R, Chamberlain AM. Heart Fail Clin. 2020;16:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and incidence of atrial fibrillation in ambulatory patients with heart failure. Pellicori P, Urbinati A, Cleland JG, et al. Heart. 2019;105:384&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31558271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The hemodynamic effect of simulated atrial fibrillation on left ventricular function. Zheng Q, Cheng Z, Wang L, Zhang Y, Li Y. Cardiovasc Eng Technol. 2022;13:456&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaquat MT, Makaryus AN. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Cardiac electrical and structural remodeling.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31855391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2019 AHA/ACC/HRS Focused Update of the 2014 AHA/ACC/HRS Guideline for the Management of Patients With Atrial Fibrillation: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines and the Heart Rhythm Society in Collaboration With the Society of Thoracic Surgeons. January CT, Wann LS, Calkins H, et al. Circulation. 2019;140:0&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30686041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2016 ESC Guidelines for the management of atrial fibrillation developed in collaboration with EACTS. Kirchhof P, Benussi S, Kotecha D, et al. Eur Heart J. 2016;37:2893&#x2013;2962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27567408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cost-effectiveness of digoxin versus beta blockers in permanent atrial fibrillation: the Rate Control Therapy Evaluation in Permanent Atrial Fibrillation (RATE-AF) randomised trial. Abdali Z, Bunting KV, Mehta S, et al. Heart. 2025;111:362&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12015011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39819610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of digoxin vs bisoprolol for heart rate control in atrial fibrillation on patient-reported quality of life: the RATE-AF randomized clinical trial. Kotecha D, Bunting KV, Gill SK, et al. JAMA. 2020;324:2497&#x2013;2508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7756234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of digoxin vs. beta blocker in atrial fibrillation: report from ESC-EHRA EORP AF Long-Term General Registry. Ding WY, Boriani G, Marin F, Blomstr&#xf6;m-Lundqvist C, Potpara TS, Fauchier L, Lip GY. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Pharmacother. 2022;8:372&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34665249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36). I. Conceptual framework and item selection. Ware JE, Sherbourne CD. Med Care. 1992;30:473&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular diseases in India: current epidemiology and future directions. Prabhakaran D, Jeemon P, Roy A. Circulation. 2016;133:1605&#x2013;1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27142605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical outcomes with digoxin vs. beta-blocker for heart rate control in permanent atrial fibrillation with heart failure. Bisson A, Ding WY, Bodin A, Lip GY, Fauchier L. Eur J Heart Fail. 2021;23:1563&#x2013;1565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34231295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>'Digoxin conundrum - Time for validation?'. Yadava OP. Indian Heart J. 2021;73:242&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8065360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33865529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digitalis glycosides for heart rate control in atrial fibrillation. Curfman G. JAMA. 2020;324:2508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug therapy monitoring (TDM) of digoxin: safety and efficacy review. Harahap U, Syahputra R, Nasution M, Satria D, Dalimunthe A. Pharmacia. 2022;69</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>