<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40834249</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1935-5548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetes care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetes Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Low-Dose Glucagon to Prevent and Treat Exercise-Associated Hypoglycemia in Individuals With Type 1 Diabetes: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1637</StartPage><EndPage>1645</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1637-1645</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2337/dc25-0702</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">People with type 1 diabetes (T1D) struggle to manage exercise because of hypoglycemia risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESEARCH DESIGN AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This systematic review and meta-analysis evaluated low-dose glucagon's efficacy for preventing and treating exercise-induced hypoglycemia in T1D. Medline, Embase, and Cochrane CENTRAL were searched for randomized controlled trials and crossover studies until September 2024. The analysis included T1D adolescents and adults treated with low-dose glucagon versus nonglucagon treatments. Studies with glucagon-like peptides, noninsulin combinations, or uncontrolled exercise settings were excluded. Two authors extracted the data. The methodological quality was assessed with the Risk of Bias-2 tool and Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluations framework. Risk of Bias 2 informed a sensitivity analysis. The meta-analysis employed a random effects model to estimate the pooled treatment effects on hypoglycemia and time below range (TBR) (glucose &lt;3.9 mmol/L), as well as secondary outcomes and adverse effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 6,792 records, 12 studies involving 248 individuals (mean age: 36 &#xb1; 10.5 years) met inclusion criteria. The meta-analysis showed significant reductions in hypoglycemia risk (risk ratio 0.54; 95% CI 0.35, 0.84) and TBR (-3.91 percentage points; 95% CI -6.27, 1.54) with low-dose glucagon. Sensitivity analysis yielded a slightly more confident effect size for hypoglycemia and TBR. However, overall adverse events increased with low-dose glucagon (risk ratio 2.75; 95% CI 1.07, 7.08). The included studies were few and heterogeneous, which may have influenced the overall outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Low-dose glucagon reduces exercise-induced hypoglycemia and TBR in T1D individuals. Future research should optimize glucagon dosage and timing for various exercise types and durations to confirm real-world effectiveness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 by the American Diabetes Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lundemose</LastName><ForeName>Sissel Banner</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4343-7777</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranjan</LastName><ForeName>Ajenthen Gayathri</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xf8;rgaard</LastName><ForeName>Ole</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suvitaival</LastName><ForeName>Tommi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xf8;rgaard</LastName><ForeName>Kirsten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1620-8271</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen, Copenhagen University Hospital, Herlev, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetes Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7805975</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0149-5992</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-92-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005934">Glucagon</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005934" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glucagon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003922" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypoglycemia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Duality of Interest.</b> K.N. serves as an adviser to Medtronic, Abbott, Connate, and Novo Nordisk; owns shares in Novo Nordisk; has received research grants to the institution from Novo Nordisk, Zealand Pharma, Dexcom, and Medtronic; and has received fees for speaking from Medtronic, and Novo Nordisk. No other potential conflicts of interest relevant to this article were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40834249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12368384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc25-0702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">163215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee . 5. Facilitating behavior change and well-being to improve health outcomes: Standards of Medical Care in Diabetes&#x2014;2022. Diabetes Care 2022;45:S60&#x2013;S82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34964866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn B, Herbst A, Pfeifer M, et al. ; DPV Initiative . Impact of physical activity on glycemic control and prevalence of cardiovascular risk factors in adults with type 1 diabetes: a cross-sectional multicenter study of 18,028 patients. Diabetes Care 2015;38:1536&#x2013;1543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26015557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, Smith TJ, Slaughter JC, et al. Iatrogenic hyperinsulinemia, not hyperglycemia, drives insulin resistance in type 1 diabetes as revealed by comparison with GCK-MODY (MODY2). Diabetes 2019;68:1565&#x2013;1576</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31092478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Vinik Ai, Erbas T, N&#xe9;voret Ml, Casellini C.. 
Neurological disease and diabetes, autonomic. In: <i>Encyclopedia of Endocrine Diseases</i>, 2nd Ed.
Huhtaniemi I, Martini L, Eds. Oxford, Academic Press, 2015. pp. 210&#x2013;215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis SN, Galassetti P, Wasserman DH, Tate D.. Effects of antecedent hypoglycemia on subsequent counterregulatory responses to exercise. Diabetes 2000;49:73&#x2013;81</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10615952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser O, Riddell MC, Eckstein ML, et al. Glucose management for exercise using continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) and intermittently scanned CGM (isCGM) systems in type 1 diabetes: position statement of the European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD) and of the International Society for Pediatric and Adolescent Diabetes (ISPAD) endorsed by JDRF and supported by the American Diabetes Association (ADA). Diabetologia 2020;63:2501&#x2013;2520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pintaudi B, Gironi I, Nicosia R, et al. Minimed Medtronic 780G optimizes glucose control in patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 2022;32:1719&#x2013;1724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35599092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JD, Lepore G, Battelino T, et al. Real-world performance of the MiniMed 780G system: first report of outcomes from 4120 users. Diabetes Technol Ther 2022;24:113&#x2013;119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34524003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neal DN, Zaharieva DP, Morrison D, McCarthy O, N&#xf8;rgaard K.. Exercising safely with the MiniMedTM 780G automated insulin delivery system. Diabetes Technol Ther 2024;26:84&#x2013;96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38377316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillip M, Nimri R, Bergenstal RM, et al. Consensus recommendations for the use of automated insulin delivery technologies in clinical practice. Endocr Rev 2023;44:254&#x2013;280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36066457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazeau A-S, Rabasa-Lhoret R, Strychar I, Mircescu H.. Barriers to physical activity among patients with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2008;31:2108&#x2013;2109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2571055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18689694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjan A, Schmidt S, Madsbad S, Holst JJ, N&#xf8;rgaard K.. Effects of subcutaneous, low-dose glucagon on insulin-induced mild hypoglycaemia in patients with insulin pump treated type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab 2016;18:410&#x2013;418</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haymond MW, Redondo MJ, McKay S, et al. Nonaqueous, mini-dose glucagon for treatment of mild hypoglycemia in adults with type 1 diabetes: a dose-seeking study. Diabetes Care 2016;39:465&#x2013;468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4764034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26861921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haymond MW, DuBose SN, Rickels MR, et al. ; T1D Exchange Mini-dose Glucagon Study Group . Efficacy and safety of mini-dose glucagon for treatment of nonsevere hypoglycemia in adults with type 1 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2017;102:2994&#x2013;3001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blauw H, van Bon AC, Koops R, DeVries JH, on behalf of the PCDIAB consortium . Performance and safety of an integrated bihormonal artificial pancreas for fully automated glucose control at home. Diabetes Obes Metab 2016;18:671&#x2013;677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5111773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26996542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boiroux D, B&#xe1;tora V, Hagdrup M, et al. Adaptive model predictive control for a dual-hormone artificial pancreas. J Process Control 2018;68:105&#x2013;117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castle JR, El Youssef J, Wilson LM, et al. Randomized outpatient trial of single- and dual-hormone closed-loop systems that adapt to exercise using wearable sensors. Diabetes Care 2018;41:1471&#x2013;1477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6014543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29752345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar A, Messier V, Legault L, Ladouceur M, Rabasa-Lhoret R.. Outpatient 60-hour day-and-night glucose control with dual-hormone artificial pancreas, single-hormone artificial pancreas, or sensor-augmented pump therapy in adults with type 1 diabetes: an open-label, randomised, crossover, controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab 2017;19:713&#x2013;720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28094472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Zealand Pharma . Beta Bionics and Zealand Pharma announce superior glycemic control in phase 2 home&#x2010;use clinical trial testing the iLet(TM) Bionic Pancreas using Dasiglucagon. 2020. Accessed 14 December 2024. Available from https://firstwordpharma.com/story/4802811</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisman A, Bai J-W, Cardinez M, Kramer CK, Perkins BA.. Effect of artificial pancreas systems on glycaemic control in patients with type 1 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of outpatient randomised controlled trials. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2017;5:501&#x2013;512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28533136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddaway NR, Grainger MJ, Gray CT.. Citationchaser: an R package and Shiny app for forward and backward citations chasing in academic searching (version 0.0.3), 2021. Accessed 24 January 2025. Available from 10.5281/zenodo.4543513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.4543513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Thomas J, Graziosi S, Brunton J, et al. 
<i>EPPI-Reviewer: Advanced Software for Systematic Reviews, Maps and Evidence Synthesis.</i>
London, EPPI Centre, 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi K-Y, Li M-Y, Chen C, Kang E, Cochrane Taiwan . Ten circumstances and solutions for finding the sample mean and standard deviation for meta-analysis. Syst Rev 2023;12:62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10068165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37005690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019;366:14898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sch&#xfc;nemann H, Bro&#x17c;ek J, Guyatt G, Oxman A (Eds.). <i>GRADE Handbook.</i>
GRADE Working Group, 2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson LM, Jacobs PG, Ramsey KL, et al. Dual-hormone closed-loop system using a liquid stable glucagon formulation versus insulin-only closed-loop system compared with a predictive low glucose suspend system: an open-label, outpatient, single-center, crossover, randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care 2020;43:2721&#x2013;2729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32907828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickels MR, DuBose SN, Toschi E, et al. ; T1D Exchange Mini-Dose Glucagon Exercise Study Group . Mini-dose glucagon as a novel approach to prevent exercise-induced hypoglycemia in type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2018;41:1909&#x2013;1916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6463733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29776987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar A, Legault L, Dallaire M, et al. Glucose-responsive insulin and glucagon delivery (dual-hormone artificial pancreas) in adults with type 1 diabetes: a randomized crossover controlled trial. CMAJ 2013;185:297&#x2013;305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3589308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23359039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar A, Legault L, Messier V, Mitre TM, Leroux C, Rabasa-Lhoret R.. Comparison of dual-hormone artificial pancreas, single-hormone artificial pancreas, and conventional insulin pump therapy for glycaemic control in patients with type 1 diabetes: an open-label randomised controlled crossover trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2015;3:17&#x2013;26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25434967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taleb N, Emami A, Suppere C, et al. Efficacy of single-hormone and dual-hormone artificial pancreas during continuous and interval exercise in adult patients with type 1 diabetes: randomised controlled crossover trial. Diabetologia 2016;59:2561&#x2013;2571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27704167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez AM, Gomez C, Aschner P, et al. Effects of performing morning versus afternoon exercise on glycemic control and hypoglycemia frequency in type 1 diabetes patients on sensor-augmented insulin pump therapy. J Diabetes Sci Technol 2015;9:619&#x2013;624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4604526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGaugh SM, Zaharieva DP, Pooni R, et al. Carbohydrate requirements for prolonged, fasted exercise with and without basal rate reductions in adults with type 1 diabetes on continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion. Diabetes Care 2021;44:610&#x2013;613</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7818338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33328284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar A, Rabasa-Lhoret R, Legault L, et al. Single- and dual-hormone artificial pancreas for overnight glucose control in type 1 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2016;101:214&#x2013;223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26523526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindkvist EB, Laugesen C, Reenberg AT, et al. Performance of a dual-hormone closed-loop system versus insulin-only closed-loop system in adolescents with type 1 diabetes. A single-blind, randomized, controlled, crossover trial. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2023;14:1073388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9899880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36755913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newswanger B, Ammons S, Phadnis N, et al. Development of a highly stable, nonaqueous glucagon formulation for delivery via infusion pump systems. J Diabetes Sci Technol 2015;9:24&#x2013;33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4495537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25550410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjan AG, Schmidt S, N&#xf8;rgaard K.. Glucagon for hypoglycaemia treatment in type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 2021;25:e3409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33090668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neylon OM, Moran MM, Pellicano A, Nightingale M, O&#x2019;Connell MA.. Successful subcutaneous glucagon use for persistent hypoglycaemia in congenital hyperinsulinism. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab 2013;26:1157&#x2013;1161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23813352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinert M, Sachs S, Kirk M, et al. Glucagon regulation of energy expenditure. Int J Mol Sci 2019;20:5407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6862306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31671603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Bon AC, Jonker LD, Koebrugge R, Koops R, Hoekstra JBL, DeVries JH.. Feasibility of a bihormonal closed-loop system to control postexercise and postprandial glucose excursions. J Diabetes Sci Technol 2012;6:1114&#x2013;1122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3570846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23063038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs PG, El Youssef J, Reddy R, et al. Randomized trial of a dual-hormone artificial pancreas with dosing adjustment during exercise compared with no adjustment and sensor-augmented pump therapy. Diabetes Obes Metab 2016;18:1110&#x2013;1119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5056819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27333970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steineck IIK, Ranjan A, Schmidt S, Clausen TR, Holst JJ, N&#xf8;rgaard K.. Preserved glucose response to low-dose glucagon after exercise in insulin-pump-treated individuals with type 1 diabetes: a randomised crossover study. Diabetologia 2019;62:582&#x2013;592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30643924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronson R, Riddell MC, Conoscenti V, Junaidi MK.. Effect of mini-dose ready-to-use liquid glucagon on preventing exercise-associated hypoglycemia in adults with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2023;46:765&#x2013;772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10090931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36689626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>