<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40965701</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-0428</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetologia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetologia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Repeated faecal microbiota transplantation for individuals with type 1 diabetes and gastroenteropathy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00125-025-06544-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS/HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Faecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) may alleviate gastrointestinal symptoms in individuals with diabetic gastroenteropathy, as demonstrated in a recent placebo-controlled trial. In most participants, symptom relief was transient, raising the need for repeated treatments. This study assessed the long-term efficacy, safety and feasibility of repeated, on-demand FMT as a maintenance treatment in this patient population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">All 20 participants from the randomised clinical trial were offered extended open-label treatment with FMT. Symptom assessments were conducted by telephone every 2-3 months using the Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale for Irritable Bowel Syndrome (GSRS-IBS). Secondary measures included bowel movement frequency, stool consistency assessed using the Bristol Stool Scale, perceived treatment benefit on a seven-point Likert scale, and adverse events (AEs). FMT was primarily given as oral capsules, and colonoscopy was used for participants who could not swallow capsules.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the original 20 participants, 17 were included in the present study and followed from September 2021 to December 2024, with a median Duration of follow-up of 33.2 months (range 14.7-39.1 months). Participants received a total of 95 FMT treatments, with a median of five per participant and a median interval of 5.3 months between treatments. FMT induced consistent symptom relief, with reduced GSRS-IBS scores across multiple treatments. At the last FMT treatment provided, the mean GSRS-IBS score had decreased from 60 (95% CI 54, 66) at baseline to 35 (95% CI 29, 40), with a mean difference of -25 (95% CI -18, -33). The occurrence of frequent bowel movements 2 weeks after treatment (&gt;&#xa0;7 per day) decreased from 19% (95% CI 10%, 28%) to 3% (95% CI 0%, 7%). Stool consistency improved after treatment, and the frequency of normal stool types (Bristol Stool Scale score 3-5) increased from 28% (95% CI 18%, 39%) to 76% (95% CI 66%, 86%). Participant satisfaction was high, with 86% reporting considerable benefits (Likert scores 5-7). Repeated FMT was generally well tolerated, with most AEs being mild and self-limiting. Fifteen serious AEs were documented, of which only one was deemed to be possibly related to FMT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS/INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Repeated, on-demand FMT is effective and safe for long-term treatment of individuals with type 1 diabetes and severe diabetic gastroenteropathy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT04749030 FUNDING: The study was funded by a Steno Collaborative Grant (no. 0058906).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xf8;yer</LastName><ForeName>Katrine L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-0101-5219</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark. kathoeye@rm.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark. kathoeye@rm.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark. kathoeye@rm.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kornum</LastName><ForeName>Ditte S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7488-4759</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baunwall</LastName><ForeName>Simon M D</ForeName><Initials>SMD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5135-7435</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klinge</LastName><ForeName>Mette W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4412-4307</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drewes</LastName><ForeName>Asbj&#xf8;rn M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7465-964X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mech-Sense, Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center North Denmark, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yderstr&#xe6;de</LastName><ForeName>Knud B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4411-3598</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Odense, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mikkelsen</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7806-1143</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erikstrup</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6551-6647</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Immunology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krogh</LastName><ForeName>Klaus</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9168-2403</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hvas</LastName><ForeName>Christian L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7973-7184</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Aarhus University Hospital, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04749030</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetologia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0006777</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0012-186X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic neuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetic gastroenteropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Faecal microbiota transplantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Acknowledgements: The authors take this opportunity to thank all of the individuals who participated in this study, the voluntary donors and the team at the Centre for Faecal Microbiota Transplantation (CEFTA) in Aarhus, Denmark, for their invaluable contributions. The authors also thank the Biostatistical Advisory Service at Aarhus University for their assistance with biostatistical analysis. The authors used Grammarly to assist with spelling and grammar corrections during the preparation of this manuscript. Full responsibility for the content rests with the authors. Data availability: Anonymised data may be made available upon reasonable request in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Access to de-identified participant data will require a formal data-sharing agreement, and, where applicable, approval from the relevant ethics committee. All inquiries and proposals should be directed to the corresponding author. Funding: Open access funding provided by Aarhus University Hospital. This study was funded by a Steno Collaborative Grant (no. 0058906). CLH received research support from Novo Nordisk Foundation (grant no. NNF22OC0074080). Authors&#x2019; relationships and activities: SMDB has received lecture honoraria from Tillotts. MWK received support from Pfizer Biopharmaceuticals Group to attend the United European Gastroenterology Week in Vienna, 2024. CLH has received honoraria for lectures from Tillotts, Merck and Johnson &amp; Johnson. Additionally, CLH is a member of the Expert Working Group at the European Directorate for the Quality of Medicines &amp; HealthCare (EDQM) of the European Council (unpaid). The remaining authors declare that there are no relationships or activities that might bias, or be perceived to bias, their work. Contribution statement: All authors met the authorship criteria established by the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors, ensuring the quality and reliability of this work. They were actively involved in the study&#x2019;s conception and drafting, critical revisions and final approval of the manuscript. The study was designed by KLH, SMDB, KK and CLH. Statistical analyses were performed by KLH and DSK. KLH, SMDB, KK and CLH had full access to the raw data presented in this study and were responsible for verifying its accuracy. Participant recruitment and treatment were conducted by KLH, SMDB, KK, MWK, AMD, KBY and CLH. Key contributions to the successful execution and validity of the study were made by KLH, SMDB, CE, SM, KK and CLH. All authors were involved in interpreting the data, providing critical insights and accessing the full dataset. The authors decided collectively to submit the manuscript for publication. KLH is the guarantor of this work and accepts full responsibility for the integrity of the work as a whole.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40965701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-025-06544-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00125-025-06544-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bytzer P, Talley NJ, Leemon M, Young LJ, Jones MP, Horowitz M (2001) Prevalence of gastrointestinal symptoms associated with diabetes mellitus: a population-based survey of 15,000 adults. Arch Intern Med 161(16):1989&#x2013;1996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.161.16.1989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11525701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalleh R, Marathe CS, Rayner CK, Jones KL, Horowitz M (2019) Diabetic gastroparesis and glycaemic control. Curr Diab Rep 19(12):153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11892-019-1281-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31792708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinge MW, Borghammer P, Lund S et al (2020) Enteric cholinergic neuropathy in patients with diabetes: non-invasive assessment with positron emission tomography. Neurogastroenterol Motil 32(1):e13731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.13731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Sloan G, Ye Y et al (2019) New perspective in diabetic neuropathy: from the periphery to the brain, a call for early detection, and precision medicine. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 10:929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2019.00929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32010062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meldgaard T, Keller J, Olesen AE et al (2019) Pathophysiology and management of diabetic gastroenteropathy. Therap Adv Gastroenterol 12:1756284819852047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756284819852047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6580709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornum DS, Krogh K, Keller J, Malagelada C, Drewes AM, Brock C (2025) Diabetic gastroenteropathy: a pan-alimentary complication. Diabetologia 68(5):905&#x2013;919</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-025-06365-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39934370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12021976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding G, Yang X, Li Y et al (2025) Gut microbiota regulates gut homeostasis, mucosal immunity and influences immune-related diseases. Mol Cell Biochem 480(4):1969&#x2013;1981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11010-024-05077-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39060829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Zogg H, Wei L et al (2021) Gut microbial dysbiosis in the pathogenesis of gastrointestinal dysmotility and metabolic disorders. J Neurogastroenterol Motil 27(1):19&#x2013;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5056/jnm20149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7786094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baunwall SMD, Lee MM, Eriksen MK et al (2020) Faecal microbiota transplantation for recurrent Clostridioides difficile infection: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. eClinicalMedicine 29&#x2013;30:100642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33437951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7788438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porcari S, Baunwall SMD, Occhionero AS et al (2023) Fecal microbiota transplantation for recurrent C. difficile infection in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Autoimmun 141:103036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaut.2023.103036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37098448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sbahi H, Di Palma JA (2016) Faecal microbiota transplantation: applications and limitations in treating gastrointestinal disorders. BMJ Open Gastroenterol 3(1):e000087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgast-2016-000087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27239328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4873946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng L, Deng Y, Yang K, Chen J, He Q, Chen H (2022) Safety and efficacy of fecal microbiota transplantation for autoimmune diseases and autoinflammatory diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Immunol 13:944387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.944387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36248877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9562921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Siliceo SL, Ni Y, Nielsen HB, Xu A, Panagiotou G (2023) Identification of robust and generalizable biomarkers for microbiome-based stratification in lifestyle interventions. Microbiome 11(1):178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-023-01604-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37553697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10408196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;yer KL, Dahl Baunwall SM, Kornum DS et al (2025) Faecal microbiota transplantation for patients with diabetes type 1 and severe gastrointestinal neuropathy (FADIGAS): a randomised, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. eClinicalMedicine 79:100300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.103000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sechovcov&#xe1; H, Mahayri TM, Mr&#xe1;zek J et al (2024) Gut microbiota in relationship to diabetes mellitus and its late complications with a focus on diabetic foot syndrome: a review. Folia Microbiol (Praha) 69(2):259&#x2013;282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12223-023-01119-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38095802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe1;zala-de-Oliveira T, Jannini de S&#xe1; YAP, Carvalho VF (2023) Impact of gut-peripheral nervous system axis on the development of diabetic neuropathy. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz 118:e220197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0074-02760220197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36946851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10027071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis SJ, Heaton KW (1997) Stool form scale as a useful guide to intestinal transit time. Scand J Gastroenterol 32(9):920&#x2013;924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365529709011203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9299672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Likert R (1932) A technique for the measurement of attitudes. Arch Psychol 22(140):1&#x2013;55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiklund IK, Fullerton S, Hawkey CJ et al (2003) An irritable bowel syndrome-specific symptom questionnaire: development and validation. Scand J Gastroenterol 38:947&#x2013;954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00365520310004209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14531531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen MM, R&#xe5;g&#xe5;rd N, Andreasen PW et al (2024) Encapsulated donor faeces for faecal microbiota transplantation: the Glyprotect protocol. Therap Adv Gastroenterol 17:17562848241289064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17562848241289065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39421003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11483698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvas CL, Dahl J&#xf8;rgensen SM, J&#xf8;rgensen SP et al (2019) Fecal microbiota transplantation is superior to fidaxomicin for treatment of recurrent Clostridium difficile infection. Gastroenterology 156(5):1324-1332.e3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2018.12.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen SMD, Hansen MM, Erikstrup C, Dahlerup JF, Hvas CL (2017) Faecal microbiota transplantation: establishment of a clinical application framework. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 29(11):e36&#x2013;e45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MEG.0000000000000958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28863010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baunwall SMD, Dahlerup JF, Engberg JH et al (2021) Danish national guideline for the treatment of Clostridioides difficile infection and use of faecal microbiota transplantation (FMT). Scand J Gastroenterol 56(9):1056&#x2013;1077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00365521.2021.1922749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services (2017) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0. Available from: https://ctep.cancer.gov/protocolDevelopment/ Accessed 25 Jan 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horv&#xe1;th VJ, Putz Z, Izb&#xe9;ki F et al (2015) Diabetes-related dysfunction of the small intestine and the colon: focus on motility. Curr Diab Rep 15(11):94</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11892-015-0672-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26374571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verrotti A, Prezioso G, Scattoni R, Chiarelli F (2014) Autonomic neuropathy in diabetes mellitus. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 5:205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2014.00205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Neng Q, Li Y et al (2021) Gastrointestinal autonomic neuropathy exacerbates gut microbiota dysbiosis in adult patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Front Cell Infect Microbiol 11:804733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2021.804733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35211420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su SH, Wu YF, Lin Q, Zhang L, Wang DP, Hai J (2022) Fecal microbiota transplantation and replenishment of short-chain fatty acids protect against chronic cerebral hypoperfusion-induced colonic dysfunction by regulating gut microbiota, differentiation of Th17 cells, and mitochondrial energy metabolism. J Neuroinflammation 19(1):313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-022-02675-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36567333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9791754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Zhou Y, Xu J et al (2024) Short-chain fatty acid-producing bacterial strains attenuate experimental ulcerative colitis by promoting M2 macrophage polarization via JAK/STAT3/FOXO3 axis inactivation. J Transl Med 22(1):369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-024-05122-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38637862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11025230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peery AF, Kelly CR, Kao D et al (2024) AGA clinical practice guideline on fecal microbiota-based therapies for select gastrointestinal diseases. Gastroenterology 166(3):409&#x2013;434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2024.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;lden E, Wong FS, Wen L (2015) The gut microbiota and type 1 diabetes. Clin Immunol 159(2):143&#x2013;153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clim.2015.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26051037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4761565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng P, Li Z, Zhou Z (2018) Gut microbiome in type 1 diabetes: a comprehensive review. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 34(7):e3043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.3043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29929213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6220847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan K, Chung SK, Vanamala J, Xu B (2018) Causal relationship between diet-induced gut microbiota changes and diabetes: a novel strategy to transplant Faecalibacterium prausnitzii in preventing diabetes. Int J Mol Sci 19(12):3720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms19123720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30467295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6320976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatanen T, Franzosa EA, Schwager R et al (2018) The human gut microbiome in early-onset type 1 diabetes from the TEDDY study. Nature 562(7728):589&#x2013;594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-018-0620-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6296767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapoport EA, Baig M, Puli SR (2022) Adverse events in fecal microbiota transplantation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Gastroenterol 35(2):150&#x2013;163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35479587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8922263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi M, Shirsalimi N, Hashempour Z et al (2024) Safety and efficacy of fecal microbiota transplantation (FMT) as a modern adjuvant therapy in various diseases and disorders: a comprehensive literature review. Front Immunol 15:1439176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1439176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39391303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11464302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi R, Masouri MM, SalehiAmniyehKhozani AA, Ramadhan Hussein D, Nejadghaderi SA (2024) Safety and efficacy of fecal microbiota transplantation for viral diseases: a systematic review of clinical trials. PLoS One 19(10):e0311731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0311731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39432486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11493255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Yan J, Li S et al (2024) Efficacy of fecal microbiota transplantation in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Endocrine 84(1):48&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-023-03606-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38001323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>