<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40772068</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2277-9531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of education and health promotion</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Educ Health Promot</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nurse-led social media-based education in diabetic patients: Effects on COVID-19 fear and self-care - A 6-month follow-up trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>270</StartPage><MedlinePgn>270</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">270</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jehp.jehp_2292_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To evaluate the effect of nurse-led, social media-based patient education on COVID-19-associated fear and self-care in diabetic patients throughout a six-month follow-up period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A single-blind randomized controlled trial. A total of 113 diabetic patients were recruited using convenience sampling and randomly assigned to the intervention group (<i>n</i> = 58) or control group (<i>n</i> = 55). Data were collected using the Fear of COVID-19 Scale (FCV-19S) and the Self-Care in COVID-19 Scale (SCOVID) at baseline, immediately after the intervention, and at two- and six-month follow-ups. The intervention group received a four-week COVID-19-related patient education program via social media, while the control group only received routine care. Data were analyzed using IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, version 20 (IBM Corp., Armonk, N.Y., USA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No significant differences in fear or self-care scores were observed between the groups at baseline (<i>P</i> &gt; 0.05). However, the intervention group exhibited significant improvements in both fear and self-care scores at all post-intervention time points compared to the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The reduction in fear scores was more pronounced between T1 (immediately after the intervention) and T2 (two months after the intervention), whereas it remained relatively stable between T2 and T3 (six months after the intervention). This indicated a sustained intervention effect over time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Social media-based nurse-led education effectively reduces COVID-19-associated fear and improves self-care in diabetic patients, with benefits sustained for up to six months. This approach is recommended for accessible, scalable patient education during pandemics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Education and Health Promotion.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadeghian</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical-Surgical Nursing, School of Nursing and Midwifery, Zanjan University of Medical Sciences, Zanjan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tataei</LastName><ForeName>Azadeh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Information Technology, School of Allied Medical Sciences, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, Urmia, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fallah</LastName><ForeName>Ramazan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, School of Medicine, Zanjan University of Medical Sciences, Zanjan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zirak</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical-Surgical Nursing, Maragheh University of Medical Sciences, Maragheh, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Educ Health Promot</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101593794</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2277-9531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social media</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40772068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12327711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_2292_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JEHP-14-270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tavakoli A, Vahdat K, Keshavarz M. Novel Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19): An Emerging Infectious Disease in the 21st Century. Iran South Med J. 2020;22:432&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdi M. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak in Iran: Actions and problems. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2020;41:754&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7137533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO  . WHO; 2021. Weekly epidemiological update on COVID-19-7 December 2021. Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/weekly-epidemiological-update-on-covid-19---7-december-2021 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghian A, Fallah R, Zirak M. The effect of patient education through social media on the COVID-19-related anxiety in patients with diabetes: A single-blind clinical trial. Avicenna J Nurs Midwifery Care. 2022;30:134&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang WR, Wang K, Yin L, Zhao W-f, Xue Q, Peng M, et al. Mental health and psychosocial problems of medical health workers during the COVID-19 epidemic in China. Psychother Psychosom. 2020;89:242&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7206349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32272480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cure E, Cure MC. Angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors and angiotensin receptor blockers may be harmful in patients with diabetes during COVID-19 pandemic. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14:349&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AK, Gupta R, Ghosh A, Misra A. Diabetes in COVID-19: Prevalence, pathophysiology, prognosis and practical considerations. Diabetes Metab Syndr Clin Res Rev. 2020;14:303&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann-Boyce J, Morris E, Goyder C, Kinton J, Perring J, Nunan D, et al. Diabetes and COVID-19: Risks, management, and learnings from other national disasters. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:1695&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musche V, Kohler H, B&#xe4;uerle A, Schweda A, Weism&#xfc;ller B, Fink M, et al. COVID-19-related fear, risk perception, and safety behavior in individuals with diabetes. Healthcare (Basel) 2021;9:480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhormi AH, Mahfouz MS, Alshahrani NZ, Hummadi A, Hakami WA, Alattas DH, et al. Psychological health and diabetes self-management among patients with type 2 diabetes during COVID-19 in the Southwest of Saudi Arabia. Medicina. 2022;58:675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9146289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35630093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bala R, Srivastava A, Potsangbam T, Anal L, Ningthoujam GD. Self care practices and psychological distress among diabetic patients in Manipur during COVID-19: A scenario from the North East. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15:93&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33316765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musche V, Kohler H, B&#xe4;uerle A, Schweda A, Weism&#xfc;ller B, Fink M, Schadendorf T, Robitzsch A, D&#xf6;rrie N, Tan S, Teufel M. COVID-19-related fear, risk perception, and safety behavior in individuals with diabetes. Healthcare. 2021 Apr 18;9(4):480. MDPI.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy A, Rogers A, Bower P. Support for self care for patients with chronic disease. BMJ. 2007;335:968&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2071971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17991978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehraeen E, Hayati B, Saeidi S, Heydari M, Seyedalinaghi S. Self-care instructions for people not requiring hospitalization for coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Arch Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Apr 2;15(COVID-19):e102978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhizhpon-Quinde TC, Mesa-Cano IC, Ram&#xed;rez-Coronel AA. Prevention of COVID-19 through Dorothea Orem&#x2019;s self-care theory. Int J Innovative Sci and Res Technol. 2021;6:809&#x2013;815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausili D, Bulgheroni M, Ballatore P, Specchia C, Ajdini A, Bezze S, et al. Self-care, quality of life and clinical outcomes of type 2 diabetes patients: An observational cross-sectional study. Acta Diabet. 2017;54:1001&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28852863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausili D, Bulgheroni M, Ballatore P, Specchia C, Ajdini A, Bezze S, et al. Self-care, quality of life and clinical outcomes of type 2 diabetes patients: An observational cross-sectional study. Acta Diabetol. 2017;54:1001&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28852863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustman PJ, Clouse RE. Depression in diabetic patients: The relationship between mood and glycemic control. J Diabetes Complications. 2005;19:113&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15745842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins LB, Braga Tibaes JR, Berk M, Teixeira AL. Diabetes and mood disorders: Shared mechanisms and therapeutic opportunities. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract. 2022;26:183&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34348557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessi J, de Oliveira GB, Franco DW, Brino do Amaral B, Becker AS, Knijnik CP, et al. Mental health in the era of COVID-19: Prevalence of psychiatric disorders in a cohort of patients with type 1 and type 2 diabetes during the social distancing. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2020;12:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7457442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32879637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee M, Chakraborty S, Pal R. Diabetes self-management amid COVID-19 pandemic. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14:351&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Maria M, Ferro F, Ausili D, Alvaro R, De Marinis MG, Di Mauro S, et al. Development and Psychometric Testing of the Self-Care in COVID-19 (SCOVID) Scale, an Instrument for Measuring Self-Care in the COVID-19 Pandemic. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:7834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7663643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awang Ahmad NA, Sallehuddin MAA, Teo YC, Abdul Rahman H. Self-care management of patients with diabetes: Nurses&#x2019; perspectives. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2020;19:1537&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33520851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mheidly N, Fares J. Leveraging media and health communication strategies to overcome the COVID-19 infodemic. Journal of public health policy. 2020;41:410&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamanian M, Foroozanfar Z, Izadi Z, Jafari S, Derakhshankhah H, Salimi M, Janbakhsh A, Sayad B, Shirvani M, Jasemi SV, Mansouri F. Association of underlying diseases and clinical characteristics with mortality in patients with 2019 novel coronavirus in Iran. Arch Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Jan 1;15(5):e104621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolmes K. Social media in the future of professional psychology. Professional Psychol Res Pract. 2012;43:606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attai DJ, Cowher MS, Al-Hamadani M, Schoger JM, Staley AC, Landercasper J. Twitter social media is an effective tool for breast cancer patient education and support: Patient-reported outcomes by survey. J Med Int Res. 2015;17:e188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigle D, Mastrian KG. Jones and Bartlett Publishers; 2015. Nursing Informatics and the Foundation of Knowledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamrani F, Nikkhah S, Borhani F, Jalali M, Shahsavari S, Nirumand-Zandi K. The effect of patient education and nurse-led telephone follow-up (telenursing) on adherence to treatment in patients with acute coronary syndrome. Iran J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2015;4:16&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahorsu DK, Lin CY, Imani V, Saffari M, Griffiths MD, Pakpour AH. The fear of COVID-19 scale: Development and initial validation. Int J Ment Health Addict. 2022;20:1537&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7100496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32226353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakasam G, Rees C, Lyden M, Parkin CG. Use of a novel smartphone-based diabetes management system improved feelings of confidence and safety and reduced hypoglycemia fear among parents/caregivers of children/adolescents with type 1 diabetes. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2017;11:182&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5375059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marker AM, Monzon AD, Nelson E-L, Clements MA, Patton SR. An intervention to reduce hypoglycemia fear in parents of young kids with type 1 diabetes through video-based telemedicine (REDCHiP): Trial design, feasibility, and acceptability. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2020;22:25&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31517512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas J, Wang D, Su Z, Ziapour A. The role of social media in the advent COVID-19 pandemic: Crisis management. mental health challenges and implications. Risk Manag Healthc Policy. 2021;14:1917&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad AR, Murad HR. The impact of social media on panic during the COVID-19 pandemic in Iraqi Kurdistan: Online questionnaire study. J Med Int Res. 2020;22:e19556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehata WM, Abdeldaim DE. Social media and spreading panic among adults during the COVID-19 pandemic, Egypt. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2022;29(16):23374&#x2013;23382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8606231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34806145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammad MA, Alqarni TM. Psychosocial effects of social media on the Saudi society during the Coronavirus Disease 2019 pandemic: A cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0248811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7971843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33735309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsaleh DA, Elliott MT, Fu FQ, Thakur R. Cross-cultural differences in the adoption of social media. J Res Int Mark. 2019;13:119&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner M, Fischer T, Riedl R. Impact of content characteristics and emotion on behavioral engagement in social media: Literature review and research agenda. Electron Commer Res. 2021;21:329&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talie Fenta E, Bogale EK, Anagaw TF. The role of social media on COVID-19 preventive behaviors worldwide, systematic review. Plos One. 2024;19:e0306284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11236194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38985700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong CM, Lee TI, Chien YM, Kuo LN, Kuo YF, Chen HY. Social media&#x2013;delivered patient education to enhance self-management and attitudes of patients with type 2 diabetes during the COVID-19 pandemic: Randomized controlled trial. J Med Int Res. 2022;24:e31449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8987969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35319478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahramani A, de Courten M, Prokofieva M. The potential of social media in health promotion beyond creating awareness: An integrative review. BMC Public Health. 2022;22:2402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9770563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raesi R, Shaye ZA, Saghari S, Sheikh Beig Goharrizi MA, Raei M, Hushmandi K. The impact of education through nurse-led telephone follow-up (telenursing) on the quality of life of COVID-19 patients. J Egypt Public Health Assoc. 2021;96:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8574947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34748085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houben-Wilke S, Go&#xeb;rtz YM, Delbressine JM, Vaes AW, Meys R, Machado FV, et al. The impact of long COVID-19 on mental health: Observational 6-month follow-up study. JMIR Mental Health. 2022;9:e33704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8914795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35200155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>