<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41006128</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2496</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Urologic oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Urol Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Addition of androgen-receptor pathway inhibitors to standard of care in metastatic hormone-sensitive prostate cancer: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1078-1439(25)00344-8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.urolonc.2025.08.017</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To evaluate activity, safety and nuances of androgen-receptor pathway inhibitors (ARPI) with standard-of-care therapy (SOC), i.e., androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) alone or with docetaxel, for metastatic hormone-sensitive prostate cancer (mHSPC). Several randomized clinical trials (RCTs) have evaluated different agents in this setting. We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis to better define the benefits and risks of combining ARPI with SOC in mHSPC. A comprehensive literature search of MEDLINE/PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, and meeting abstracts from the American Society of Clinical Oncology (ASCO) and European Society of Medical Oncology (ESMO) was performed in April 2025. The study adhered to PRISMA guidelines for systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Overall survival (OS) was the primary endpoint, with progression-free survival (PFS), time-to-progression of pain and PSA, and safety as secondary endpoints. Summary hazard ratios (HRs) were calculated for survival outcomes, and risk ratios (RRs) for safety. Random- or fixed-effects models were applied based on study heterogeneity. Eight RCTs fulfilled the prespecified inclusion criteria. The combination of ARPI and SOC significantly improved OS (HR = 0.74; P &lt; 0.00001) and PFS (HR = 0.50 for clinical PFS, HR = 0.49 for radiological PFS; P &lt; 0.0001) compared to the SOC. The benefit was confirmed excluding docetaxel. We did not show heterogeneity among treatment efficacy and disease burden, onset timing or treatment strategy. Adverse events (AEs) were not increased after adding ARPI to SOC, except from hypertension and any grade cardiac AEs. This meta-analysis supports the addition of ARPI to SOC in mHSPC, significantly improving survival outcomes. Uncertainties persist regarding the role of triple therapies including docetaxel. Identifying prognostic and predictive biomarkers is critical to tailoring therapy for patients most likely to benefit from different approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maiorano</LastName><ForeName>Brigida Anna</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy. Electronic address: maiorano.brigida@hsr.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mercinelli</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cigliola</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tateo</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gandaglia</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Briganti</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montorsi</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Necchi</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, IRCCS San Raffaele Hospital, Milan, Italy; Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Urol Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9805460</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-1439</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ARPI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abiraterone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apalutamide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Castration sensitive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Darolutamide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enzalutamide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormone sensitive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MCSPC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MHSPC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prostate cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following conflicts of interest: BAM: Honoraria: Bayer, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Merck; Consulting or Advisory role: Bayer, AstraZeneca, Astellas, Janssen, IPSEN, Merck. Research Funding (Institution): Merck. Travel, Accommodations, Expenses: AstraZeneca, Janssen, IPSEN, Merck. GG: Honoraria: Bayer, Accord, IPSEN, Janssen. AB: Consulting or advisory role: Astellas, Janssen-Cilag, OPKO Health, MDxHealth, Ferring, Bayer, AstraZeneca, Hauora and Pfizer; speakers' bureau: Astellas; Research funding: Sandoz-Novartis, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Janssen, and Pfizer. G.S.K. reports honoraria: AbbVie, Tersera, Bayer, Knight Pharmaceuticals, AstraZeneca Canada and PhotoCure; Consulting or advisory role: Merck, Theralase, Janssen Oncology, Ferring, Verity Pharmaceuticals, Bristol Myers Squibb, EMD Serono, Pfizer, Novartis and enGene. AN: Honoraria: Roche, MSD, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Foundation Medicine, BMS, Astellas. Consulting or Advisory role: MSD, Roche, Bayer, AstraZeneca, Clovis Oncology, Janssen, Incyte, Seattle Genetics/Astellas, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Rainier Therapeutics, Bicycle Therapeutics, GlaxoSmithKline, Basilea Pharmaceutica, Catalym. Research Funding (Institution): MSD, AstraZeneca, Ipsen, Gilead. Travel, Accommodations, Expenses: Roche, MSD, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Rainer Therapeutics, Pfizer. Employment and Stock Ownership (spouse): Bayer. The other authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41006128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.urolonc.2025.08.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1078-1439(25)00344-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>