<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40342737</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0972-8988</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary world</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet World</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Therapeutic potential of <i>Coprinus comatus</i> nanogels: Antiarthritic and anti-inflammatory effects in rheumatoid arthritis models.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>582</StartPage><EndPage>597</EndPage><MedlinePgn>582-597</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14202/vetworld.2025.582-597</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Rheumatoid arthritis (RA) is a chronic autoimmune disorder characterized by persistent joint inflammation and systemic immune dysregulation. The current pharmacological treatments, primarily synthetic drugs, often present adverse effects and long-term toxicity. This study explores the therapeutic potential of <i>Coprinus comatus</i> nanogels as a novel herbal formulation with antiarthritic and anti-inflammatory properties in a Complete Freund's Adjuvant (CFA)-induced rat model of RA. The study aims to evaluate the efficacy of <i>C. comatus</i> nanogels in reducing pro-inflammatory cytokine levels, antibody production, paw edema, and arthritis indices and to assess their potential as a safer alternative to conventional RA therapies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-four male Wistar rats were randomized into six groups: Healthy control, negative control (CFA-induced without treatment), positive control (sodium diclofenac 0.012 g/mL), and three treatment groups (TG1, TG2, and TG3) receiving 250, 500, and 750 mg/kg <i>C. comatus</i> nanogels, respectively. Oral treatments were administered for 30 days. Pro-inflammatory cytokines (tumor necrosis factor-alpha [TNF-&#x3b1;], interleukin [IL]-6, IL-1&#x3b2;), antibodies (immunoglobulin [Ig]G, IgE), cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) enzyme activity, paw edema, and arthritis indices were measured using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay and standard methods. Statistical analyses were conducted using one-way analysis of variance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The 750 mg/kg dose of <i>C. comatus</i> nanogels significantly reduced TNF-&#x3b1; (17.71%), IL-1&#x3b2; (19.83%), and IgE (23.91%) levels. The 250 mg/kg dose exhibited the highest reductions in IL-6 (30.88%) and COX-2 (16.54%) levels. TGs demonstrated a 27.75% reduction in paw edema and a 45.45% reduction in arthritis indices. Key bioactive compounds contributing to these effects included flavonoids, polyphenols, triterpenoids, and &#x3b2;-glucans.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED"><i>C. comatus</i> nanogels demonstrated promising anti-inflammatory and antiarthritic properties, suggesting their potential as an alternative herbal treatment for RA. Further studies are recommended to explore the long-term safety and clinical applicability of <i>C. comatus</i> nanogels in human RA management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Ratnaningtyas and Husen.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratnaningtyas</LastName><ForeName>Nuniek Ina</ForeName><Initials>NI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Faculty of Biology, Universitas Jenderal Soedirman (UNSOED), Purwokerto 53122, Central Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Husen</LastName><ForeName>Fajar</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory of Technology, Bina Cipta Husada College of Health Science, Purwokerto 53144, Central Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Vet World</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101504872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0972-8988</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coprinus comatus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-inflammatory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokine reduction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">herbal medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nanogels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40342737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12056907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14202/vetworld.2025.582-597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">Vetworld-18-582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Husen F, Fitrianto N. Lingzhi or reishi medicinal mushroom Ganoderma lucidum (Agaricomycetes) nanogel in complete Freund's adjuvant-induced rheumatoid arthritis (RA) rat model:Anti-arthritic, anti-inflammatory, and antioxidative activity. Int. J. Med. Mush. 2024;26(8):27&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng M, Yao J, Zhang Y, Sun H, Liu M. Potential anti-rheumatoid arthritis activities and mechanisms of Ganoderma lucidum Polysaccharides. Molecules. 2023;28(6):2483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10052150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36985456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo S.H, Lee J, Hutchinson D, Song Y.W. Prevalence of rheumatoid arthritis in relation to serum cadmium concentrations:Cross-sectional study using Korean National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (KNHANES) data. BMJ Open. 2019;9(1):e023233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6326419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Hu W, Wang R, Yang Q, Zhu M, Li M, Cai J, Rose J, Mao J, Zhu Y.Z. Signaling pathways in rheumatoid arthritis:Implications for targeted therapy. Signal Transduct. Target Ther. 2023;8(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36797236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirani K, Iranshahi M, Askari V.R, Gholizadeh Z, Zadeh A.A, Zeinali M, Hassani F.V, Taherzadeh Z. Comparative evaluation of the protective effects of oral administration of auraptene and umbelliprenin against CFA-induced chronic inflammation with polyarthritis in rats. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2021;139:111635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34243601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Ma H, Zhang H, Deng C, Xin P. Recent advances on signaling pathways and their inhibitors in rheumatoid arthritis. Clin. Immunol. 2021;230:108793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34242749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbiantcha M, Almas J, Shabana S.U, Nida D, Aisha F. Anti-arthritic property of crude extracts of Piptadeniastrum africanum in complete Freund's adjuvant-induced arthritis in rats. BMC Comp. Alternat. Med. 2017;17(1):111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5311858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju Z, Li M, Xu J, Howell D.C, Li Z, Chen F.E. Recent development on COX-2 inhibitors as promising anti-inflammatory agents:The past 10 years. Acta Pharma Sin B. 2022;12(6):2790&#x2013;2807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35755295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Hernayanti Ekowati N, Husen F. Nephroprotective and antioxidant effects of ethanol extract of Coprinus comatus mushroom fruit-bodies on streptozotocin-induced diabetic rat models. IOP Conf Ser. Earth Environ. Sci. 2021;948:012078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Hernayanti H, Ekowati N, Husen F. Ethanol extract of the mushroom Coprinus comatus exhibits antidiabetic and antioxidant activities in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Pharm. Biol. 2022;60(1):1126&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9186368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35675226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Husen F, Hernayanti Ekowati, N, Budianto B.H. Anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressant activity of Coprinus comatus ethanol extract in carrageenan-induced rats of Rattus norvegicus. Molekul. 2022;17(3):336&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valkov&#xe1; V, D&#xfa;ranov&#xe1; H, Falcimaigne-Cordin A, Rossi C, Nadaud F, Nesterenko A, Moncada M, Orel M, Ivani&#x161;ov&#xe1; E, Chlebova Z, Gabriny L, Ka&#x10d;&#xe1;niov&#xe1; M. Impact of freeze-and spray-drying microencapsulation techniques on -glucan powder biological activity:A comparative study. Foods. 2022;11(15):2267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stilinovi&#x107; N, &#x10c;apo I, Vukmirovi&#x107; S, Ra&#x161;kovi&#x107; A, Tomas A, Popovi&#x107; M, Sabo A. Chemical composition, nutritional profile and in vivo antioxidant properties of the cultivated mushroom Coprinus comatus:Comprimus comatus properties. R. Soc. Open Sci. 2020;7(9):200900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Wang Q.W, Zuo J, Chen J.W, Li X. Anti-arthritic activity of ethanol extract of Claoxylon indicum on Freund's complete adjuvant-induced arthritis in mice. BMC Complement Alter. Med. 2017;17(1):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5216541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28056924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamgir A.N.M. Herbal drugs:Their collection, preservation, and preparation;evaluation, quality control, and standardization of herbal drugs. Pharmacognosy. 2017;1:453&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Alhareth K, Mignet N. Advancement in Nanogel formulations provides controlled drug release. Int. J. Pharm. 2020;584:119435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava S, Saha S, Jakhmola V. Nanogel:Types, methods of preparation, limitation, evaluation and application-a systematic review. Int. J. Drug Deliv. Tech. 2023;13(4):1631&#x2013;1639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitwell C, Indra S.S, Luke C, Kakoma M.K. A review of modern and conventional extraction techniques and their applications for extracting phytochemicals from plants. Sci Afr. 2023;19(5):e01585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadab M, Alhakamy N.A, Aldawsari H.M, Kotta S, Ahmad J, Akhter S, Alam M.S, Khan M.A, Awan Z, Sivakuymar P.M. Improved analgesic and anti-inflammatory effect of diclofenac sodium by topical nanoemulgel:Formulation development-in vitro and in vivo studies. J. Chem. 2020;1:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Husen F, Sukmawati D, Wibowo E.S, Hikam A.R, Aksoy A. Antidiabetic effects and enzymatic antioxidant activity of chicken drumstick mushroom (Coprinus comatus) extract in diabetic rats model. J. Pure Appl. Microbiol. 2022;16(4):2764&#x2013;2774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Hernayanti Ekowati N, Husen F, Maulida I, Kustianingrum R, Vika V. Antioxidant activities and properties of Coprinus comatus mushroom both mycelium and fruiting body extracts in streptozotocin-induced hyperglycemic rats model. Biosaintifika J. Biol. Biol. Educ. 2022;14(1):9&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annamalai P, Thangam E.B. Local and systemic profiles of inflammatory cytokines in Carrageenan-induced paw inflammation in rats. Immunol. Invest. 2017;46(3):274&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27967265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snekhalatha U, Anburajan M, Venkatraman B, Menaka M. Evaluation of complete Freund's adjuvant-induced arthritis in a Wistar rat model:Comparison of thermography and histopathology. Z. Rheumatol. 2013;72(4):375&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23208192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi H, Mostafazadeh M, Sadeghi H, Barmak M.J, Talebianpoor M.S, Mehraban F. In vivo anti-inflammatory properties of aerial parts of Nasturtium officinale. Pharm. Biol. 2014;52(2):169&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24160746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd-Allah A.A.M, El-Deen N.A.M.N, Mohamed W.A.M, Naguib F.M. Mast cells and pro-inflammatory cytokines roles in assessment of grape seeds extract anti-inflammatory activity in rat model of Carrageenan-induced paw edema. Iran J. Basic Med. Sci. 2018;21(1):97&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5776444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;uczak A, Madej M, Kasprzyk A, Doroszko A. Role of the eNOS uncoupling and the nitric oxide metabolic pathway in the pathogenesis of autoimmune rheumatic diseases. Oxid. Med. Cell Long. 2020;2020:1417981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguemnang D.S.F, Tsafack E.G, Mbiantcha M, Gilbert A, Atsamo A.D, Nana W.Y, Matah Marthe Mba V, Adjouzem C.F. In vitro anti-inflammatory and in vivo antiarthritic activities of aqueous and ethanolic extracts of Dissotis thollonii Cogn. (Melastomataceae) in rats. Evid. Based Complement Alternat. Med. 2019;2019:3612481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6881768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31827550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowakowski P, Naliwajko S.K, Markiewicz-&#x17b;ukowska R, Borawska M.H, Socha K. The two faces of Coprinus comatus-functional properties and potential hazards. Phytother. Res. 2020;34(11):2932&#x2013;2944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7754439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engdahl C, Bondt A, Harre U, Raufer J, Pfeifle R, Camponeschi A, Wuhrer M, Seeling M, Martensson L.L, Nimmerjhn F, Kroke G, Scherer H.U, Fosbald-d'Elia H, Schett G. Estrogen induces St6gal1 expression and increases IgG sialylation in mice and patients with rheumatoid arthritis:A potential explanation for the increased risk of rheumatoid arthritis in postmenopausal women. Arthritis Res. Ther. 2018;20(1):84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Q, Gong F.Y, Gong Z, Hua S.H, Zeng K.Q, Gao X.M. IgG immunocomplexes sensitize human monocytes for inflammatory hyperactivity via transcriptomic and epigenetic reprogramming in rheumatoid arthritis. J. Immunol. 2018;200(12):3913&#x2013;3925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29712771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem A, Saleem M, Akhtar M.F, Shahzad M, Jahan S. Moringa rivae leaf extracts attenuate Complete Freund's adjuvant-induced arthritis in Wistar rats via modulation of inflammatory and oxidative stress biomarkers. Inflammopharmacology. 2020;28(1):139&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31037575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Zhang J, Liu X, Yang Q, Dong Y, Jia L. The antioxidant activities of alkalic-extractable polysaccharides from Coprinus comatus on alcohol-induced liver injury in mice. Sci. Rep. 2018;8(1):11695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6076309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanno T, Kazumura K, Niwa T, Harada E, Miyake Y, Osawa T. Evaluation of anti-inflammatory properties of hot water extract from Coprinus comatus using HL-60 and 3T3-L1 cells. J. Food Chem. Saf. 2020;27(2):53&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnaningtyas N.I, Hernayanti Ekowati N, Sukmawati D, Widianti H. Chicken drumstick mushroom (Coprinus comatus) ethanol extract exerts a hypoglycaemic effect in the Rattus norvegicus model of diabetes. Biocatal. Agric. Biotech. 2019;19:101050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhambri A, Srivastava M, Mahale V.G, Mahale S, Karn S.K. Mushrooms as potential sources of active metabolites and medicines. Front. Microbiol. 2022;13:837266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35558110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y.L, Han F, Luan S.S, Ai R, Zhang P, Li H, Chen L.X. Triterpenoids from Ganoderma lucidum and their potential anti-inflammatory effects. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2019;67(18):5147&#x2013;5158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30995041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Te&#x161;anovi&#x107; K, Pejin B, &#x160;ibul F, Matavulj M, Ra&#x161;eta M, Janju&#x161;evi&#x107; L, Karaman M. A comparative overview of antioxidative properties and phenolic profiles of different fungal origins:Fruiting bodies and submerged cultures of Coprinus comatus and Coprinellus truncorum. J. Food Sci. Tech. 2017;54(2):430&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5306037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28242942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golak-Siwulska I, Ka&#x142;uzewicz A, Spizewski T, Siwulski M, Sobieralski K. Bioactive compounds and medicinal properties of Oyster mushrooms (Pleurotus sp.) Folia Hortic. 2018;30(2):191&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waktola G, Temesgen T. Pharmacological activities of Oyster mushroom (Pleurotus ostreatus) Novel Res. Microbiol. J. 2020;4(2):688&#x2013;695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayasuriya W.J.A.B.N, Handunnetti S.M, Wanigatunge C.A, Fernando G.H, Abeytunga D.T.U, Suresh T.S. Anti-inflammatory activity of Pleurotus ostreatus, a culinary medicinal mushroom, in Wistar rats. Evid. Based Complement. Alternat. Med 2020. 2020:6845383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7077046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serafini M, Peluso I, Raguzzini A. Flavonoids as anti-inflammatory agents. Proc. Nutr. Soc. 2010;69(3):273&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20569521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husen F, Hernayanti H, Ekowati N, Sukmawati D, Ratnaningtyas N.I. Antidiabetic effects and antioxidant properties of the saggy ink cap medicinal mushroom, Coprinus comatus (Agaricomycetes) on streptozotocin-induced hyperglycemic rats. Int. J. Med. Mushrooms. 2021;23(10):9&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34595888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>