<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40988828</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vitamin D Supplementation in Deficiency States and Combined Calcium-Vitamin D Therapy in Diabetes Prevention and Management: A Systematic Review of Clinical Evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e90776</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e90776</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e90776</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.90776</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vitamin D and calcium are necessary for maintaining metabolic and endocrine homeostasis. These micronutrients may be linked to the onset of diabetic mellitus (DM), according to recent research. To examine the impact of vitamin D and calcium supplementation on the prevention and treatment of type 1 DM (T1DM) and type 2 DM (T2DM), the body of existing research is critically assessed in this systematic review.&#xa0;A comprehensive and methodical literature search was conducted across multiple databases, including PubMed, Embase, Scopus, and the Cochrane Library, covering publications up to January 2025, to identify relevant studies assessing the association between vitamin D and/or calcium levels and the risk of diabetes or glycemic control. The review considered various study designs, such as randomized controlled trials (RCTs), prospective and retrospective cohort studies, as well as case-control analyses, to ensure a robust evaluation of the available evidence. From an initial pool of 3,247 publications, 68 studies qualified for final inclusion. Increased level of vitamin D concentrations was constantly linked to a lower risk of developing T2DM across multiple studies. In addition, other clinical studies demonstrated that supplementation of vitamin D resulted in significant improvements in insulin sensitivity and enhanced pancreatic &#x3b2;-cell function, with the most evident benefits in vitamin D-deficient subjects. While calcium alone showed inconsistent effects, combined supplementation yielded modest yet statistically significant improvements in blood glucose regulation. Vitamin D is a proven micronutrient to regulate glucose metabolism and reduce DM risk, especially in deficient populations. Calcium-vitamin D co-supplementation shows an effective agent for diabetes care; however, more in-depth studies are needed to determine how vitamin D alone, calcium alone, and both together regulate glucose metabolism, and to provide clear evidence to diabetes researchers about how these molecular mechanisms work.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Saad et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saad</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Government Medical College Karimnagar, Karimnagar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sathyam</LastName><ForeName>Durgam</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Government Medical College Kumuram Bheem Asifabad, Pippalgaon, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koora</LastName><ForeName>Sravanthi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Surabhi Institute of Medical Sciences, Siddipet, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kottireddy</LastName><ForeName>Satyanarayana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Government Medical College Karimnagar, Karimnagar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">co-supplementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glycemic control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 1 diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin d</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40988828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12451038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.90776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of care in diabetes-2023. ElSayed NA, Aleppo G, Aroda VR, et al. Diabetes Care. 2023;46:0&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36507649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization: Diabetes. 2024. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/diabetes https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/diabetes</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IDF Diabetes Atlas, 11th Edition. Brussels, Belgium: International Diabetes Federation; 2025. IDF Diabetes Atlas 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis and classification of diabetes: standards of care in diabetes-2024. Diabetes Care. 2024;47:0&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10725812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38078589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutrition therapy for adults with diabetes or prediabetes: a consensus report. Evert AB, Dennison M, Gardner CD, et al. Diabetes Care. 2019;42:731&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7011201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D deficiency. Holick MF. N Engl J Med. 2007;357:266&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17634462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and immune function. Prietl B, Treiber G, Pieber TR, Amrein K. Nutrients. 2013;5:2502&#x2013;2521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23857223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identification of a vitamin D response element in the human insulin receptor gene promoter. Maestro B, D&#xe1;vila N, Carranza MC, et al. J. Steroid Biochem. Mol. Biol. 2003;84:223&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12711007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and calcium intake in relation to type 2 diabetes in women. Pittas AG, Dawson-Hughes B, Li T, Van Dam RM, Willett WC, Manson JE, Hu FB. Diabetes Care. 2006;29:650&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16505521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D supplementation and prevention of type 2 diabetes. Pittas AG, Dawson-Hughes B, Sheehan P, et al. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:520&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6993875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of vitamin d supplementation on glucose control and inflammatory response in type II diabetes: a double blind, randomized clinical trial. Al-Sofiani ME, Jammah A, Racz M, et al. Int J Endocrinol Metab. 2015;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4338666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25745497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baseline serum 25-hydroxy vitamin d is predictive of future glycemic status and insulin resistance: the Medical Research Council Ely Prospective Study 1990-2000. Forouhi NG, Luan J, Cooper A, Boucher BJ, Wareham NJ. Diabetes. 2008;57:2619&#x2013;2625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2551670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18591391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypovitaminosis D is associated with insulin resistance and beta cell dysfunction. Chiu KC, Chu A, Go VL, Saad MF. Am J Clin Nutr. 2004;79:820&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15113720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, diabetes, and ethnicity in the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Scragg R, Sowers M, Bell C. Diabetes Care. 2004;27:2813&#x2013;2818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15562190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood 25-hydroxy vitamin D levels and incident type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis of prospective studies. Song Y, Wang L, Pittas AG, Del Gobbo LC, Zhang C, Manson JE, Hu FB. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:1422&#x2013;1428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23613602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of vitamin D supplementation on prevention of type 2 diabetes in patients with prediabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zhang Y, Tan H, Tang J, et al. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:1650&#x2013;1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33534730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of vitamin D and calcium supplementation on pancreatic &#x3b2; cell function, insulin sensitivity, and glycemia in adults at high risk of diabetes: the calcium and vitamin D for diabetes mellitus (CaDDM) randomized controlled trial. Mitri J, Dawson-Hughes B, Hu FB, Pittas AG. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;94:486&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3142723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of vitamin D supplementation on insulin and glucose metabolism in overweight and obese individuals: systematic review with meta-analysis. Jamka M, Wo&#x17a;niewicz M, Jeszka J, Mardas M, Bogda&#x144;ski P, Stelmach-Mardas M. Sci Rep. 2015;5:16142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26543018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary calcium, vitamin D, and the prevalence of metabolic syndrome in middle-aged and older U.S. women. Liu S, Song Y, Ford ES, Manson JE, Buring JE, Ridker PM. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:2926&#x2013;2932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16306556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intratrial exposure to vitamin d and new-onset diabetes among adults with prediabetes: a secondary analysis from the vitamin D and type 2 diabetes (D2D) study. Dawson-Hughes B, Staten MA, Knowler WC, et al. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2916&#x2013;2922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7770274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33020052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of vitamin D and calcium in type 2 diabetes. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pittas AG, Lau J, Hu FB, Dawson-Hughes B. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007;92:2017&#x2013;2029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2085234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Expression of 25-hydroxyvitamin D3-1alpha-hydroxylase in pancreatic islets. Bland R, Markovic D, Hills CE, Hughes SV, Chan SL, Squires PE, Hewison M. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2004;89:121&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15225758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intake of vitamin D and risk of type 1 diabetes: a birth-cohort study. Hypponen E, Laara E, Reunanen A, et al. Lancet. 2001;358:1500&#x2013;1503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11705562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D supplementation in early childhood and risk of type 1 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zipitis CS, Akobeng AK. Arch Dis Child. 2008;93:512&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18339654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical review: effect of vitamin D3 supplementation on improving glucose homeostasis and preventing diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Seida JC, Mitri J, Colmers IN, et al. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014;99:3551&#x2013;3560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4483466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25062463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of vitamin D supplementation on glycaemic control and insulin resistance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. George PS, Pearson ER, Witham MD. Diabet Med. 2012;29:142&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22486204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of vitamin D supplementation on the incidence of diabetes mellitus. Barbarawi M, Zayed Y, Barbarawi O, et al. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32491181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. BMJ. 2021;372:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J. Chichester, UK: Wiley; 2019. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. BMJ. 2019;366:4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells GA, Shea B, O'Connell D, et al. Ottawa: Ottawa Hospital Research Institute (OHRI); 2014. The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration and subsequent risk of type 2 diabetes. Mattila C, Knekt P, M&#xe4;nnist&#xf6; S, Rissanen H, Laaksonen MA, Montonen J, Reunanen A. Diabetes Care. 2007;30:2569&#x2013;2570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17626891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcium, vitamin D and dairy intake in relation to type 2 diabetes risk in a Japanese cohort. Kirii K, Mizoue T, Iso H, et al. Diabetologia. 2009;52:2542&#x2013;2550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19823801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and mortality in older men and women. Pilz S, Dobnig H, Nijpels G, et al. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2009;71:666&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19226272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin d is associated with markers of the insulin resistant phenotype in nondiabetic adults. Liu E, Meigs JB, Pittas AG, McKeown NM, Economos CD, Booth SL, Jacques PF. https://doi.org/10.3945/jn.108.093831. J Nutr. 2009;139:329&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2646208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration and metabolic syndrome among middle-aged and elderly Chinese individuals. Lu L, Yu Z, Pan A, et al. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:1278&#x2013;1283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19366976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations are associated with a favorable serum lipid profile. Jorde R, Figenschau Y, Hutchinson M, Emaus N, Grimnes G. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejcn.2010.176. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2010;64:1457&#x2013;1464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20823896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baseline serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentrations in the Troms&#xf8; Study 1994-95 and risk of developing type 2 diabetes mellitus during 11 years of follow-up. Grimnes G, Emaus N, Joakimsen RM, et al. Diabet Med. 2010;27:1107&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plasma 25-hydroxyvitamin D concentration and risk of incident type 2 diabetes in women. Pittas AG, Sun Q, Manson JE, Dawson-Hughes B, Hu FB. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:2021&#x2013;2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20805275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of vitamin D with insulin resistance and beta-cell dysfunction in subjects at risk for type 2 diabetes. Kayaniyil S, Vieth R, Retnakaran R, et al. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:1379&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20215450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and incidence of diabetes: a prospective cohort study. Gonz&#xe1;lez-Molero I, Rojo-Mart&#xed;nez G, Morcillo S, et al. Clin Nutr. 2012;31:571&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22204964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort study and metaanalysis. Afzal S, Bojesen SE, Nordestgaard BG. Clin Chem. 2013;59:381&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23232064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Associations of serum calcium levels and dietary calcium intake with incident type 2 diabetes over 10 years: the Korean Genome and Epidemiology Study (KoGES) Kim KN, Oh SY, Hong YC. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2018;10:50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6006916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and risk of developing type 2 diabetes in the SUN project: a prospective cohort study. Valer-Martinez A, Bes-Rastrollo M, Say&#xf3;n-Orea C, et al. J Endocrinol Invest. 2024;47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11368983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38459212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glucose intolerance and impairment of insulin secretion in relation to vitamin D deficiency in east London Asians. Boucher BJ, Mannan N, Noonan K, Hales CN, Evans SJ. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00422375. Diabetologia. 1995;38:1239&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8690178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D, glucose tolerance and insulinaemia in elderly men. Baynes KC, Boucher BJ, Feskens EJ, Kromhout D. Diabetologia. 1997;40:344&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9084975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role of vitamin D in insulin secretion and insulin sensitivity for glucose homeostasis. Alvarez JA, Ashraf A. Int J Endocrinol. 2010;2010:351385&#x2013;351310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2778451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20011094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correlation between serum 25 hydroxy vitamin D3 and laboratory risk markers of cardiovascular diseases in type 2 diabetic patients. Bonakdaran S, Varasteh AR. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19370277/ Saudi Med J. 2009;30:509&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19370277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D levels at birth and risk of type 1 diabetes in childhood: a case-control study. Cadario F, Savastio S, Pagliardini V, et al. Acta Diabetol. 2015;52:1077&#x2013;1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26018939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D status and its association with insulin resistance among type 2 diabetics: a case -control study in Ghana. Fondjo LA, Owiredu WK, Sakyi SA, Laing EF, Adotey-Kwofie MA, Antoh EO, Detoh E. PLoS One. 2017;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5396912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28423063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Systematic review: associations of calcium intake, vitamin D intake, and physical activity with skeletal outcomes in people with Type 1 diabetes mellitus. Gil-D&#xed;az MC, Raynor J, O'Brien KO, Schwartz GJ, Weber DR. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00592-019-01334-5. Acta Diabetol. 2019;56:1091&#x2013;1102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6751023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30989378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D deficiency is significantly associated with retinopathy in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a case-control study. Castillo-Ot&#xed; JM, Galv&#xe1;n-Manso AI, Callejas-Herrero MR, Vara-Gonz&#xe1;lez LA, Salas-Herrera F, Mu&#xf1;oz-Cacho P. Nutrients. 2021;14:84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8746564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correlation between levels of vitamins D&#x2083; and E in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a case-control study in Serdang, Selangor, Malaysia. Razip NN, Gopalsamy B, Abdul Mutalib MS, et al. Nutrients. 2021;13:2288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8308395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A case-control study on the association between vitamin D deficiency and type 2 diabetes mellitus at tertiary care hospital in Jaipur. Gupta DK, Jain R, Choudhary S, et al. Int J Health Sci. 2022;6:11659&#x2013;11669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcium plus vitamin D supplementation and the risk of incident diabetes in the Women's Health Initiative. de Boer IH, Tinker LF, Connelly S, et al. Diabetes Care. 2008;31:701&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18235052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of different doses of vitamin D(3) on markers of vascular health in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomised controlled trial. Witham MD, Dove FJ, Dryburgh M, Sugden JA, Morris AD, Struthers AD. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-010-1838-1. Diabetologia. 2010;53:2112&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20596692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of cholecalciferol as adjunctive therapy with insulin on protective immunologic profile and decline of residual &#x3b2;-cell function in new-onset type 1 diabetes mellitus. Gabbay MAL, Sato MN, Finazzo C, Duarte AJS, Dib SA. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2012;166:601&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22751874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of 12 weeks high dose vitamin D3 treatment on insulin sensitivity, beta cell function, and metabolic markers in patients with type 2 diabetes and vitamin D insufficiency - a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Kampmann U, Mosekilde L, Juhl C, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1016/j.metabol.2014.06.008. Metabolism. 2014;63:1115&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25044176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomised controlled trial of high dose vitamin D in recent-onset type 2 diabetes. Elkassaby S, Harrison LC, Mazzitelli N, Wentworth JM, Colman PG, Spelman T, Fourlanos S. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2014.08.030. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2014;106:576&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25438937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of therapeutic dose of vitamin d on serum adiponectin and glycemia in vitamin d-insufficient or deficient type 2 diabetic patients. Baziar N, Jafarian K, Shadman Z, Qorbani M, Khoshniat Nikoo M, Abd Mishani M. https://doi.org/10.5812/ircmj.21458 Iran Red Crescent Med J. 2014;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4270651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25593737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of combined calcium and vitamin D supplementation on insulin secretion, insulin sensitivity and &#x3b2;-cell function in multi-ethnic vitamin D-deficient adults at risk for type 2 diabetes: a pilot randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Gagnon C, Daly RM, Carpentier A, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0109607 PLoS One. 2014;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4192133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25299668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of moderate-dose vitamin D supplementation on insulin sensitivity in vitamin D-deficient non-Western immigrants in the Netherlands: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Oosterwerff MM, Eekhoff EM, Van Schoor NM, et al.  https://doi.org/10.3945/ajcn.113.069260. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;100:152&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24898240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of supplementary vitamin D on improvement of glycemic parameters in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus; a randomized double blind clinical trial. Nasri H, Behradmanesh S, Maghsoudi AR, Ahmadi A, Nasri P, Rafieian-Kopaei M. https://doi.org/10.12861/jrip.2014.10. J Renal Inj Prev. 2014;3:31&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4206038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25340161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of high-dose vitamin d repletion on glycemic control in African-American males with prediabetes and hypovitaminosis d. Barengolts E, Manickam B, Eisenberg Y, Akbar A, Kukreja S, Ciubotaru I. https://doi.org/10.4158/EP14548.OR. Endocr Pract. 2015;21:604&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4916973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25716637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of calcium plus vitamin d supplementation on anthropometric measurements and blood pressure in vitamin D insufficient people with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Tabesh M, Azadbakht L, Faghihimani E, Tabesh M, Esmaillzadeh A. J Am Coll Nutr. 2015;34:281&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25738212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of vitamin D supplementation on glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes (SUNNY trial): a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Krul-Poel YH, Westra S, ten Boekel E, et al. Diabetes Care. 2015;38:1420&#x2013;1426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25972575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomised controlled trial evaluating the impact of targeted vitamin D supplementation on endothelial function in type 2 diabetes mellitus: the DIMENSION trial. Dalan R, Liew H, Assam PN, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1177/1479164115621667. Diab Vasc Dis Res. 2016;13:192&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4834510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26818228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of vitamin D, K and calcium co-supplementation on carotid intima-media thickness and metabolic status in overweight type 2 diabetic patients with CHD. Asemi Z, Raygan F, Bahmani F, et al. Br J Nutr. 2016;116:286&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27198036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of vitamin D supplementation on wound healing and metabolic status in patients with diabetic foot ulcer: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Razzaghi R, Pourbagheri H, Momen-Heravi M, Bahmani F, Shadi J, Soleimani Z, Asemi Z. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2016.06.017. J Diabetes Complications. 2017;31:766&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27363929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D supplementation has no effect on insulin sensitivity or secretion in vitamin D-deficient, overweight or obese adults: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Mousa A, Naderpoor N, de Courten MP, et al.  https://doi.org/10.3945/ajcn.117.152736. Am J Clin Nutr. 2017;105:1372&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of vitamin D supplementation on oral glucose tolerance in individuals with low vitamin D status and increased risk for developing type 2 diabetes (EVIDENCE): a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Moreira-Lucas TS, Duncan AM, Rabasa-Lhoret R, Vieth R, Gibbs AL, Badawi A, Wolever TM. https://doi.org/10.1111/dom.12794. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2017;19:133&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of vitamin D&#x2083; supplementation on insulin sensitivity and secretion in subjects with type 2 diabetes. Gulseth HL, Wium C, Angel K, et al. Diabetes Care. 2017;40:872&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28468770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A high weekly dose of cholecalciferol and calcium supplement enhances weight loss and improves health biomarkers in obese women. Subih HS, Zueter Z, Obeidat BM, et al. Nutr Res. 2018;59:53&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of oral vitamin D on glycated haemoglobin (HbA1c) in type 2 diabetics having vitamin D deficiency - a randomized controlled trial. Khan DM, Jamil A, Randhawa FA, Butt NF, Malik U. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29885163/ J Pak Med Assoc. 2018;68:694&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29885163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of 6-month vitamin D supplementation on insulin sensitivity and secretion: a randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lemieux P, Weisnagel SJ, Caron AZ, et al. Eur J Endocrinol. 2019;181:287&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31344685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of vitamin D and curcuminoids supplementation on anthropometric measurements and blood pressure in type 2 diabetic patients with coexisting hypovitaminosis D: A double-blind, placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial. Ebrahimkhani S, Ghavamzadeh S, Mehdizadeh A. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnesp.2020.02.017. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2020;37:178&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The joint effect of energy reduction with calcium supplementation on the risk factors of type 2 diabetes in the overweight population: a two-year randomized controlled trial. Wei W, Jiang W, Gu W, et al.  https://doi.org/10.18632/aging.202485. Aging (Albany NY) 2021;13:5571&#x2013;5584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7950291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33589569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of vitamin D(3) supplementation on the incidence of type 2 diabetes in healthy older adults not at high risk for diabetes (FIND): a randomised controlled trial. Virtanen JK, Hantunen S, Kallio N, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-024-06336-9. Diabetologia. 2025;68:715&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11950068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39621103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D supplementation vs. placebo and incident type 2 diabetes in an ancillary study of the randomized Vitamin D and Omega-3 Trial. Tobias DK, Pradhan AD, Duran EK, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-58721-6. Nat Commun. 2025;16:3332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11978796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40199888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regulation of insulin exocytosis by calcium-dependent protein kinase C in beta cells. Trexler AJ, Taraska JW. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceca.2017.07.008. Cell Calcium. 2017;67:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29029784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D improved the free fatty-acid-induced insulin resistance in cultured C2C12 cells. Zhou QG, Hou FF, Guo ZJ, Liang M, Wang GB, Zhang X. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2008;24:459&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18551686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genetics and biology of vitamin D receptor polymorphisms. Uitterlinden AG, Fang Y, Van Meurs JB, Pols HA, Van Leeuwen JP. Gene. 2004;338:143&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15315818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Free 25-hydroxyvitamin D: impact of vitamin D binding protein assays on racial-genotypic associations. Nielson CM, Jones KS, Chun RF, et al. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2016;101:2226&#x2013;2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4870848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27007693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D deficiency in early life accelerates type 1 diabetes in non-obese diabetic mice. Giulietti A, Gysemans C, Stoffels K, et al. Diabetologia. 2004;47:451&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14758446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regulation of glucose homeostasis by GLP-1. Nadkarni P, Chepurny OG, Holz GG. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci. 2014;121:23&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin D and genomic stability. Chatterjee M. Mutat Res. 2017;771:99&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11295155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>