<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40819070</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing a community-based intervention to improve help-seeking for depression care: study protocol for a randomized factorial trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>293</StartPage><MedlinePgn>293</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">293</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-025-09014-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Depression is a common mental health issue that can be effectively managed in primary and community health care settings. However, there is a significant gap between the number of individuals in need of care and those who actually receive treatment, with the greatest gap in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs). Although efforts have been made in LMICs to improve access to mental health services by addressing supply-side barriers, there has been less attention to demand-side obstacles. On the demand side, factors such as stigma, negative attitudes, and limited awareness of available services lead to underutilization of mental health services. This protocol describes a study of active ingredients of a community-based intervention aimed at enhancing help-seeking for depression care in Nepal, a LMIC with low rates of mental health treatment seeking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study will take place in two municipalities in eastern Nepal, utilizing the Multiphase Optimization Strategy (MOST) with a 2&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;3 factorial randomized controlled trial design. Female Community Health Volunteers will be trained to identify individuals with depression using the Community Informant Detection Tool, a proven community-based strategy for proactive case detection, and subsequently implement the Gain Life intervention, which aims to promote help-seeking for depression care. The Gain Life intervention comprises four components: (i) information about depression, (ii) awareness of available services, (iii) stigma reduction by dispelling myths and facts about depression, and (iv) a life transformation story. The study will target the adult population, with eligibility criteria including being 18&#xa0;years or older, residing in specific municipalities, meeting the CIDT threshold for depression, providing consent, and having proficiency in Nepali. The sample size will be 288, with the primary outcome being help-seeking behaviour.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this protocol paper, we outline how the MOST framework can optimize a community-based intervention aimed at improving help-seeking for depression care. The findings from this study will guide decisions on whether to proceed with a fully randomized controlled trial or conduct an additional optimization study to finalize the intervention components.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT06574074. Registered on 27 August 2024.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luitel</LastName><ForeName>Nagendra P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8291-0205</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Transcultural Psychosocial Organization (TPO) Nepal, Baluwatar, Kathmandu, Nepal. luitelnp@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Global Mental Health Equity, Department of Psychiatry, The George Washington University, Washington, DC, USA. luitelnp@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kohrt</LastName><ForeName>Brandon A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3829-4820</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Transcultural Psychosocial Organization (TPO) Nepal, Baluwatar, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Global Mental Health Equity, Department of Psychiatry, The George Washington University, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lamichhane</LastName><ForeName>Bishnu</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Transcultural Psychosocial Organization (TPO) Nepal, Baluwatar, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhardwaj</LastName><ForeName>Anvita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5622-9128</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pscyhological and Brain Sciences, Boston University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gautam</LastName><ForeName>Kamal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9401-9359</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Transcultural Psychosocial Organization (TPO) Nepal, Baluwatar, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordans</LastName><ForeName>Mark Jd</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5925-8039</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Transcultural Psychosocial Organization (TPO) Nepal, Baluwatar, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Service and Population Research Department, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, Centre for Global Mental Health, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06574074</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>222001_Z_20_Z</GrantID><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009390" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Nepal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="Y">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057545" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Stigma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003156" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community Mental Health Services</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066505" MajorTopicYN="Y">Help-Seeking Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003150" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community Health Workers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Help-seeking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiphase optimization strategy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nepal</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study has received ethical approval from the Nepal Health Research Council (NHRC) (Ref number: 184&#x2013;2024). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40819070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12358067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-025-09014-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-025-09014-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andrade LH, Alonso J, Mneimneh Z, Wells JE, Al-Hamzawi A, Borges G, Bromet E, Bruffaerts R, de Girolamo G, de Graaf R, Florescu S, Gureje O, Hinkov HR, Hu C, Huang Y, Hwang I, Jin R, Karam EG, Kovess-Masfety V, Levinson D, Matschinger H, O&#x2019;Neill S, Posada-Villa J, Sagar R, Sampson NA, Sasu C, Stein DJ, Takeshima T, Viana MC, Xavier M, Kessler RC. Barriers to mental health treatment: results from the WHO world mental health surveys. Psychol Med. 2014;44(6):1303&#x2013;17. 10.1017/s0033291713001943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4100460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin MP. Antenatal screening and early intervention for &#x201c;perinatal&#x201d; distress, depression and anxiety: where to from here? Arch Womens Ment Health. 2004;7(1):1&#x2013;6. 10.1007/s00737-003-0034-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14963727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera AZ, Torres LD, Munoz RF. Prevention of depression: the state of the science at the beginning of the 21st century. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2007;19(6):655&#x2013;70. 10.1080/09540260701797894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18092243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter AJ, Charlson FJ, Somerville AJ, Whiteford HA. Mental disorders as risk factors: assessing the evidence for the global burden of disease study. BMC Med. 2011;9:134. 10.1186/1741-7015-9-134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3305628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22176705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenman NF, Luitel NP, Mall S, Jordans MJD. Demand and access to mental health services: a qualitative formative study in Nepal. BMC Int Health Hum Rights. 2014;14:22. 10.1186/1472-698x-14-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25084826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AW, Tetzlaff JM, Altman DG, Laupacis A, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Krle&#x17e;a-Jeri&#x107; K, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Mann H, Dickersin K, Berlin JA, Dor&#xe9; CJ, Parulekar WR, Summerskill WSM, Groves T, Schulz KF, Sox HC, Rockhold FW, Rennie D, Moher D. SPIRIT 2013 statement: defining standard protocol items for clinical trials. Ann Intern Med. 2013;158(3):200&#x2013;7. 10.7326/0003-4819-158-3-201302050-00583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5114123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23295957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaulagain A, Pacione L, Abdulmalik J, Hughes P, Oksana K, Chumak S, Mendoza J, Avetisyan K, Ghazaryan G, Gasparyan K, Chkonia E, Servili C, Chowdhury N, Pinchuk I, Belfar M, Guerrero A, Panteleeva L, Skokauskas N. WHO mental health gap action programme intervention guide (mhGAP-IG): the first pre-service training study. Int J Ment Health Syst. 2020;14: 47. 10.1186/s13033-020-00379-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7325034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhary N, Anand A, Dimidjian S, Shinde S, Weobong B, Balaji M, Patel V. The Healthy Activity Program lay counsellor delivered treatment for severe depression in India: systematic development and randomised evaluation. Br J Psychiatry. 2015.&#xa0;10.1192/bjp.bp.114.161075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4816974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26494875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen H, Griffiths KM, Gulliver A, Clack D, Kljakovic M, Wells L. Models in the delivery of depression care: a systematic review of randomised and controlled intervention trials. BMC Fam Pract. 2008;9:25. 10.1186/1471-2296-9-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2390560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18454878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement S, Schauman O, Graham T, Maggioni F, Evans-Lacko S, Bezborodovs N, Morgan C, R&#xfc;sch N, Brown JSL, Thornicroft G. What is the impact of mental health-related stigma on help-seeking? A systematic review of quantitative and qualitative studies. Psychol Med. 2015;45(1):11&#x2013;27. 10.1017/s0033291714000129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24569086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement S, Williams P, Farrelly S, Hatch SL, Schauman O, Jeffery D, Henderson RC, Thornicroft G. Mental health-related discrimination as a predictor of low engagement with mental health services. Psychiatr Serv. 2015;66(2):171&#x2013;6. 10.1176/appi.ps.201300448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25642612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codony M, Alonso J, Almansa J, Bernert S, de Girolamo G, de Graaf R, Kessler RC. Perceived need for mental health care and service use among adults in Western Europe: results of the ESEMeD project. Psychiatr Serv. 2009;60(8):1051&#x2013;8. 10.1176/appi.ps.60.8.1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19648192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins LM. Optimization of behavioral, biobehavioral, and biomedical interventions. The Multiphase Optimization Strategy (MOST). 2018. Cham, Switzerland: Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins LM, Baker TB, Mermelstein RJ, Piper ME, Jorenby DE, Smith SS, Christiansen BA, Schlam TR, Cook JW, Fiore MC. The multiphase optimization strategy for engineering effective tobacco use interventions. Ann Behav Med. 2011;41(2):208&#x2013;26. 10.1007/s12160-010-9253-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3053423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21132416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig P, Dieppe P, Macintyre S, Michie S, Nazareth I, Petticrew M. Developing and evaluating complex interventions: the new Medical Research Council guidance. Int J Nurs Stud. 2013;50(5):587&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2012.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson DA, Grant BF, Stinson FS, Chou PS. Estimating the effect of help-seeking on achieving recovery from alcohol dependence. Addiction. 2006;101(6):824&#x2013;34. 10.1111/j.1360-0443.2006.01433.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16696626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Pino-Sede&#xf1;o T, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Pacheco H, Gonz&#xe1;lez de Le&#xf3;n B, Serrano-P&#xe9;rez P, Acosta Artiles FJ, Valcarcel-Nazco C, Trujillo-Mart&#xed;n MM. Effectiveness of interventions to improve adherence to antidepressant medication in patients with depressive disorders: a cluster randomized controlled trial. Front Pub Health. 2024;12:1320159. 10.3389/fpubh.2024.1320159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11022850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38633230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devkota G, Basnet P, Thapa B, Subedi M. Factors affecting utilization of mental health services from primary health care (PHC) facilities of western hilly district of Nepal. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(4): e0250694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards JR, Lambert LS. Methods for integrating moderation and mediation: a general analytical framework using moderated path analysis. Psychol Methods. 2007;12(1):1&#x2013;22. 10.1037/1082-989x.12.1.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17402809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans-Lacko S, Aguilar-Gaxiola S, Al-Hamzawi A, Alonso J, Benjet C, Bruffaerts R, Chiu WT, Florescu S, de Girolamo G, Gureje O, Haro JM, He Y, Hu C, Karam EG, Kawakami N, Lee S, Lund C, Kovess-Masfety V, Levinson D, Navarro-Mateu F, Pennell BE, Sampson NA, Scott KM, Tachimori H, ten Have M, Viana MC, Williams DR, Wojtyniak BJ, Zarkov Z, Kessler RC, Chatterji S, Thornicroft G. Socio-economic variations in the mental health treatment gap for people with anxiety, mood, and substance use disorders: results from the WHO world mental health (WMH) surveys. Psychol Med. 2018;48(9):1560&#x2013;71. 10.1017/s0033291717003336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans L, Chang A, Dehon J, Streb M, Bruce M, Clark E, Handal P. The relationships between perceived mental illness prevalence, mental illness stigma, and attitudes toward help-seeking. Curr Psychol. 2023. 10.1007/s12144-023-04329-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9975862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37359578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari AJ, Charlson FJ, Norman RE, Patten SB, Freedman G, Murray CJL, Vos T, Whiteford HA. Burden of depressive disorders by country, sex, age, and year: findings from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. PLoS Med. 2013;10(11): e1001547. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1001547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3818162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24223526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin NI, Bradley NG, Lohr KN, Meltzer-Brody S, Gartlehner G, Swinson T. Perinatal depression: a systematic review of prevalence and incidence. Obstet Gynecol. 2005;106(5, Part 1):1071&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbody S, Richards D, Brealey S, Hewitt C. Screening for depression in medical settings with the patient health questionnaire (PHQ): a diagnostic meta-analysis. J Gen Intern Med. 2007;22(11):1596&#x2013;602. 10.1007/s11606-007-0333-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2219806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg PE, Fournier AA, Sisitsky T, Pike CT, Kessler RC. The economic burden of adults with major depressive disorder in the United States (2005 and 2010). J Clin Psychiatry. 2015;76(2):155&#x2013;62. 10.4088/JCP.14m09298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25742202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulliver A, Griffiths KM, Christensen H. Perceived barriers and facilitators to mental health help-seeking in young people: a systematic review. BMC Psychiatry. 2010;10: 113. 10.1186/1471-244x-10-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3022639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21192795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulliver A, Griffiths KM, Christensen H, Brewer JL. A systematic review of help-seeking interventions for depression, anxiety and general psychological distress. BMC Psychiatry. 2012;12: 81. 10.1186/1471-244x-12-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3464688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22799879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holvast F, Massoudi B, Oude Voshaar RC, Verhaak PFM. Non-pharmacological treatment for depressed older patients in primary care: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(9): e0184666. 10.1371/journal.pone.0184666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5609744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28938015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iswanto ED, Ayubi D. The relationship of mental health literacy to help seeking behavior: systematic review. J Soc Res. 2023. 10.55324/josr.v2i3.726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack-Ide IO, Uys L. Barriers to mental health services utilization in the Niger Delta region of Nigeria: service users&#x2019; perspectives. Pan Afr Med J. 2013;14:159. 10.11604/pamj.2013.14.159.1970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3683509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23785564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordans M JD, Kohrt BA, Luitel NP, Komproe IH, Lund C. Accuracy of proactive case finding for mental disorders by community informants in Nepal. Br J Psychiatry. 2015;207(6):501&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26450582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordans MJD, Kohrt BA, Luitel NP, Lund C, Komproe IH. Proactive community case-finding to facilitate treatment seeking for mental disorders, Nepal. Bull World Health Organ. 2017;95(7):531&#x2013;6. 10.2471/blt.16.189282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5487974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28670018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordans MJD, Kohrt BA, Sangraula M, Turner EL, Wang X, Shrestha P, Ghimire R, van&#x2019;t Hof E, Bryant RA, Dawson KS, Marahatta K, Luitel NP, van Ommeren M. Effectiveness of group problem management plus, a brief psychological intervention for adults affected by humanitarian disasters in Nepal: a cluster randomized controlled trial. PLoS Med. 2021;18(6):e1003621. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8211182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34138875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordans MJD, Luitel NP, Kohrt BA, Rathod SD, Garman EC, De Silva M, Komproe IH, Patel V, Lund C. Community-, facility-, and individual-level outcomes of a district mental healthcare plan in a low-resource setting in Nepal: a population-based evaluation. PLoS Med. 2019;16(2): e1002748. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1002748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6375569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30763321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzman MA, Anand L, Furtado M, Chokka P. Food for thought: understanding the value, variety and usage of management algorithms for major depressive disorder. Psychiatry Res. 2014;220(Suppl 1):S3-14. 10.1016/s0165-1781(14)70002-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25539872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenfield SA, Philip EJ, Phillips SM, Meyerhardt JA, Chan JM, Atreya CE, Kim M-O, Harris Q, Steiding P, Macaire G, McCullough ML, Piawah S, Johnson WY, Kurttila FA, Lewis WL, Pesmen C, Watson Y, Van Blarigan EL. Optimizing intervention tools to improve nutrition and physical activity for colorectal cancer survivors (tools to be fit): study protocol of a randomized factorial experiment. Contemp Clin Trials. 2022;123: 107009. 10.1016/j.cct.2022.107009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10561599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36396066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keynejad R, Spagnolo J, Thornicroft G. WHO mental health gap action programme (mhGAP) intervention guide: updated systematic review on evidence and impact. Evid Based Ment Health. 2021;24(3):124&#x2013;30. 10.1136/ebmental-2021-300254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8311089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knol MJ, Twisk JW, Beekman AT, Heine RJ, Snoek FJ, Pouwer F. Depression as a risk factor for the onset of type 2 diabetes mellitus. A meta-analysis. Diabetologia. 2006;49(5):837&#x2013;45. 10.1007/s00125-006-0159-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16520921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt BA. Vulnerable social groups in post-conflict settings: a mixed-methods policy analysis and epidemiology study of caste and psychological morbidity in Nepal. Intervention. 2009;7:239&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt BA, Jordans MJD, Turner EL, Rai S, Gurung D, Dhakal M, Bhardwaj A, Lamichhane J, Singla DR, Lund C, Patel V, Luitel NP, Sikkema KJ. Collaboration with people with lived experience of mental illness to reduce stigma and improve primary care services: a pilot cluster randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(11):e2131475. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.31475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8567115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34730821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt BA, Jordans MJD, Turner EL, Sikkema KJ, Luitel NP, Rai S, Singla DR, Lamichhane J, Lund C, Patel V. Reducing stigma among healthcare providers to improve mental health services (RESHAPE): protocol for a pilot cluster randomized controlled trial of a stigma reduction intervention for training primary healthcare workers in Nepal. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2018;4: 36. 10.1186/s40814-018-0234-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5781273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt BA, Luitel NP, Acharya P, Jordans MJD. Detection of depression in low resource settings: validation of the patient health questionnaire (PHQ-9) and cultural concepts of distress in Nepal. BMC Psychiatry. 2016;16:58. 10.1186/s12888-016-0768-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4782581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26951403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt BA, Turner EL, Gurung D, Wang X, Neupane M, Luitel NP, Kartha MR, Poudyal A, Singh R, Rai S, Baral PP, McCutchan S, Gronholm PC, Hanlon C, Lempp H, Lund C, Thornicroft G, Gautam K, Jordans MJD. Implementation strategy in collaboration with people with lived experience of mental illness to reduce stigma among primary care providers in Nepal (RESHAPE): protocol for a type 3 hybrid implementation effectiveness cluster randomized controlled trial. Implement Sci. 2022;17(1): 39. 10.1186/s13012-022-01202-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9205129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35710491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt BA, Turner EL, Rai S, Bhardwaj A, Sikkema KJ, Adelekun A, Dhakal M, Luitel NP, Lund C, Patel V, Jordans MJD. Reducing mental illness stigma in healthcare settings: proof of concept for a social contact intervention to address what matters most for primary care providers. Soc Sci Med. 2020;250: 112852. 10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.112852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32135459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakshmana G, Sangeetha V, Pandey V. Community perception of accessibility and barriers to utilizing mental health services. J Educ Health Promot. 2022;11:56. 10.4103/jehp.jehp_342_21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8974990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35372598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luitel NP, Breuer E, Adhikari A, Kohrt BA, Lund C, Komproe IH, Jordans MJD. Process evaluation of a district mental healthcare plan in Nepal: a mixed-methods case study. BJPsych Open. 2020;6(4):e77. 10.1192/bjo.2020.60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32718381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luitel NP, Jordans MJD, Kohrt BA, Rathod SD, Komproe IH. Treatment gap and barriers for mental health care: a cross-sectional community survey in Nepal. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(8): e0183223. 10.1371/journal.pone.0183223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5560728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28817734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luitel NP, Jordans MJD, Sapkota RP, Tol WA, Kohrt BA, Thapa SB, Komproe IH, Sharma B. Conflict and mental health: a cross-sectional epidemiological study in Nepal. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2013;48(2):183&#x2013;93. 10.1007/s00127-012-0539-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKinnon DP, Fairchild AJ, Fritz MS. Mediation analysis. Annu Rev Psychol. 2007;58:593&#x2013;614. 10.1146/annurev.psych.58.110405.085542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2819368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16968208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhmud A, Thornicroft G, Gronholm PC. Indirect social contact interventions to reduce mental health-related stigma in low- and middle-income countries: systematic review. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2022;31: e79. 10.1017/s2045796022000622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9677443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36348492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus M, Yasamy MT, van Ommeren M, Chisholm D, Saxena S. Depression: a global public health concern. World Health Organization Paper on depression. 2012:6-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlister FA, Straus SE, Sackett DL, Altman DG. Analysis and reporting of factorial trials: a systematic review. JAMA. 2003;289(19):2545&#x2013;53. 10.1001/jama.289.19.2545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12759326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaren T, Peter LJ, Tomczyk S, Muehlan H, Schomerus G, Schmidt S. The seeking mental health care model: prediction of help-seeking for depressive symptoms by stigma and mental illness representations. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):69. 10.1186/s12889-022-14937-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9831378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36627597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta N, Clement S, Marcus E, Stona AC, Bezborodovs N, Evans-Lacko S, Palacios J, Docherty M, Barley E, Rose D, Koschorke M, Shidhaye R, Henderson C, Thornicroft G. Evidence for effective interventions to reduce mental health-related stigma and discrimination in the medium and long term: systematic review. Br J Psychiatry. 2015;207(5):377&#x2013;84. 10.1192/bjp.bp.114.151944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4629070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26527664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mental Health Innovation Network. WHO Special Initiative for Mental Health. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miret M, Ayuso-Mateos JL, Sanchez-Moreno J, Vieta E. Depressive disorders and suicide: epidemiology, risk factors, and burden. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2013;37(10 Pt 1):2372&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2013.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23313644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MoHP. National Mental Health Strategy and Action Plan-2077. Kathmandu Ministry of Health and Population. 2077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshki M, Baloochi Beydokhti T, Cheravi K. The effect of educational intervention on prevention of postpartum depression: an application of health locus of control. J Clin Nurs. 2014;23(15&#x2013;16):2256&#x2013;63. 10.1111/jocn.12505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24329943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mugisha J, Hanlon C, Knizek BL, Ssebunnya J, Vancampfort D, Kinyanda E, Kigozi F. The experience of mental health service users in health system strengthening: lessons from Uganda. Int J Ment Health Syst. 2019;13: 60. 10.1186/s13033-019-0316-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6728966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31516548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muth&#xe9;n LK, Muth&#xe9;n BO. <i>Mplus User</i>&#x2019;<i>s Guide</i>. 6th ed. Los Angeles, CA: Muth&#xe9;n &amp; Muth&#xe9;n; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation> National Statistics Office. National Population and Housing Census 2021 Accessed through https://censusnepal.cbs.gov.np/results/literacy on 30 April 2023. 2023. Kathmandu, Nepal: Government of Nepal, Office of the Prime Minister and Council of Ministers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHRC. Report of National Mental Health Survey 2020. Kathmandu Nepal Health Research Council, Government of Nepal. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel V, Simon G, Chowdhary N, Kaaya S, Araya R. Packages of care for depression in low- and middle-income countries. PLoS Med. 2009;6(10): e1000159. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1000159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2747016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19806179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy MS. Depression: the disorder and the burden. Indian J Psychol Med. 2010;32(1):1&#x2013;2. 10.4103/0253-7176.70510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickwood DJ, Braithwaite VA. Social-psychological factors affecting help-seeking for emotional problems. Soc Sci Med. 1994;39(4):563&#x2013;72. 10.1016/0277-9536(94)90099-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7973856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickwood DJ, Deane FP, Wilson CJ. When and how do young people seek professional help for mental health problems? Med J Aust. 2007;187(S7):S35-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saade S, Lamarche AP, Khalaf T, Makke S, Legg A. What barriers could impede access to mental health services for children and adolescents in Africa? A scoping review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23(1):348. 10.1186/s12913-023-09294-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10080850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnyder N, Panczak R, Groth N, Schultze-Lutter F. Association between mental health-related stigma and active help-seeking: systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2017;210(4):261&#x2013;8. 10.1192/bjp.bp.116.189464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ten Have M, de Graaf R, Ormel J, Vilagut G, Kovess V, Alonso J. Are attitudes towards mental health help-seeking associated with service use? Results from the European study of epidemiology of mental disorders. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2010;45(2):153&#x2013;63. 10.1007/s00127-009-0050-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19381427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornicroft G, Mehta N, Clement S, Evans-Lacko S, Doherty M, Rose D, Koschorke M, Shidhaye R, O&#x2019;Reilly C, Henderson C. Evidence for effective interventions to reduce mental-health-related stigma and discrimination. Lancet. 2016;387(10023):1123&#x2013;32. 10.1016/s0140-6736(15)00298-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26410341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhaya N, Regmi U, Gurung D, Luitel NP, Petersen I, Jordans MJD, Komproe IH. Mental health and psychosocial support services in primary health care in Nepal: perceived facilitating factors, barriers and strategies for improvement. BMC Psychiatry. 2020;20(1):64. 10.1186/s12888-020-2476-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7020582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32054462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldmann T, Staiger T, Oexle N, R&#xfc;sch N. Mental health literacy and help-seeking among unemployed people with mental health problems. J Ment Health. 2020;29(3):270&#x2013;6. 10.1080/09638237.2019.1581342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weissman MM, Olfson M. Depression in women: implications for health care research. Science. 1995;269(5225):799&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7638596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteford HA, Degenhardt L, Rehm J, Baxter AJ, Ferrari AJ, Erskine HE, Charlson FJ, Norman RE, Flaxman AD, Burstein R, Murray CJL, Vos T, Johns N. Global burden of disease attributable to mental and substance use disorders: findings from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet. 2013;382(9904):1575&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23993280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. mhGAP intervention guide for mental, neurological and substance use disorders in non-specialized health settings: mental health Gap Action Programme (mhGAP) &#x2013; version 1.0. Geneva, Swizerland: WHO. 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23741783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Depression and other common mental disorders: global health estimates. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>